<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, FEBRUARY 8, 1845. N  6.
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="cit">
            
            <span class="quote">Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the busi-
                ness of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by con-
                sent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something
               worse.
            </span>
            
            <div class="bibl">
               <span class="person" id="jlocke">Locke</span>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p1">
            
            <p>Poems by Sir 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Edward Lytton Bulwer</span>. Edited by 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">C. Donald
                  Macleod
               </span>. New York: Farmer &amp; Daggers, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">C. Donald Macleod</span>, whose name is no doubt familiar to the readers of the  Lady s Book  and  Graham s
               Magazine,  has favored the public with a collection of poems
               by Sir 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Edward Lytton Bulwer</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p> The work here offered,  says the compiler,  contains, I
               believe, the first general collection. ... He has published
               two or three volumes of verse, none of which were well received.  The Rebel  and the  Siamese Twins  met quick
               oblivion, and indeed deserved no better fate. In his last publication,  Eva and Other Poems,  there were many pieces of
               exquisite beauty; but there was heaviness enough in the
               book to sink all. ... This collection, made from Novel,
               Drama, and Poems, embraces nearly all that is worthy of
                his reputation. 
            </p>
            
            <p>These words, from Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> s Preface, affect us as an
               ill omen of the book. We fancy that we see in them a singular deficiency of straight thinking. We profess little faith
               in the discrimination of a compiler who begins with calling
               his compilation a  general  one, and proceeds in the same
               breath to state that he has omitted every thing from this general compilation that has been considered worth publishing
               at all by the author whose writings he has compiled.
            </p>
            
            <p>Frankly, Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> is young in letters, has given no
               special evidence of even what is called general ability none
               at all of critical ability. We shall be pardoned, therefore,
               for accepting only cum grano salis, his mere dicta that the
                Rebel  and the  Siamese Twins   deserved no better fate
               than quick oblivion  that there  was heaviness enough to
               sink all  in Eva and other Poems or that  this collection,
               made from Novel, Drama, and Poems, embraces nearly all
               that is worthy of the reputation  of 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Bulwer</span>. What is here
               so roundly asserted, may or may not be true. We have no
               reference either to its truth or its fallacy. What we wish to
               insinuate is, that Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span>, being Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> and no
               more, should, in common justice, have either given us all
               the poems of the author, or something that should have
               worn at least the semblance of an argument in objection to
               the poems omitted. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> we say, should have done
               one of these two things, for the sake of the commonest
               common sense for the sake of Sir 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Edward Lytton Bulwer</span> 
               for the sake of the public for the sake of himself (Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Ma</span>cleod) and for the sake of that hope with which he so happily makes an end of his Preface the hope  that a ray from
               the Glory which surrounds the Master may wander toward
               the Alcolyte. 
            </p>
            
            <p>As a common rule, to be sure, rays are about the only
               things in the world which never wander at all. By way of
                showing, however, that it is not to any particular dogma of
               Mr. M. that we object, nor to any particular set of his dogmas, but to the principle of dogmatizing in general, we are
               willing to admit that we coincide with him in one half of his
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>opinion about the poems of 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Bulwer</span>. We think as he does,
               (Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span>,) that the omitted compositions were scarcely
               worth including in a book; but we go even a few steps farther, and maintain that the effusions so cavalierly treated
               deserved the treatment much less than those which have
               been honored with a niche in the temple of the American
               compiler. The matter, indeed, seems to stand thus. What
               
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Bulwer</span> thought worth collecting, he collected. What he
               collected Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> has pronounced unworthy collection.
               The author, in our opinion, knew better the state of the case
               than the editor; but neither appears aware of the fact, that
               Sir 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Edward</span> is more estimable as a judge of poetry than as a
               poet, and that, to come at once to the point, he has never
               written a poem at all.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is but fair to mention, nevertheless, that this opinion of
               ours, honestly entertained and deliberately expressed, is in
               direct opposition to that of a somewhat celebrated man who
               is quoted in the Introduction of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span>.  The author
               of Tremaine says of him,  writes Mr. M:   He is the
               most accomplished writer of the most accomplished era of
               English letters: practising all styles and classes of composition, and eminent ia all Novelist, Dramatist, Poet, Historian, Moral Philosopher, Essayist, Critic, Political Pamphleteer; in each superior to all others, and only rivalled in each
               by himself  that is to say, we presume, that
               
               <br></br> None but himself can be his parallel. 
            </p>
            
            <p>But if Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> is serious in thinking that the author
               of Tremaine (which may be co sidered as the quintessence
               of prose) did not intend to be bitterly satirical when he penned all this about the author of the  Siamese Twins,  we
               have only to regret that a gentleman who edits a respectable
               looking book should labor under so painful an hallucination.
               We mean to say that Mr. 
               <span class="person">Ward</span>, (who although he did write
               De Vereis by no means a fool,) could never have put to
               paper, in his sober senses, anything half so absurd as the
               paragraph above quoted, without stopping at every third
               word to hold his sides or thrust his pocket-handkerchief in
               his mouth.
            </p>
            
            <p>If Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span>, however, will insist upon the serious intention, we have to remark that the opinion is the mere opinion of a writer remarkable for no other good trait than that
               of putting his readers decorously to sleep according to rules
               Addisonian, and with the least possible loss of labor and
               time. But as the mere opinion of even a Jeffrey, a Gifford,
               or a Macaulay, we have an inalienable right to meet it with
               another. As a novelist, then, 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Bulwer</span>is far more than respectable although he has produced few novels equal and
               none superior to Robinson Crusoe to one or two of Smollet s to one or two of Fielding s to Miss 
               <span class="person" id="fburney">Burney</span>s Evelina  to two or three of the Misses 
               <span class="person" id="jporter">Porter</span> s to five or six
               of Miss 
               <span class="person" id="medgeworth">Edgeworth</span> s to three or four of 
               <span class="person" id="wgodwin">Godwin</span> s to the
               majority of 
               <span class="person" id="wscott">Scott</span> s to one or two of 
               <span class="person" id="bdisraeli">D Israeli</span> s to three or
               four of 
               <span class="person" id="cdickens">Dickens</span> to the  Ellen Wareham  of 
               <span class="person" id="ajsullivan">Mrs. Sullivan</span>,
               or to the Ellen Middleton of Lady 
               <span class="person" id="gcfullerton">Georgiana Fullerton</span>.
               From the list of foreign novels we could readily select a hundred which he could neither have written nor conceived for
               his life. As a dramatist he deserves more credit, although
               he receives less. His "Richelieu,   Money,  and  Duchesse
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page82"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>de la Valiere,  have done much in the way of opening the
               public eyes to the true value of what is superciliously termed  stage-effect  in the hands of one able to manage it.
               But if commendable at this point, his dramas fail egregiously at others: so that, upon the whole, he can be said to have
               written a good play only when we think of him in connexion with the still more contemptible "old-dramatist imitators who are his contemporaries and friends. As historian
               he is sufficiently dignified, sufficiently ornate, and more than
               sufficiently self-sufficient and ill-informed. His  Athens 
               would have received an Etonian prize, and it has all the
               happy air of an Etonian prize essay revamped. His political
               pamphlets are very good as political pamphlets, and very disreputable as any thing else. His essays leave no doubt upon
               any body s mind that with the writer they have been essays
               indeed. His criticism is really beneath contempt. His moral philosophy is the most ridiculous of all the moral philosophies that ever have been imagined upon earth.
            </p>
            
            <p> The men of sense,  says 
               <span class="person" id="cahelvetius">Helvetius</span>,  those idols of the
               unthinking, are very far inferior to the men of passions. It
               is the strong passions which, rescuing us from Sloth, can
               alone impart to us that continuous and earnest attention
               necessary to great intellectual efforts. 
            </p>
            
            <p>When the Swiss philosopher here speaks of inferiority,
               he has reference to inferiority in worldly success. By his
                men of sense,  he intends indolent men of genius. And
               Sir 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Edward Lytton Bulwer</span> is emphatically one of the  men
               of passions  contemplated in theapopthegm. His passions,
               with opportunities, have alone made him what he is. Urged
               by a rabid ambition to do much, in doing nothing he would
               assuredly have proved himself an idiot. Something he has
               done. While aiming at Crichton, he has hit the target an
               inch or two above 
               <span class="person" id="whainsworth">Harrison Ainsworth</span>. Not to such intellects belong the honors of universality. His works bear
               about them the unmistakeable indications of mere talent :
               talent, we grant, of an unusual order, and nurtured to its
               extreme of development with a very tender and elaborate
               care. Nevertheless it is talent still. Genius it is not. And
               the proof is, that while we often fancy ourselves about to
               be enkindled beneath its influence, fairly enkindled we never
               are. That 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Bulwer</span> is no poet, follows as a corollary from
               what has already been said. To speak of a poet without
               genius is merely to put forth a contradiction in terms.
            </p>
            
            <p>In taking up Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> s volume, of course we had no
               intention to be elaborate. We have nothing to prove or to
               disprove. The matter has been long since thoroughly settled to our hands by that strong popular instinct which,
               when absolutely untrammeled in its development, is as unerring as the sun. What few words we have farther to say
               it will be unnecessary to say otherwise than at random.
            </p>
            
            <p>Beyond the obvious external form, there is really nothing
               distinctive between what Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> calls the poetry of
               
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Bulwer</span>, and what the world has agreed to understand as his
               prose.  The Ill-omened Marriage,  which is the longest
               composition of the book before us, is only not exactly similar
               to any one of the author s novels, because no one of the latter has been done into very indifferent verse. In each we
               find the same intermingled merit and demerit a language
               glowing and sonorous, but inflated and involute a plot skil
               fully conceived, but wrought into development with artificiality rather than with art a mannered epigrammatism of
               tone that has been termed  brilliant  for want of a more
               definite epithet a general interjectional rhetoricianism such
               as we might imagine would have delighted 
               <span class="person">Curran</span> when
               drunk an absolutely ludicrous array of metaphor run mad
                and a continuous strain of didacticism, always obtrusive,
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>sometimes entertaining, often equivocal, now and then sophistical, frequently preposterous, but at no time failing to wear
               those habiliments of apparent profundity which were wont
               so cleverly to disguise the no-meaning of the nonsense-verses
               of 
               <span class="person" id="gdsdubartas">Du Bartas</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>In his rhythm in his sole distinctive feature between his
               poetry and his prose 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Bulwer</span> s generally elaborate art seems
               to have abandoned or to have misguided him altogether. He
               has contented himself with the dryest and most insensate
               technicalities of the schools. Clearly, he has no capacity
               for the construction of true rhythm, and no ear for its appreciation when constructed. All is hard, stiff, pedantic, common-place, and artificial, without the ars celare artem which
               only the divine instinct of the true Genius can bestow.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is by no means our intention to accuse Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> of
               having undertaken a task above his powers, but i n this topic
                (of rhythm) there are certain passages of his Introduction
               which have amazed us in no little degree. What, for example, are we to think of a paragraph such as this?
            </p>
            
            <p>In versification he is always happy in some kinds peculiar, as in  
               <span class="person" id="jrmazarin">Mazarin</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="amchenier">Andre Chenier</span>,  the  Last Crusader, 
               and others. In these the music is stately and solemn in the
               music of a march. 
            </p>
            
            <p>On reading this we turned with some curiosity to  
               <span class="person" id="jrmazarin">Maza</span>rin  and "
               <span class="person" id="amchenier">Andre Chenier</span>." The versification in these poems
               is identical. We give a specimen from the latter:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>And must I die so soon? sighed forth the young man unresigned,
               
               <br></br>And leave this pleasant world before a name is left behind?
               
               <br></br>I feel the glorious something stir within my burning brain,
               
               <br></br>That tells me what my life would be a prophet and in vain!
               
            </div>
            
            <p>The metre here would be called, in the ridiculous Greek
               prosodies, iambic heptameter acatalectic. In plain English
               it consists of seven feet, each foot being a short syllable succeeded by a long, and this is one of the very commonest metres in the world; the iambic rhythm that is to say, the
               mere succession of iambuses, is unquestionably the most usual of all. But the line employed by 
               <span class="person" id="eblytton">Bulwer</span> in the present
               instance, if we add a single short syllable at the end, is identically that of the  Oh, Miss 
               <span class="person">Bailey</span>  ballad of which we
               transcribe the first line:
            </p>
            
            <br></br>A captain bold of Halifax who dwelt in country quarters.
            
            <p>Now Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span>maintains that Miss Bailey is peculiar; but if so the only peculiarity about her lies in her tripping and frisky character the character universally and justly attributed to this metre in the prosodies. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span>,
               however, not satisfied with having it "peculiar," insists upon making it "stately and solemn the music of a march. 
            </p>
            
            <p>We might comment, perhaps, on some other niaiseries, or
               at least on some other inadvertences of our compiler, and we
               might find much fault with many of the individual poems
               compiled, as well as designate among them a vast number
               of individual beauties that are truly poetical in themselves,
               although involved in a medley of mere prose. But in doing
               all this we should demonstrate only what has long ceased to
                need any demonstration.
            </p>
            
            <p>We dismiss the volume, therefore, with a request which
               will not be complied with that in any future edition Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="cdmacleod">Macleod</span> will cut out his Introduction, and give us in place of
               it, the poems of Bulwer which have been, whether rightfully
               or wrongfully, have been omitted.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="p2">
            
            <p>Why a National Literature cannot flourish in the United
               States of North America. By 
               <span class="person" id="jrochietti">Joseph Rocchietti</span>. Turner &amp;
               Hayden, 10 John street, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a very imposing title page, in more senses than
               one, for it is a gross imposition upon the reader, since the
               contents of the book do not offer any reasons why a National
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page83"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>Literature cannot flourish in the United States. A work on
               a purely literary subject should, at least, be tolerably grammatical, but this book sets all conventional rules of composition at defiance. It is not written in English at all, but in
               broken English, and very badly broken too. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrochietti">Rocchietti</span>,
               according to his own statement, has been fourteen years in
               America, and during that time a teacher of languages. Such
               being the fact, his ignorance of English is very puzzling.
            </p>
            
            <p>Out of one hundred American ladies who learned modern languages of me,  says Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrochietti">Rocchietti</span>,  I cannot
               reckon five gentlemen. 
            </p>
            
            <p>If Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrochietti">Rocchietti</span>had not assured us that he was an Italian we should have taken him for an Irishman, and as it is,
               we have doubts respecting his country. Notwithstanding
               there are many similar obscurities of expression in the book,
               it contains on the whole much wholesome counsel, which,
               if put in passable language, might do good. The author
               should have written it in his native tongue, and then procured a translation into English: in its present form it would
               be extremely difficult to render it in any spoken language.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrochietti">Rocchietti</span> is fond of eggs, and moreover, a marvellous
               thing in a foreigner, he defends the American practice of
               eating them out of tumblers, because he likes them in that
               way himself.
            </p>
            
            <p> It is a pity in seeing writers finding fault with nations, because
               they do est with a knife and fork, or because they do not eat three
               eggs in a tumbler. Knives and forks are convenient, when the meat
               is hot; and I, who am fond of eggs, like to crack four eggs in a tumbler, provided the present sensible American does not care of the puerile English observation. Besides, if I am pleased in looking at the
               fine architecture of an Italian palace, I am pleased also in seeing that
               the small, modest and nearly uniform houses of the United States of
               North America, have the blessed appearance of a nation, whose richest citizens do not outshine the poor. What right has he, the man of
               talent, or the handsome man, to ridicule he who has no talent, or he
               who is deformed? He who ridicules a nation shows his perfect ignorance of nations. Can we find a nation without faults? 
            </p>
            
            <p>We judge from the following remarks that among the
               other virtues of the Italians, is a very strict regard for the
               fifth commandment; Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrochietti">Rocchietti</span> is the first gentleman
               that we ever knew, who considered it an honor to have an
               acquaintance with his own mother. It is putting a very
               literal construction upon  honor thy father and mother. 
            </p>
            
            <p> There are religious people in this world for whom, had I the mind
               of Voltaire, and obliged to live with them, I have no doubt they would
               have rendered me the most religious man: and among like blessed religious persons, my mother, and a few others I have the honor to be
               acquainted with, are ot the number. But history, aud the very fanaticism of the middle age, which we have witnessed lately in Philadelphia, are enough to make angels, and Sophy weep.
            </p>
            
            <p>Our author is both a politician and a prophet, as appears
               from the following passages.
            </p>
            
            <p>How can such a despotical state as Massachusetts, preach abolition against his slave, brother states of the south, it is what a
               sound
               mind cannot understand; unless we perceive in it the blind, uncharitable language of the self pocket interest, with which the north holds
               the tariff, against the interests of the south. The burning of the convent of those innocent Ursulines, and the little knowledge I have of
               this country, caused me to foretell the last horrors of Philadelphia.
               It was not a prophecy; it was but a coming event, not different from
               those we read ot in ancient history. If from smoke we argue it must
               be some fire; from fanaticism we must expect civil wars. 
            </p>
            
            <p>We keep looking in vain for some reason why a National
               Literature cannot flourish in the United States, but we find
               almost everything besides. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrochietti">Rocchietti</span> is as much
               vexed with American tourists in Italy, as we with English
               travellers in America. He takes hold of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">Headley</span>, whom
               he handles without mittens, for very good reasons, as he
               states.
            </p>
            
            <p> No nation has yet reached the civilization for which God created
               As the lover of a little discrimination sees better the faults of the
               lady whom he loves, than the faults of them he does not love, a man
               of letters, who has at heart the improvements of society, sees the
               faults of all the countries, with which he feels an interest. Of the
               blind lovers of my country, I will say here nothing more, than I
               would of those, who had no kind feeling for Italy. Besides there are
               so many, who wrote on Italy, that, were I undertaking to comment
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>on them, it would be a work too long for me, and unfit here. However, as such kind of writers form one of the most extensive branches
               of our present literature, I will take up  Italy and the Italians,  by
               
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">J. T. Headley</span>, for two good reasons. The first, because I find in it,
               the least to say against, and the second, because it is the most recent
               I know of on the subject.
            </p>
            
            <p> How could Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">Headley</span> entitle his short reflections of six months
               which he spent in that country,   Italy and the Italians,  I cannot
               understand. It seems to me, such a title is rather a too pompous one
               when we reflect at the same time, that Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">Headley</span>by this very confession, we learn, that he did not know, at that time, the Italian language.
            </p>
            
            <p> It was no more than one or two days had Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">Headley</span> stepped on a
               shore of Italy, Genoa, when he found himself offended by two individuals. The first was a mustached officer, who eyed him in askance
               as he passed: and the second, a black robed priest, not deiguing him
               even a look, as he went. Here, I find the very logic of the wolf, disposed to eat the lamb at the water spring, The officer offended the
               writer, because he looked at him; and the priest because he did not
               deign to look at him! Next, comes an elegantly drest woman, who,
               I suppose, having seen Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">Headley</span> offended, because the priest did
               not look at him, she lifted her quizzing glass, coolly scanning him
               from head to foot, and with a smile of self-satisfaction on her face,
               walked on. For me I always like to see a lady looking at me: it is
               a sign of kind feeling, and innocence: and children not spoiled by too
               fond parents, look at strangers with like pleasing curiosity. 
            </p>
            
            <p>The following remarks on the study of the dead languages, we have no doubt are very good; the great difficulty
               is to understand them.
            </p>
            
            <p>Out of one hundred American ladies, who learned modem languages from me, I cannot reckon five gentlemen. I have no doubt
               there must be good professors of Greek, and Latin, as well as among
               any other nation in the world; but, a dead language will always be a
               dead language, even from the mouth of the best professor; and a
               Buscheron, the deceased professor of the Latin language in Turin,
               Italy, was one of those rare birds which does not appear on this
               earth, but during one thousand years, if it does: and when it does,
               such a bird, I mean such a professor, might be unable to impart his
               Latin to others. 
            </p>
            
            <p>We are glad to find an encouraging account of our Theatres, which appear to have been a particular object of study
               with Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrocchietti">Rocchietti</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p> Ten years ago the theatres in America were thought immoral
               places: and if Niblo s theatre was frequented by the best class, it
               was for no other reason, but because it did pass under Niblo s garden.
               Though every year the American theatre is gaining ground, and as it
               seems, time will bring it to the consideration which it deserves, it is
               still in a state of infancy to what it should be; and it is just because
               it is in a bad repute, that talented American writers did not yet display their genius in such a rich branch of literature.
            </p>
            
            <p> Good theatres are so necessary to a civilized country, and such an
               indisputable branch of literature, that when I met in America persons
               who did object to them, it seemed as if I had come into a barbarous
               country, and not in this very country, which can glory to possess the
               best government of our present century throughout the world. 
            </p>
            
            <p>In the following passage Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrocchietti">Rocchietti</span> echoes a thought
               which we have expressed elsewhere; it will appear heterodox to many, no doubt, but it contains more truth, than, at
               first blush will appear evident.
            </p>
            
            <p> If the English Theatre has not yet reached the Italian or French
               perfection, it is owing to a national religious veneration for everything
               written by 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>; and when the English critic will not be awed
               by the great Shakspeare, and, really 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> is great, I do not see
               why the English Theatre w[i]ll not be as good as any. 
            </p>
            
            <p>The only part of the book which has any pertinence to
               the subject on which it professes to treat, is a short chapter
                on International Copyright, wherein we find the main prin-
                ciples of the question simply set forth. We have read Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="jrocchietti">Rocchietti</span> s book on account of its title, which has a very
               taking look; but the first page of it is enough to show that
               he has no qualifications for the very serious labor which he
               has undertaken. If we were disposed to be merry over a
               well-meant performance, we could pick out fun enough from
               its pages to fill up our paper.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         
         <div class="head"> AMERICAN ILLUSTRATED BOOKS.</div>
         
         <p>Harper s Illuminated and New Pictorial Bible, Nos. 1 to 17.</p>
         
         <p>Very great expectations were excited by the announcement of this edition of the Bible, which the first number, with
            its pink title-page, and red and yellow cover, rather tended to
            increase in the minds of the multitude; but any one with the
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page84"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>slightest knowledge of art, could have foreseen from the cover
            alone, that the prodigious sensation which it had begun to
            cause, would very soon subside into a dead quiet. The first
            number contained about twice the quantity of illustrations
            that any of its successors has done; but these were not given
            with a view to entice the public to take hold of the initial
            number, of course, because the publishers, being men of unimpeachable honor, and the Bible a work in which professedly
            religious merchants would not dare to practice deception for
            the sake of profit, such a thought cannot be entertained; and
            if the shadow of so foul a suspicion should have crossed the
            mind of any of our readers, we hope that they will immediately dispel it by illuminating their minds with the torch of
            charity. We have looked with very great care through the
            entire work, as far as it has been published, with the expectation of meeting with the  illuminated  parts of it, but
            have not discovered the smallest trace of any thing that can
            be called by that name. Here, again, we must caution our
            readers not to impute any blame to the publishers, since it is
            very clear that they would never have used the term if they
            had understood its meaning. The term  new pictorial  is
            also of doubtful meaning, since it cannot be supposed to apply to the Bible itself, and the oldness of some of the pictures
            equally forbids its application to the illustrations which it contains. But the whole title, taken together, may, perhaps,
            elucidate the meaning of its separate members.  Harper s
            Illuminated and New Pictorial Bible,  sounds something
            clearer. It may be old to somebody else, but it is new to
            Harper. We think that this must be the solution. So in regard to the  illuminated,   which may not be illuminated to
            another person, but is to Harper. We have been thus particular with the title, because wehave heard frequent discussions as to its meaning, which, we hope, we have helped to
            make understood.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is greatly to be deplored, that in an undertaking like this,
            where so much was promised, so much money expended,
            and so fine a chance afforded to promote the cause of art in
            this country, that more has not been done. The Bible is too
            vast a work to be illustrated by one hand alone, not only because its subjects are too various to be grasped by one mind,
            but because the designs of the same hand, often repeated,
            must at last grow monotonous and wearisome. A publisher
            has an undoubted right, as well as another man, to do
            what he likes with his own; and if the Harpers chose to employ one artist to make a thousand designs instead of dividing
            so great an amount of patronage among other members of
            the profession of equal talent, they had a right to do so; an
            inalienable right secured to them by law, which is not the
            case with all inalienable rights, as a large portion of our people can attest. But still, we repeat, that when any considerable amount of patronage is to be bestowed upon the fine arts
            in this country, it should, for the sake of art, be as equally
            distributed as possible, for it is with patronage, as with manure, a great heap of it will produce nothing better than
            mushrooms, but when scattered over the earth it will bring
            forth wheat.
         </p>
         
         <p>We do not know who designed the ornaments on the cover
            of this work, and we are glad that we do not; we hope that no
            American did it, for it is the most utterly destitute of artistic
            merit, of any ornamental drawing that we have ever seen;
            infinitely better designs for such a purpose might have been
            selected from a case of shilling calicoes. It is simply meaningless, and destitute of grace. The same may be said of
            the borders which surround the large engravings in the Bible,
            adding that two of them are paltry, and one hideous. The
            same borders with the same emblems, grapes and grotesques,
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>surround all sorts of subjects, without any regard to harmony
            of expression. The designs enclosed in these borders are all
            wretched; there is not a tolerable one among them, and the
            engraving, if possible, is worse than the drawing. We are
            left entirely in the dark as to the producer of these illuminations, but we cannot believe that they are stolen, or rather
            borrowed, for two reasons: first, we are not willing to believe
            that the publishers would sanction such a thing; and second,
            we do not believe that such bad designs could have been
            found elsewhere.
         </p>
         
         <p>The vignette on the first page, to which we find Chapman s
            name attached, is a very pretty illustration, both in drawing
            and cutting; it reflects credit on both Mr. 
            <span class="person">Chapman</span> and Mr.
            
            <span class="person">Adams</span>. Some of the large vignettes at the heads of chapters
            are also very good; but we fear that the greater part of them
            are reproductions, for we see no artist s name attached to
            them, and they are not of a character which any of our painters would be likely to disown. The little drawings, which
            are evidently all by 
            <span class="person">Chapman</span>, are most of them exceedingly
            well done; some of them have a good deal of truth and
            sweetness. We recognise a good many old acquaintances in
            one form and another among them, but considering the great
            number, more than three hundred, they have more originality
            and character than we had a right to expect. Mr. 
            <span class="person">Chapman</span>
            shows to better advantage everywhere than on canvass; he
            makes dreadful work with his colors, but in drawings like
            these, he possesses, undeniably, a good deal of available
            talent. It is a kind, too, that many artists of equal and greater pretensions, often lack.
         </p>
         
         <p>The initial letters, a very important feature in illustrated
            books, are all as poor as they can possibly be; meagre, feeble, and paltry. They show an utter incapacity for art in
            the designers, which is mortifying when exhibited in a work
            of this magnitude, which we must believe is an example of
            the best that can be done in art amongst us.
         </p>
         
         <p>The publishers of this Bible had it in their power to do four things.</p>
         
         <p>First: to give an impetus to art in the United States, by
            employing the best artists in the country to furnish original
            designs for the work.
         </p>
         
         <p>Second: to gain the lasting gratitude of their country, by
            producing an illustrated book which they could point to with
            a just pride as a monument of the perfection of art among
            them.
         </p>
         
         <p>Third: to immortalize themselves.</p>
         
         <p>Fourth: to make a handsome addition to their fortunes.</p>
         
         <p>The last they may do with the present edition, but it
            could have been done to a greater extent, and the other things
            accomplished too, by the same outlay which this will cost.
         </p>
         
         <p>These seventeen numbers contain four hundred and thirty,
            seven engravings; too many by half. One quarter of the
            number at one half the cost would be twice as valuable. But
            one or two good designs, well executed, in each number,
            from different artists, would be much more satisfactory. One
            good drawing would be worth the whole four hundred and
            thirty-seven which the work now contains, and would be
            more highly prized by the country, and be more profitable to
            the publishers in the end.
         </p>
         
         <p>While every country in Europe is putting forth illustrated
            works of a national character, in the highest reach of art, we
            have yet done nothing in the same way of which we have
            any right to boast. But the genius is among us to do great
            things if it only had an opportunity to exert itself.
         </p>
         
         <p>In all that relates to the getting up of this Bible, the work
            reflects great credit on the publishers. The type is very clear
            and neat; the ink of an exceedingly brilliant jet black, and
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page85"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>the paper of a superior quality. Our remarks about the illustrations are such as we feel ourselves bound to make. It
            is a work that we could not let pass in silence, and we could
            not slobber it over with the unmeaning praise of those who
            feel themselves bound to say something kind in return for a
            presentation copy.
         </p>
         
         <p>After writing the foregoing remarks, we accidentally discovered on the back cover of one of the numbers the publishers 
            advertisement, by which we learn that Mr. 
            <span class="person">Chapman</span>is the designer of the initial letters, the ornamented borders, the shapeless scrawls on the covers, and fourteen hundred out of sixteen
            hundred designs with which the entire work is to be illustrated.
            Our strictures were written without any knowledge of these
            facts, and we shall not, therefore, qualify what we have written.
            But we feel ourselves bound to repeat, that the ornamental
            borders betray an entire absence of any knowledge of the first
            principles of design in that department of art. It is a branch
            of the fine arts which has received but little attention in this
            country, but it is one of great importance to our national prosperity; since a very great part of our manufactured goods
            derive one half or more of their value from the mere art of
            the ornamentalist. With all our boasting of American genius,
            we have not yet been able to design a pattern for a cap ribbon. Now, if such things are worth having at all, they are
            worth producing, but this we can never do, unless a great
            genius like 
            <span class="person">Raffaelle</span> or 
            <span class="person">Cellini</span>appear among us, or we establish schools for the education of artists, like France and England. We are not a little surprised to see such designs as
            these in Harper s Bible coming from the hands of a member of our National Academy. It would be unjust to our artists, to compare their drawings in this department of ar t
            which has been so little cultivated among us, with the productions which emanate from the French and English
            schools of design; but we surely have a right to expect an
            evidence of a right aim, let the execution be what it may, in
            the works of the members of so pretending an institution as
            that of our National Academy. If our artists do not imbibe
            correct principles, they can never accomplish any thing, let the
            manipulating skill be ever so great. In all that an artist attempts to do, he must seek to imitate nature. Nothing can
            be accomplished if this be forgotten. But we are compelled
            to believe, that the Harpers Bible artist holds such a principle in high contempt. Whoever looks at the monstrosities
            that he has huddled together around the borders of many of
            the designs in that work, will see that he turned his back
            upon Nature, and she turned hers upon him.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         
         <div class="head">THE NAVY.</div>
         
         <p>Mr. Editor, The fourth number of the Broadway Journal,  (January 25th,) commences with some remarks on
             Hints on the Reorganization of the Navy,  a pamphlet
            published by Wiley &amp; Putnam. Agreeing with you in the
            motto,  Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure
            of knowledge, and also believing you possess sufficient interest in its subject to look at the pamphlet again, you will
            not regard this communication either as uncivil or officious.
            To me it seems the author and reviewer agree in opinion,
            generally, with this simple difference, the author strives at
            what he conceives to be the foundation of the evils encompassing the common sailors in the Navy, by first calling attention to the relative position of civil officers in the Navy,
            showing that chaplains, surgeons, pursers, &amp;c., require some
            protection by having their rights defined. If a commanding
            officer so far forgets his dignity, as to curse a surgeon, or
            chaplain, or purser,  in loud tones on the quarter-deck,  it
            is not very curious, if he should also curse others under his
            command, or otherwise maltreat them. It is vain to expect
            any improvement in the condition of the sailors, who are
            generally without sufficient education to plead before the nation for themselves, while those who are universally admitted
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>to be their superiors in knowledge and standing in all situations in life, plead in vain to have their rights recognized,
            and to be protected from aggression or tyranny while serving
            in the Navy.
         </p>
         
         <p>The reviewer has not said fairly, that the author  does
            not appear to know that there are such things as sailors on
            board of our national ships.  The following hints from the
            pamphlet, (page 47,) are indicative of the author s feelings
             towards the sailors.
         </p>
         
         <p> The Queen s regulations are not limited to the officers in the Navy,
            but define the position and rights of all, from the smallest boy in the
            ship to the admiral of the fleet. Means have been taken to improve
            the condition of seamen. Books and schoolmasters are supplied, and
            laudable efforts seem to be making for increasing their knowledge.
            There is nothing in the nature of our naval service to forbid us the
            imitation of the example; on the contrary, it is in accordance with the
            broad principle of obtaining the greatest good for the greatest number."
         </p>
         
         <p>No man who did not regard the condition of sailors, would
            give as broad a hint as that. The inference is, that notwithstanding our boast of equality of rights, democracy, &amp;c., the
            sailors of the Queen are better looked after than in our own
            Navy. The rights of all, officers, sailors, and all, are defined
            in the English Navy, and the author suggests that we should
            take the hint. Again:
         </p>
         
         <p>It is in vain to hope for the general improvement of any community, while one or two classes exclusively enjoy legal protection, and
            all the other classes belonging to it, are left at the mercy of the few
            possessing power and authority, undefined by law or regulation. There
            are wide-spread grievances among the majority of persons serving in
            the Navy. Many remain silent through fear of personal interest; a
            few have complained, and the complaints of others will naturally,
            though slowly, follow; and it is pleasant to believe, that in time all
            will obtain redress. A separate act will redress a separate grievance;
            and as a result of partial legislation, the statute-book of the Navy will
            present a collection of conflicting laws, unless certain fundamental
            principles be laid down for the gradual reorganization of the Navy. 
         </p>
         
         <p>Again, page 48:</p>
         
         <p>"The precedence and rank of all classes separately, should be
            clearly pointed out, and the rights and privileges of all, from the side-boy
            to the admiral, should be equally respected, and the interests of all pro-
            tected. The result would be happiness, harmony and efficiency every
            where, from the forecastle to the cabin. 
         </p>
         
         <p>On page 49, there is a hint for devising the plan or scheme
            for getting rid of the defects in the present organization of the
            Navy. It seems to be worth consideration.
         </p>
         
         <p>The above extracts serve to show that the author of the
             Hints  does know something about poor Jack, and has
            thought of him, as well as others. He seems to
            urge a strict
            requirement of ability from all, to discharge properly the du- ties of the Navy, in
            all its branches; he asks:
         </p>
         
         <p> Is it certain that every man who has passed his examination fora
            lieutenant s commission, can be entrusted in charge of a watch at sea,
            night or day?  (Page 56.)
         </p>
         
         <p>The reviewer answers:</p>
         
         <p> We happened once to witness an instance where the commander
            of one of our national vessels would not allow one of his lieutenants to
            have charge of a watch in the night time, because he was afraid to
            trust the ship in his keeping. 
         </p>
         
         <p>There is a communication in the New York Courier and
            Enquirer, of January 23d, evidently written by a lieutenant
            in the Navy, scouting the idea that any but those who now
            wear epaulettes, are entitled to any consideration. The bare
            supposition that a surgeon, chaplain, purser, or physician,
            can be brought up alongside of a lieutenant, and compared
            with him, to be fitted for rights, seems to be sickening, and
            to compare a physician who has been twenty years in the
            Navy, and possibly fifty in the world, with a commander, is
            overwhelming, and not to be borne.
         </p>
         
         <p>To illustrate this point, let me ask, whether a common,
            friendless sailor is likely to meet much favor at the hands of
            officers, who, taking advantage of their situation on shipboard, and declaring that none ought to be protected but
            themselves, would feel themselves privileged to deny all
            rights and consideration to such men as Dr. 
            <span class="person">Mott</span>, or Dr.
            
            <span class="person" id="asdoane">Doane</span>, and be offended if a comparison were made between
            them. Yet were he in the Navy, Dr. 
            <span class="person">Mott</span> would not be
            thought worthy of being compared with a commander in the
            Navy; in other words, the sea-officers would consider it an
            outrageous presumption, even to propose to assimilate Dr.
            
            <span class="person">Mott</span> in rank with a commander, were he of the Navy. Such
            is the inference from the communication referred to above.
         </p>
         
         <p>The pamphlet is worth looking at again. If you will examine the pay proposed, you will find, I think, it is a very
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page86"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>considerable reduction of the present salaries in very many instances.
         </p>
         Truth.
         
         <div class="note">[We give place to the above communication with a good deal of
            pleasure; if we misunderstood the author of the pamphlet on the reorganization of the Navy, we regret it, and will very cheerfully correct our mistake. The subject is one of too great importance to be treated lightly, and perhaps, the only way in which any reform can be
            effected in any department of the government, is by beginning with
            one offence at a time. We shall recur to the subject again. Ed.]
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         
         <div class="head">The Fine Arts</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            
            <div class="head">THE ART OF THE USE OF COLOR IN IMITATION IN PAINTING, NO. 1.</div>
            
            <div class="byline">BY 
               <span class="person" id="wpage">WILLIAM PAGE</span>.
            </div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">
               <p>[We give the first number of a series of articles on a subject
                  which is
                  always of interest among painters. The manifest ability of the
                  writer, and the originality and boldness of his views, must gain for
                  these articles the consideration to which they are entitled, from
                  the profession. To the mere amateur they will be of high interest,
                  as setting before him very plainly, correct principles in an Art
                  which few understand, and all pretend to a knowledge of. We
                  think that any one who reads the initial number will be satisfied of
                  the writer s ability, and will look for the other papers of the series
                  with eager anticipation. Many eminent painters have spent their
                  whole lives in trying to learn the art of using color; and even now
                  there is no settled principle among artists but each is left to make
                  his own discoveries. Every picture that Sir 
                  <span class="person">Joshua Reynolds</span>painted, was an experiment, and he died after a life-time of labor, still
                  in apprenticeship. Ed.]
               </p>
            </div>
            
            <p>Imitation I understand to be the means whereby in Art
               the effects of Nature are imitated, or reproduced , and the
               more nearly the means used correspond with, or are analogous to those used by nature in the production of her effects,
               the nearer will be the impression made on the eye by such
               artistic result to that made by the real object in nature itself.
            </p>
            
            <p>Sir 
               <span class="person">Joshua Reynolds</span> declares that 
               <span class="person">Gerard Douw</span>, with his
               high finishing, was a closer imitator of nature than 
               <span class="person">Raphael</span>.
               This is false, or, to say the least, calculated to mislead the
               understanding. In the imitation of the minutiae of the merely
               external portions of inanimate objects, he no doubt was, for
                this is what he saw most clearly before him. But to say that
               
               <span class="person">Raphael</span>did not also find in nature what he wished to represent, viz. beauty of form and exalted harmonious expression,
               would be to my mind a palpable absurdity. These he saw
               in nature, and transferred to his works; and though the
               judgment of the world has left but little doubt which is to be
               preferred, it is still less doubtful that they equally proceeded
               on the principle of the immediate imitation of nature,  
               each expressing to the best of his abilities that of which he
               had the clearest perception as did 
               <span class="person">Titian</span> and Correggio in
               color and chiaro-scuro, they having a keener relish for these
               qualities, than for expression or form.
            </p>
            
            <p>Then who will pretend to say, that 
               <span class="person">Raphael</span> would not
               have been exalted to a higher pitch of excellence by the addition of the minute exactness of 
               <span class="person">Gerard Douw</span>, the color of
               Titian, or the clare obscure of Correggio, if these could have
               been superadded to his own, if you will, higher possessions,
               without displacing any of his already attained excellencies.
               And that such a thing might be, needs only eyes to see that
               in nature herself all this, and more, is accomplished; there
               the minuteness that puts 
               <span class="person">Douw</span> s best efforts to shame, and
               causes 
               <span class="person">Titian</span> s color to pale at the comparison, and the light
               and dark of Correggio to look heavy and dull, lie side by side
               with a diviner exaltation of expression than ever 
               <span class="person">Raphael</span>
               could dream, and add to its force and truth.
            </p>
            
            <p>In Sculpture we have an illustration. The busts of our
               countryman, 
               <span class="person">Hiram Powers</span>, which have all the breadth of
               the finest antique heads, and a minuteness of finish in all the
               details unknown to that gifted people the Greeks, and still
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>more so to modem nations, without disturbing either breadth
               of form or expression, shall yet make the world wonder that
               such things should have been done in our midst, and never a
               cry of a miracle, a miracle!
            </p>
            
            <p>It may here be well, to a clearer understanding of the subject, to observe, that in Sculpture the means used are fully
               adequate to the end to be produced being, with a perfectly
               pliant substance, wet clay, to imitate or reproduce the form
               of any natural object, giving only one body for a like form of
               body in another substance. Which will at once show the
               wide difference between these two imitative arts, when we
               consider that in Painting the flat surface must appear rotund,
               or otherwise the form of the thing to be imitated, where the
               form is not, but only the appearance; to say nothing of the
               light, dark, and color, necessary to give those other innumerable qualities demanded in a picture. And this brings us to
               the means used in the latter art to convey impressions as of
               natural objects, more particularly color.
            </p>
            
            <p>Now there are but three primitive colors used by the Creator to adorn and beautify this all-beautiful world of his creation, viz.: Red, Yellow, and Blue. Yet these three, to
               which all tints, hues, and variations are to be traced, together with Light and Dark, so imperfectly represented in
               painting by White and Black are all the feeble means we
               have, with our own short sight, to compete with that infinite
               variety of nature which has been the love and admiration of
               all mankind from the beginning. It will then seem evident,
               that economy with these slender means must be of the last
               importance; and that he who uses these most ingeniously
               and with the least outlay of them, so that he produces the
               desired effect- and has most power in reserve, will be the
               truest artist.
            </p>
            
            <p>If white and black are the extreme limits of our scope with
               which we must represent, if at all, that infinite stretch in
               nature between her intensest ray of light, and that outer
               darkness where no light is for after we have used our utmost
               skill to make the surface of our canvas, or the plane on which
               we produce our picture, as dark as pigments will make it,
               it will cast a shadow in noon-day darker than itself; and so
               when our brilliant white has been exhausted in imitating
               light, a little diamond would blaze upon its surface. This
               being so, may well teach us how limited is our power to cope
               with the Infinite, and, that humility and the following humbly, afar off, in Art, as in Religion, the Almighty leading
               makes us most like what we would most wish to be.
            </p>
            
            <p>Now to bring these indefinite extremes of nature within
               our own range of mental vision, let us suppose them divided
               into five degrees, equally removed from each other, the first
               being light, and the last perfect darkness; but though this
               simple division will answer our purpose for illustration in
               writing, the artist must make an almost infinite subdivision
               in his practice. Then suppose in like manner the painter s
               representatives of light and darkness, so divided into a like
               number of degrees, so that the medium or third degree in the
               scale is equally removed from each extreme in either case,
               will not this give us the nearest approach that we can get
               in art, to the medium or third degree in nature in the scale
               which we have indicated above? If so, let us fix this in our
               minds as the centre whence all analysis begins. We shall
               hereafter have occasion to refer to this more particularly.
            </p>
            
            <p>The painting of human flesh has always been considered
               the best test of the powers of a colorist; and the human face
               may well be considered as the highest test, as the wellknown focus (so to speak) of expression. 
               <span class="person" id="jwvgoethe">Goethe</span> has well
               said in his  Theory of Colors,  that here nature seems to
               have exhausted all her resources, having so used all the pri
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page87"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               mitive colors, and so interwoven and combined them, that
               we scarce know which predominate, (I quote from memory)
               and, he might have added, that all other known qualities,
               too, present themselves to our eyes here, or rather evade our
               search and strive to hide themselves from our observation,
               as any painter who has tried to represent them, well knows.
            </p>
            
            <p>Although one of these abovenamed primitive colors blue,
               has been found to exist in nature, in the case of the blue sky,
               as the product of light over dark, (that is, the darkness of
               space beyond, teen by us through the light of the atmosphere
               of earth, producing, as darkness seen through light always
               does, the blueness;) and has on this account been rejected
               by some as a primitive color; yet as it cannot be resolved
               back again to the other two primitives, or be produced by
               any known combination of these, we must occupy it.
            </p>
            
            <p>I should wish to call this color of the sky an accidental
               color, in contradistinction to the local color of the violet, or
               any other blue thing where the color cannot be separated
               from the substance, but is always a part of it.
            </p>
            
            <p>Now it will be clearly seen, that if we had the pigments
               capable of representing perfect light and perfect dark, we
               should very readily produce a complete resemblance to this
               color of the sky, by making a ground of perfect darkness, and
               when this was dry, so as not to mix these extremes, or the
               pigments representing them, passing over it a layer of perfect light, so as to allow that dark to appear through as in
               the reality.
            </p>
            
            <p>This accidental blue is not alone produced by the atmosphere, but is also to be found in the blue veins, where it is
               likewise nothing more than the darker masses of blood covered by, and seen through, not only the light coating of the
               veins, but the skin, and the light resting on the surface of the
               flesh; so that I have often known it produced in painting
               without the use of any blue pigment, only indeed by drawing
               the lines of dark red where the veins were to be represented,
               and then passing over these a light corresponding to the light
               color of the skin and coating of the veins; the veins appearing more or less blue, as the red color under had been darker
               or lighter.
            </p>
            
            <p>Indeed, to show that this method, so far as it can be used,
               is the only way in which these or other like effects in nature
               can be truly represented, is the object for which I now undertake to write, and I trust I shall be able to demonstrate it
                clearly enough; at least to make more obvious to the mind
               of some wavering searcher after truth, the necessity of a devoted adherence to that reason by which alone any thing can
               be done worthy the name of Art.
            </p>
            
            <p>Not that I would discard that higher quality which sometimes soars beyond the reach of reason, called by so many
               names and so little known inspiration or genius; but that
               so far as I have yet learned, the highest geniuses have been
               found the truest advocates of, and the most indebted to this
               faculty, of any other class of men and that they have never
               used any other means than simple reason for the attainment
               of that which simple reason can teacb. When we have
               scaled the summit of this pyramid, we shall do right, perhaps, to unfold our wings and make an essay at the moon; 
               but until we have used all the stepping stones that she presents, we had best keep our wings to ourselves, and out of
               sight, lest by a too violent fluttering of their half fledged
               pinions in the vain effort to fly whilst so near the surface of
               the earth, and before we well know how to crawl, we measure
               our own short length in the dust, or at least, throw it into
               other s eyes, a thing which has been too often done of late
               to need a repetition.
            </p>
            
            <p>But to return to the imitation of flesh. Now in imitating
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>the appearance of this human substance, we are first to ask
               how nature has arranged her material, that is colors, to produce it, knowing, that like causes will produce like effects,
               and that  Art is formation, as nature is. 
            </p>
            
            <p>When we look at flesh we see into it that is, the vision
               penetrates below the surface and sees what, if the surface
               were perfectly impervious to the vision, could not be seen at
               all, the red blood far beneath or under the skin. If then we
               wish to imitate this quality of flesh, it will be very apparent
               that the truest way in which to do it will be to paint our red
               color on our canvas at first, as the basis of the flesh, to be
               afterwards more or less obscure, as the blood approaches nearer to, or is farther removed from the surface. And again,
               this flesh is sufficiently transparent to be penetrated by the
               natural light which illuminates it, making the red color more
               or less apparent, as more or less light falls upon or into it, for
               we see more of the peculiar properties or qualities of flesh
                beneath than on the surface.
            </p>
            
            <p>This source of light is not from within the flesh itself 
               outward, but from without, penetrating inwards; it would of
               course illuminate most brilliantly the parts nearest itself,
               that is, the outside of the flesh, or skin, and fade as it penetrates deeper and deeper into the body, losing itself at a certain depth in total darkness.
            </p>
            
            <p>It must then follow from the facts, that to come nearest to
               the representation of these qualities, the flesh to be painted
               should not only be begun red, but darker than it is intended
               to remain when finished.
            </p>
            
            <p>Red color has the peculiar property of retaining its hue
               more fully through all the gradations down towards darkness than any other of the primitive colors, as in the deeper
               shades of either yellow or blue, they seem as it were to lose
               their identity, so that they cannot be discerned as color when
               illuminated by the small amount of light necessary to make
               the red perfectly apparent. This if rightly understood will
               explain the well known fact that a red color seen in day light
               side by side with a blue of an apparently equal depth, shows
               itself much darker in comparison when seen at twilight, and
               is consequently rendered, by all good engravers in their copy
               of a picture when this color occurs, darker than the color itself appears to ordinary eyes. So that we see nature here, is
               as wise in the use of this color, as the basis of the color of
               flesh, as we always find her to be when we search her meaning out; for had any other of the primitive colors than red
               been used for the color of the blood, it could not have been
               seen in such deep shadow as that in which the human blood
               circulates.
            </p>
            
            <p>If there be any yellow in a complexion to be imitated, it
               must of course occur nearer the surface than the red, and consequently the red be seen through it, and so must it be painted over the red, and not mixed with it.
            </p>
            
            <p>But as in the finest complexions, there is least yellow according to the poets, who have ever admired the white and
               red. If we take a pigment most resembling in color and its
               degree of transparency, and opacity, the skin, and pass over
               the already represented blood color, every where obscuring
               that as it is obscured in nature, where it never comes fully
               to the surface of the flesh, but is always seen through that
               surface, we shall have the unity of color as well as the quality of the blood seen through the skin, which is one of the
               most prominent characteristics of flesh.
            </p>
            
            <p>Thus far have we treated the local qualities of flesh quite
               generally, but to a more thorough understanding of the subject, it must be considered in connection with those peculiar
               modifications of light which nature presents in such endless
               variety.
            </p>
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page88"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            
            <p>We must be indulged a little farther in these general remarks before we can descend effectually to their more practical application.</p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            
            <div class="head">A NEW DISCOVERY IN ART.</div>
            
            <p>We gave an extract in our second number, from the London Art Union, announcing a new discovery in the Art of
               Copying Engravings, which promised something really astounding. Since then we have received a copy of the engraving produced by the newly invented process, which
               may be seen at our office, 153 Broadway. The following
               account of this marvellous invention we take from the January number of the Art-Union of London. It is a subject
               of vast importance which interests, not artists and amateurs
               alone, but the whole civilised world.
            </p>
            
            <p>In this age of wonders it is, at all events, a consolation to know
               that matter is not endowed with intellectual power that machinery
               cannot think; for imagination may scarcely limit the boundaries to
               which science may attain, or calculate the extent to which the work
               of man s hand wilt do the work of man. We do not, at the present
               moment, design to speculate upon the ultimate result of accumulated
               marvels, to which every day seems to add at least one; we are not
               called upon to say whether we would or would not arrest for instance
               __the progress of an invention which at first sight, seems to threaten
                ruin to a very numerous and important class of the community; we
               cannot stay its onward course it we would. With reference to this
               branch of our subject, we shall only say, by way of introduction, that
               whatever shall tend to make cheap that is to say, accessible to the
               many good Art and good Literature, is a boon to mankind; an
               advantage to society at large, although it may prejudice as all innovations inevitably do existing interests. We snail be called upon to
                consider this topic at greater length; at present let it suffice that, if
               the invention we are about to notice will fully accomplish that which
               is assumed, the engraving must be first produced; the mind must have
               been exercised before the mechanic can be employed. We are, we
               verily believe, on the eve of other inventions capable of no inference
               so satisfactory. It will be our duty to announce and describe them
               ere long.
            </p>
            
            <p>The new process by which engravings may be multiplied ad infinitum, we have now to consider. All we know of it may be briefly told.
               Some months ago we stated that  a discovery had been made, by
               which, in a few days, a large and elaborate line engraving might be
               so accurately copied that there should be no perceptible difference between the original and the copy; that an engraving on steel or copper
               might be produced from an impression of the print the original plate
               never having been seen by the copyist; and that such a plate should
               be warranted to yield from 10,000 to 20,000 impressions. We stated,
               also, that it was stated to us, that the producer would undertake to
               supply a Bank of England note so exactly copied that the person who
               signed and issued it should not be able to swear which was the original and which the copy. 
            </p>
            
            <p>Farther we may add, that the inventor an Englishman is an engraver by profession. He has produced our example under serious disadvantages being in ill health, having had to work in dark frosty
               weather, and having been far too much hurried by us, in consequence
               of our desire to issue our copies with our January part. Moreover,
               the steel was not prepared expressly for the purpose, and was by no
               means fortunate for work.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have no doubt whatever that, under more auspicious circumstances
               the inventor may produce a plate so exactly resembling the original proof
               that there shall be no perceptible difference between the two even to the
               practised eye; and that he may achieve this work within eight days.
            </p>
            
            <p>And we think that all who examine this example fairly will be of
               our opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is all we know about the matter. We subjected the invention
               to the severest test by selecting a subject so accessible that any person who will take the trouble to do so may compare the original with
               the copy.
            </p>
            
            <p>It would be idle to attempt to solve this mystery; the inventor has
               taken out no patent, neither can he do so, insomuch as, if he do, any
               unprincipled person may at once adopt it with little probability of
               being able to prove that his process has been the medium by which
               the print has been produced.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is not very likely that such a secret can be very long retained; it
               will no doubt be soon universally known, and extensively acted upon.
               If as perfect as it may be as we verily do believe it will be there is
               no knowing to what extensive changes in legislation it may conduce; for if any printed or written document can be forged with so
               much ease and certainty as to defy detection, the consequences may
               be more appalling than we care to anticipate.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Art-Union also contains a hint of another wonderful
               discovery in the art of reproduction, called Anastatic printing,  which is not of equal importance with the other, but is
               quite as marvellous.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is the reproduction of any engraving or lithograph, in an unlimited quantity, in an inconceivably brief space of time. Any journal
               for
               instance, say the Times, might in twenty minutes be prepared for rep[r]inting merely from a single number, and worked on with the ordi
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               nary rapidity of the steam-press. It is our purpose fully to describe
               in the next number of the Art-Union, the procoss whereby this is effected, and to show the admirable applicability of the invention to
               all
               those kinds of croquis drawings, sketches, &amp;c. &amp;c., which have hitherto been presented to the public eye as wood-engravings by giving
               as a specimen a page of drawings by distinguished artists printed in
               this manner. Tne proprietors are scarcely yet prepared to work their
               patent on as extensive scale as they contemplate. We have, however,
               seen a set of drawings, fresh from the hands of the artists, prepared
               for printing, and printed off in little more than a quarter of an hour!
               In less than a quarter of an hour from the time of receiving the sketch the
               printer will present to the artist proofs of his work, which shall resemble
               the original as perfectly as if it had been reflected on paper touch for
               touch."
            </p>
            
            <p>There is an English artist now in this country, who pretends to be in possession of the secret of the process of copying engravings, as detailed above; in fact, he pretends to be
               the inventor or discoverer of the method. We speak of his
               pretensions, for we have no evidence of the truth of his statement. But the secret cannot long remain a secret, if it be
               of any importance to the welfare of the world. Nature makes
                no exclusive endowments. It is not a little remarkable that
               no important discovery has ever been made, without several
               persons laying claim to the right of it. As the steam-engine,
               the electric fluid in clouds, the Daguerreotype, the electrotype,
               and many others. In the case of the electrotype, the claims
               of the two discoverers were thoroughly examined by a competent body, and priority of invention awarded, without detracting from the honorable character of either claimant. If
               all disputes of a similar nature could be as fairly determined,
               it would save the world much unprofitable wrangling.
            </p>
            
            <p> Early in the year 1838, Mr. 
               <span class="person">Thomas Spencer</span>, an eminent pictureframe maker in Liverpool, and an intelligent cultivator of science for
               its own sake, was led to observe points of similarity, almost amounting to identity, between chemical and electrical forces: his inquiries
               on the subject led him to institute a long series of ingenious experiments, in the course of which he found that under certain circumstances of galvanic action, a solution oi sulphate of copper could be dissolved, and that the copper thus separated from the acid might be
               atomically deposited on another copper plate, where it would form a
               new layer of copper, exhibiting a perfect lacsimile of the original plate
               in the most minute particulars. This discovery received the name of
               the electrotype, and it was hailed as a most valuable means of multiplying medals, copperplates, and raised ornaments. Some months after 
               <span class="person">Spencer</span> s publication of his discovery, Professor 
               <span class="person">Jacobi</span>, of St. Petersburg, obtained the same results at which the English inventor had
               previously arrived, and forthwith claimed for himself the exclusive
               merit of the discovery. When the British Association for the promotion of Science met in Glasgow, Spencer aud 
               <span class="person">Jacobi</span> appeared before
               the Chemical Section, where their rival claims were discussed with
               great earnestness and attention. The prejudices of the scientific body
               were in favor of 
               <span class="person">Jacobi</span>: he was an eminent professor, having kuown
               rank and position in the scientific world; he belonged to the same order
               as the majority of his judges, and they naturally felt some interest in
               the maintenance of his fame. On the other hand, men of science felt
               that there was something derogatory to their order, in the fact that an
               important discovery, making revelations which escaped the cognizance
               and even the suspicions of professional chemists, should be assigned
               to a simple tradesman of Liverpool, whose name was now heard of for
               the first time beyond the precincts of his limited locality. Nor was
               this prejudice confined to the professional philosophers. We were present at the meeting, and took some interest in the matter. We know
               that the feelings generally were against 
               <span class="person">Spencer</span>, until he produced
               such overwhelming evidence that 
               <span class="person">Jacobi</span> himself was left without the
               power of reply. The decision of the Chemical Section was, that both
               gentlemen had independently arrived at the same result, but that the priority of invention was undoubtedly Spencer s. 
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            
            <p>Valentines. Mr. 
               <span class="person">Coleman</span>has got the prettiest collec tion of Valentines that we have ever seen; some of them
                are very brilliantly illuminated with all manner of ingenious
               devices, and would make suitable presents for all seasons.
               It is equal to a show to look through his assortment of lace
               edged papers; it is the greatest glorification of Cupid that
               we ever met with; out of sight more gorgeous and taking
               than 
               <span class="person">George Cruikshank</span> s  Triumph of Cupid,  which we
               thought the greatest triumph of the little rogue. In addition to the Valentines, we hear Mr. 
               <span class="person">Coleman</span> has an Artist,
               from the Herald s Office, we believe, who emblazons to order, in a very beautiful style, verses or designs, in gold and
               crimson.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page89"></div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p8">
         
         <div class="head">THE BISHOP.</div>
         
         <p>The case of the Bishop is one with which the public have no business, for although
            he is in a certain sense a public character, yet it is but a very small part of the public who should have been
            allowed to know anything of the charges which
            caused his suspension from the sacred office which he had filled so long. As to his
            guilt or innocence we have no opinion
            to express; but as to the propriety of infesting the community with the highly
            objectionable details of his trial, we think
            that there can be no difference of opinion. He was legally tried according to the
            Canons of his own sect, and all that the
            public had any need of knowing about the matter, was the verdict of his judges. If
            they, knowing the 
            <span class="person">Bishop</span>and his accusers thoroughly, were not competent to decide upon his case, the
            public who can know but little of either, surely are not
            It is altogether an unhappy affair, and every body concerned in it, in any shape,
            is a subject of compassion, rather than
            ridicule or censure. If the Bishop had been tried for an ecclesiastical offence, we
            should never have heard of a bench of
            Bishops running about from one bookseller to another bargaining for the copy-right
            of the trial. But it was the taint of
            uncleanness which gave popularity to the trial, and caused it to be hawked about
            the streets like the dying speech of a
            murderer; as it was the virulence and personal abuse in the 
            <span class="person">Carey</span> trials, and the
            
            <span class="person">Potts</span> and 
            <span class="person">Wainright</span> controversies, which
            caused them to monopolize for nine days the talk of the town.
         </p>
         
         <div class="figure">
            
            <div class="head">A SUSPENDED BISHOP.</div>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">SE BROWN</span>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <p>We give an illustration of the Bishop s case from a very sincere desire to avoid any
            committal on the subject. The
            bishop appears here  suspended.  Dr. 
            <span class="person">Seabury</span> and the six Bishops who believed him
            innocent of the charges laid at his
            door, will say that the dragon on whose back he rides is the foul spirit of
            Detraction by which he is suspended; while the
            eleven and his enemies will call it the unclean monster that instigated him to his
            misdeeds, and now keeps him suspended
            from his church. The old man rides securely in a serene atmosphere, and whether he
            go up or down, we wish him well.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page90"></div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         
         <div class="head">Original Poetry.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            
            <div class="head">THE TWO PATHS.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Aye, they in plodding on so steadily
               
               <br></br>Did gain a heap of gold,
               
               <br></br>While I, who hurried on so merrily,
               
               <br></br>Gained brighter wealth ten-fold.
               
               <br></br> A wealth of thought and cheerfulness
               
               <br></br>The coinage of the soul,
               
               <br></br>And more than all, a hope to bless,
               
               <br></br>With promise fill d my bowl.
               
               <br></br>They ride in princely chariot proud,
               
               <br></br>By blooded coursers drawn, 
               
               <br></br>They feast in stately halls the crowd
               
               <br></br>Of friends in lace and lawn.
               
               <br></br>My carriage is the wide-winged thought,
               
               <br></br> By fancy wheeled above, 
               
               <br></br>My home the world-wide space unbought,
               
               <br></br>My feast the feast of love.
               
               <br></br>They labored on till life was waning
               
               <br></br>To live above all strife, 
               
               <br></br> I lived the whole, the present gaining,
               
               <br></br>And with me cherish'd life.
               
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">
               <p>We copy the following poem from the American Review, the new
                  Whig Magazine, on account of its unusual beauty. It will have been
                  read by many of our city subscribers, we have no doubt, before it
                  reaches them in our columns, but there are others to whom it will be
                  as welcome as it is new.
               </p>
               
               <p>Mr. 
                  <span class="person">Willis</span> copies it into the Mirror with the following remarks.
                  "In our opinion it is the most effective single example of fugitive poetry ever published in this country; and unsurpassed in English
                  poetry
                  for subtle conception, masterly ingenuity of versification and consistent
                  sustaining of imaginative lift. It is one of those   dainties bred in a
                  book,' which we feed on. It will stick to the memory of everybody
                  who reads it."
               </p>
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">THE RAVEN.</div>
            
            <div class="byline">BY 
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <div class="lg">  
                  <br></br>Once upon a midnight dreary, while I pondered, weak and weary,
                  
                  <br></br>Over many a quaint and curious volume of forgotten lore,
                  
                  <br></br>While I nodded, nearly napping, suddenly there came a tapping,
                  
                  <br></br>As of-some one gently rapping, rapping at my chamber door.
                  
                  <br></br> Tis some visiter,  I muttered,  tapping at my chamber door 
                  
                  <br></br>Only this, and nothing more. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg"> 
                  <br></br>Ah, distinctly I remember it was in the bleak December,
                  
                  <br></br>And each separate dying ember wrought its ghost upon the floor.
                  
                  <br></br>Eagerly I wished the morrow; vainly I had tried to borrow
                  
                  <br></br>From my books surcease of sorrow sorrow for the lost Lenore 
                  
                  <br></br>For the rare and radiant maiden whom the angels name Lenore 
                  
                  <br></br>Nameless here for evermore.
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>And the silken sad uncertain rustling of each purple curtain
                  
                  <br></br> Thrilled me filled me with fantastic terrors never felt before
                  
                  <br></br>So that now, to still the beating of my heart, I stood repeating
                  
                  <br></br> 'Tis some visiter entreating entrance at my chamber door 
                  
                  <br></br>Some late visiter entreating entrance at my chamber door; 
                  
                  <br></br>This it is, and nothing more. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br> Presently my soul grew stronger; hesitating then no longer,
                  
                  <br></br> Sir,  said I,  or Madam, truly your forgiveness I implore;
                  
                  <br></br>But the fact is I was napping, and so gently you came rapping,
                  
                  <br></br>And so faintly you came tapping, tapping at my chamber door,
                  
                  <br></br>That I scarce was sure I heard you  here I opened wide the door;
                  
                  <br></br>Darkness there, and nothing more.
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>Deep into that darkness peering, long I stood there wondering, fearing,
                  
                  <br></br>Doubting, dreaming dreams no mortal ever dared to dream before;
                  
                  <br></br>But the silence was unbroken, and the darkness gave no token,
                  
                  <br></br>And the only word there spoken was the whispered word,  Lenore! 
                  
                  <br></br>This I whispered, and an echo murmured back the word,  Lenore! 
                  
                  <br></br>Merely this and nothing more.
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg"> 
                  <br></br>Then into the chamber turning, all my soul within me burning,
                  
                  <br></br>Soon I heard again a tapping somewhat louder than before.
                  
                  <br></br>'' Surely,  said I,  surely that is something at my window lattice;
                  
                  <br></br>Let me see, then, what thereat is, and this mystery explore 
                  
                  <br></br>Let my heart be still a moment and this mystery explore
                  
                  <br></br>'Tis the wind and nothing more! 
               </div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>Open here I flung the shutter, when, with many a flirt and flutter,
                  
                  <br></br>In there stepped a stately raven of the saintly days of yore;
                  
                  <br></br>Not the least obeisance made he; not an instant stopped or stayed he;
                  
                  <br></br>But, with mien of lord or lady, perched above my chamber door 
                  
                  <br></br>Perched upon a bust of Pallas just above my chamber door 
                  
                  <br></br> Perched, and sat, and nothing more.
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg"> 
                  <br></br>Then this ebony bird beguiling my sad fancy into smiling,
                  
                  <br></br>By the grave and stem decorum of the countenance it wore,
                  
                  <br></br> Though thy crest be shorn and shaven, thou,  I said,  art sure no craven,
                  
                  <br></br>Ghastly grim and ancient raven wandering from the Nightly shore 
                  
                  <br></br>Tell me what thy lordly name is on the Night s Plutonian shore! 
                  
                  <br></br>Quoth the raven  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>Much I marvelled this ungainly fowl to hear discourse so plainly,
                  
                  <br></br>Though its answer little meaning little relevancy bore;
                  
                  <br></br>For we cannot help agreeing that no living human being
                  
                  <br></br> Ever yet was blessed with seeing bird above his chamber door 
                  
                  <br></br>Bird or beast upon the sculptured bust above his chamber door,
                  
                  <br></br>With such name as  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>But the raven, sitting lonely on the placid bust, spoke only
                  
                  <br></br>That one word, as if his soul in that one word he did outpour.
                  
                  <br></br>Nothing farther then he uttered not a feather then he fluttered 
                  
                  <br></br>Till I scarcely more than muttered   Other friends have flown before 
                  
                  <br></br>On the morrow he will leave me, as my hopes have flown before.
                  
                  <br></br>Then the bird said  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>Startled at the stillness broken by reply so aptly spoken,
                  
                  <br></br>"Doubtless  said I,  what it utters is its only stock and store
                  
                  <br></br>Caught from some unhappy master whom unmerciful Disaster
                  
                  <br></br>Followed fast and followed faster till his songs one burden bore 
                  
                  <br></br>Till the dirges of his Hope the melancholy burden bore
                  
                  <br></br>Of  Nevermore  of  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>But the raven still beguiling all my sad soul into smiling,
                  
                  <br></br> Straight I wheeled a cushioned seat in front of bird, and bust and door;
                  
                  <br></br>Then upon the velvet sinking, I betook myself to linking
                  
                  <br></br>Fancy unto fancy, thinking what this ominous bird of yore 
                  
                  <br></br>What this grim, ungainly, ghastly, gaunt, and ominous bird of yore
                  
                  <br></br>Meant in croaking  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">  
                  <br></br>This I sat engaged in guessing, but no syllable expressing
                  
                  <br></br>To the fowl whose fiery eyes now burned into my bosom s core;
                  
                  <br></br>This and more I sat divining, with my head at ease reclining
                  
                  <br></br>On the cushion s velvet lining that the lamplight gloated o er,
                  
                  <br></br>But whose velvet violet lining with the lamplight gloating o er.
                  
                  <br></br>She shall press, ah, nevermore!
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>Then, methought, the air grew denser, perfumed from an unseen censer
                  
                  <br></br>Swung by angels whose faint foot-falls tinkled on the tufted floor.
                  
                  <br></br>" Wretch,  I cried, "thy God hath lent thee by these angels he hath sent thee
                  
                  <br></br>Respite respite and nepenthe from thy memories of Lenore!
                  
                  <br></br>Quaff, oh quaff this kind nepenthe and forget this lost Lenore! 
                  
                  <br></br>Quoth the raven  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br> Prophet!  said I,  thing of evil! prophet still, if bird or devil! 
                  
                  <br></br>Whether Tempter sent, or whether tempest tossed thee here ashore,
                  
                  <br></br>Desolate yet all undaunted, on this desert land enchanted 
                  
                  <br></br>On this home by Horror haunted tell me truly, I implore 
                  
                  <br></br>Is there is there balm in Gilead tell me tell me, I implore! 
                  
                  <br></br>Quoth the raven  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">    
                  <br></br> Prophet!  said I,  thing of evil prophet still, if bird or devil!
                  
                  <br></br>By that Heaven that bends above us by that God we both adore 
                  
                  <br></br>Tell this soul with sorrow laden if, within the distant Aidenn,
                  
                  <br></br>It shall clasp a sainted maiden whom the angels name Lenore 
                  
                  <br></br>Clasp a rare and radiant maiden whom the angels name Lenore. 
                  
                  <br></br>Quoth the raven  Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br> Be that word our sign of parting, bird or fiend!  I shrieked, upstarting 
                  
                  <br></br> Get tbee back into the tempest and the Night s Plutonian shore!
                  
                  <br></br>Leave no black plume as a token of that lie thy soul hath spoken!
                  
                  <br></br>Leave my loneliness unbroken! quit the bust above my door!
                  
                  <br></br>Take thy beak from out my heart, and take thy form from off my door! 
                  
                  <br></br>Quoth the raven "Nevermore. 
               </div>
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>And the raven, never flitting, still is sitting, still is sitting
                  
                  <br></br>On the pallid bust of Pallas just above my chamber door;
                  
                  <br></br>And his eyes have all the seeming of a demon that is dreaming,
                  
                  <br></br>And the lamp-light o er him streaming throws his shadow on the floor;
                  
                  <br></br>And my soul from out that shadow that lies floating on the floor
                  
                  <br></br> Shall be lifted nevermore!
               </div>
               
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page91"></div>
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p11">
         
         <div class="head">CHRONOLOGY.</div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY 
            <span class="person">R. H. SCHOOLCROT</span>.
         </div>
         
         <p>The original tribe of the Phoenecians believed that their
            ancestors were grasshoppers, and came out of the ground.
            The Persians believed that 
            <span class="person">Zoroaster</span> lived twenty years in
            the wilderness on one cheese, which never grew old, and that
            he was purified in flames of fire, which fell from the skies.
            The Ahouandates or Wyandots, believed that their ancestors,
            and indeed all the Indian tribes, crept out of the ground, as
            men, not grasshoppers, at a certain mountain. The Oneidas
            have put a little more imagination into the same idea, and
            boldly proclaim that they sprang out of a rock complete men,
            club in hand. Now, one of these theories is, historically, just
            as good as another, with this qualification, that if there be
            any preference, on the score of thought, it is in favor of the
            red men of our continent.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Monatons, or as we have the word, Manhattanese,
            may have looked back as far as 
            <span class="person">Adam</span>, for aught that is on
            record, for their origin, but all that we know of these traditions on this point is, that they were of the Mohegan stock 
            a sub-type of that great 
            <span class="person">Algonquin</span> family, who spread, under
            various names, and modification of dialect, from the farthest
            southern limits of Virginia to the gulf of St. Lawrence. Local names have much bewildered and befogged writers, but
            philology leaches us a lesson on this subject which is easily
            read. Were old 
            <span class="person">Powhattan</span> and his kinsfolk alive, they might
            tell us the claims they had to originality of type and sovereignty, and if they had as much self-complacency as most
            nations, there is but little doubt that their old grey-headed
            chroniclers would have made out a strong plea for the red
            sons of the  Ancient Dominion.  They went, however, to
            their graves, without the inquiry being made, so far as we
            know.
         </p>
         
         <p>The next people, in point of position, following the sweep
            of the gulf stream north, who have claims to such a preeminence, and who have asserted these claims, are the 
            <span class="person">Lennie Lenapes</span>, of Pennsylvania, who, with their closely affiliated bands, the Nanticokes of Maryland and eastern Virginia,
            and the Minci of New Jersey and the west banks of the Hudson, spread their lodges over all this part of the Atlantic coast.
            A river is often a national boundary, across which wars are
            conducted, and it was so with the Mohegan, the Chatimuc,
            or as we call it, the Hudson River. This stream separated
            the Mohegans from their affiliated tribe the Minci, whom,
            by the way, they thought it no disparagement to their lineage,
            to fight and plunder whenever they deemed it best. Their
            relationship to the Minci, and through them to the Lenapes,
            or Delawares, they nevertheless freely acknowledged. They
            told the Moravians these things, and as this benevolent
            brotherhood were better christians than they were philologists or ethnographers, and believed, moreover, on indisputed authority, that all mankind were brothers, they found no
            difficulty in reporting the Manhattanese to be veritable Delawares, although they were actually two removes, by tribal
            affinity, from the Lenape type.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Manhattanese cared nothing about these questions
            Neither is there any evidence that they gave much heed to
            missionary instruction of any kind. They admired Holland
            gin and Dutch manufactured tobacco, much more than Dutch
            theology the latter of which was, however, sound. If
            
            <span class="person">Hans Megolipenesis</span>, and the Reverend Mr. 
            <span class="person">Pyrlaus</span> were
            alive, there is no doubt but they would affirm this position.
            Certain it is, that the Manhattanese fought the nations east,
            West and north all around them; sung their war songs, trapped beaver, worshipped whom they would worship, and died'
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>They had their villages at Capsee, and Warpoes, and Natonk, and many other places, now covered by the great city,
            where they feasted, and danced, and sung. If any one was
            sick they raised a high pole before the priest s or juggler s
            door, upon which they hoisted offerings of animals and other
            things, to the gods of the air. As they were idolators, and
            not sure, a long time together, which of their numerous gods
            was the strongest, this was the inquiry they were constantly in doubt on this point, and it is no wonder, on philosophical principles, that where their divinity was so infinitely multiplied, there should be very little power in any single god.
            Generally the sick person died, while these ceremonies were
            in process, and he was buried very near the village. In this
            way, the dead, in the course of long years, were strewed
            throughout the island, and it may, without exaggeration, be
            added, that the city has its foundations on Indian bones.
            Whether this be the cause that there is so much evil in it, and
            so strong an inclination to worship the devil, in sundry classes,
            high and low, we must leave to nice observers of cause and
            effect, moral and physical, to settle.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is true, observes the reader, you told us that the Manhattans were Mohegans, but who, pray, were the Mohegans,
            and what was their particular lineage and origin? This inquiry also, we may endeavor, in due time, to answer.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p12">
         
         <div class="head">THE CONCERT ROOM.</div>
         
         <p>The Euterpean Society. This Society, venerable in its
            age, though youthful in its spirit, gave its Annual Concert
            and Ball at Niblo s Saloon, on Wednesday the 29th ult.
         </p>
         
         <p>The programme was excellent as usual, consisting mostly
            of instrumental pieces. Three overtures were played the
            Felhsen Muelhe, Macon and La Sirene; the two last by
            Auber. A septette by Hummel, and three instrumental so los performed by Messrs. 
            <span class="person">Rapetti</span>, 
            <span class="person">Ribas</span>, and Ensyn.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Septette by 
            <span class="person">Hummel</span>was undoubtedly the best performance of the evening. Mr. 
            <span class="person">Timm</span>, on the piano, executed
            his portion exquisitely, and Mr. 
            <span class="person">Boucher</span>, (violencello) is
            justly entitled to the same praise. The other parts were
            well sustained, and the Amateurs deserve much commendation for the careful way in which they played their several
            portions. Tne overtures were ably led by Dr. 
            <span class="person">Quin</span>, and we
            must do the Amateur and professional gentlemen concerned
            the justice to say, that his efforts were, by them, most warmly seconded.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss 
            <span class="person">Northall</span> is a very young singer, and has very much
            to learn before she can take her stand as a public performer.
            Her education has been but indifferently attended to; she has
            contracted a very vicious style, which, if not speedily corrected, will ruin her prospects forever. She has been lavishly
            and injudiciously lauded by our friends of the Mirror, whose
            good nature, and total absence of musical critical acumen,
            will naturally lead them into puffing anybody, and unless real
            and judicious friends can be found, to tell her some wholesome, but bitter truths, she will quietly sink from before the
            public, as too many have done before her. We shall take
            that necessary but unpleasant duty upon ourselves, when we
            next have the opportunity of hearing her.
         </p>
         
         <p>One word about our friend the leader, before we close the
            notice of this excellent society. Doctor 
            <span class="person">Quin</span>, a highly talented and eminent physician, Homeopathic, has for many
            years been the life, soul, and almost body of the Euterpean
            Society. He is one of the very few amateurs of music whose
            enthusiasm is real, earnest and unaffected. His mind highly
            educated and refined, has carried him far beyond the trivialities which delight the ordinary amateur. Music has been to
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page92"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>him, like his profession, a study. The old masters are as
            familiar to him as Latin, Greek, German, and French. He
            has studied their beauties and feels them knowingly. We
            have the pleasure of a personal acquaintance with him, and
            can therefore speak confidently upon the subject. We cordially congratulate the Euterpean Society upon the possession of such a leader, and we feel assured that while he continues with them the cause for which the society was established will never want an able and earnest advocate.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss 
            <span class="person">Bramson</span> s Concert. This very clever young lady
            gave a concert at the Tabernacle on the 30th ult. She was
            assisted by her sister, a mere child of some six or seven years
            of age, a Mr. 
            <span class="person">Napoleon Knight</span>, a Mr. 
            <span class="person">Rosbach</span>, 
            <span class="person">Signor Ra</span>petti, and a skeleton band.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is a singular fact, and one which shows the perversity
            of human nature, that the public appreciation of an artist,
            rarely comes up to his own appreciation or that of his friends.
            How often do we see the Tabernacle taken by artists who
            firmly and modestly believe that the public will, or ought, to
            rush in crowds to fill it, but how seldom do we see the public
            fulfil the expectation of the artist. Concert-givers are hard
            to convince they will not learn by the experience of others:
            they see failure upon failure, but they attribute them in every
            instance to the want of that particular attraction which they
            believe themselves to possess in the highest degree. If
            Mr. 
            <span class="person">Bramson</span> had been content with the Apollo Saloon,
            or the Minerva Rooms, the audience would nearly have filled
            either, and he would have been money in pocket.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss 
            <span class="person">Bramson</span> is a very excellent pianist, she has a light
            elastic touch, a flexible wrist, good execution, and for one so
            young, she exhibits much taste and expression. She ought
            to be withdrawn from the public, and her education should
            be attended to with the greatest care; her mind should be
            directed to a higher school than that of 
            <span class="person">Herz</span> and 
            <span class="person">Czerny</span>; a
            succession of the preludes of Old 
            <span class="person">Sebastian Bach</span> or 
            <span class="person">Cramer</span>,
            should be interspersed with 
            <span class="person">Mozart</span>, 
            <span class="person">Hummel</span>, 
            <span class="person">Weber</span>, Beethoven, and a host of other great and classical Piano Forte
            writers. Teachers but too often begin at the wrong end,
            making the light, easy, and frivolous works, the grand course,
            while the classical works sometimes are added, but only as
            entrees. This is altogether wrong.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss 
            <span class="person">Bramson</span> the less, plays as well as a child of five or six years can be expected to
            play.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. 
            <span class="person">Napoleon Knight</span> is a failure. Had 
            <span class="person">Napoleon</span> never
            ventured into Russia, in all human probability, he would
            have remained unconquered still; and by parity of reasoning,
            had Mr. 
            <span class="person">Napoleon Knight</span>remained in England, his reputation would be now as great as ever ( !! ) We do not appreciate his peculiarities; want of correct intonation, vulgarity
            of pronunciation, and coarseness of style, are looked upon by
            us as faults, though they may be considered beauties in the
            region whence lie comes.
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person">Signor Rapetti</span> did as much as could be expected with the incompetent band under his
            direction.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         
         <div class="head">VARIETIES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            
            <div class="head">THE CURSE OF CRITICISM.</div>
            
            <p>Malice often makes the pretence of criticism the convenience of circulating her detractions; but honest criticism has
               no more evil in it than the scalpel of the surgeon. Doubtless
               much harm is done by malicious spirits who assume the office
               of the critic to gratify their propensities for inflicting pain.
               Such imps of fame have brought discredit upon the honorable and necessary office which malicious men, above all
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>others, are least qualified to fill, let their pretensions be what they
               may.
            </p>
            
            <p>We do not remember of ever meeting with a sadder account of the wrongs inflicted by malicious criticism than that
               contained in a statement of the death of an artist in Paris,
               the last month, by suicide.
            </p>
            
            <p>
               <span class="person">Samuele Jesi</span> was an Italian engraver, who undertook
               twenty years ago to make a line engraving of the portraits
                of 
               <span class="person">Leo the Tenth</span> and the Cardinals de Medici and 
               <span class="person">de Rossi</span>,
               from a painting by 
               <span class="person">Raffaelle</span> in the Pitti Palace at Florence.
               For twenty years this work was his sole care and hope, he
               gave his life literally to his plate, and when it was finished
               he entrusted the publication of it to the celebrated print sellers, Messrs. 
               <span class="person">Goupil</span> and 
               <span class="person">Vibert</span>. After so long a period of
               patient labor, and utter exhaustion of resources, it may readily be believed that the result was a matter of harrowing
               anxiety to the devoted artist. The engraving is represented
               as the first of its class, a pure line engraving, and so treated
               that every object and material in the composition are represented with a most appropriate feeling. But competition
               among artists in Paris is very great, and criticism proportionally keen. It appears that in some quarters an ungenerous feeling was shown towards the work of 
               <span class="person">Signor
                  Jesi
               </span>, which so affected him that he put an end to his existence by shattering his skull against the marble chimney
               piece of his sleeping room.
            </p>
            
            <p>He was the pupil and friend of 
               <span class="person">Rafaelle Morghen</span>, and his
               early works are said to resemble, in a striking manner, those
               of his master.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            
            <div class="head">A NEW WASHINGTON MONUMENT.</div>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person">Robert Kerr</span> has published a large lithographic print
               of a design for a Washington Monument, which is much less
               objectionable than that of Mr. 
               <span class="person">Pollard</span> s, as a work of art; but
               which has the same incongruous principle of uniting in one
               structure, a house and a monument; two things so entirely
               unlike, that they can never be made to harmonize together.
               Mr. 
               <span class="person">Kerr</span> says, that the  principle of utility  has been kept
               in view in making his design. But his idea of utility differs
               essentially from our own. The utility of a house consists of
               it habi:ableness; the utility of a monument consists of its
               monumental completeness; when its perfectness as a monument is destroyed, its utility is destroyed, even though it be
               made a house of refuge for the homeless.
            </p>
            
            <p> Such a structure cannot be a small one,  says Mr. 
               <span class="person">Kerr</span>;
               but small and large are mere relative terms; his own structure is to be 220 feet high, which Mr. 
               <span class="person">Pollard</span> would consider
               very small, for it is only half the altitude of his design.
               The true size for a monument of a hero is the life size; there
               is no greatness in mere expansion of dimensions. The Greeks
               erected colossal statues in honor of the victor in one battle,
               but the conqueror of three was represented of a life size,
               which is the true standard of dignity. A glance at the monster Washington, by 
               <span class="person">Greenough</span>, in the capitol, will satisfy
               any body how much the human form loses in dignity of
               expression by exaggeration.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person">Kerr</span> s monument shows infinitely more invention than
               Mr. 
               <span class="person">Pollard</span>'s, but we do not think it worth while to survey
               in detail a work which is grossly wrong in principle. We
               do not object to it because it is not classical, but because it is
               not perfect in itself. It seems to be but little more than three
               choragic monuments set on top of each other, and made habitable. The choragic monuments, though the largest among
               the Greeks, were of the lowest order; and the use of any
               structure resembling them, for such a purpose as a monument
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page93"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>in honor of Washington, would always have a be-littling effect upon the feelings, even though it were as vast as St.
               
               <span class="person">Peter</span> s. The only description of monument in honor of
               Washington, which can be devised, that will not outrage
               good feeling, must represent him either in his own majestic
               proportions, or else, by seme figure symbolical of his greatness,
               in which simplicity and truth, united with grace of execution,
               will create the feeling of veneration, which mere magnitude
               can never do.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            
            <div class="head">THE SNOW.</div>
            
            <p>The Snow-storm of Tuesday and Wednesday. This is
               the grand event of the season. We have not had such an avalanche of snow since the winter of 1836. After a season of
               unexampled mildness, just as the davs were getting longer,
               and the sun hotter, and every body had given up all hopes of
               a sleigh-ride, there comes upon us such a fall of snow flakes,
               as we shall rarely witness. The streets, for two days,
               have been nearly impassable, but such is the exciting effect
               of snow, that many people were out for the fun of it, who
               could not be tempted out by fine weather. We have not
               heard so much hearty laughter for a year, as we heard in the
               streets yesterday. Men would get almost smothered in attempting to cross the street, and boys had the finest sport
               conceivable, in throwing snow-balls at each other; added to
               all, was the merry jingle of the sleigh-bells, which are always
               stirring to the blood. We would not exchange one good oldfashioned snow storm, like this that has just visited us, fora
               twelve-month in the tropics. But amid all the hearty merriment, caused by the falling snow, the shouting voices of
               boisterous apprentices, and muffled-up omnibus drivers, we
               could not keep our thoughts from the poor sailors on the coast,
               and the poor women and children in our cellars. God help
               them all. Perhaps there were some good monks, like the
               brothers of St, 
               <span class="person">Bernard</span>, out yesterday in the snow-drifts, seeking, with baskets of provender and bundles of flannel, for the
               feeble folk who were overtaken by the storm; we hope so!
               The wind howled frightfully through the Park trees in the
               evening, and towards morning, a disastrous fire broke out in
               the Tribune Buildings, and heightened somewhat the desolate
               grandeur of the whole scene. It was worth looking at. Such
               a combination of sublime elements is not often witnessed; a
               hurricane, a snow-storm, and a conflagration. It was a subject for Cole.
            </p>
            
            <p>But a snow-storm is nothing in the city. It is one of the
               delights of the country. While the snow lasts it is a high
               holiday. All labor partakes of the character of an amusement; bells jingle, horses sweat, neighbors visit, boys are
               kept from school, turkeys are killed, cider is drank, something hot is always at hand, fiddlers find full employment,
               Parties are made, dinners are given, balls are got up in a
               hurry, darkies grin with delight (poor things) to see others so
               happy, and every thing is jollity and merriment.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p16">
         
         <div class="head">THE MAGAZINES.</div>
         
         <p>There are two kinds of Magazines, those that appear on the first
            of the month, and those that appear in the middle of it. The first
            are the five dollar ones without illustrations, the others the three dollar ones with them. Instead of illustrations, perhaps it were safer to
            say pictures; and again, instead of pictures, it would be safer still to
            say engravings. There is still another point of difference between
            the Magazines. One kind are printed in Philadelphia and the other in
            New York. Nothing higher than three dollars in the shape of a
            Magazine, has ever thriven in Philadelphia; nothing lower than five
            dollars has ever done well in New York. We have thus, we believe,
            given the distinguishing features of the two species of the Magazines.
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>We might distinguish them still farther, as: the three dollar species
            have pinkish colored covers, fifty leaved, and are of both sexes; while
            the five dollar species are generally males, have a hundred leaves, and
            are bluish or brown covered. In other respects the points of difference
            are not very marked. The three Magazines now before us are of the
            five dollar kind.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>The Knickerbocker comes first, being the oldest Magazine alive,
            and entitled, as a matter of course, to precedence. The number for
            this month contains the customary variety of papers, among which is
            the fourth paper of a series on Cuba, which contains much valuable
            and interesting information regarding that Island. The Editor s Table, which has a marked idiosyncrasy, has the customary set out of
            pleasant dishes, among which every taste is sure to find something to
            its liking.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Democratic Review is embellished with a very truthful
            looking portrait of 
            <span class="person">Auguste Davezac</span>, which is itself illustrated by
            what the writer calls,  a very brief sketch of the skeleton of Major
            
            <span class="person">Davezac</span> s Life.  This brief sketch of the skeleton of the Major s
            Life is altogether a work of supererogation. The portrait itself tells the
            whole story. We have never seen a belter summary of a character
            than that made by the lines of the Major s portrait. Were it not for
            the concluding passage of the  Sketch of the Skeleton of Major
            
            <span class="person">Davezac</span> s Life,  we should think that he wrote it himself. But it ap.
            pears to be the work of one who has been is the  same legislative
            councils  with the Major.
         </p>
         
         <p> In regard to his political character,  says the writer of the
             Sketch of the Skeleton,   we can testify from intimate intercourse
            in the same legislative councils, as well as much other political association, that he is one of the most thoroughly ingrained Democrats we
            have ever known. It is not only a thought in his head, but a deep
            rooted feeling in his heart. And as the English Queen said that the
            name Calais would be found visibly impressed upon her head after
            her death, so do we almost believe that Democracy may be found
            stamped on that of our venerable friend; unless, indeed, that of Andrew 
            <span class="person">Jackson</span>should have monopolized the whole surface of the Organ a point of no great importance, synonymous as the latter may
            almost be regarded as being for the former. 
         </p>
         
         <p>We regard this brief sketch as the most remarkable piece of writing that we have ever encountered in any Magazine, whether three
            dollar or five dollar. The Democratic contains several fine papers,
            embodying much wholesome thought and many aids to reflection.
            The article on Army Organization manifests considerable learning on
            a subject which is happily falling into disrepute every day. The
            " first eight days in England  by Judge 
            <span class="person">Carleton</span>of New Orleans, evinces much more good will than discrimination. The Judge had no
            need to go to Manchester to see little children with naked feet in mid
            winter. Our own streets are full of such sights, and more mud than
            can be found in any city in Europe. There are all sons of ways of
            attracting attention in a Coffee House. Mr. 
            <span class="person">Weed</span> informed us in his
            letters from Dublin, that he made quite a sensation one morning by
            calling out to the waiters to take away the silver fork they had
            brought him, and give him a steel one in its place. Judge 
            <span class="person">Carleton</span>,
            finding himself in the Coffee-room of a Liverpool hotel, where nobody
            seemed disposed to notice him, determined to arrest the attention of
            somebody; and adopted the following ingenious expedient.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Opposite to me,  says the Judge,  sat a stout gentleman whose
            abstraction announced that silence was not to be broken. He seemed
            unconscious of my presence; nevertheless I resolved to unlock his
            frozen speech. But how? I studied my part, and throwing down my
            knife, I exclaimed,1 At last I have seen that beautiful, that unspeakably beautiful England! I studied its geography when a boy, its history when a man, and the half had not been told me! Such an exclamation as this in a room where gentlemen were quietly eating their
            breakfast, gained the Judge ihe attention which he coveted, as a matter of course.
         </p>
         
         <p>The article on Pascal; Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span> s Essay on 
            <span class="person" id="wcbryant">Bryant</span> s poetry;
            and the characteristic story of South-Western Life, by the writer who
            calls himself 
            <span class="person" id="cwelmi">C. Wilkins Elmi</span>, are well worth reading.
         </p>
         
         <p>The American Review for this month is a decided improvement
            upon th ' first number. It contains many pleasant articles, and a poem
            by Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="eapoe">Poe</span>, which is not ascribed to that gentleman, for what reason
            we are at a loss to conceive, lor it is a piece of verse which the best
            of our poets would hardly wish to disown. The prefatory remarks of
            the Editor arc rather mystifying, and seem to tend to the disparagement of the poem as principally recommended by its versification. 
            "The Literary Prospects of 1845,   is a very agreeable and genial
            paper by Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="eaduyckinck">Duyckinck</span>, who is one of those rare men that devote
            their time and abundance to the cultivation of letters, not as a means
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page94"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>of dissipating time and procuring a refined enjoyment, but as the
            means of doing good to others, and promoting social reform. The
            Review of 
            <span class="person" id="aalison">Alison</span> s History by Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="jtheadley">Headley</span>, is long and able,
            but too much in the massacrante style for the dignity of a review. It
            would be difficult to account for the popularity of 
            <span class="person" id="aalison">Alison</span> s History in
            this country, were it not that we make it a point to read everything
            that is popular in England; and that it is a passion with the English
            to read everything that is called history.  Words  by 
            <span class="person" id="epwhipple">E. P. Whip
               pie
            </span>, is a very bright and sparkling essay. The article on Post Office
            reform, must be a commendable paper, since it advocates reform of
            some kind; but we widely differ with the writer in regard to the opening idea of his essay. " Of all the manifold devices supplied by the
            ingenuity of man to promote the progress of civilization, a National
            Post Office stands in the foremost ranks of importance.  Now we
            think that the very reverse is the truth. A National Post Office which
            puts a curb upon individual enterprise, is not only a drag upon civilization, but it will continue to be, what it has long been, one of the
            most prolific sources of political corruption in our system. Any modification of our present Post Office laws cannot be otherwise than beneficial; but any alterations short of abolishing the system entirely,
            will always leave something to be reformed. The American Review
            was established with the professed design of counteracting the influences of the Democratic Review, and it seems to be admirably
            adapted to that end. We have never seen two works so nearly alike.
            Extract from each the mere partisan slang which marks their political essays, and it would be difficult to decide which was which.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s6">
         
         <div class="head">LITERARY NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            
            <p>The Treasury of History, No. 2. Price 2ft cents. 
               <span class="person" id="dadee">Daniel Adee</span>, 107 Fulton street.
            </p>
            
            <p>A work of great value at a very low price. As a book of historical
               reference it will be indispensable in a library. We are happy to perceive that this edition of Maunder's Encyclopoedia of History is to be
               enriched by a History of America, by 
               <span class="person" id="jinman">John Inman</span>.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            
            <p>A Chaunt of Life and other Poems, with Sketches and Essays, by 
               <span class="person" id="rhoyt">Ralph Hoyt</span>, in Six
               Parts. Part 1. 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is too little material in this delicate volume to base an opinion of the author s poetic ability upon. The poems are but five short
               pieces of verse, besides the Chaunt the Sketches and Essays do not
               appear. The author says that " these compositions appear in compliance with the wishes of many of the writer s friends.  We cannot
               conceive of a better reason for publishing a volume of poems, or one
               better calculated to disarm criticism. The embellishments of Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="rhoyt">Hoyt</span> s modest volume are rather an injury to it.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="gcatlin">Catlin</span>s New Work. North American Indian Portfolio, containing Hunting Scenes. Amusements, Scenery and Costume of the Indians of the
               Rocky
               Mountains and Prairie* of America, a series of 25 magnificent lithographic
               plates, printed in tints by Day &amp; Haghe, accompanied by full and interesting letter press descriptions. Half bound morocco, price  5 5s. Or
               with
               the plates beautifully colored in the style of Drawing, mounted on tinted
               cards, enveloped in a handsome portfolio, price  10 10s. Henry G. Bohn,
               York street, Covent Garden.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            
            <p>Rome as seen by a New Yorker in 1843-4. New York and London: Wiley and Putnam.
               1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>It would be idle to look for any thing new in a book professing to
               give the observations of a looker-on in Rome, even though he is a New
               Yorker, and we are not disappointed therefore upon inspecting the
               work before us; but if we find nothing new in its pages, we find nothing
               that is objectionable, saving a few remarks on classic Art, wherein the
               author appears to make some very common mistakes about ideality
               and actuality. In other respects the book is a very agreeable one, and
               perhaps fully equal to its pretensions. In external appearance it is one
               of the neatest specimens of book-making that we have encountered
               since we began to look into books, with the special design to discern
               their defects and merits. The author s name is not given, but it is
               understood to be from the pen of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="wmgillespie">W. M. Gillespie</span>, whose letters in
               the Tribune, a year or two since, were very generally admired.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            
            <p>The Wonderful Adventures of Baron Munchausen. New York: Farmer and Daggers, 30 
               <span class="person">Ann</span>
               street.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have not met the Baron before for many a long year, and we
               welcome him back to us now, as we would any other old friend who
               had delighted us in our youth. We have often wondered that some of
               our publishers did not re-introduce the marvellous story-teller to the
               present generation of wonder-loving boys.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            
            <p>Blackwood's Magazine, for January. Republished by Leonard Scott &amp; Co., 112 Fulton
               street.
            </p>
            
            <p>The present number contains a paper from 
               <span class="person" id="jwilson">Christopher North</span>, on
               
               <span class="person" id="stcoleridge">Coleridge</span>, very much in the manner of his early essays, which gained
               him his great renown.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            
            <p>The Southern Quarterly Review. No 13. January, 1845. Charleston.</p>
            
            <p>It is a matter of surprise that a work of this character should not be
               more extensively known. The proprietor seems to have no particular
               ambition to give it a circulation north of the Potomac; for we cannot
               find that he has any agents for the sale of it in any of the northern
               cities, excepting Boston. Being a New-Englander and a resident of S.
               Carolina, it is very natural that Boston and Charleston should form
               his two points d appui. Southern Reviews not being articles of prime
               necessity, like rice and turpentine, will not be sought after with the
               same perseverance that those commodities are by northern speculators. If the South would have us take her literary productions she
               must send them to us. The only iood that the north has ever sought
               at the South is food for the body. These remarks must not be taken
               unfairly; we only mean what we say, and have no thought of disparaging the work before us, which strikes us as being equal in most
               points
               to the North American.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is a genuine quarterly Review, modelled after the recognized
               standards, which it seems ambitious of equalling, not excelling. It is
               a form of literature that has never succeeded well in this country, and
               we doubt whether it be calculated to meet the requirements of our
               people. Some of the articles in the present number of the Southern
               Quarterly are apparently able, and one of them, a Review of Mrs.
               
               <span class="person" id="ecjgray">Gray</span> s History of Etruria, by 
               <span class="person" id="gfholmes">George Frederick Holmes</span>, is learned,
               but too ambitiously smart. The longest and most imposing article, on
               Education in Europe, is from the pen of the editor, Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="dkwhitaker">Whitaker</span>.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p24">
         
         <div class="head">MUSICAL INTELLIGENCE.</div>
         
         <p>Madame Pico is in Boston. She was engaged to sing at the Philharmonic Society, and intends, we understand, to give several Concerts on her own account. It is also rumored that after giving Concerts in various places, Madame Pico, with 
            <span class="person">Sanquirico</span>, 
            <span class="person">Yaltellina</span> and
            others, will perform at the Italian Opera, 
            <span class="person">Chiara di Rosenberg</span>, Cenerentola,&amp;c. &amp;c.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is reported that Madame Valtellina will be the Prima Donna at
            the Opera House with Pico. The season to commence in a week or
            two.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is also rumored that 
            <span class="person">Signora Amalia Ricci</span> will appear at the Opera shortly in one of
            Donizetta s operas.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Seguins are playing with distinguished success at Charleston.
            Miss 
            <span class="person">Moss</span> is with them, and performs the character of the Queen in
            the Bohemian Girl.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. 
            <span class="person">George Loder</span>s Concert takes place on the 22d inst. Mendelsshon s splendid composition, the Lobegesang, or Hymn of Praise, is to
            be performed, for the first time in this country. The solo parts are to be
            sung by Mrs. 
            <span class="person">E. Loder</span>, 
            <span class="person">Miss Watson</span>, 
            <span class="person">Signor Antognini</span>. The chorus
            will be sustained by the members of the New York Vocal Society,
            with others; and the instrumental part by the principal members of
            the Philharmonic Society. It will be a fine performance in every respect. There will be a miscellaneous act in which many popular singers will appear.
         </p>
         
         <p>The new grand Opera House is at present but an air built house, and
            if promises are not resolved into action, so it will remain. We hear of
            many offering to take shares to a large amount, but nothing we believe
            is as yet definitely settled.
         </p>
         
         <p>We understand that the New York Harmonist Quartette Club propose to give a series of Concerts in a week or two.</p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s7">
         
         <div class="head">BITS OF NEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span> s Poets and Poetry of Europe will be published in about six weeks.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#pg28">
            
            <p>Carey and Hart have in press a new work of native humor by the
               author of Major Jones s Courtship, which will be illustrated by 
               <span class="person">Darley</span>
               of Philadelphia. The same publishers will soon issue a genuine Southwestern book, rich in adventure and humor, such as are encountered by
               voyagers down the Mississippi; the author is a Kentuckian. We shall
               give due notice of its appearance.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p29">
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person">Petre</span>, the British Consul in Philadelphia, a gentleman hardly more distinguished
               for his fine social qualities than for his profound
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page95"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>and almost universal acquaintance with the classic authors, has ready for
               the press the  Poets and Poetry of Greece and Rome. 
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p30">
            
            <p>A New Edition of 
               <span class="person" id="tcarlyle">Carlyle</span>.
               <span class="person"> Carey</span> and 
               <span class="person">Hart</span> have in press, a complete
               edition of the Critical and Miscellaneous Writings of 
               <span class="person" id="tcarlyle">Thomas Carlyle</span>,
               with a Preface by 
               <span class="person" id="rwemerson">Ralph Waldo Emerson</span>. This is to be published for the author s
               benefit.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p31">
            
            <p>Powers, the sculptor, has nearly finished a work for a distinguished gentleman in
               Philadelphia, which is said by good critics in Italy very much to surpass his Eve.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p32">
            
            <p>The Harpers will publish, in a few days, a new edition of 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span> s
               Poems, which will contain, it is said, some pieces never before published.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p33">
            
            <p>
               <span class="person">Leutze</span> is engaged on the greatest of all his pictures, the Landing of
               the Norsemen in America. One of the most celebrated of the living
               sculptors of Germany, in writing to a gentleman in Philadelphia in regard to 
               <span class="person">Leutze</span>, relates, that several eminent artists and men of
               letters
               from Denmark were in his studio, and looked with expressive silence
               on his unfinished picture some time, and when they turned away, exclaimed simultaneously,  It breathes the very spirit of our Sagas! 
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         
         <p>To Readers and Correspondents. There are a good many enquiries
            as to the success of our undertaking, for which we are extremely grateful. Many of our good friends, we are informed, are waiting to
            see whether we succeed before they lend us their aid. Excellent friends! The world
            is full of such, and every prosperous undertaking is sure
            of their support. They are always ready to go on a second voyage of
            discovery when everything has been discovered. They are always the
            first in at every death. They monopolize all the fat offices under Government, let what party be in power that wilt. They always wait to
            see whether a thing will succeed, before they will lend the light of their
            countenance to it. They are the patrons of genius, after genius has
            overcome its first difficulties. They know nothing of the early streaks
            of morning, but are sure to be up with the sun. We have a great respect for the entire class, because they are so numerous; they are in
            fact the majority, out of whose sixpences we expect to make our profits;
            we therefore hasten to assure them that our success is complete, beyond
            the possibility of a contingency: if they aid us they will have the pleasant feeling, so grateful to the class, of knowing that they aid those
            who
            can afford to do without their assistance. Of course they will note send
            along their subscriptions, and request their friends to subscribe too;
            when they write anything good they will, of course, send it to us,
            and instead of requesting pay, will give us something for inserting their
            brilliant effusions in our columns. To the opposite of this class, those
            who generously gave us a push at the outset, with no other motive than
            a desire to help us foward, we return our sincere thanks, and hope that
            we may not disappoint their expectations. It is our misfortune that
            people will insist on making comparisons between our Journal and the
            London weekly papers; such as the Athenaeum, the Literary Gazette,
            and The Spectator. It would be idle to attempt a rivalship with these
            long established and costly journals. We have not a tithe of the materials in New York to compose a weekly magazine of the character of
            the Athenaum. We have neither learned societies, new books, nor
            works of art to comment upon. We have neither buyers nor readers to
            depend upon; and above all, we have hardly any of the same class of
            advertisers that exist in London. There, the weekly press is almost entirely supported by publishers, here publishers advertise only in daily
            journals. Furthermore our paper contains nearly as much reading
            as the Literary Gazette, and is sold at one third the price of that paper.
             But with all these disadvantages, which we were wide-awake to before
            we began our Journal, the way opens before us; and we have little
            doubt of permanent success. Many readers complain that our paper
            is not scrappy enough; but nothing is more easy than to fill our columns with shreds and patches; with all manner of cold bits like a beggar s wallet; but it is our ambition to do something better. A beggar
            who had never been used to anything but discarded crusts and cast off
            garments, would of course have an uncomfortable feeling if seated before an untouched sirloin; he would miss the refuse of tin table which
            his appetite had become inured to. This is the exact case with our
            weekly magazine readers, they have been so long accustomed to stale
            reading and little scrappy bits of news which they had seen elsewhere,
            that they cannot at once accustom themselves to a well considered article
            of moderate length, which they had never seen before. One of our
            principal objects was to establish a journal which could be depended upon for an expression of honest opinion, whether it were able or not;
            and this point we mean to keep constantly in view; let our statements
            be worth what they may, they shall be honest.
         </p>
         
         <p>There are a good many people who have keen saying the last year or two,
            that a work, something like ours, was needed, and if established, would
            be supported; wt expect that all such will lend us their aid, and when
            they see that we are well under way they can either withdraw their support, or claim to be put upon the list of eleemosynary subscribers. We
            have found more difficulty than wt had anticipated, in securing a
            certain kind of reporting, which we mean to secure as soon as we can
            find it, which will add greater value to our columns. The engravings
            of new buildings have been delayed, too, because we have not found the
            kind of talent which we think it necessary to employ. But it is among
            us, and we mean to bring it out.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have in the hands of an artist a portrait of a distinguished prose writer, which we hope to give in our next number accompanied by an essay
            on his genius.
         </p>
         
         <p>The communication from E. O. S. of Hartford, has by some accident been misplaced.
            It
            will appear as soon as we can lay our hands upon it.
         </p>
         
         <p>The paper by E. S." B.H. H.F. B. and Also" have been re ceived.</p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s8">
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">BY THE CAMBRIA VALENTINES!</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Ho for the day, when true lovers may
               
               <br></br>Their vows to each other impart,
               
               <br></br>Uncensur d by those who feign would oppose
               
               <br></br>The spontaneous flow of the heart.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>THE Proprietor has the pleasure to announce to the
               Public that he has received probably the largest, most superb and beautiful
               assortment of English Valentines that has been imported by any other house
               in the city, or perhaps in the country. It comprises a great number of new
               and novel designs and devices, illuminations, silver wreath in relief, lace and
               satin work, mirrors, &amp;c. He can furnish Valentines of such superior magnificence, on vellum, illuminated and ornamented on the four sides, as
               to be
               worth $30 which may be preserved for generations, as beautiful curiosities!
            </p>
            
            <p>W. A. C. has also prepared a handsome variety of elegantly written Val-
               entines, filled with beautiful, gay, poetical and complimentary sentiments.
               Valentines splendidly painted and illuminated with Names, Devices, and
               Verses, to order, at short notice. Please call before purchasing elsewhere.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">
               <span class="person">WM. A. COLMAN</span> S, No. 203 Broadway.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE AMERICAN REVIEW.</div>
            
            <p>A WHIG JOURNAL OF POLITICS, LITERATURE, ART AND SCIENCE. Edited by 
               <span class="person" id="ghcolton">Geo. S. Colton</span>, and published monthly at 118 Nassau St. New York, and by Wiley 4c Putnam 161
               Broadway, and 6 Waterloo Placc, Regent Street, London, at Five Dollars
               per anum in advance Single Nos. fifty cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is the aim of this Review discarding all national and sectarian influence
                to harmonize in a kindlier acquaintanceship the different sections of the
               country; to set forth more clearly the inexhaustible resources of our territory; to elevate the morals of the people: to withstand pusillanimity
               at home
               and indignities abroad; to promote American science, and diffuse throughout
               the land a higher order of taste in letters and the Arts. Though established
               ostentsibly on partisan grounds, the Review proposes to itself no mere party
               triumph but the moral, social and literary welfaie of the commonwealth.
            </p>
            
            <p>The following is from the origional Prospectus issued at Washington by
               the Whig Members of the Twenty-Seventh Congress:
            </p>
            
            <p> Earnestly approving of the plan of such a national organ, long needed
               and of manifest importance, the undersigned agree to contribute for its pages, from time to time, such communications as may be requisite to set
               forth
               and defend the doctrines held by the united Whig Party of the Union  Geo.
               
               <span class="person" id="gpmarsh">P. Marsh</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="ddbarnard">D. D. Barnard</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jringersoll">J. R. Ingersoll</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="ejmorris">E. Joy Morris</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="tlclingman">T. L. Clingman</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jmberrien">J.
                  McPheison Berrien
               </span>, 
               <span class="person" id="dwebster">Daniel Webster</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="rcwinthrop">Robert C. Winthrop</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="tbking">Thomas Butler
                  King
               </span>, 
               <span class="person" id="hfish">Hamilton</span> Fish, 
               <span class="person" id="jpkennedy">J. P. Kennedy</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jcollamer">J. Collamer</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jjhardin">John J. Hardin</span>
               <span class="person" id="wsarcher"> Wm. S.
                  Archer
               </span>, 
               <span class="person" id="rchoate">Rufus Choate</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="ahstephens">Alexander H. Stephens</span>. 
            </p>
            
            <p>In addition to these, a number of writers have been enlisted for its various
               other departments, so that even- number, besides strong political articles
               will contain about 80 pages of Literary Miscellany in History, Biography,
               Criticism, Fiction, Poetry, Statistics, Science and the Arts, three or four Engravings of the most finished the likenesses of men eminent in the
               present
               or past age, will be given in the course of the year. No pains will be spared
               or means left unemployed, to make it the first of American periodicals. 
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person">JOHN DOUGLAS</span>, 
               BOOK AND JOB PRINTER
            </div>
            
            <p>NO. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every description of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
               with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, ou terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
            </p>
            
            <p>January 16, 1845.</p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DR. 
               <span class="person" id="tarnold">ARNOLD</span> S LIFE AND CORRESPONDENCE.
            </div>
            
            <p>D APPLETON &amp; CO. have just published, THE LIFE
               AND CORRESPONDENCE OF THOMAS ARNOLD, D.D.
               By Rev. 
               <span class="person" id="apstanley">E. P. Stanley</span>, M.A. From the Third English Edition, 2 vols
               8vo. in 1 vol. 12mo. Price $1 50.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Life of Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="tarnold">Arnold</span> will be found to be of unusual value and in
               terest to all literary persons. Heads of Colleges and Seminaries of
               Learning, Students and Teachers in public and private schools.
            </p>
            
            <p>No considerable review in England, representing either the high or
               low parties in Church or State no weekly or daily publication has
               failed to express the wonderful power and beauty of this volume of
               Biography.
            </p>
            
            <p>NEW HISTORY OF THE FRENCH REVOLUTION. D. Appleton and Co. have recently published History of the
               French Revolution its causes and consequences j by 
               <span class="person" id="fmrowan">F. Maclean Rowan</span>; 2 vols 18mo, cloth 75 cts., or 1 vol. 63cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>This work has many and valuable recommendations. Its comoilation has been effected with care and good judgment; its stvle is esl
               sentially popular, its arrangements clear and methodical and the
               whole form as condensed, comprehensive, and succinct a history of the
               most important event of this age, (both in itself and its consequences as we
               remember to have seen in so brief a space. _English Critic, Sept. 16, 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>In a few days, Part 2, price 25 cents 
               HISTORY OF FRANCE, from the earliest period;
               translated from the French of 
               <span class="person" id="jmichelet">M. Michelet</span>, by 
               <span class="person">G. H. Smith</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>The celebrity of this work on the continent, and the want in English
               literature of a good history of France, has induced the publishers to
               introduce it to the American public at a price within the means of all.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page96"></div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
            </p>
            
            <p>The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. 
               <span class="person">A. G. Bigelow</span> s
               professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished aud skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Hon. 
               <span class="person">J. W. M. Berrien</span>, Geo. 
               
               <br></br>   
               <span class="person">Joshua Herrick</span>, Me. 
               
               <br></br>   
               <span class="person">James Irvin</span>, Pa.
               
               <br></br>Hon. 
               <span class="person">John B. Dawson</span>, La.
               
               <br></br>   
               <span class="person">John H. Lumpkin</span>, 
               <span class="person">Geo</span>.
               
               <br></br>   
               <span class="person">J. Thompson</span>, Miss. 
               
            </div>
            
            <p>Dr. 
               <span class="person">A. G. Bigelow</span> s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty St., New York.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PROPOSALS FOR PUBLISHING BY SUBSCRIPTION,
               TRANSACTIONS
               OF THE
               Ethnological Society of New York
               VOLUME I.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS volume will consist of articles by members of the
               Ethnological Society, relating to various topics of interest to the
               Antiquary and Philologist. It will consist of from four to five hundred
               pages 8vo., printed on good paper and in the best manner.
            </p>
            
            <p>A number of engravings illustrative of the several papers, will accompany the volume.</p>
            
            <p>Art. II. An Essay on the Grave-Creek Mound in the Ohio Valley 
               By 
               <span class="person" id="hrschoolcraft">Henry R. Schoolcraft</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>Art. III. A Dissertation on some curious evidences of an Era of Ancient Semi-civilization in the West, noticed in the progress
               of settlements in the Mississippi Valley and the Lakes. By
               
               <span class="person" id="hrschoolcraft">Henry R. Schoolcraft</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>Art. IV. An account of Ancient Remains in Tennessee. By 
               <span class="person" id="gtroost">Gerard
                  Troost
               </span>, M. D., Prof. of Chemistry, Geology, &amp;c. in the
               University of Tennessee.
            </p>
            
            <p>Art. V. On the recent discoveries of Himyaritic Inscriptions, and the
               attempts made to decipher them. By 
               <span class="person" id="wwturner">Wm. W. Turner</span>
            </p>
            
            <p>Art. VI. A visit to the I.ybio-Phcenician Monument at Dugga, near
               the site of ancient Carthage. By 
               <span class="person" id="fcatherwood">Frederic Catherwood</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>Art. VII. An Account of the Serreculies, or Serranalies, with h ints respecting several other tribes or families of people composing
               the Fullah nation, and those inhabiting the neighboring
               Counties of Western Nigritia. By 
               <span class="person">Theodore Dwight</span>, Jr.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, Booksellers
               and Importers, 7 Astor House, New-York.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">HUNT S MERCHANTS  MAGAZINE
               AND COMMERCIAL REVIEW.
            </div>
            
            <p>BY 
               <span class="person" id="fhunt">FREEMAN HUNT</span>, Editor and Proprietor. Published Monthly, at 142 Fulton Street, New York at Five Dollars
               per annum, in Advance.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE MERCHANTS MAGAZINE and COMMERCIAL REVIEW, embraces every subject connected with Commerce, Manufactures and Political Economy, as follows: Commercial Legislation;
               Commercial History and Geography; Mercantile Biography; Descriptive, Statistical and Historical Accounts, of the various commodities which form the subject of Mercantile transactions; Port Charges;
               Tariffs: Customs and Excise Regulations; Commercial Statistics of
               the United States and the different countries of the world, with which
               we have intercourse, including their Physical Character, Population,
               Productions, Exports, Imports, Seaports, Monies, Weight*, Measures
               Finance and Banking Associations, and Enterprises connected with
               Commerce, embracing Fisheries, Incorporated Companies, Railroads,
               Canals, Steamboats, Docks, Post Offices, &amp;c.; Principles of Commerce, Finance and Banking, with Practical and Historical Details
               and Illustrations; Commercial Law,and Mercantile Law Reports, and
               Decisions of Courts in the United States and Europe, including Insuranee, Partnership, Principal and Agent, Bills of Exchange, Sale,
               Guaranty, Bankruptcy, Shipping and Navigation, &amp;c., and whatever
               else shall tend to develope the resources of the country and the
               world, and illustrate the various topics bearing upon Commerce and
               Commercial Literature.
            </p>
            
            <p>It has been, and will continue to be, the aim of the Editor and Proprietor of the Merchants Magazine, to avoid every thing of a party, political, or sectional bus or bearing, in the conduct of the work
               opening its pages to the free and fair discussion of antagonistic doctrines connected with the great interests of Commerce, Agriculture,
               Manufactures and the Currency.
            </p>
            
            <p>Complete sets of the Merchants' Magazine, embracing eleven
               semi-annual volumes, of about 600 large octavo pages each, bringing
               it down to December, 1S44, inclusive, may be obtained at the Publisher s Office, 142 Fulton-street, New-York, at the subscription
               price.
            </p>
            
            <p>Publishers of newspapers, in the United States, by giving this
               advertisement two or three insertions, and remitting Two Dollars to
               the Proprietor, will be entitled to the Magazine for one year.
            </p>
            
            <p>Office of Merchants  Magzine, January 1st, 1845.</p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY</div>
            
            <p>AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
               Corner of Murray street, (Over Tennys Jewelry Store,) awarded
               the Medal, four first Premiums, and two  Highest Honors,  at the
               Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
               the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
            </p>
            
            <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
               at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
               the score of economy.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B. Imported German Cameras, also French and American Instruments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polishing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received
               promptly attended to.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lhsigourney">Sigourney</span> s Pictorial Reader.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE PICTORIAL READER, for the Use of Schools, consisting of Original Articles for the Instruction of Young Children.
               By Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lhsigourney">L. H. Sigourney</span>. Being an Introduction to the Boy s Reading Book and Girl s Reading Book, by the same author. Illustrated
               by nearly One Hundred aed Fifty Engravings. A very interesting and
               instructive Book for Children, whether in school or ont. Published by
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John Street, And for sale by all the Booksellers.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">The First Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for
               the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
               NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            </div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons ot one hour each. Terms Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationary. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours 9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen,
               and from 11 to 1 o clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale Goldsmith s Gems of Penmanship,  elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27. 1844.</p>
            
            <p>
               <span class="person">Goldsmith</span> s Gems of Pennmanship. The Chirographic art is
               much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
               Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
               volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
               of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
            </p>
            
            <p>From the New York Express.</p>
            
            <p>Goldsmith s Gems of Penmanship. We have seen the original, as
               executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
               wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
               to be  more potent thun the sword,  we never witnessed before.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person">CHARLES PERABEAU</span>, Professor of Music,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 9 Whitehall Street, New York.</div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="p26">
         
         <div class="head">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal. To be Published every Saturday.</div>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
            to make it worthy ot patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers ill the country; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may "let loose their
            thoughts,  will be the means of drawing out some ot the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may
            dictate.
            It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octavo form of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.</p>
         
         <p>A liberal discount lo Periodical Agents.</p>
         
         <p>All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor
            of the Broadway Journal, and all letters on business to
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.</div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="ab">
            <span class="person">John Douglas</span>, Printer, 68 Ann Street.
         </div>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>