<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">VOL. 1.NEW YORK, SATURDAY, MARCH 1, 1845. No. 9.</div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="cit">
            
            <span class="quote">Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something
               worse.
            </span>
            
            
            <div class="bibl">
               
               
               <span class="person">Locke.</span>
               
               
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">The Sanitary Condition of the Laboring Population of New
               York.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab"> With suggestions for its improvement. A discourse (with
               
               <br></br>additions) delivered on the 30th December, 1844, at the Repository
               
               <br></br>of the American Institute. By John H. Griscom, M. D., Fellow
               
               <br></br>of the College of Physicians and Surgeons; Physician of the New
               
               <br></br>York Hospital; late Physician of the city and eastern dispensaries.
               
               <br></br>New York; Harper &amp; Brothers, 82 Cliff street. 1845.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">(Second Notice.) </div>
            
            <p>Although Dr. Griscom’s labors are mainly in behalf of
               the poor, yet he very clearly proves to the rich that their
               own welfare is closely connected with that of the lower
               orders.
            </p>
            
            <p>"At all seasons of the year, there is an amount of sickness and death,
               in this, as in all large cities, far beyond those of less densely peopled,
               more airy and open places, such as country residences. Even in villages of small size, there is an observable difference over the isolated
               country dwelling, in the proportionate amount of disease prevailing ;
               proving conclusively that the congregation of animal and vegetable
               matters, with their constant effluvia, which has less chance of escape
               from the premises, in proportion to the absence of free circulation of
               air, is detrimental to the health of the inhabitants.
            </p>
            
            <p>" These circumstances have never yet been investigated in this city,
               ns they should be. Our people, especially the more destitute, have
               been allowed to live out their brief lives in tainted and unwholesome
               atmospheres, and be subject to the silent and invisible encroachments
               of destructive agencies from every direction, without one warning voice
               being raised to point to them their danger, and without an effort to
               rescue them from their impending fate. Fathers are taken from their
               children, husbands from their wives, "ere they have lived out half
               their days,"—the widows and orphans are thrown upon public or private charity for support, and the money which is expended to save
               them from starvation, to educate them in the public schools, or, perchance, to maintain them in the work house or the prison, if judiciously spent in improving the sanitary arrangements of the city, and
               instilling into the population a knowledge of the means by which their
               health might be protected, and their lives prolonged and made happy,
               would have been not only saved, but returned to the treasury in the
               increased health of the population, a much better state of public morals, and, by consequence, a more easily governed and respectable community."
            </p>
            
            <p>The amount of suffering in our city, as detailed in this
               pamphlet, from causes within the power of our municipal
               government to remove, is much greater than we had supposed could exist. One great cause of disease, as shown by
               Dr. Griscom, is the practice of sub-tenantage, which prevails to a very great extent among the very poor, and which
               is, perhaps, wholly beyond the power of the Corporation to
               remedy; but the greatest evils grow out of filthy streets,
               and these the Corporation have entirely under their own
               control; but the people have suffered so long from this
               grievance, that they now seem hardly conscious of its existence, and sit down contentedly in their Glenburneyism,
               without making an effort for its removal. Yet we believe
               that any party which will give us clean streets for six
               months, will be kept in power forever by the people, out of
               gratitude for their good works. As Dr. Griscom truly observed, New York is more favorably situated than any other
               city in the world for the preservation of health; yet with
               all the advantages that nature has so bountifully bestowed
               upon us for the increase of happiness, we continue by the
               most violent departures from obvious rules of health to cultivate as great an amount of disease and suffering as any
               other city on the Continent.
            </p>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            
            <p>Dr. Griscom devotes a good part of his pamphlet to the
               subject of ventilation, on which our people need enlightening to a fearful extent. The wealthy classes are generally
               as deficient of knowledge on this important subject as the
               laboring poor, and not unfrequently suffer acutely for lack of
               fresh air, of which they ignorantly deprive themselves. In
               remarking on the necessity of making physiology as applied
               to the laws of life, and the preventive of diseases, a study in
               all our private, public and common schools, the author says;
            </p>
            
            <p>"It is needless to say to an ignorant adult apparently free from
               sickness, that he lives, works and sleeps, in too confined an atmosphere—he will answer that he is well enough, and a change would be
               irksome, and cost money, and he will not believe what you say, for
               he cannot be easily made to understand the importance, or even the
               right use, of air. But bring up his child in a knowledge of the value
               and necessity of pure fresh air, by teaching him the relations which it
               bears to the blood, the digestion and other functions—teach him never to fear it, that it is his immediate and incessant source of life and
               health, give him a knowledge of the diseases and dangers to which its
               absence will subject him, and think you he would not avoid its impurities, as he would poison or the pestilence? In his school-room, his
               sitting-room, his chamber or his work-shop, he would seek for a pure
               clear atmosphere, as when thirsty he would seek the cool water, as
               the weary "hart panteth after the water brook." "Ventilate, Ventilate," would be his natural demand, in tones of earnestness proportioned to the necessity which his expansive lungs, and ever freshened
               feelings, would readily discover. The humble tenement of the laborer,
               would then, though but a single room, be no longer shut night and
               day, unvisited by the refreshing air of heaven; the work-shop would
               then be no longer a receptacle of foul effluvia of human and outer origin, and our churches, public rooms, and lecture halls, be no longer
               unventilated. (En passant, what a strange inconsistency is it, in the
               refined and polished, to object to sip a mouthful of water from the
               same glass as another, in which there can be no possible contamination, and yet swallow over and over again, the breath of others shut
               up in the same apartment, and which has passed through hundreds
               of lungs, perhaps diseased, and over teeth in every stage of decay.")
            </p>
            
            <p>The appropriation of the Common Council the present year
               for the Alms House, amounts to $197,000. Probably one
               quarter of that sum expended in keeping the residences of
               the poor in a healthy condition, would save another quarter
               at least, as may be seen from the extracts which follow.
            </p>
            
            <p>" As upon the condition of health of an individual are based his
               physical and mental strength, his ability for self-maintenance, his
               personal happiness, and that of others dependent on him, and also his
               usefulness to his family, to the community and his country; and as
               the community depends for its prosperity upon the performances of
               its members, individually and collectively, in the measure of influence
               committed to them respectively, so does the health of the people affect the capacity and interests of the state.
            </p>
            
            <p>" As upon the individual, when sick, falls an increased pecuniary
               burden, with (in general) a suspension of income, so upon the state
               or city, must rest, not only the expenses of removing an unsound
               condition of public health, but also, from the attendant loss of character, a diminution of its resources.
            </p>
            
            <p>" When individuals of the pauper class are ill, their entire support,
               and perchance, that of the whole family, falls upon the community.
               From a low state of general health, whether in an individual or in
               numbers, proceed diminished energy of body and of mind, and a
               vitiated moral perception, the frequent precursor of habits and deeds,
               which give employment to the officers of police, and the ministers of
               justice."
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">Prescott’s Ferdinand and Isabella.</div>
            
            <p>The Harpers have lately issued the tenth edition of Mr.
               Prescott’s invaluable " History of the Reign of Ferdinand and
               Isabella, the Catholic." It is not our intention of course, at
               this late day, to say anything critically of a work whose
               preeminent merit is as definitely settled, and as generally
               admitted as that of any history in existence. It would be
               difficult indeed, to urge anything, with a show of reason,
               against the book, considered with reference to Mr. Prescott’s
               intention in undertaking it—and it seems a matter of nearly
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page130"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>equal difficulty to add, in the way of approbation, a syllable
               to what has already been said. We are guilty of a sheer trueism in maintaining that "Ferdinand and Isabella" is a
               thorough, elaborate, well arranged, well-toned, and original
               record of an epoch replete with events of importance to mankind and of especial importance to Americans. If there lies
               upon this record a shadow of blame it is on the score of a
               very pardonable partiality for the principal personages introduced.
            </p>
            
            <p>Our purpose in penning this notice, now, is simply to call
               attention to the issue of a new edition, and to say a word or
               two of the book as a book merely, and as a very desirable
               acquisition to any library which shall happen to be without it.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is the sole work giving a particular account of the epoch
               it discusses—the reign of Ferdinand and Isabella—although
               there are particular narratives, in an unbroken series, from
               Charles the First to Charles the Third. Yet it was in the
               reign of Ferdinand and Isabella that the several provinces
               into which Spain had been so long parcelled off, were reduced into one dominion—that the kingdom of Naples was
               conquered—that the Spanish Arabian empire was overthrown
               —that the Jews were banished—that the Inquisition was established—and, finally, that America was re-discovered by
               Columbus. This reign, too, (which should have been the
               historical basis of all the others) was rendered notable not
               only through Columbus, but through the illustrious statesman Ximenes, the " Great Captain" Gonsalvo de Cordova,
               and several other remarkable individuals, to say nothing of
               Isabella herself, in the illustration of whose character alone
               a bulky volume might be profitably written.
            </p>
            
            <p>The only continental histories of the period are "L'Histoire des Rois Catholiques Ferdinand et Isabelle par L'Abbe
               Mignot"—and the "Geschichte der Regierung Ferdinand
               des Katholischen, von Rupert Becker." These works, however, are very brief and compendious ; neither of them equalling in bulk one of our ordinary novel volumes. Their authors refer only to the most accessible materials, and make
               no claim to research.
            </p>
            
            <p>The truth is, that previous to the period at which Mr. Prescott commenced his task (which was, we believe, in 1826 or
               1827), there were comparatively no facilities for its accomplishment. The researches of Spanish literati have lately
               thrown much light, at random, on various points of the
               theme. Llorente, for example, the noted Secretary of the
               Inquisition, has issued his pregnant history of that memorable institution ; Conde has given a literal version of the Spanish Arab chronicles; Sempere, Marina, and Capmany have
               written diffusely on the political aspect of Spain ; Navarrette
               has made an extensive collection of original documents concerning Columbus; and Clemencin has completed the sixth
               volume of the Memoirs of the Royal Academy of Spanish
               History. To these sources Mr. Prescott is. of course, very
               very greatly indebted, and he is the first to avail himself of
               the vast advantages they afford. Mr. Irving’s "History of
               Columbus" and "Chronicle of Granada" were very partial
               and very unexpected, although unquestionably very beautiful anticipations of small portions of Mr. Prescott’s great design.
            </p>
            
            <p>The edition now issued by the Messrs. Harpers, is carefully prepared from the third English edition, which embraces many important matters not embodied in the original
               work. While the second edition was passing through the
               press, Mr. Prescott ireceived copies of two valuable Spanish works having reference to his theme, but which from the
               recency of their issue, had not previously come to his know
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               ledge. He was also enabled to avail himself of the "Mahommedan Dynasties of Spain," a book of great merit just
               then published by Don Pascual de Gayangos, and which
               throws much light upon the Arabian portion of the Peninsular Annals.
            </p>
            
            <p>The mechanical execution of the "Ferdinand and Isabella"
               is every thing that can be desired. It is issued in three royal octavo volumes of about 400 pages each, printed on fine
               thick paper, with bold type, and illustrated with portraits of
               Isabella, Ferdinand, Columbus, Ximenes, and Gonsalvo of
               Cordova. It furnishes also numerous autographs of these
               and other celebrated personages of the time discussed. The
               binding is very neat and durable.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">Woman in the Nineteenth Century.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">By S. Margaret Fuller. New York, Greeley &amp; McElrath. 1845. Price 60 cents.</div>
            
            <p>It will be a happy time for the world, but especially happy for the reading part of it, when people shall be content to
               accomplish, in the shortest time possible, whatever they may
               feel themselves called to do. Time flies, should be inscribed on the door-posts of every author’s dwelling. An emblematic figure, like that in the Hall of our National Legislature, does not appear to be sufficiently striking, though it
               tells the hours as they fly. The author who writes to amuse,
               may write as long as he can amuse, even though he should
               write tales longer than the Grand Cyrus, or Sir Charles
               Grandison ; but the author who writes to instruct, cannot
               write too briefly, for we have much to learn, and but little
               time to learn in ; one third must be given to sleep, another
               third, at least, to labor, and the rest to study, to amusements,
               to writing, and talking, and sight-seeing. The time that the
               best of us can devote to reading, is but short, and therefore,
               we cannot afford to read books which lack method, or which
               contain more words than are necessary to convey the author’s
               meaning, provided he have any. That Miss Fuller is justly
               chargeable with wasting the time of her readers, her most devout admirer cannot deny. Her book consists of two hundred pages, but all that it contains of her own suggesting,
               might be fairly compressed into a third of the space. The
               title is a misnomer to begin with; the one under which
               the essay was once published, " The great Law-suit, Man
               vs. Men: Woman vs. Women," was much better, because,
               having no particular meaning, it created no improper expectations. Miss Fuller informs us that she changed it because
               it was not understood ; she will have to change the present
               one, for an opposite reason. We keep looking for woman of
               the nineteenth century, but we only find a roster of female
               names from Panthea to Amelia Norman. The propriety of the
               title is the more doubtful from the following passage in her
               preface.
            </p>
            
            <p>"By man, I mean both man and woman. I lay no especial stress on
               the welfare of either. I believe the welfare of the one cannot be effected without that of the other. My highest wish is that this truth
               should be distinctly and rationally apprehended ; and the conditions
               of life and freedom recognised as the same for the daughters and the
               sons of time."
            </p>
            
            <p>The style is somewhat stilted, but the thought is just and
               philosophical, and proves Miss Fuller to be a thinking,
               right-judging person. Why could she not, then, since she
               thinks so correctly, call her book, Man, or Society in the
               Nineteenth century, and so plead in a straight forward manner in behalf of man, without any specialities about woman’s
               rights or woman’s wrongs, as though she had either rights
               or wrongs, which are not also the rights and wrongs of men.
               We certainly did not expect from a woman of Miss Fuller’s
               natural and acquired powers, the wretched cant which we
               hear so often from men, who, having no claim upon man,
               seek for the sympathies of women, and from women, who,
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page131"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               having as little claim upon the sympathies of men, try for it
               by speaking in the name of their sex, about woman’s mission,
               woman’s influence, and woman’s rights; and we have not
               been disappointed ; she seems to entertain a wholesome horror of the whole tribe of shallow canters. But then, if we do
               not misapprehend her, which we are not sure of, she has
               errors of her own which are more dangerous, because not so
               shallow as the others. She forgets, or rather seems to forget,
               that God created man male and female, notwithstanding the
               declaration in her preface, which we suspect, contains, like
               the postscript of a woman’s letter, the fact which she intended to put into the body Of her work. She is dissatisfied that
               women are not men, and takes offence at the term "women
               and children"; words which to us sound sweeter for being
               spoken together. She is offended that women should esteem
               it a compliment to be called masculine, while men consider
               it a reproach to be called feminine. "Early I perceived,"
               she says, "that men, in no extremity of distress, ever wished
               themselves women." Of course not. It is the law that woman shall reverence her husband, and that he shall be her
               head. We may love those whom we protect, but we can
               never wish ourselves in their place, although we naturally
               wish to be like those from whom we receive protection. The
               wish of Desdemona that Heaven had made her like Othello,
               is the sweetest touch of nature in Shakspeare. Some have
               doubted what she meant, but they have only to read her wish
               by the light of revelation, and her meaning is clear. Miss
               Fuller says:
            </p>
            
            <p>"I have urged on woman, independence of man, not that I do not
               think the sexes mutually needed by one another, but because in woman,
               this fact has led to an excessive devotion, which has cooled love, degraded marriage, and prevented either sex from being what it should be
               to itself or the other. * * * That her hand may be given with
               dignity, she must be able to stand alone."
            </p>
            
            <p>This, we conceive to be the radical error of Miss Fuller’s
               reasoning, and directly opposed to the law of nature, of experience and revelation. She says,
            </p>
            
            <p>"A profound thinker has said, that no married woman can represent
               the female world, for she belongs to her husband. The idea of woman
               must be represented by a virgin."
            </p>
            
            <p>He was a very shallow thinker, or a joker. It would be as
               reasonable to say that none but a deaf man could give a true
               idea of music. Woman is nothing but as a wife. How, then,
               can she truly represent the female character who has never
               filled it? No woman can be a true woman, who has not
               been a wife and a mother. These are not accidental characters like those of mistress and servant, which may be thoroughly understood without being acted ; but they are the
               natural destiny of woman, and if she is kept from them, her
               nature is distorted and unnatural; and she sees things
               through a false medium. Her report, therefore, of a character which she never filled, must be received with distrust.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is not easy to discover from Miss Fuller’s essay what her
               precise ideas of the true relation of man and woman are;
               although on some points she is sufficiently distinct. Mrs.
               Jamieson, with true womanly feeling, said that she would prefer being Mary of Scotland to Elizabeth of England; but
               Miss Fuller would prefer being the termagant Queen and
               swearing by "God’s teeth." Colonel Emily Plater and
               Madame George Sand souod pleasantly in her ears. "If you
               ask me what offices women may fill," says Miss Fuller, "I
               reply any; let them be sea captains if you will." Very good,
               let them. We have a queen of England, and England claims
               to be mistress of the seas; let us have a woman Admiral.
               But we take sides with Spinoza, and answer that woman
               cannot command. She lacks the chief qualities of a commander. She cannot invent. She is an apt imitator, but she
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               cannot originate; and therefore we have no fears that we
               shall ever see woman in our halls of legislature, or in command of our ships or armies. "A party of travellers lately
               visited a lonely hut on a mountain. There they found an old
               woman that told them she and her husband had lived there
               forty years; why, they said, did you chose so barren a spot?
               She did not know, it was the man’s notion. And during forty
               years she had been content to act, without knowing why, upon the man’s notion. I would not have it so"; says Miss
               Fuller. In the name of all that is monstrous, what would
               she have? Would she have the woman to leave her husband, or would she have the husband abandon what he believed to be for his interest to do, to satisfy a whim of his
               wife? She is not bound to provide for him, but he is bound
               to provide for her, and therefore he must be allowed the privilege of following his own business in his own way, unless
               she can advise him better; but he must be the judge of the
               advice. The old woman was a true woman and a good wife,
               who had no thought but to please her husband. Women
               who have any other thoughts have no business with a husband. If there is anything clear in revealed and natural
               law, it is that man is the head of the woman. All the beauty, all the harmony, all the happiness of life is centred in this
               truth. The most perfect woman that the world has ever
               known, one who was tried as no other woman was ever tried,
               who was endowed by nature as few women have ever been
               endowed, the sweetest, purest being that ever bore the name
               of woman, counted herself nothing but the wife of her husband, would know no law but his will, no happiness but his
               love; and when his love grew cold, and he became dead to
               her, though living, she still remained true to him. The
               world has abounded in Ephesian widows, but there has been
               only one Eloisa. Yet Eloisa is the true type of perfect woman. But Eloisa is not the type of Miss Fuller’s ideal wife:
               she is better pleased with such a wife as Madame Roland,
               whose equality with her husband, and congeniality of tastes
               and employments, made her his companion and friend. She
               was, in truth, no wife at all, at least, to him, and she fully
               exemplified the truth which Miss Fuller denies, that love is
               a necessity with woman.
            </p>
            
            <p>"This is one of the best instances (the marriage of Madame Roland) of a marriage of friendship. It was only friendship, whose basis was esteem; probably neither party knew
               love, except by name;" says Miss Fuller. But Thiers says ;
               "Elle respectait et chérissait son époux comme un père: elle
               éprouvait pour l’un des Girondins proscrits une passion profonde, qu’ elle avait toujours contenue."
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE ART OF THE USE OF COLOR IN IMITATION IN PAINTING.
            NO. III.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY 
            <span class="person">WILLIAM PAGE</span>.
         </div>
         
         <p>We all know that our picture, when it is done, should answer to a catechism like this, "If you tickle us, shall we not
            laugh? if you prick us, shall we not bleed? and if you
            wrong us, shall we not revenge?
         </p>
         
         <p>Now let us suppose that we have a white canvas on which
            we are to paint a head. White is not only the best receiver of color, but indeed the only equal receiver of all colors, as well as that on which we can get the greatest
            transparency and permanence, and is least likely to swallow
            up eventually the colors put upon it, as is the case in dark
            grounds.
         </p>
         
         <p>On this white ground then we draw very carefully the outline, in red ink, so that
            it
            cannot be washed off by the
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page132"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            paint when passed over it, and so that it will Dot need correction or removal, because whenever this has to be done, it
            must make a patch, which no skill can wholly hide; and
            then let us begin with the simplest colors we can get of
            known permanence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Take on the pallette Venetian Red, Vermillion and Prussian Blue—and only these, the first being really not a perfect
            red, but rather an orange color, that is, one in which yellow
            is mingled with the red. So indeed are almost all known
            pigments more or less mixed, and we have not the colors
            wherewith to represent perfectly the red, yellow, and blue,
            of nature, any more than those to represent light and darkness.
         </p>
         
         <p>Let us then take in a brush, some Venetian red, together
            with drying-oil, the only vehicle fit for oil painting, and
            brush over the place of the flesh with this red, so that we
            half obscure the white ground, covering every part of it, until it is perhaps half as dark as this color would make it if
            laid on to a solid body, which must not however be done
            anywhere, because this would make it opaque at the last, and
            the light ground should appear somewhat through, even to
            the end. After heightening the reds in the lips, cheeks. &amp;c.,
            where the carnations are to be more purplish, when completed, with Vermillion; proceed to make out the shadows
            with the Venetian red, stronger as they deepen, until the
            forms are faintly indicated, and a tolerable idea of the rotundity of the head is given.
         </p>
         
         <p>But if the complexion of the subject is very clear, with
            uncommonly brilliant color; before laying on the Venetian
            red, paint in those bright parts with Vermillion on the white
            ground, and paint around them with the other reds. Then,
            whilst it is still wet, take a soft brush with Prussian blue,
            rather thin, and well diffused through the brush, sweep
            gently over those parts that either retire from the light, or
            the eye, neutralising with this, the red color more or less, as
            it is more or less indefinite in the head before you, until you
            have made out a complete general resemblance to the original. Be careful not to destroy the unity by entirely obliterating the red or the white ground anywhere, except, perhaps, in the deepest points of dark, as in the pupils of the
            eyes, for they are to be passed over with the rest, the nostrils, and the darkest parts of the mouth. The hair may be
            treated in like manner, unless it be very peculiar in color, as
            a good preparation for after painting.
         </p>
         
         <p>When this painting is perfectly dry, if it should be found
            weak in effect, the same process may be repeated, until the
            full force of Chinese Vermillion be given in the cheeks, &amp;c.,
            that is, as much power of color as this pigment can be
            made to exhibit, for it will be brightest before it is perfectly solid, or before it entirely obliterates the white ground.
         </p>
         
         <p>This stage, which in its progress will resemble as much
            as may be the mode used by miniature painters, on paper
            or ivory, must continue until all the force of color the pigments are capable of is produced, and the effect of the whole
            is as harmonious as possible.
         </p>
         
         <p>By this time it will be brought to that tone which I have
            attempted to describe, and in which alone it can attain its
            full force. As the color is yet only on the surface, it may
            perhaps be leathery, not however a discouraging circumstance, unless the complexion to be imitated is remarkably
            clear, in case of which the blue must continue to be used
            over in the first painting, until something of a pearly or cool
            effect is produced, by the red being almost neutralised. If
            there be any while near the flesh, it should be treated in
            this way ; Venetian red passed over the white ground, until
            reduced to as low a tone as need be, and then, whilst it
            is wet, blue used over it, until all the red disappears.
         </p>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>For what Sir Isaac Newton calls while, and produced by
            rapidly turning the seven prismatic colors on a wheel so as
            to mix them all together—was not white, which is positive,
            but the negation of color. This may also be done by so
            mixing the three primitive colors together, that neither is
            seen to predominate, and this, in its proper relation, will
            appear white; though in reality it will come into that medium degree of light which I have before named, and am
            obliged so often to refer to. So that what is called Venetian
            red being, as before stated, orange, and having added to it
            blue until the red and yellow of the orange disappear, or are
            neutralized, becomes, in this stage of the picture, the representative of white.
         </p>
         
         <p>It will then be seen that such a white you may heighten
            at pleasure, or represent shining objects upon, as could not
            be done, if you had already exhausted your power by the
            use of positive white. The picture in this state will of
            course have the look of glazing; this will be the look
            of wetness also, which all glazing has. Though this will
            not be so entirely wet as if the colors used had been what
            are known as transparent, and all known pigments except
            metals, have some degree of this transparent quality ; that
            is, they will all, with one exception, show through them
            something of the color on which they are laid, if they be not
            too thickly impasted thereon, (I speak of colors in oil.) And
            these more opaque pigments, Venetian red and Vermillion,
            are recommended, because the more transparent want that
            look of body, necessary to give the full force and solidity of
            flesh.
         </p>
         
         <p>Should the picture be capable of receiving additional
            strength from glazing reds or yellows, this is the state in
            which to use them to their fullest extent; though if it is
            as low as it should be in tone, it will appear to the uninitiated lower than nature, and cause one who lacks experience in this mode, to fear that he has his flesh below
            that of Titian’s; but if it be really carried to a complete unity in this stage, as it should be, the after process will, if well
            applied, cause your eyes to sparkle with the result which
            nature only need surpass.
         </p>
         
         <p>Let us suppose, then, that all the parts are complete, in
            their proper relations, no blackness in the shadows, and yet
            all the lights so far removed from white, that as seen by twilight, the whole picture seems to sink to a fiat tone, and
            when it is sufficiently dark to hide the colors, shows as a
            blank canvas, of a low middle-tint, yet in the light of day,
            has all the power of the pallette in color.
         </p>
         
         <p>When this former painting is completely dry, take Naples yellow, which is the most opaque of all the colors in
            common use, and carries more light than anything but
            white itself, and mix with it a small portion of Ultramarine,
            enough to make the Naples yellow, which is, when best, a
            delicate orange color, perfectly neutral, so that it shows as
            much blue as either red or yellow. This is to be, in the
            next stage, your representative of light, which it is well calculated to do from its opacity, because light itself is opaque,
            particularly when seen concentrated or focussed on any glossy substance, glass for instance, where through the highest
            light no color can be seen, however brilliant.
         </p>
         
         <p>Now the picture being perfectly dry, and this light tint
            mixed for the purpose, let it be carefully spread over the
            flesh, light, dark, middle-tint and all; carefully I say, of
            course with the original before yon, using more or less, as
            the skin more or less obscures the blood beneath, but everywhere some, though the less of this light that is required to
            produce the desired effect the better, as it weakens the
            colors beneath, which need to be kept as pure as possible,
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page133"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            oftentimes mere skin-deep, but as the skin is everywhere
            over the flesh, the surface everywhere lighter than beneath
            that surface, even in the deepest shadows, this will so represent it, that through all the shadows, the skin will appear to
            pass, showing everywhere the blood beneath, and ten thousand silvery tones will be produced, surpassing the most
            skilful mixing of colors that can be attained without passing
            light over dark.
         </p>
         
         <p>Though everywhere this light must be passed over, yet no
            where must it be so thickened as wholly to obscure the
            color beneath, or the flesh where it occurs will be opaque—
            and only in the extremest locus of the lights is this the case
            in nature, the light every where else falling into the flesh,
            and the vision following it, and so will light and vision fall
            into the picture.
         </p>
         
         <p>Now, though the picture before this last process was apparently very low in tone, this has made it seem to be filled
            with light, and indeed it is so, for you see through it all, as
            well as into it, and the light penetrates to the ground and is
            reflected back again, bringing color with it. This use of the
            white ground is the only compensation we have to make
            amends in painting, for the great depth to which the light
            passes into real flesh, owing to the greater transparency
            of its substance, and that of the blood; but in the picture
            we get the surface comparatively opaque, colorless, and
            light, to represent the skin, and the red beneath comparatively transparent, and dark, for the blood.
         </p>
         
         <p>The flesh will now appear as light as need be, but you
            will remember that if you had used all the light of the mixture, which would be far too much, it would still be a very
            great way removed from white.
         </p>
         
         <p>Let us now take the same color which we used over the
            flesh for light, and with it make out, as economically as
            possible, the white spoken of above, taking care not to
            make it very light any where, that is, allowing the darker
            preparation to show through, unless the stuff to be imitated
            be many thicknesses of linen, for linen too shows the darkness through it, and must in a picture, or Titian himself
            could not make it more than tolerable, and certainly not low
            in tone.
         </p>
         
         <p>When this is again dry, take pure white and breathe it
            here and there on the high lights very thinly, bringing it to a
            small focus on the eyes, and where it shines the brightest,
            but always with the same strict economy that I have inculcated, never using more light than the least that will serve,
            and if you have done well what is here advised, your picture will possess what few modern pictures can boast, and
            yet what are the universal qualities of flesh in nature; the
            full force ol color, together with unity, and a skin over its
            surface, with ten thousand minuter beauties, nameless from
            their multitude, which yet the dullest eye can see when compared with the productions of the usual modes adopted in
            the painting of pictures. For all true general laws act perfectly in the smallest particulars; witness the laws of the
            Creator.
         </p>
         
         <p>Wrong modes of color have often been so ingeniously
            used, and with so much feeling and perception of beauty,
            as to make a feeble means founded on false principles appear to those who wanted experience and thought in the
            Matter, the true way. But in this that I have attempted
            thus far to present, though even so slightly sketched, may
            be found the broad principles of imitation and rational
            thought, and the only way I am well assured that can make
            Art worthy to be the study of such men as could adorn any
            liberal pursuit, and might revive a hope, in these days, of
            producing anything worthy admiration, or fit to be handed
            down to coming time.
         </p>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>I neglected above to mention particularly the reason, as I
            promised to do, why the rich browns are found in the old
            masters in place of the greys of the moderns—though any
            one who understands well what I have written, can scarcely
            have failed to see ere this the cause. It is, that the " Old
            Colorists’" painting, as I said before, on the low key, with the
            full power of the primitives, could not fail, when these were
            united in full tone, to produce browns of great depth and
            richness; but now, painters introducing more light into their
            color, and of course weakening it thereby, when they mix
            them together produce greys instead of browns.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">GAMBLING.</div>
         
         <p>Of the evils of gambling it is needless to say a word.
            All the world are agreed that it is one of the most disastrous
            of vices—surpassed, perhaps, in the deplorable character of
            its results, by drunkenness alone. The crusade waged against
            the latter, found its most effective weapon, not in dissertation on the iniquity, but in exposition of the physical ill.
            Men who listened to sermons on intemperance as to matters
            that might or might not be worth thinking about at some
            future indefinite day, were startled at once into good resolves
            by a simple inspection of the coats of a drunkard’s stomach.
            The books and lectures of Mr. J. H. Green, the reformed
            gambler, are, upon the same principle, the most effective
            remedies for the vice he is endeavoring to overthrow. It is
            all very well to say in our pulpits " do not gamble, for it is a
            heinous sin but it is far better to demonstrate to the public satisfaction, that the man who gambles, without being
            himself a sharper, is at the absolute mercy of those who are.
            Let it be once clearly shown that there is really no chance in
            the matter, and that all is an absolute certainty in favor of
            the swindler by profession, and we put an end to gambling
            in general, by removing the inducement to gamble.
         </p>
         
         <p>Now Mr. Green proves all this in a manner which must
            satisfy the most incredulous. In his books, he gives a full
            exposition of the various rogueries practised by the gambling
            fraternity ; and the man who reads these books and gambles
            in any shape again, is little better than an idiot. But more
            than this;—Mr. Green will have no objection to convince
            any one who may feel interested—to convince him by ocular
            demonstration of the absolute mastery held by the gambler
            over his victim. He will show that he (Mr. Green) can tell
            any card by the ordinary marks on its back—that it is in his
            power in dealing, to give himself a hand to suit his own pur.
            poses—in short that, in all games at cards, what his opponent shall win or lose is entirely at the option of himself
            (Mr. Green). He will show, also, the deceptive mechanism
            of the faro-boxes, and roulette-tables, and explain in the
            clearest and most irrefutable manner, that the usual system
            of lottery-drawing is only a more comprehensive method of
            picking the public pocket.
         </p>
         
         <p>Now we maintain that the press has the victory over this
            vice within its own hands. If Mr. Green fail, the press only
            is responsible. He has done his part with a courage—with
            an unflinching resolution, to be estimated by those alone who
            have opportunities of knowing the desperate animosity of the
            class whose profession is thus to be overthrown. If the
            press now come to his aid—if it give publicity to his efforts
            —gambling will be more thoroughly suppressed than ever
            has been intemperance through the exertions of its opponents.
            It may be said Mr. Green’s object is merely to make money.
            And what then ? we have nothing to do with his private
            object; nor will the public object be one iota the less attained because, in attaining it, the public puts money in the
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page134"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            pocket of Mr. Green. He has been at much trouble, and
            encountered great danger, in effecting a purpose which cannot fail of being highly advantageous to mankind. He has
            labored and is worthy of his hire; this altogether independently of his immediate motives, which nevertheless we believe to be commendable. He seems actuated by a sincere
            desire to render the public a service, and by a very profound,
            and certainly a very natural disgust to the fraternity he has
            abandoned.
         </p>
         
         <p>We call therefore upon our brethren of the press to aid Mr. Green in his efforts.
            
         </p>
         
         <p>His books are "Gambling Unmasked," "The Arts and
            Miseries of Gambling," and "The Gambler’s Mirror"—the
            latter a serial work of which only the first number is as yet
            issued. They are to be obtained of all booksellers.
         </p>
         
         <p>Independently of their value as affording not only very
            full, but the sole existing expositions of all the arts of the
            blackleg, these publications have the merit of presenting numerous vivid pictures of the wretchedness wrought by the
            vice in question. These pictures are clearly from nature—
            from life. They bear with them distinct internal evidence
            of their truth. The volumes have often, too, a less painful
            interest, and are sometimes exceedingly amusing. We quote
            from the "Arts and Miseries" a specimen of highly ingenious trickery:
         </p>
         
         <p>"To show still further the industry of this class of persons in inventing means to deceive and win money, I will relate a trick played
            upon a merchant in Shrevesport. A gambler, who was there, bad a
            very fine dog, which he shut up two days without feeding him. The
            gambler told his secret partner to go and get into conversation with
            the merchant, and he would soon come by with his dog, which the
            partner would call into the store, and tell the merchant to weigh him;
            and he (the owner) would pass on and make no stop. The partner
            was also to suggest to the merchant the great probability of winning
            some champagne on the weight of the dog, as he, after weighing him,
            would know his weight better than the owner. The plan pleased the
            merchant, as he knew the owner to be a man always ready to bet.
            He weighed the dog, and turned him loose. The dog went home to
            his owner, who gave him some two or three pounds of meat to eat,
            and then walked back by the store with his dog, and made a stop to
            converse a while with some of his acquaintances. The merchant proposed to make a trifling bet that he could tell the dog’s weight as near
            as the owner ; and finally a very large bet was made. The merchant
            guessed first, and the owner guessed about two pounds more, and
            won ; for the meat he had just given his dog made about that difference. The merchant could not, for a long time, account for his being
            deceived, as but a few minutes had elapsed since he had first weighed the dog. But he had, unwisely, suffered himself to be drawn into
            a bet with a man who had made betting his whole business, and who
            never calculated to be beaten.
         </p>
         
         <p>But there is a gambling principle which lies deeper than the
            plummet of Mr. Green’s experience has sounded, and which
            requires exposure by some stronger hand. There are other
            gamblers than those who shuffle cards and rattle dice. Nine
            tenths of our leading politicians are gamblers, who make a
            business of calculating the chances of success in nominating
            men for office, and then bet and speculate accordingly,—not
            always for the lore of money, the love of power, or of office,
            but from the love of excitement: never, however, from the
            love of good principles. A very great part of our politicians
            gamble in more ways than in politics. Wall street operators are nearly all gamblers. The subject is too notorious
            to require more than a hint; but if any one would like to
            see the gambling principle in full play, he may find as perfect a development of it among the outside brokers of Wall
            street, who cluster about the doors of the Exchange just after the adjournment of the "Board," as can be witnessed at
            any of the Hells in London or Paris. Merchants are generally strongly imbued with gambling propensities; there are
            but few mercantile adventures which are not undertaken in
            a gambling spirit. One of the chief causes which influenced
            the Legislature in abolishing lotteries, was the frequent development of frauds committed by fiduciary agents to cover
            their losses in lottery gambling. But such frauds were not
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            diminished in the slightest degree by the abolition of lotteries. Gambling was never carried to such an extent as in
            1836, when the whole nation, from the priest in the pulpit
            to the President in Washington, gambled in land. There
            are many innocent people in New York, who read with great
            horror accounts of gambling in Paris, New Orleans and London, and are quite familiar with Crockford’s and other houses in St. James’s, who never dream that they daily walk
            in the shadow of Hells quite as brilliant and quite as black
            as any in those cities. Young gentlemen are enticed to such
            places at first by a gratuitous supper, when all the elegances
            of the table are spread in lavish profusion, and afterwards
            they are drawn into the alluring maelstrom by a hope of
            gain, a love of excitement, or some other similar motive.
         </p>
         
         <p>Excitement of some kind all men, excepting only a few
            human sloths, require, and they will seek it as they will
            food—without any thought of consequences. The chief aim
            of the reform must be, to give this love of excitement a proper direction. Mr. Green is himself, doubtless, as favorable
            an illustration of our principle as could be afforded. If his
            motive could be strictly analysed, we have not a doubt that
            it would be found that his former gambling and his present
            exposures of the acts of the gambler, result from one cause.
            It is for this reason that the greatest sinners always make
            the greatest saints—as St. Paul and others.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE NEW YORK GALLERY OF FINE ARTS.</div>
         
         <p>Good and bad pictures should never be exhibited together,
            for a poor work of art which might attract attention by itself, will appear disgusting when hung by the side of a
            work of real merit; for this reason, if for no other, the directors of this excellent institution have acted very unwisely
            in placing in the exhibition several pictures which do not
            deserve to be exhibited even by themselves. In the beginning of an institution which is to continue forever, and to
            influence people who will hardly know the names of its
            founders, it is of the greatest importance that right principles of action should be adopted; otherwise errors innumerable must be the consequence. We do not find in the
            Constitution of the " New York Gallery of the Fine Arts,"
            or in the remarks appended to the Catalogue of pictures,
            any hint of the principles by which the trustees will be
            guided in their selections cl works of art, to be added to
            the gallery. We regard this as a very great oversight, as
            it leaves a wide door open to admit anything and everything which the whims or incapacity of any future trustees
            may choose to purchase, or accept as a donation; and according to the Constitution no work can ever be alienated
            from the Institution after it has become its property either
            by gift or purchase.
         </p>
         
         <p>In founding this Gallery, an opportunity was offered to
            render it unique and an honor to the country, by forming it
            exclusively of the best works of American Artists alone.
            It was a matter of trifling consequence whether it numbered ten or a hundred pictures, if they were all of a
            high order of merit. A rigid impartiality in excluding second-rate performances would have gained for it in the
            outset a high character, which would have attracted more
            visitors than a thousand works of ordinary merit could ever
            do. Above all things, copies of every kind should have been
            excluded.
         </p>
         
         <p>And it should have been one of the chief aims of the Institution to have at least one picture from every American
            Artist of any pretensions. But we find eleven paintings in
            the collection by G. W. Flagg, and not one by Inman or
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page135"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            Page. Of Mr. Flagg’s eleven pictures, not more than one deserves a place in the gallery; but they are all fastened there
            for eternity, and unless a fire should snap them up some of
            these wintry nights, they will hang upon the walls until
            they drop from their frames, Falstaff and Lady Jane Grey
            and all. There are several other pictures which belong to
            the Gallery, and must, therefore, remain in its collection
            forever, which should be hung in a dark corner where
            they could never be seen: for instance, a Magdalen after
            Corregio; an Allegory—Italian school; View from Roster
            Hill, Richardson; Landscape—Dutch school; Boy fallen
            asleep over his dinner—Philip; Interior—Dutch school; Pan
            and Midas—Goltzius ; Assumption of the Virgin—Annibale
            Caracci; and the Old Fiddler after Teniers.
         </p>
         
         <p>Cole and Ingham have each presented a valuable picture
            to the gallery, and other artists have promised to do so.
            Mr. Ingham’s gift is an original portrait of Lafayette, painted by himself, and Cole’s is a view in Sicily, one of his finest
            landscapes.
         </p>
         
         <p>Among the works loaned for exhibition are two of Mr.
            Edmonds’ most pleasing compositions, the boy stealing milk
            and the " bashful cousin;" an admirable copy from Titian,
            by Durand, and the Day Dream, by Ingham, probably the
            best female head he has ever painted. In addition to the
            paintings, there is a fine collection of rare engravings, which
            should be attentively studied by the public as an antidote to
            the magazine plates with which we are flooded every month.
         </p>
         
         <p>Taken altogether, the Gallery presents a very fine collection of paintings, which are well worth visiting; but if it
            contained only the pictures by Cole and Mount, it might
            well be regarded with pride by a New Yorker.
         </p>
         
         <p>The public, no less than a re-public, is apt to be guilty of
            the sin of ingratitude, and like a pampered child, never
            troubles itself about the source whence its enjoyments are
            derived. We trust that the multitude who will gain pleasure
            and instruction from visiting this collection of works of Art,
            will bear in mind that it is not a spontaneous production, and
            that they are indebted to somebody for its existence. We believe that the gentleman who was mainly instrumental in the
            formation of the " New York Gallery of the Fine Arts," is
            Jonathan Sturges, the former mercantile partner of Mr. Reed,
            to whose liberality we are indebted for the collection. Other
            gentlemen, of course, have lent their aid, among whom, we
            believe, Janies Brown, Shepard Knapp, F. W. Edmonds, and
            Charles M. Leupp, took an active part. Most of the grocers
            too, in Front street, out of respect to the memory of Mr. Reed,
            who held an eminent position among them, have subscribed
            liberally.
         </p>
         
         <p>We were a little premature in announcing that the Common Council had unanimously resolved to allow the use of the
            Rotunda, to the Gallery, at a merely nominal rent, in spite
            of the Mayor’s veto of their former resolution ; it was only
            the Board of Aldermen that passed the unanimous resolutions ;
            the Board of Assistants, whose assistance, in this case, has
            not been of any particular help, referred the matter to a special committee, who will, it is apprehended, report adverse
            to it.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">Original Poetry</div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE PILGRIMAGE TO KEVLAAR.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">TRANSLATED FROM THE GERMAN OF HENRY HEINE.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               I.
               
               <br></br>At the window stands the mother,
               
               <br></br>In bed her son doth lie,
               
               <br></br>" Wilt thou rise and look out, William?
               
               <br></br>The procession goeth by."
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               
               <br></br>" I am so sick, my mother,
               
               <br></br>I can see and hear no more;
               
               <br></br>I think of my dead Margaret,
               
               <br></br>That makes my heart so sore."
               
               <br></br>" Rise, we will go to Kevlaar,
               
               <br></br>Book and rosary we will bear.
               
               <br></br>And the dear mother of our Lord
               
               <br></br>Will heal thy sick heart’s care."
               
               <br></br>The chaunters they are chaunting,
               
               <br></br>Swell the church's banners fine,
               
               <br></br>And the long procession goeth
               
               <br></br>To Cologne upon the Rhine.
               
               <br></br>The crowd the mother follows,
               
               <br></br>Her sick son carries she,
               
               <br></br>While both do sing in chorus,
               
               <br></br>" Oh, Mary, praise to thee!"
               II.
               
               <br></br>The Virgin unto Kevlaar
               
               <br></br>In gayest clothes they bear;
               
               <br></br>To-day she has much work to do,
               
               <br></br>For many sick come there;
               
               <br></br>And the sick people carry,
               
               <br></br>As offering good and meet,
               
               <br></br>Full many waxen members,
               
               <br></br>And waxen heads and feet.
               
               <br></br>Whoso a waxen hand offers,
               
               <br></br>Heals on his own the wound;
               
               <br></br>Whoso a waxen foot offers,
               
               <br></br>His own is thenceforth sound.
               
               <br></br>Some who went there on crutches,
               
               <br></br>Could dance on ropes that day;
               
               <br></br>Some who had scarce a finger
               
               <br></br>On the violin could play.
               
               <br></br>The mother took a wax light,
               
               <br></br>And moulded thence a heart,—
               
               <br></br>" Bear that unto our mother,
               
               <br></br>So shall she heal thy smart."
               
               <br></br>Sighing he takes the wax heart,
               
               <br></br>Sighing to Mary goes,
               
               <br></br>Tears from his eyes are flowing,
               
               <br></br>Prayer from his full heart flows.
               
               <br></br>" Oh, thou most holy mother,
               
               <br></br>Thou Virgin good and pure,
               
               <br></br>Thou Queen of all the Heavens,
               
               <br></br>Thou can’st my sorrow cure !"
               
               <br></br>" I dwell with my dear mother
               
               <br></br>In the city of Cologne,
               
               <br></br>That may hundred chapels
               
               <br></br>And churches high doth own.
               
               <br></br>" And near to us dwelt Margaret,
               
               <br></br>Who is dead for evermore.
               
               <br></br>Mary, I bring thee a wax-heart,
               
               <br></br>Heal thou my heart so sore.
               
               <br></br>" If my sick heart thou healest,
               
               <br></br>Early and late from me
               
               <br></br>Shall ever rise the song and prayer,
               
               <br></br>Oh, Mary, praise to thee !"
               III.
               
               <br></br>The sick son and his mother
               
               <br></br>In the little chamber lie,
               
               <br></br>The Holy Virgin cometh
               
               <br></br>And softly draweth nigh.
               
               <br></br>She bends above the sick one,
               
               <br></br>And then her hand doth lay
               
               <br></br>On his poor heart so gently,
               
               <br></br>And smiling fades away.
               
               <br></br>All in dreams the mother seeth,
               
               <br></br>And more had seen in sleep,
               
               <br></br>But she wakened from her slumbers—
               
               <br></br>The dog he howled so deep.
               
               <br></br>There lay stretched out before her,
               
               <br></br>Her son—and he was dead !
               
               <br></br>On his pale cheek was playing
               
               <br></br>The tender morning red.
               
               <br></br>His hands the mother folded,
               
               <br></br>She knew him dead to be,
               
               <br></br>Then sang devout and softly,
               
               <br></br>" Oh, Mary, praise to thee !"
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">MARIA LOWEL</span>.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page136"></div>
      
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="figure">
            
            <div class="head">ONE OF THE "UPPER TEN THOUSAND."</div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page137"></div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE GREAT TOWER OF TARUDANT.</div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY 
            <span class="person">ROBERT OLIVER</span>.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">(Continued from page 119.)</div>
         
         <p>Swiftly his noble steed bore him on, all that day and during
            the succeeding night. Much they suffered from hunger and
            thirst, but they were stouthearted and patient, and they quailed not nor flagged until mom came, the fresh and fragrant
            mom, when the king found himself at no great distance from
            a well, around which were growing palm trees and green
            and tender herbage. Joyfully he led his good horse to the
            water, and taking off his trappings turned him loose to feed
            and bask amid the delicious grass. He then slaked his own
            thirst, plucked and ate some of the dates that hung above
            his head, and sat down to rest and contemplated the scene
            before him.
         </p>
         
         <p>The well was full of beautiful clear water, but of such
            depth that the king could by no means perceive the bottom,
            but only far down a darkness deepening to intense obscurity.
            It was covered by a light and elegant dome of simple architecture, whose cieling was adorned with silver stars, and in
            the midst an image of the moon, which were constantly reflected in the still, transparent fluid beneath. The dome was
            supported by sixteen octagonal pillars of white marble whereon were engraved in letters of gold the holy words of the
            Koran. The tall and thickly tufted palms so completely
            sheltered the building, that even at noonday, when the surrounding desert glowed like a furnace, it was cool and pleasant beneath that graceful roof.
         </p>
         
         <p>In this sweet place the king remained three days; each
            day drinking of the refreshing water and eating of the nourishing dates. In the cool of the morning he rode about on
            the sand to exercise his horse, and the rest of the day employed in reading the words engraven on the pillars and in
            meditating on their meaning. At night he prayed and slept
            beneath the dome.
         </p>
         
         <p>On the morning of the fourth day feeling much invigorated
            and full of hope, he resolved to depart, though loth to quit
            so delightful a dwelling-place. His heart was cheered and
            his mind strengthened by the words he had read on the pillars, and the future gave him no anxiety. Having saddled
            his horse he approached the well and knelt down to return
            thanks to Allah and drink a parting draught. During each
            hour of his sojourn the water of the well had been growing
            clearer and clearer, and he now saw to an immense depth,
            though no glimpse of the bottom could yet be obtained. As
            he gazed downwards farther than ever before, he was startled
            to perceive the water troubled, and presently with amazement, but also with delight, he beheld emerge from the well
            a female figure, habited in a beautiful blue garment, spangled
            with silver stars. About her neck was a string of pearls,
            and on her head a silver crescent like the rising moon. In
            her right hand was a wand, also of silver. Her form was
            commanding, though elegant, and her countenance lovely in
            feature, but cold and pale, no trace of color being visible.
         </p>
         
         <p>She looked upon Abdallah for a moment, and then said:—
            " You have been long expected, king of Tarudant, and are
            now well prepared. I am ready to be your guide."
         </p>
         
         <p>" Who and what art thou ?" inquired the monarch, as soon as his astonishment would
            suffer
            him to speak. 
         </p>
         
         <p>" I am a fairy who for ages have dwelt at the bottom of
            this well, which never before was visited by mortal to whom
            I could reveal myself. Notwithstanding my seclusion, I
            know your history and your present condition. Trust to my
            guidance and you will be restored to your kingdom, and the
            false magician cast down from his bad eminence."
         </p>
         
         <p>There was something in the appearance of the fairy that
            commanded the king’s confidence, though he could not divest
            himself of a feeling of awe at her presence, and though she
            addressed him with a grave coldness, that bordered on austerity. Joy flowed into his heart with her words, and he
            warmly expressed his willingness to submit to her control.
            She continued:
         </p>
         
         <p>" Upon a mountain in the east, in the mighty Atlas chain,
            dwells a twin sister of mine, without whose assistance I can
            do little, with it, almost everything. First of all, we must
            seek her abode, which is distant and difficult of access. The
            way is toilsome and beset with dangers—are you ready to
            pursue it?"
         </p>
         
         <p>" I will go with you to the ends of the earth, O beautiful
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            and benign fairy! Cheered by the light of your presence, I
            can endure all toils and defy all dangers." 
         </p>
         
         <p>" Come, then. Light indeed will be the toils I spoke of,
            and harmless the dangers, if you steadfastly abide with me,
            and yield willing obedience to my counsels ; but turn aside
            or falter in your faith and you are lost forever."
         </p>
         
         <p>She then gave him a silver bottle filled with water from
            the well, and a sack in which to put dates for himself and
            grass for his horse. They left the dome together and commenced their journey over the desert, the fairy gliding lightly along beside him. Said the king, glancing at the surrounding barrenness—"Why do you not, O wise and powerful fairy, make use of the water of your well to fertilize this
            desert, to clothe it with beautiful vegetation, and people it
            with happy inhabitants ?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"I care nothing for the things you speak of," coldly replied the fairy, " I leave them to the sister we are seeking,
            whose whole delight is in such like works. My pleasure is
            to sit still at the bottom of my well in the clear, cool water,
            and contemplate the moon and stars and graven words above."
         </p>
         
         <p>This answer seemed strange to the king, " for why," said
            he to himself, " if she delights not in deeds of benevolence,
            has she taken me under her protection and engaged to guide
            me on a long and perilous journey, having for its end the recovery of my kingdom ?" But a certain awe restrained him
            from speaking his thought, though he more than suspected
            that silence could not conceal it from the fairy.
         </p>
         
         <p>On they went for many days and nights, and Abdallah
            soon found to his great astonishment that he need take no
            thought for what he should eat, or what he should drink,
            nor for the sustenance of the good steed whereon he rode.
            The bottle of water and the sack of dates and grass which
            the fairy had given him, proved to be endowed with the most
            marvellous qualities; use did not diminish their contents, nor
            did time and heat despoil them of their freshness. This
            miracle inspired him with confidence in his wondrous guide,
            so strong that he felt nothing could ever shake it. Henceforth he proceeded with a heart still lighter, and a mind still
            more assured.
         </p>
         
         <p>On the morning of the fourth day, soon after sunrise, as
            they were passing through a valley bounded by low hills of
            sand, a loud roaring was heard upon their left, so sudden and
            so frightful that the king’s hair stood straight upon his head,
            and his horse sprung aside with a start that nearly unseated
            the rider. In an instant after, six monstrous leopards came
            leaping over the hillock and fell upon Abdallah, whose first
            impulse was to draw his sabre and defend himself; but immediately remembering his guide and protectress, whom the
            leopards did not seem to see, he turned to her with a look
            of confident appeal. She smiled, and waved her silver wand.
            The beasts, one of whom had already fastened his claws upon the horse, were struck with furious madness; quitting
            their expected prey, they rushed down the valley, tearing
            each other as they went and filling the air with howls of
            rage and pain, till they were lost to view in the desert.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Had you trusted alone to your own arm," said the fairy,
            when the king’s look returned from following the leopards to
            fall with gratitude upon her face, " they would have torn
            you limb from limb; earth breeds no fiercer beasts than they,
            and your weapon would have been but as a straw against
            their strength."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Words cannot express my thankfulness, O blessed fairy,
            for this deliverance; but see, my poor horse is dreadfully
            wounded—what can I do to relieve him ?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"Wash the wound with water from the silver bottle."
            The king did so, and when the blood was cleared away, the
            fairy passed her hand over the place and instantly the horse
            was healed, as sound and strong as ever.
         </p>
         
         <p>They proceeded on their way, and Abdallah, rendered vigilant by this encounter, kept wary watch on all sides, but
            perceived nothing alarming until just at high noon his glance
            fell upon a strangely shaped shadow flitting over the sand.
            Surprised at this, for the sky of the desert had been hitherto
            cloudless, he looked up to ascertain the cause, and beheld
            one of the monstrous green birds that he had last seen flying
            to and fro in the smoke of the tower, coming down directly
            over his head, with a large tortoise clutched in its talons.
            When the monster saw that it was seen, it screamed with
            baffled rage and let fall the tortoise, which would have
            crushed the king to earth had he not spurred his horse aside
            just in time to avoid the missile. It struck where he had
            stood with such force as to sink deep into the sand.
         </p>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page138"></div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>The king looked around for the fairy, but she was nowhere
            to be seen. He had no lime to be amazed at her disappearance, for the bird had descended almost as quickly as the
            tortoise, and was rushing at him with its seven heads
            stretched greedily forwards, and its mighty wings beating
            the air with such force that the sand flew up as if raised by
            a whirlwind. Retreat was impossible. Nerving himself
            with a brief prayer to Allah, the king drew his sabre and
            awaited the onset. He scarcely hoped that his horse would
            endure the sight of so terrible a creature ; but the good steed
            bravely faced the monster, which in an instant was upon them
            and seized the king’s left arm with one of its beaks, while
            with the others it strove to pluck out his eyes and those of
            the horse. At a blow Abdallah struck off the head that griped his arm. The blood spouted forth like a fountain, and
            the screams of the bird rang far and wide through the desert,
            startling the wild beasts in their lairs, and arousing a thousand answering roars. Mad with pain and fury, the monster
            grasped with all its remaining beaks the arm that had inflicted the wound, and would have torn it off, but just then a
            dove appeared, flying downwards, and alighted upon the
            head of the king’s horse—a small white dove with coralcolored feet and eyes of ruby hue.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">INDIAN NAMES OF THE ISLANDS AND BAY OF NEW YORK.</div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY 
            <span class="person">H. R. SCHOOLCRAFT</span>.
         </div>
         
         <p>The first name, which occurs, is that of the Hudson river.
            It does not appear that the discoverer thought of giving it
            his own name. In the narrative of his voyage, it is called
            the Great River of the Mountains, or simply the Great river.
            This term was simply translated by his employers, the servants of the Dutch West India Company, who, on the
            early maps of Nova Belgica, called it Groote Riviere. It
            was afterwards called Nassau, after the reigning House, but
            this name was not persevered in. After a subsequent time,
            they gave it the name of Mauritius, after Prince Maurice, but
            this name, if it was ever much in vogue, either did not prevail against, or was early exchanged for the popular term of
            North River—a name which it emphatically bore to distinguish it from the Lenapihittuck or Delaware, which they
            called South river. [Zuydt Rivier.] That the name of
            Mauritius was but partially introduced, is indicated by the
            reply made by the New England authorities to a letter respecting boundaries of Gov. Kieft, in 1646, in which they
            declare, in answer to his complaint of encroachments on its
            settlements, their entire ignorance of any river bearing this
            name.
         </p>
         
         <p>Neither of the Indian names by which it was called, appear to have found much favor. The Mohegans called it
            Shatemuc. Shaita, in the cognate dialect of the Odjibwa,
            means a pelican. It cannot be affirmed, to denote the same
            object in this dialect, nor is it known that the pelican has ever been seen on this river. Uc is the ordinary inflection for
            locality. The Mincees, occupying the west banks, called it
            Mohegan-ittuck. The syllable itt, before uck, is one of the
            most transitive forms, by which the action of the nominative
            is engrafted upon the objective, without communicating any
            new meaning. The signification of the term is, Mohegan
            river. The Iroquois, (as given bv the interpreter John
            Bleecker, and communicated by the late Dr. Samnel L.
            Mitchell in a letter to Dr. Miller in 1811,) called Ca ho ha
            ta tè a,—that is to say, if we have apprehended the word,
            the "real river having mountains beyond the Cahoh or Cahoes
            Falls.
         </p>
         
         <p>The three prominent Indian names for the Hudson
            are therefore the MOHEGAN, the CHATEMUC, and the CAHOTATEA.
         </p>
         
         <p>The river appears also to have been also called, by other
            tribes of the Iroquois confederacy, Sanataty. The word
            ataty, here, is the same written atatea, above, and is descriptive of various scenes according to its prefix. The English first named the river, the Hudson, after the surrender
            of the colony in 1664. It does not appear, under this name,
            in any Dutch work or record, which has been examined. It
            may be observed, that the term has not exclusively prevailed
            to the present day, among New Yorkers in the river counties,
            where the name of North River is still popular. It will be
            recollected, as a proof of the prevailing custom, that Fulton
            called bis first boat, to test the triumph of steam, "The
            North River."
         </p>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>If the river failed to bear to future times, either of its
            original names, the island, as the nominative of the city,
            was equally unfortunate, the more so it is conceived, as the
            name of the city became the name of the state. Regret has
            been expressed, that some one of the sonorous anil appropriate Indian names of the west, had not been chosen to designate the state. The colonists were but little regardful of
            questions of this kind. Both the Dutch in 1609 and the English in 1665, came with precisely the same force of national
            prepossession—the first in favor of Amsterdam, and the second in favor of New York—both connected with the belittling adjective "New." It is characteristic of the English,
            that they have sought to perpetuate the remembrance of
            their victories, conquests and discoveries, by these geographical names. And the word New York, if it redound less to
            their military or naval glory, than Blenheim, Trafalgar and
            Waterloo may be cited to show, that there was an early developed trait of character of the English, abroad as
            well as at home. It would be well, indeed, if their descendants in America had been a little more alive to the influence of this trait. Those who love the land, and cherish
            its nationalities, would at least have been spared, in witnessing the growth and development of this great city, the continued repetition of foreign, petty or vulgar names, for our
            streets and squares and public resorts, while such names as
            Saratoga and Ticonderoga, Niagara and Ontario, Iosco and
            Owasco, are never thought of.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Indians called the Island MON-A-TON—dropping the
            locol inflection uk. The word is variously written by early
            writers. The sound as pronounced to me in 1827 by Metoxon, a Mohegan chief, is Mon ah tan uk, a phrase which is
            descriptive of the whirlpool of Hellgate. Mon or man, as
            here written, is the radix of the adjective bad, carrying as it
            does, in its multiplied forms, the various meanings of violent,
            dangerous, &amp;c., when applied in compounds. Ah tun, is a
            generic term for a channel, or stream of running water. Uk,
            denotes locality, and also plurality. When the tribe has thus
            denoted this passage, which is confessedly the most striking
            and characteristic geographical feature of the region, they
            called the island near it, to imply the Anglicised term,
            Man-hat-tan, and themselves Mon-a-tuns, that is to say,
            " People of the Whirlpool." It is well known that the Indian tribes, have, generally, taken their distinctive names
            from geographical features. The Narragansetts, as we are
            told by Roger Williams, took that name, from a small island
            off the coast. Massachusetts, according to the same authority, signifies the Blue Hills, and is derived from the appearance of lands at sea. Mississaga, signifies they live at the
            mouth of a large river, and by an inflection, the people who
            live at the mouth of the large river or waters. Onondaga,
            means the people who live on the hill. Oneida, the people who sprang from a rock, &amp;c. These names afford no
            clue to nationality, they preserve no ethnological chain.
         </p>
         
         <p>The tradition that this island derives its name from the
            accidental circumstance of the intoxication of the Indians on
            Hudson’s first visit, in 1609, is a sheer inference, unsupported by philology. That the tradition of such an event was
            preserved and related to the early missionaries by the Mohegan Indians, admits of no doubt, nor is there more, that the
            island was referred to as the place where their ancestors first
            obtained the taste of ardent spirits. That the island had no
            name prior to 1609, or if well known by a characteristic
            name, that this elder name was then dropped and a new
            name bestowed, in allusion to this circumstance of the intoxication, is not only improbable, on known principles, but is
            wholly unsustained, as will have been perceived by the above
            etymology. The word for intoxication, or dizziness from
            drink, in the Algonquin, and with little change in all the
            cognate dialects, is Ke wush kwä bee. The verb to drink in
            the same dialects is Min e kwä, in the Mohegan "Minahn"
            —words having none of the necessary elements of this compound. Very great care is, indeed, required in recording Indian words, to be certain that the word given, is actually expressive of the object of inquiry. Some curious and amusing
            examples of mistakes of this kind might be given, did it comport with the limits of this report.
         </p>
         
         <p>There were several Indian villages, or places of resort, on
            the island of Mon-à-tun, for which the original names have
            survived. The extreme point of land, between the junction
            of the East and North rivers, of which the Battery is now a
            part, was called Kapsee—and within the memory of persons
            still living was known as "the Copsie point"—a term which
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page139"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            appears to denote a safe place of landing, formed by eddy
            waters. There was a village called Sapokanican, on the
            shores of the Hudson, at the present site of Greenwich.
            Corlear’s Hook was called Naghtogok. The particle took,
            here, denotes sand. A tract of meadow land on the north
            end of the island, near Kingsbridge, was called Muscoota,
            that is, meadow or grass land. Warpoes was a term bestowed on a piece of elevated ground, situated above and
            beyond the small lake or pond called the Kolck. This
            term is, apparently, a derivative from Wawbose, a hare.
         </p>
         
         <p>The islands around the city had their appropriate names.
            Long Island was called Metòac, after the name of the Metòacks, the principal tribe located on it. It is thus called by
            Van Der Donck in 1656, and in all the subsequent maps of
            authority, dowa to Evans’, in 1775. Smith calls it Meitowacks. In Gov. Clinton’s discourse, it is printed Meilowacks, but this is evidently a typographical error.
         </p>
         
         <p>Staten Island, we are informed by De Vries, was occupied
            by the Mon-a-tans, who called it MONOCKNONG with a verbal
            prefix. The termination is ong, denotes locality. Manon is
            the ironwood tree, ack denotes a tree, or trunk, and admits
            a prefix from " manadud," bad. By inquiry it does not appear that the Ironwood, although present, ever existed in
            sufficient abundance to render the name from that characteristic. The other, it is too late to investigate. It is believed
            the expression had an implied meaning, and denoted the
            Haunted Woods.
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus far the colonial maps and records, so far as they have
            fallen under the committee’s notice. The vocabulary of the
            Mohegans affords, however, a few other terms, the application of which may be well assumed from their etymology.
            Of this kind is the term NAOSH, for Sandy Hook, meaning a
            point surpassing others. MINNISAIS, or the lesser island, for
            Bedlow’s island ; and KIOSHK, or Gull island, for Ellis’s island.
            The heights of Brooklyn are graphically described in the
            term Ihpetonga; that is, high sandy banks.
         </p>
         
         <p>The geological structure of the island was such as to bring
            it to a much narrower point, than it now occupies. By the
            recent excavations for the foundations of Trinity Church, and
            the commercial buildings on the site of the Old Presbyterian
            Church in Wall-street, the principal stratum is seen to be of
            coarse grey sea sand, capped with a similar soil, mixed with
            vegetable mould and feruginous oxide. From the make of
            the land, the Indian path, on the Trinity plateau, forked at
            the foot of the Park, and proceeded east of the small lake
            called the Kolck [Agieҫon] to the rise of ground at Chatham
            square. Here, or not far from it, was the eminence called
            WARPOES, probably the site of a village, and so named from
            its chief. The stream and marsh existing where Canal street
            now runs, gave this eastern tendency to the main path. At
            or beyond Warpoes, another fork in the path became necessary to reach the banks of the Hudson at the Indian village
            of LAPINIKAN, now Greenwich. In this route laid the eminence ISHPATENA, late Richmond Hill, at the corner of Charlton and Varick streets. The path leading from the interjunction at Warpoes, or Chatham square, to NAHTONK, or
            Corlear’s Hook, had no intermediate village, of which the
            name has survived. This portion of the island was covered
            with a fine forest of nut wood, oaks, and other hard-wood
            species, interspersed with grassy glades, about the sites of the
            Indian villages. The upper part of the island was densely
            wooded. Above Fortieth street it was unfavorable for any
            purpose but hunting, and much of the middle part of it, as
            between Fifth and Eighth Avenues, was either shoe-deep
            under water or naturally swampy. This arose, as is seen at
            this day, from a clayey stratum, which retains the moisture,
            whereas the whole island below this location, particularly
            below the brow of the sycnitic formation of Thirty-seventh
            street, &amp;c., consisted of gravel and sand, which absorbed the
            moisture and rendered it the most favorable site for building
            and occupation. On the margin of the Hudson, the water
            reached, tradition tells us, to Greenwich street. There is a
            yellow painted wooden house still standing at the northeast
            corner of Courtland and Greenwich streets, which had the
            waternear toil. Similar tradition assures us that Broadstreet
            was the site of a marsh, and small creek. The same may
            be said of the foot of Maiden lane, once Fly Market, and of
            the outlet of the Muskeeg or Swamp, now Ferry street.
            Pearl street marked the winding margin of the East river.
            Foundations dug here reach the ancient banks of oyster
            shells. Ashibic denotes the probable narrow ridge or ancient
            cliff north of Beekman street, which bounded the marsh
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            below. OCITOC is a term for the heighth of land in
            Broadway, at Niblo’s ; ABIC, a rock rising up in the Battery ;
            PENABIC, Mt. Washington, or the Comb mountain. These
            notices, drawn from philology, and, in part, the earlier geographical accounts of New Belgium, might be extended to a
            few other points, which are clearly denoted ; but are deemed
            sufficient to sustain the conclusions, which we have arrived
            at, that the main configuration of the leading thoroughfares
            of the city, from the ancient canoe-place at Copsie or the
            Battery, extending north to the Park, and thence to Chatham
            square and the Bowery, and west to Tivoli Garden, &amp;c.,
            were ancient roads, in the early times of Holland supremacy,
            which followed the psimary Indian foot-paths.
         </p>
         
         <p>Governor’s island bore the name of Nut island, during the
            Holland supremacy, in Dutch Nutten ; but whether, as is
            suspected, this was a translation of the Indian Pecanuc, or
            "nut-trees," is not certain. As a general remark, it may be
            said that the names of the Mon-à-tons, or Manhattanese,
            were not euphonous, certainly less so than those of the Delawares or Iroquois.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">GRAHAM'S MAGAZINE,</div>
         
         <p>Whatever may be the merits or demerits, generally, of
            the Magazine literature of America, there can be no question as to its extent or its influence. The topic—Magazine
            literature—is therefore, an important one. In a few years its
            importance will be found to have increased in geometrical
            ratio. The whole tendency of the age is Magazine-ward.
            The quarterly reviews have never been popular. Not only
            are they too stilted (by way of keeping up a due dignity ), but
            they make a point, for the same reason, of discussing only
            topics which are caviare to the many, and which, for the
            most part, have only a conventional interest, even with the
            few. Their issues, also, are at too long intervals: their
            subjects get cold before being served up. In a word, their
            ponderosity is quite out of keeping with the movement--with
            the rush of the age. We now demand the light artillery of
            the intellect: we need the curt, the condensed, the pointed
            the readily diffused—in place of the verbose, the detailed,'
            the voluminous, the inaccessible. On the other hand, the
            lightness of the artillery must not degenerate into pop-gunnery—by which character we may designate the character
            of the greater portion of the newspaper press; whose sole
            legitimate object is the discussion of ephemeral matters in an
            ephemeral manner. Whatever talent may be brought to bear
            upon our daily journals, (and in many cases this talent is very
            great) still the imperative necessity of catching, currente
            calamo, every topic as it flits before the eye of the public
            must, of course, materially narrow the limits of their power.
            The bulk, and the period of issue of the Monthly Magazine
            seem to be precisely adapted, if not to all the literary wants
            of the day, at least to the largest and most imperative as
            well as the most consequential portion of them.
         </p>
         
         <p>With these views, we shall, of course, regard attentively
            all that concerns our Magazines. It is our design to treat
            this class of journals with a consideration to which hitherto
            they have been unaccustomed. We propose neither to be
            laud nor to abuse them ; but in regarding them as the most
            important arenas for our literary men, we shall be pardoned
            for sweeping them clean of all that is adventitious.
         </p>
         
         <p>Keeping these intentions in mind, as points to be accomplished in the future, we shall content ourselves, this Week
            with a few observations, at random, on the March number of
            Graham’s Magazine—reserving its general character, as well
            as the general character of its class, for more deliberate investigation hereafter. 
         </p>
         
         <p>The two first plates are capitally designed and engraved;
            the "Dacota Woman and Assiniboin Girl," in especial is
            worthy of all commendation. No annual has been issued in
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page140"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            America which might not have been proud of these illustrations. The third plate, called the " Love-Letter," is disgraceful in every respect. The flesh of the woman is sheep’s
            wool, and the hand holding the love-missive, has the air of
            having been carved by a very small child, with a dull knife,
            from a raw potato. The essay on Egotism is well written
            and pointed. Miss Sedgwick’s " Incidents at Rome" is only
            mediocre; it has little either of force or novelty. Mr.
            Simms’ " Boatman's Revenge" is a spirited tale, by one of our
            best narrators of similar things—a man whose literary interests have suffered by too pertinacious a residence in the
            South. Mr. Simms is full of fault, but he has a true vigor
            which more than redeems it. The division of his present
            story into chapters is without meaning, and has a stiffness
            which is objectionable. " Serenading" is only so-so. " Lucy
            Dutton," by Fanny Forrester, is gracefully told. "Foreign
            Mysteries," by Grund, and " Carry Carlisle" by Mrs. Osgood,
            are the best contributed prose articles in the number; the
            latter piece embodying also some of the best poetry. The
            editorial criticisms of " Graham" are in general vigorous and
            pungent—but the notice of " Lowell’s Conversations" in the
            present number, by no means does justice, we think, to the
            very great and peculiar abilities of the author reviewed.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE LOST BOY.</div>
         
         <div class="note" type="headnote">We find the following, remarkable story in the New York
            Evangelist of last week, without any indication of the source
            whence it was derived. But it has all the appearance of
            truth, and all the strangeness of fiction; it is a novel incident
            in American life, which somebody or other will doubtlesss
            make the foundation of a tale.
         </div>
         
         <p>In 1835, Mr. Ammi Filley, of Windsor, Ct., removed with his family
            to the town of Jackson, in the State of Michigan. In this town,
            then a wilderness, he located himself, and by his industry and economy he soon found himself in the possession of a productive and profitable farm; and by the accession of settlers, the town became populous
            and flourishing. Although in the vicinity of various tribes of savages,
            and often visited by wandering families of the natives, all was peace
            and quietness, and every thing conspired to render their abode
            pleasant and happy.
         </p>
         
         <p>On the 3d of August, 1837, his little son, then a child of four years
            old went out to a swamp in the vicinity of their dwelling, with a
            hired girl, to gather whortleberries. The swamp was in the direction
            from Mr. Filley’s to the dwelling of Mr. Mount, the father of the girl,
            whither they expected to go to spend the night—and the scene of
            their toil was about a mile from the house of the former, and some
            twenty or thirty rods from the dwelling of the latter. Having satisfied
            himself with picking berries, the child displayed a desire to return,
            whereupon the girl conducted him to the road, and placed him in the
            direction to the house of Mr. Mount—not doubting, as the house was
            in plain sight, and only a few rods distant, but the little fellow would
            reach it in perfect safety. 
         </p>
         
         <p>The girl returned to the swamp, and after completing her supply of
            berries, went home to the house offer father, and found to her astonishment, as well as that of the family, that William had not arrived.
            Notice was immediately given to the parents, an alarm given through
            the settlement, and the whole population rushed at once to the assistance and relief of the almost distracted parents. Day and night, for
            more than a week, the whole country, in every direction, to an extent
            of more than twenty miles, was searched with untiring vigilance.
            Every pond and stream of water was examined and dragged—and
            every rod of ground scrutinized, for many successive days, but no trace
            could be discovered of the absent child.
         </p>
         
         <p>As suspicions were entertained that foul play had been practised by
            the Indians, inquiries were made of the different tribes and families
            in the vicinity, and pecuniary offers tendered to their chiefs and influential men, and Mr. Filley himself traversed for months the wilds of
            Michigan, Wisconsin and Iowa, but his efforts proved vain. No discovery could be made, and no tidings had, and he returned to his
            broken-hearted family, with the sad reflection that his William was
            lost!
         </p>
         
         <p>For seven long years this stricken family endured the agony of an
            affliction which seldom falls to the lot of human nature to submit to—
            " months of vanity and wearisome nights were appointed to them."
         </p>
         
         <p>Since the decease of his wife. Mr. Filley has visited Connecticut, the
            place of his nativity, and while here, by a mysterious course of events
            beyond the comprehension of human wisdom to fathom, his long lost
            child has appeared and been restored to his embraces.
         </p>
         
         <p>It seems that the lad, before reaching the house of Mr. Mount, was
            overtaken and kidnapped by a band of Indians, who in their wanderings happened to pass that way. In this family he lived, and travelled
            with them in all their movements, from the time he was captured until
            the autumn of 1843.
         </p>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>About this time his family visited Albany, N. Y., and while there
            this white child was discovered among them. The municipal authorities of the city becoming acquainted with the circumstance, at once
            caused their arrest, and took measures to compel them to disclose the
            means by which they became possessed of the child. They were alternately flattered and threatened, but no disclosure could be obtained,
            as they seemed resolved to submit to any punishment rather than
            make any communication by which the paternity of the child could
            be ascertained. They were therefore discharged, and the child very
            humanely placed in the Orphan Asylum.
         </p>
         
         <p>Subsequently, in the spring of 1844, Mr. Cowles, of Tolland, Mass.,
            being in want of a boy in his family, was recommended to this place,
            and furnished with this lad, whom he brought home with him to his
            residence in Tolland.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the month of December last, a most marvellous concurrence of
            circumstances, the facts in relation to this boy, so far as it concerned
            the transactions at Albany, came to the knowledge of the Rev. Dr.
            Cooley of Granville. The Dr. having frequently heard the circumstances under which the child was lost, immediately communicated
            the intelligence he had obtained to Mr. Marvin, the grandfather of the
            child, and he without loss of time, made known the tidings to Mr.
            Filley, who was then with his friends in Connecticut. From the knowledge thus obtained, Mr. Filley visited Mr. Cowles in Tolland, with
            whom the lad then resided.
         </p>
         
         <p>Although time and exposure had somewhat obliterated the fair features of his youth, his personal appearance was the counterpart of the
            other members of his family. His size, his age, the complexion of his
            eyes and hair, and all his prominent characteristics indicated those of
            his child; arid upon appealing to a known scar upon his hand, and examining an indubitable mark in the hair of his head, his identity was
            fully recognized; and in the joy of his heart he pressed to his bosom
            his long lost son.
         </p>
         
         <p>From the story of the boy it appears that he has constantly resided
            in the same family, which consisted of four Indians—Paul Pye, Phebe
            Anne Pye, his wife, Martha Anne Pye, their daughter, and Thomas
            Williams, an inmate of the family. They adopted him as their son,
            and he was taught and believed that Paul and Phebe Aon were his
            parents, and Martha his sister. He supposed himself an Indian boy,
            and was nor aware of any difference of complexion, or distinction of
            nature, until his deliverance at Albany. He has an indistinct recollection of attending school, but when or where he knows not.
         </p>
         
         <p>This seems to be the only remaining fact in his memory that he can
            recognize as having transpired prior to his capture, and he does not
            seem to associate this with any other fact indicative of his home, except that he did not go to school with the Indians.
         </p>
         
         <p>He recollects living near Detroit, Utica, Brothertown, Catskill and
            Hudson, and several months at Hillsdale, N. Y. In all their wanderings in summer and winter he travelled barefoot, suffering in winter
            from cold, and at all times from hunger and fatigue ; but his Indian
            sister, like a second Pocahontas, took unwearied pains to mitigate his
            sufferings and make his captivity endurable.
         </p>
         
         <p>Although he cannot recognize his new friends, yet he rejoices that
            he has found a permanent home in a land of civilization, and all parties
            feel it their duty to render their grateful thanks to the author of all
            good for this marvellous dispensation of Providence.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE CONCERT ROOM.</div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">MR. GEORGE LODER'S CONCERT.</div>
            
            <p>This much talked-of and long expected Concert was given at the
               Apollo Saloon on Saturday evening last. The appearance of the weather had for several days indicated rain, but the promise was not fillfilled until about an hour, or so, before the Concert commenced, when
               it fell heavily. It was very unfortunate, and almost destructive to Mr.
               Loder’s hopes and just expectations. However, despite the storm,
               some five or six hundred persons assembled, and among them many of
               onr first citizens, and most accomplished amateurs.
            </p>
            
            <p>The performance commenced with Mendelssohn’s Lobegesang,
               performed by about one hundred and twenty instruments and voices:
               most of them were picked artists, chosen for their professional capability.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Lobegesang is a Sinfonia-Cantata, consisting of three movements for the instruments—an Allegro, an Allegretto Agitato, and an
               Adagio, which are followed by choruses, duetts, and solos. The first
               movement is in B flat, in which the work also ends, and commences
               with two bars for the Trombone, in which is developed the leading
               idea,the prominent thought, which is wonderfully elaborated in this
               movement, and stands out in bold relief in almost every other piece,
               and is the phrase in the work. We might almost say that the Lobegesang is a work of one idea, embodying in music the following words
               —All that has life and breath, sing to the Lord—for the countless
               exquisite thoughts which crowd the composition, are to that one
               thought secondary and subservient. The subject of the Allegro we
               take to be the voice of Faith proclaiming aloud—" Sing to the Lord."
               This lofty and elevating strain is broken in upon by a melody of exquisite beauty, hopeful and trusting in its sentiment, and symbolical of
               simple but earnest adoration, but ever and anon, the stern and unyielding phrase—" Sing to the Lord"—bursts forth as warning to the
               wavering and confimation to the believer. This movement is great in
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page141"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               its design and is instrumented most massively, and yet with a variety
               which precludes all feeling of weariness. A few bars at its close introduces us to the second movement, Andante Agitato, which for the
               beauty of its melody, its tearful and plaintive sorrow, agitated and
               doubting, its exquisitely varied treatment for the orchestra, has no
               parallel in instrumental writing. To compare the great in design,
               with the comparatively trifling, it reminds us of that exquisite weeping
               song " L’Hoperduta me meschina" in Mozart’s La Nozze de Figaro. In
               the midst of this heart thrilling movement, the voice of Faith is heard
               saying in commanding tones, " Sing to the Lord." But the mourner,
               wrapped in his sorrow as in a shroud, would not be comforted; again
               and again the voice was heard, and lo! unable to resist its stem control, the heart which grief had hardened, bows down in supplication
               and in prayer. The penitent and prayerful spirit is exquisitely pourtrayed in the Adagio Religioso. It is a most lovely movement; gratitude, devotion, and faith break forth in every phrase in the
               measure.
            </p>
            
            <p>This Sinfonia was admirably executed; each one in the band
               seemed to vie with the other in the endeavor to produce something
               as near perfection as possible. The violins were too lew, as is usual
               in Amercan orchestras, but these few were firm and drew a vigorous
               bow. Messrs. Marks and Tyte are equal to any four men.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is impossible, we find, to notice this great work in detail, as it
               was our intention to have done, we must, therefore, content ourselves
               with mentioning a few of the prominent beauties. The recit. and aria,
               by Signor Antognini, Sing ye praise, and the chorus, All ye that cried
               unto the Lord ; duetto, Mrs. E. Loderand Miss Watson, I waited for
               the Lord, and chorus, O blessed are they, and the duett, Mrs. Loder
               and Sig. Antognini, My song shall be therefore, Thy Mercy, are such of
               the work as will be most felt by the public, for they are truly surfeited
               with beauty. The three great chorusses are, however, the first, fourth,
               and sixth.
            </p>
            
            <p>The chorusses were admirably performed, every point was taken up
               with firmness and precision, and a body of sound produced altogether
               disproportioned to the small body of singers. But difficulties become
               easy when the true spirit animates us in the struggle.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mrs. E. Loder has received so much praise on every hand for her
               beautiful and chaste execution of this difficult and classical music, that
               we need not make any further comment. Miss Watson also acquitted
               herself to the satisfaction of all, and received in the second Act, the
               heartiest applause of the evening, for her chaste and simple style of
               singing an admired ballad.
            </p>
            
            <p>Signor Antognini sang some of the music of the Lobegesang with
               much taste and expression, but his style is neither suited to our vernacular, nor to the music of Mendelssohn. The genius of the German
               music is entirely opposed to the Italian school; there is no one point
               of union ; not even a half-way house. The Italian finds himself fettered by the music, and his style either becomes heavy and strained,
               or the poor music becomes unmercifully ostracised. Signor Antognini,
               however, did admirably, considering that he is not familiar with the
               language, and less familiar with the music.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Offertorium, by Henri Vieuxtemps, contains some passages of
               beauty, but we do not much admire it. It is an attempt to imitate the
               strict school of writing, but in attempting this, he has not only imitated the school, but the masters. Mozart has contributed largely to
               the Offertorium. As a vocal composition, it proves that M. Vieuxtemps is unaccustomed to write for voices, and though the union with
               the full orchestra renders the effect somewhat imposing, we do not
               think the work will add to the fame of the author.
            </p>
            
            <p>To Mr. Loder we again give all praise and commendation. He conducted throughout the evening with judgment and firmness, and proved
               himself equal to the task he had undertaken. The cordial support and
               assistance he met with from the best of his brother Professors, must
               prove truly gratifying to him, as marking their respect and esteem.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Lobegesang should be repeated at the Tabernacle, at Fifty Cents a
               ticket, so that the people may have a chance lo hear one of the greatest compositions of the present day.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE SACRED MUSIC SOCIETY.</div>
            
            <p>On leaving the Tabernacle on Monday evening, we asked ourselves
               if we had heard the Messiah ? The answer was, No ! Handel’s Messiah, like Shakspeare’s plays, has become subject to travestie; the
               levelling and depreciating spirit of the age has laid its slimy hand upon
               it, and every chattering jay may libel in annotations, or emasculate by
               interpolation or emendation. In days past, and yet so recently, that
               the past is treading upon the hem of their retreating garment, in days
               scarce past, we say, the Messiah of Handel, like the Iliad of Homer
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               or Paradise Lost of Milton, was looked upon as the great classical
               epic, as the great musical epic, of time. It was held sacred; and
               each one deemed it incumbent upon him, within his sphere, to preserve it as much as possible, in its original and majestic purity. It
               was then graciously conceded by liberal souls, that the composer of a
               great work knew his own mind, and put down his conceptions as he
               wished them executed, while the singer considered he had enough to do
               to study to give effect and do justice to the composer’s manuscript. But
               we have fallen upon better days ; the composer’s task is easy; he has
               only to fashion the rough outline, and leave all the rest to the more
               exquisite taste, extensive knowledge and profound judgment of the
               singer, who is supposed of course to know a little more than singers
               usually do; for instance, he or she must be able to tell the name of a
               note when shewn to them, and also able to play the common chord in
               two positions. These accomplishments, considering the education
               usnally bestowed upon singers, would be acknowledged great. It will
               be therefore perceived, that the singer is now the composer, and the
               composer the drudge. " The public is therefore respectfully informed
               that the skeleton of the Messiah, by Handel, will be performed this
               evening; the principal characters by the principal singers, who will
               give an entire new version of this almost obsolete work, done up to suit
               the times. N. B. The public may rest assured that no vestige of its
               former classical style shall be allowed to remain. N. B. No. 2. Composers can have their works altered and ornamented to suit the modem
               taste and refinement, on the shortest notice. N. B. No. 3. Mendelsshon cooked after the Italian style, to suit the taste of the " Upper
               ten
               thousand." Such will be the announcements in future, we expect.
               Such were our reflections on listening to the Messiah on Monday
               evening. Of Madame Pico we have little to say. Unacquainted with
               the language, and a stranger to the strict style of Handel’s school, we
               expected but little, and we can only reiterate the general expression,
               that Madame Pico did extremely well—considering. The contralto
               songs lay very unfortunate for her, resting chiefly upon the middle part
               of her voice, which is comparatively weak, and thereby contrasting
               too strongly with her lower and stronger tones. Her ornaments were
               out of place, and consequently in bad taste. Some portions of the
               music she seemed to feel, and the few words she knew perfectly, she
               gave with good emphasis. But we never wish to hear Handel after
               the Italian fashion again.
            </p>
            
            <p>Miss Northall has a very good quality of voice, but the upper region,
               though clear, is thin, and has a tendency to extreme sharpness. She
               should not attempt to extend her compass beyond A, for too many
               voices arc ruined by a foolish ambition to possess an extensive compass. The consequence is, that the whole scale becomes thinned
               and weakened. With respect to Handel’s music, we state distinctly,
               that Miss N. knows nothing of its sentiment, its style, its execution.
               It cannot be sung unless it is felt and appreciated mentally. It cannot
               be sung properly unless the singer has been trained up in a strictly
               classical school, and has had constant opportunities of studying classical models. Respectable mediocrity may be attained without this
               course, but no step higher. Miss Northall, on Monday evening, disfigured her music by a host of common-place cadences, hackneyed
               closes and affected sentiment, produced by constantly slurring one note
               into another, or by continued anticipation, faults of a most vicious
               school. Her cadence at the close of Rejoice greatly was so ridiculous
               and startling, that every body doubted the evidence of their senses.
               We must now state, that we believe Miss Northall to possess good
               capabilities both mentally and physically, and we feel assured that if
               she will look more to nature, and strive to banish from her mind that
               meretricious style which offends the judicious, and palls most rapidly
               upon the multitude, we shall shortly have the pleasure of speaking
               more in her praise, than we have ever said to her prejudice.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Jones executed his music with much taste. Some faults we
               might find, but he stood so preeminently superior to all who sang that
               evening, that we refrain from fault-finding, and are content to praise
               most warmly.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Brough never did, never could, and never can sing any thing
               that Handel ever wrote. We have warm respect for Mr. Brough as a
               man but we beg of him, for the sake of all that is classical, to connect
               himself entirely with the " Monks of Old," and such like ballads, and
               quit the legitimate.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Meyer labors under many difficulties, and we feel that, considering the circumstances, we ought to refrain fom saying all we
               know.
            </p>
            
            <p>The chorusses were extremely inefficient. Each separate chorus
               was rendered with no more of effect than an amateur church choir.
               The tempo of every chorus was was by one half too slow; the trebles
               were repeated out of tune; twenty well disciplined voices would have
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page142"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               completely drowned the entire mass. In short, we could scarcely recognise the chorusses of Handel, so utterly were they devoid of the
               spirit and the sentiment.
            </p>
            
            <p>The band, though composed of good men, was totally inefficient;
               indeed, we speak advisedly when we say, that a worse performance,
               in relation to its advertised importance, we never witnessed in our
               life.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are sure that Mr. Hill will agree with us in all that we have
               said. The only blame which attaches to Mr. Hill is this: as conductor of the Society, he should not have allowed the performance to
               take place, knowing, as we are sure a man of his experience must
               know, that it could not redound to the credit of the Society. He retrieved the singers, the chorus and the band, by his steadiness. We
               can only regret that he was not firm enough to prevent the Society
               so disgracing itself.
            </p>
            
            <p>We shall in a future number give some advice to the Government of this Society, for
               it
               ought to be the greatest Society in the country. 
            </p>
            
            <p>The three thousand persons, including five hundred of the upper ten,
               and twenty-five hundred extremely serious people, stated by the
               Evening Mirror to have been present at Madame Pico’s Concert, have
               dwindled down to some six or seven hundred. Verily these men in
               buckram do multiply by the thousand.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">MUSICAL REVIEW.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Works received from Oliver Ditson, 115 Washington St.,
            
            <br></br>Boston.
         </div>
         
         <p>"The Christian Graces," written by the Rev. J. Reynell Wreford,
            F.S.A., composed by Stephen Glover. This is a sacred song well suited for a Sabbath evening. The poetry is very beautiful, breathing a
            spirit of deep and pure devotion—penitential, yet hopeful. The music is simple in its character, and, if it cannot be called original, it
            is
            not offensively copied. The melody is flowing, and easy to be learned. In the fifth bar the B flat in the treble should be A sharp.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Take back the Gems you gave me." Composed by George Linley.
            Mr. Linley is undoubtedly one of the pleasantest ballad writers of the
            day. His songs are all singable, and we occasionally find much musician-like feeling in his writing. The ballad under notice is very pretty—quite a drawing-room piece, and is one of the most teachable
            ballads published for some time.
         </p>
         
         <p>" Dear Normandie." Written and arranged by Stanhope Gordon.
            This is a new arrangement of a well-known air. The words are very
            pretty, and well adapted to the music. It is a very pleasing song. In
            the fifth bar of the second page, the last note in the voice part should
            be E instead of D. It has a handsome and well executed lithographic
            frontispiece. The lady, however, in the foreground, if standing up,
            would measure some seven feet six inches in height.
         </p>
         
         <p>"The Rose of Tyrone." Written by Mrs. Crawford, composed by
            E. L. Hime. The words of this song are sentimental, but the music is
            in the Rory O’More style, an imitation of the regular rollicking Irish
            school. The music and the words, though wedded, are by no means
            matched. The frontispiece is the portrait of the Rose of Tyrone, full
            blown and bewitching.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Beauties of L’Elisir d’Amore," arranged for the piano forte by
            S. F. Rimbault. This is a collection of very easy arrangements of the
            most popular melodies from Donizetti’s well-known opera, the Elixir
            of Love. The pieces are fingered throughout, and will prove popular
            among beginners, serving as relaxation from severer studies.
         </p>
         FOR REVIEW.
         
         <div class="ab">From A. Fiot, 196 Chesnut St., Philadelphia, and W. Dubois, 315</div>
         
         <div class="ab">"Twelve Nouvelles Vocalises, pour Mezzo-Soprano, dediees a son
            
            <br></br>S. A. R. Madame La Duchesse de Nemours, par Marco Bordogni."—
            
            <br></br>In two books.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">"Abd-EI-Kader Quick Step," for the piano forte, composed by J.
            
            <br></br>C. Viereck.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">"The Reproach" (Il Rimprovero), duettino, words translated from
            
            <br></br>Metastasio, by B. S. Barclay. The music by F. Florino.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">"Le Tremolo, sur un Theme de Bethoven, pour le Piano Forte,
            
            <br></br>composee par Henri Herz."
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">LITERARY NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">A Manual of Ancient and Modern History. </div>
            
            <div class="ab">By W. C. Taylor, L.L.D., M.R.
               
               <br></br>A.S., of Trinity College, Dublin. Revised, with a chapter on tne History
               
               <br></br>of the United Stain, by C. S. Henry, D.D., Profenaor of Philosophy and
               
               <br></br>History in the University of the City of New York. D. Appleton &amp; Co.,
               
               <br></br>300 Broadway.
            </div>
            
            <p>"The use of history is not to load the memory with facts, but to
               store the mind with principles," says Dr. Taylor, in his preface ; but
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               if this were true, it would be an idle labor to compress a world of facts
               into the compass that he has done in his manual; principles alone
               would have answered a better purpose. But it is an unmeaning sentence. The principles of history, like the principles of chemistry, are
               facts: we have need of nothing else. Facts are to the mind what manure is to the soil—nothing of value will grow without them. How
               absurd it would be for a man to talk of the philosophy of history,
               whose memory was not well stored with facts. Happily for us, Dr.
               Taylor has not acted on his own theory, but has given us as many
               historical facts as could well be disposed of in 800 pages; and it is
               this, not his principles, which gives so high a value to his manual.
               There is yet no settled principle in regard to the best manner of pursuing historical studies ; aud it is not probable that there ever will
               be.
               In nine cases out of ten, accident will guide the student in his choice
               of books; and elegance of style more than any other cause, will gain
               popularity for an historian. Some of the worst histories that have
               been written, are the most popular ; indeed, a good history will stand
               but little chance of popularity. If every man knew himself thoroughly, he would have need of no other knowledge of mankind, for history, which sounds so grand, is only an exceedingly imperfect account
               of the lives of men precisely like ourselves; and whether they wore
               crowns or tarpaulins, the particulars of their lives are alike valuable
               as materials for philosophy. The life of any milliner in Broadway is
               as good material for history as the life of Queen Anne. If the whole
               plan of writing histories were reversed, and the quarrels and speeches
               of corporals and hucksters from the earliest periods to the present
               time were given, we should know as much of the philosophy of the
               human mind as we do now. The most important fact to be gleaned
               from the history of mankind, is whether or not the human mind has
               improved since the creation ; and the only way to determine it is by
               comparing man at the outset with man at the present. But history
               can aid us but little here ; we must have a more reliable source than
               the records which men make of each other. The true objects for the
               student of humanity will be found in the monuments which men have
               left of their habits, like foot prints in the Band, by which we ascertain
               in what direction they have travelled. A comparison of the Astor
               House with the pyramid of Cheops, if we but knew the uses to which
               both buildings were put, will enable us to determine, better than any
               history that has been written, whether the human mind has made any
               advances during the last three thousand years.
            </p>
            
            <p>But we are undesignedly uttering all manner of heterodoxies, when
               we had only intended to call attention to the very valuable work under notice, whose original value has been enhanced by an additional
               chapter by Professor Henry, (we call him Professor, lest he be confounded with Dr. Henry, the historian of England,) on the history of
               the United States, which brings down our history literally to the present time, giving an account of President Tyler’s Texas message to
               Congress.
            </p>
            
            <p>The work is divided into ancient and modem history, the first part
               beginning with the Egyptians and ending with the creation of the
               Western empire, and a separate chapter on India. The second part
               commences with the Gothic kingdom of Italy, and ends with the affairs of yesterday. There are also separate chapters devoted to the
               history of Colonization, the history of the Jews, and the history of
               China.
            </p>
            
            <p>As a manual of history it will be found one of the most useful, and
               at the same time most readable compends, that have been published.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">The Nune, or Life in a Convent,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">By one of the Sisterhood, first American
               
               <br></br>from the fifth London edition. Fanner &amp; Daggers, 30 Ann st.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">GENERAL INTELLIGENCE.</div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">Anastic Printing </div>
            
            <div class="ab">From Wiley and Putnam’s News letter for March.
               
               <br></br>AMERICAN LITERARY AGENCY,
               
               <br></br>6 Waterloo Place, London, Feb. 1, 1845.
            </div>
            
            <p>Anastatic Printing—About five weeks since I had an opportunity
               of seeing a practical experiment in this new and extraordinary process ; but as the patentee’s arrangements were not then completed, he
               did not wish to have the invention prematurely announced. The practical details—or as much of them as are explained—are given In the
               Art Union for February. The invention is even more wonderful and
               certainly more Important than that for reproducing line engravings,
               as described in the January number of the same journal. It is sufficient to say here, that I desired a copy to be made of the page of a
               newspaper with three illustrations on wood, the inventor engraved the
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page143"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               page, type, cuts and all and gave him six copies in less than ten minutes !
               the zinc plate thus engraved being capable of producing 20,000 impressions, and then of being re-engraved, ad infinitum. Thus an octavo volume, with wood or steel illustrations to any extent, may be reproduced in two or three days or less; and hundreds of thousands
               struck off, equal in all respects to the original.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Dana’s System of Mineralogy," has been reviewed at great length
               in the new number of the North British Review, and the highest praise
               awarded to it.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">Lots of Theology.</div>
            
            <p>—At the sale of the first portion oi the
               stock of the late eminent bookseller of London, Mr. John Bohn, there
               were 5813 lots of theology, and in the other portions 30,000 lots.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">Spontaneous Combustion of Guano.</div>
            
            <p>—This article is likely
               to prove extra-hazardous. An English bark, returning from Ichaboe,
               with a load of guano, was recently destroyed in consequence of the
               spontaneous combustion of her cargo, which was caused by salt water
               uniting with it. A volume of smoke arising from the hatchway warned
               the crew of their danger. They look to the boats, and immediately a
               tremendous explosion of the gas, engendered by the partially fired
               guano, blew the stem out of the vessel, which then filled and sunk.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">A New Poem by Arthur Cleavland Cox.</div>
            
            <p>—It was announced more than two years ago, that a sacred drama by the author
               of "Athanasion," entitled, "Saul, a mystery, in five acts," would
               soon appear. We now learn that it is in press, and will be published
               by Parsons, of Hartford, and Wiley and Putnam, New York.
            </p>
            
            <p>Saul was sketched six or seven years ago, and has since been carefully revised. The former productions of the author will gain for it
               the attention of all lovers of poetry.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">The Rev. Mr. Wright of Philadelphia,</div>
            
            <p>in a letter to the
               Northern Whig, a Belfast newspaper, calls Mr. Tyler, a "Presidential
               man-stealer," and accuses him of selling his own children, according to
               the Liverpool Times; but it is pretty generally known in this country
               that Mr. Tyler could never have sold any of his offspring, at least his
               male children, as it would be extremely difficult to find anybody willing
               to purchase them.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">Chirography.</div>
         
         <p>—The point of perfection in any art or
            science is difficult to determine ; since almost every day heralds an
            improvement in some department of practical knowledge. We think
            however, that Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith’s system of instruction in pen
            manship is as near perfection as can be attained in an art purely mechanical. His writing and flourishing have been submitted to the test
            of comparison with those of his most accomplished rivals, and the result has been the award of five premiums to Mr. G. While thus standin? at the head of his profession, Mr. Goldsmith has reduced his terms
            below those of his compeers, and we observe that he now advertises
            to give a course of lessons for $2,50, at his rooms, 189 Broadway.
            As a matter of course his classes will, on such terms, fill up rapidly.
            In the department of book-keeping, Mr. G. is assisted by Mr. W. T.
            Plummer, who is thoroughly competent to give instruction in that
            bunch of a business education.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">Mr. Disbrow’s Riding School.</div>
         
         <p>—We conceive that we are rendering
            a service to the public, in recommending to their favorable notice the
            Equestrian Academy of Mr. Wm. H. Disbrow. The manner in which
            that establishment is conducted, the moderate charges, and the tout
            ensemble of its internal arrangements cannot fail, when they become
            known, to render the establishment eminently popular. The Ladies
            have peculiar advantages in the schools, as the horses are broken expressly for their use, and as no possible accident can befal them. As
            a teacher of horsemanship Mr. Disbrow is certainly unparalleled in this
            city, at least; and all who may place themselves under his tuition,
            will derive much valuable information relative to the management of
            the horse. As the art of riding is daily becoming more necessary as
            an accomplishment to both ladies and gentlemen, we would earnestly
            recommend all who desire to become proficients in the art, to visit
            Mr. Disbrow’s Menage.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">Notices to Correspondents.</div>
         
         <p>—The communication by R. H. will appear next week; we shall be glad to hear from him often.
            We have taken the liberty to clip off a part of the letter from "Horace,"
            because it contains a puff on ourselves: we have not the least repugnance to a puff, but we do not like the plan of helping to give one currency.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have ample reason to believe that we did the publisher of Graham’s
            Magazine an injustice last week in respect to his paying contributors.
            We are assured that he has uniformly paid liberally where pay has
            been asked, and that during the last three or four years he has paid
            more to American authors than any other publisher in the country.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">OLIVER DITSON,
               
               <br></br>Dealer in all kinds of
               
               <br></br>SHEET MUSIC, MUSIC BOOKS,
               
               <br></br>and Second-hand Piano-Fortes. 
               
               <br></br>NO. 115 WASHINGTON STREET, BOSTON.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">M. DUMSDAY’S IMPROVED ACCORDEON.</div>
            
            <div class="figure">
               
               <div class="head">Additional Modulations</div>
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE ACCOMPANIMENT OF ALL ACCORDE- 
               
               <br></br>ons heretofore has been confined to one key, in music. By applying the
               
               <br></br>above improvement, (on the bottom of the instrument.) we are enabled to
               
               <br></br>play accompaniments in various major and minor keys. The above im-
               
               <br></br>provement added to any Accordeon, having the large and small keys on
               
               <br></br>reasonable terms. Mr. D., professor of music, continues to teach ladies and
               
               <br></br>gentlemen of New York, at their residences, the following instruments, in a
               
               <br></br>scientific and modern style, in a very short time, by his new system of teach-
               
               <br></br>ing: Guitar and Singing, Accordeon, Violin, Trombone and Cornopean.
               
               <br></br>Terms moderate. Satisfactory city and other references given, on applica-
               
               <br></br>tion at No. &amp;5 Chrystie st., above Walker.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">FAMILY groups TAKEN by Mons. EDOUART in an unique style pe-
               
               <br></br>culiarly his own, which has been patronized by the Crowned heads of Eu-
               
               <br></br>rope and the most distinguished families of America. Mons. E. begs to ob-
               
               <br></br>serve that his likenesses are true to nature, and that the manner he disposes
               
               <br></br>of the figures constituting his Family Group has always elicited the highest
               
               <br></br>commendation from eminent artists of both hemispheres The large num-
               
               <br></br>ber 0f groups in his possesion (which are for sale,) evince his natural talent.
               
               <br></br>A collection of 150,000 likenesses with autographs ap, ended, preserved in
               
               <br></br>hook, and large groupings of distinguished characters, are testimonials of his
               
               <br></br>unrivalled skill Those who wish to leave mementos to posterity should not
               
               <br></br>lose the present opportunity. A call at his exhibition room (free) will satisfy
               
               <br></br>all that these works are entirely unique and capable of resisting the destruc-
               
               <br></br>tive influences of time.—His Fireside Groups, representing the members of
               
               <br></br>families united, which union must be of short duration, separations occur-
               
               <br></br>ing by marriage, change of location and demise, can be faithfully preserved
               
               <br></br>in the works of Mons. Edouart, thus affording mementos to those remaining,
               
               <br></br>of time past, and to posterity, of ancestors long since departed.
               
               <br></br>Mons. E. leaves for Europe in a short time. An early visit from patrons
               
               <br></br>at No. 285 Broadway, near Granite Buddings, is solicited and will receive
               
               <br></br>immediate attention; or attendance at the family residence if required.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">DISBROW’S RIDING SCHOOL, NO. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette
               
               <br></br>Places. New York.
               
               <br></br>Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Even-
               
               <br></br>ing, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.
               
               <br></br>TERMS:
               
               <br></br>Lecture Lessons.
               
               <br></br>16 Lessons. . . . . . . . . . . $15 00
               
               <br></br>10 " . . . . . . . . . . . 10 00
               
               <br></br>4 " . . . . . . . . . . . .5 00
               
               <br></br>Single Lessons . . . . . . . . . . . 2 00 
               
               <br></br>Road " . . . . . . . . . . . 2 50
               
               <br></br>Exercise Riding. 
               
               <br></br>1 Month.................................$12 00
               
               <br></br>20 Rides....................................10 00
               
               <br></br>10 "    ....................................6 00
               
               <br></br>Single Rides................................0 75
               
               <br></br>N. B.--Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let. 
               
               <br></br>Evening Class. 
               
               <br></br>12 Lessons ...........$ 9 00 
               
               <br></br>Single   " ............ 1 00
               
               <br></br>20 Rides............ $ 10 00 
               
               <br></br>Single Ride 0 75 
               
               <br></br>RULES 
               
               <br></br>1 All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.
               
               <br></br>2. One hour allowed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.
               
               <br></br>3. One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.
               
               <br></br>4 Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 3 P. M.
               
               <br></br>5 Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.
               
               <br></br>6. No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladies. 
               
               <br></br>A card of address is requested previous to commencing. 
               
               <br></br>N B. Gentlemen keeping their horses at this establishment, will have the
               
               <br></br>privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page144"></div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">KEIGHTLEY’S HISTORICAL WORKS. THE HISTORY OF GREECE.—By Thomas Height-
               
               <br></br>ley, with notes and additions by G. Toulman Smith, in one volume. 
               
               <br></br>THE HISTORY OF ROME- By the same author, with notes and addi-
               
               <br></br>tions in the same manner, in one volume.
               
               <br></br>THE HISTORY OF THE ROMAN EMPIRE—Being a continuation of
               
               <br></br>the History of Rome. By the same author. In one volume.
               
               <br></br>THE HISTORY OF ENGLAND—From the Invasion of Julius Caesar to
               
               <br></br>the close of the reign of George IV. By the same author, with notes
               
               <br></br>and additions as above. In two volumes. Published by
               
               <br></br>TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John St.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">HUNT’S MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE 
               
               <br></br>AND COMMERCIAL REVIEW.
               
               <br></br>BY FREEMAN HUNT, Editor and Proprietor. Pub-
               
               <br></br>lished Monthly, at 142 Fulton Street, New York—at Five Dollars
               
               <br></br>per annum, in Advance.
               
               <br></br>THE MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE and COMMERCIAL RE-
               
               <br></br>VIEW, embraces every subject connected with Commerce, Manufac-
               
               <br></br>tures and Political Economy, as follows:—Commercial Legislation;
               
               <br></br>Commercial History and Geography; Mercantile Biography; Des-
               
               <br></br>criptive, Statistical and Historical Accounts, of the various commodi-
               
               <br></br>ties which form the subject of Mercantile transactions; Port Charges;
               
               <br></br>Tariffs : Customs and Excise Regulations ; Commercial Statistics of
               
               <br></br>the United States and the different countries of the world, with which
               
               <br></br>we have intercourse, including their Physical Character, Population,
               
               <br></br>Productions, Exports, Imports, Seaports, Monies, Weights, Measures
               
               <br></br>Finance and Banking Associations, and Enterprises connected with
               
               <br></br>Commerce, embracing Fisheries, Incorporated Companies, Railroads,
               
               <br></br>Canals, Steamboats, Docks, Post Offices, &amp;c.; Principles of Com
               
               <br></br>merce, Finance and Banking, with Practical and Historical Details
               
               <br></br>and Illustrations; Commercial Law, and Mercantile Law Reports, and
               
               <br></br>Decisions of Courts in the United States and Europe, including Insu-
               
               <br></br>rance, Partnership, Principal and Agent, Bills ol Exchange, Sale,
               
               <br></br>Guaranty, Bankruptcy, Shipping and Navigation, &amp;c., and whatever
               
               <br></br>else shall tend to develope the resources of the country and the
               
               <br></br>world, and illustrate the various topics bearing upon Commerce and
               
               <br></br>Commercial Literature.
               
               <br></br>It has been, and will continue to be, the aim of the Editor and Pro-
               
               <br></br>prietor of the MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE, to avoid every thing of a par-
               
               <br></br>ty, political, or sectional bias or bearing, in the conduct of the work
               
               <br></br>—opening its pages to the free and fair discussion of antagonistic doc-
               
               <br></br>trines connected with the great interests of Commerce, Agriculture,
               
               <br></br>Manufactures and the Currency.
               
               <br></br>☞Complete sets of the MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE, embracing eleven
               
               <br></br>semi-annual volumes, of about 600 large octavo pages each, bringing
               
               <br></br>it down to December, 1844, inclusive, may be obtained at the Pub-
               
               <br></br>lisher’s Office, 142 Fulton-street, New-York, at the subscription price.
               
               <br></br>☞Publishers of newspapers, in the United States, by giving this
               
               <br></br>advertisement two or three insertions, and remitting Two Dollars to
               
               <br></br>the Proprietor, will be entitled to the Magazine for one year.
               
               <br></br>Office of MERCHANTS’ MAGZINE, January 1st, 1845.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE AMERICAN REVIEW.
               
               <br></br>A WHIG JOURNAL OF POLITICS, LITERA-
               
               <br></br> TURE, ART AND SCIENCE. Edited by Geo. S. Colton, and pub-
               
               <br></br>lished monthly at 118 Nassau St. New York, and by Wiley &amp; Putnam 161
               
               <br></br>Broadway, and 6 Waterloo Place, Regent Street, London,—at Five Dollars
               
               <br></br>per anum in advance—Single Nos. fifty cents.
               
               <br></br>It is the aim of this Review—discarding all national and sectarian influence
               
               <br></br>—to harmonize in a kindlier acquaintanceship the different sections of the
               
               <br></br>country ; to set forth more clearly the inexhaustible resources of our territo-
               
               <br></br>ry ; to elevate the morals of the people: to withstand pusillanimity at
               borne,
               
               <br></br>and indignities abroad; to promote American science, and diffuse throughout
               
               <br></br>the land a higher order of taste in letters and the Arts. Though established
               
               <br></br>ostensibly on partisan grounds, the Review proposes to itself no mere party
               
               <br></br>triumph—but the moral, social and literary welfare of the commonwealth.
               
               <br></br>The following is from the origional Prospectus issued at Washington by
               
               <br></br>the Whig Members of the Twenty-Seventh Congress:
               
               <br></br>"Earnestly approving of the plan of such a national organ, long needed
               
               <br></br>and of manifest importance, the undersigned agree to contribute for its pa-
               
               <br></br>ges, from time to time, such communications as may be requisite to set forth,
               
               <br></br>and defend the doctrines held by the united Whig Party of the Union.—Geo
               
               <br></br>P. Marsh, D. D. Barnard, J. R. Ingersoll, E. Joy Morris, T. L. Clingman, J.
               
               <br></br>McPherson Berrien, Daniel Webster, Robert C. Winthrop, Thomas Buffer
               
               <br></br>King, Hamilton Fish, J. P. Kennedy, J. Collamer, John J. Hardin, Wm. S.
               
               <br></br>Archer, Rufus Choate, Alexander H. Stephens."
               
               <br></br>In addition to these, a number of writers have been enlisted for its various
               
               <br></br>other departments, so that every number, besides strong political articles,
               
               <br></br>will contain about 80 pages of Literary Miscellany in History, Biography,
               
               <br></br>Criticism, Fiction, Poetry, Statistics, Science and the Arts, three or four En-
               
               <br></br>gravings of the most finished—the likenesses of men eminent in the
               present
               
               <br></br>or past age, will be given in the course of the year. No pains will he spared,
               
               <br></br>ormeans left unemployed, to make it the first of American periodicals.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">JOHN DOUGLAS,
               
               <br></br>BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
               
               <br></br>No. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every de-
               
               <br></br>scription of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
               
               <br></br>with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, on terms which he feels con-
               
               <br></br>fident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
               
               <br></br>January 16, 1845.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">CHARLES PERABEAU, Professor of Music,
               
               <br></br>No. 9 Whitehall Street, New York.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
               
               <br></br>The first Premium awarded five years by the American Institute
               
               <br></br>for the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
               
               <br></br>GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
               
               <br></br>NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
               
               <br></br>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
               
               <br></br>tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               
               <br></br>in 10 lessons ot one hour each. Terms Reduced to TWO DOLLARS
               
               <br></br>AND A HALF.
               
               <br></br>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               
               <br></br>course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               
               <br></br>Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
               
               <br></br>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen 
               
               <br></br>and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
               
               <br></br>For sale " Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship," elegantly bound.
               
               <br></br>Price Five Dollars.
               
               <br></br>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27, 1844.
               
               <br></br>Goldsmith’s Gems of Pennmansiiip.—The Chirographic art is
               
               <br></br>much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
               
               <br></br>Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
               
               <br></br>volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
               
               <br></br>of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
               
               <br></br>From the New York Express.
               
               <br></br>Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship.—We have seen the original, as
               
               <br></br>executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
               
               <br></br>wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
               
               <br></br>to be " more potent than the sword," we never witnessed before.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">DISEASES OF THE TEETH. 
               
               <br></br>Washington, D. C., May, 1844.
               
               <br></br>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               
               <br></br>and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
               
               <br></br>The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
               
               <br></br>professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               
               <br></br>Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               
               <br></br>cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               
               <br></br>the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               
               <br></br>durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
               
               <br></br>Hon. J.W. M. Berrien, Geo. Hon. John B. Dawson,
               
               <br></br>La. Joshua Herrick, Me. John H. Lumpkin, Geo. 
               
               <br></br>James Irvin, Pa. J. Thompson, Miss. 
               
               <br></br>Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY
               
               <br></br>AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
               
               <br></br>Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
               
               <br></br>the Medal, four first Premiums, and two " Highest Honors," at the
               
               <br></br>Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
               
               <br></br>the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
               
               <br></br>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
               
               <br></br>at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
               
               <br></br>the score of economy.
               
               <br></br>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American In
               
               <br></br>struments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polish
               
               <br></br>ing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders receive
               
               <br></br>promptly attended to.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">To be Published every Saturday.</div>
         
         <p>THE BROADWAY JOURNAL will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         
         <p>ILLUSTRATIONS will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
            to make it worthy of patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers in the country ; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may "let loose their
            thoughts," will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>THE BROADWAY JOURNAL will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate.
            It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octavo form of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum—Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.</p>
         
         <p>A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.</p>
         
         <p>All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the EDITOR
            of THE BROADWAY JOURNAL--, and all letters on business to 
            JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street</div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>