<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450222</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">?THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, FEBRUARY 22, 1845. N  8.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body"> 
       
      
      <div>
         <div class="cit">
            <span class="quote">Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</span>
            
            <div class="bibl">
               <span class="person">Locke</span>
               
            </div>
            
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p1">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Sanitary Condition of the Laboring Population of New
               York
            </div>
            <div class="biblPage">113</div>
            
            <p>The Sanitary Condition of the Laboring Population of New
               York. With suggestions for its improvement. A discourse (with
               additions) delivered on the 30th December, 1844, at the Repository
               of the American Institute. By 
               <span class="person" id="jhgriscom">John H. Griscom</span>, M. D., Fellow
               of the College of Physicians and Surgeons; Physician of the New
               York Hospital; late Physician of the city and eastern dispensaries.
               New York; Harper &amp; Brothers, 82 Cliff street. 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>If any evidence were needed to prove the utter incapacity
               of the men into whose hands the government of this great
               city has fallen, to discharge the duties of their fearfully responsible station, the following extract from the preface of
               this important pamphlet would furnish it.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The subject matter of the following pages was originally addressed, in the form of a letter, to the Chief Magistrate of the city. Its
               preparation was undertaken, principally with a view to an exposition
               of the true principles which should regulate the action of public bodies,
               in matters relating to the health of cities, in a knowledge of, or concern for, which, recent events had shown our own munic pal legislature
               to be somewhat deficient. Appreciating fully the importance of its
               facts and suggestions, the Mayor transmitted the communication to a
               co-ordinate branch of the City Government, recommending it to their
               serious attention. After several weeks' deliberation upon it, the committee to whom it was referred arrived at the conclusion, embodied
               in the following language quoted from their report: 'Your committee do
               not profess to be judges of the subject, or in other words, they do
               not think it proper at this time, to go into such a measure,' and they
               recommended that the paper be returned to its author."
            </p>
            
            <p>We do not intend to cast any peculiar blame on the Native
               American party, as the politicians are called who have the
               welfare of our citizens in their hands at present, because we
               believe that either of the other two parties who strove for the
               management of our municipal affairs would have acted in
               the same manner. In truth, our politicians have yet to learn
               their alphabet in the art of government; but the misfortune
               of it is, that their instructors, the people, are wofully deficient in this kind of knowledge themselves. The happiness
               of the people seems never to be thought of in municipal legislatures. The exact objects aimed at by our Common Council it would be difficult toascertain. The spending of a good
               deal of money, and the best way of getting it from the people, seem to be the only definite notions of government that
               any of our boards of aldermen have had during the past
               twenty years. The present party in power regard the reading of some particular books in the district schools as the
               great point to be settled by them; and while the people are
               literally dying in consequence of inhaling the unhealthy miasma of filthy streets, the party that has the power to purge
               the atmosphere, and make the city a desirable residence,
               wastes all its energies in forcing a certain part of the children
               under their charge to take their first lessons in reading out of
               particular books which are repugnant to the feelings of their
               parents. It matters not a whit to a denizen of our streets
               what the city fathers have done or are doing, so long as the
               thoroughfares and byways are nearly impassable for filth.
               If it were an object to the citizens of this great metropolis, to
               tax themselves at the enormous rate which they were compelled to do for the sake of pure water, it is quite as much
               of an object to them to tax themselves for the sake of pure
               air; and we have no doubt that taxation would be submitted
               to as cheerfully in one case as in the other. Clean streets
               would keep many a family in New York that now is compelled to seek for a healthier home in Brooklyn, or Jersey
               City, or Staten Island. Gentlemen who have moved over
               upon Long Island, after living many years in the city,
               find that they make a very great saving in their doctor's
               bills.
            </p>
            
            <p>Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="jhgriscom">Griscom</span> says; "A highly respectable friend, a distinguished advocate, informed me lately, that some of his children had not had a day's illness during the two years they
               had been at school in the country, while the others, residing
               at home, though in a comparatively salubrious position in
               the city, cost him from twenty to thirty dollars each, for
               medicine and medical attendance."
            </p>
            
            <p>And yet in spite of this experience on the part of this distinguished advocate, he will continue to reside in the city,
               when he might by a very trifling sacrifice live in the country,
               and preserve his own and his children's health. We know
               several distinguished advocates whose families live ten or
               twelve miles from the City Hall, who contrive to be pretty
               constant in their attendance at the courts. There is very little more inconvenience, for a lawyer, in living on Staten
               Island, than in living in Chelsea or Union Square; while the
               increased vigor which they derive from daily crossing the
               water and breathing the pure air of the country, enables them
               to accomplish quite as much labor as the time lost in travelling to and from their office would do. It is an unaccountable delusion that keeps men confined in the city when business will allow of a residence in the country. Setting aside
               all the enjoyments of a rural home, the cheapness of it should
               induce a prudent man to prefer it. A tolerably respectable
               house in town costs from four hundred to eight hundred dollars per annum. Within ten or twelve miles of the Battery,
               a comfortable country house with an orchard, garden, and
               so forth, may be had at from one to two hundred dollars; an
               extra hundred dollars will cover all the expenses of travel,
               while the gain in health would be worth a sum which cannot be estimated in dollars and cents. Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="jhgriscom">Griscom</span> very
               clearly proves that a city residence cannot be healthy, even
               in the most favorable situations; what it must be then, in
               the least favorable, the following appalling statement will
               snow.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Almost every one can recall to mind, some proof of the effects of
               nauseous odors, of the inhalation of foul air, or of sleeping in a small
               confined apartment, upon his own health and feelings. These effects
               may have been only temporary, but they will serve to show that a prolonged continuance of them, must, in reason, produce permanently bad
               results upon the mental and corporeal powers. If the inhaled air (one
               great source of the life, health, and vigor of the animal structure) is
               deteriorated in quality, or diminished in quantity, below the standards
               necessary for a perfect decarbonization of the blood in the lungs, the
               blood necessarily becomes burdened with impurities, and fails to impart
               to the system the qualities demanded by nature for the due maintenance of health and strength. Every city resident who takes a stroll
               into the country can testify to the difference between the two atmospheres of the two situations;--the contrast of our out-door (to say
               nothing of the in-door) atmosphere, loaded with the animal and vegetable exhalations of our streets, yards, sinks, and cellars--and the air
               of the mountains, rivers, and grassy plains, needs no epicurean lungs
               to detect it. The superior corporeal activity, and the mental exhilaration imparted by it, are the prima facie proofs of its superiority. Compare the pale face of the city belle, or matron, after the long confinement of the winter and spring, with the same countenance in the fall,
               upon her return from a lew weeks' tour to the Springs and Niagara,
               and observe whether the return of the long absent rose upon the cheek
               
               is not accompanied with a greater elasticity of frame, and a happier
               and stronger tone of mind. 
            </p>
            
            <p>"Descend a few steps further, from the airy and well-lighted chamber and parlor, to the confined apartments of the pent-up court, and
               the damp, secluded cellar; draw a contrast between the gay inhabitant of the former, and the attenuated tenant of the latter, and we
               may then judge of the influences of the air which they respectively
               respire.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Observe, further, the vast difference in the development of frame,
               healthiness of countenance, and power of endurance, between the children of the farmer, and offspring of the city resident.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The following facts show, by figures, the sad condition in which a very large number
               of our people may be said barely to exist. 
            </p>
            
            <p>"As a great part of the population of these places are destitute of
               the means of paying for medical assistance, the duty of ministering to
               them in hours of sickness, falls upon the Dispensary Physicians. I
               find, upon examining the records of their labors, the reports of the
               three medical charities for the year ending March, 1844, there were
               prescribed for at the offices, and the homes of the poor, at the 
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Northern Dispensary, 13,317 Patients,Eastern "17,107 "New York " 23,858 "Total,
               54,282
            </div>
            
            <p>From this number a deduction is to be made of those vaccinated, being 4505. In visiting the sick poor at their homes, however, it happens very frequently that some are prescribed for whose names are
               neglected to be entered, so that it is perfectly safe to estimate the
               number of sick persons who received aid from these charities, to be
               over 50,000 in one year. In the corresponding year there were admitted into the Alms House Hospital 2332 patients, and into the City
               Hospital about 1000, exclusive of seamen, making a total of over
               53,000, without enumerating the sick poor attended by private charity."
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">[To be continued.]</div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Art of the Use of Color in Imitation in Painting, No.
            2
         </div>
         <div class="biblPage">114</div>
         <div class="head">THE ART OF THE USE OF COLOR IN IMITATION IN PAINTING.
            NO. II.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY 
            <span class="person">WILLIAM PAGE</span>.
         </div>
         
         <p>There are, as we have before stated, only three primitive
            colors in Nature or Art, and when any of these, or the compounds made from them, are brought into contact by being
            placed near or against each other, it is found that their apparent brilliancy is increased, or set off by the contrast, &amp;c.
            As for instance, Red, when seen by the side of Green, appears more Red by the contact,--Green being the other two
            primitives combined into one color. In like manner, Yellow
            is affected by Purple, and Blue by Orange; so that for simple
            contrast, we have but to take one primitive color, no matter
            which, and combine the other two, to make an opposition
            to the first, such as all times and nations have accepted as,
            agreeable to the eye; whereas, any two of the primitive
            colors, brought directly together, produces a discord, often
            very harsh and disagreeable in itself, but when skilfully
            used by the artist, becoming a great power in his hands, to
            drive together into a more intimate harmony the less discordant colors used.
         </p>
         <p>These primitives, when all mixed together, produce Brown.
            This is the universal color of Nature, and the grand harmonizer of those old masters, who understood colors the best;
            and which Brown, many moderns have observed as making
            up the greater proportion of the tone of the pictures of the
            best colorists, and the want of which, in modem schools, as
            I shall show, is but another proof of that deficiency of knowledge of colors in this day, that I have more than hinted at.
            This Brown color, as I said, being composed of Red,
            Yellow, and Blue, is capable of infinite variations, as it
            may pass from reddish-brown to blackish-brown, or yellowish-brown, at the will of the painter; so that, if he desires
            to make a Red more powerful by the opposition to it of his
            ground or surrounding color, he has but to make it (the
            ground) tend in its hue, towards greenish-brown; or if he
            would merge it in, or harmonize it with the surrounding
            ground-color, he makes the aforesaid ground of a reddishbrown, for these two opposite principles of harmony and contrast, comprehend all that this external application of color
            can do. For, when the painter would make any one of the
            primitive colors more striking to the eye, he surrounds it with
            a compound mostly composed of the other two, thereby forming the greatest opposition; and when he would harmonize
            or soften its effect to the eye, he uses least of these opposites.
            A few experiments made on white paper in water colors,
            with Red, Yellow, and Blue, will soon enable any artist to
            thread all the intricacies of the whole scale of color, and their
            possible oppositions and harmonies, as matter of mere contrast and harmony of external color. This, and what grows
            immediately out of this, is all the superficial knowledge of
            what is called the present English School of Painting, of
            which we Americans have taken to ourselves more than can
            do us good, unless we learn better where to bestow it, in its
            proper place, subject to higher laws, the laws of the imitation, or the reproduction of Nature's works.
         </p>
         <p>It is so notorious as to cause comment to be made the
            world over, wherever there are to be found modern, and
            good old Pictures, that the new are light, or white and feeble, or glaring in color, when compared with the old, or even
            good copies from them. The Royal Academy Exhibitions
            strike all observers in this, whether they be Englishmen or
            Americans, as being an assemblage of bright colors and
            white-wash, having no type any where in Nature, but only
            like itself, or other modern exhibitions of pictures, whether
            on the continent of Europe, or here in America, ever the same
            crude, feeble, gray, garish, unharmonised patches of gaudy
            colors and staring whiteness. Whereas, the better works of
            the old Painters, particularly those who can lay claim to any
            knowledge of color, are uniformly found to be low in tone,
            rich, brown and harmonious, the flesh (the test of color in Art)
            in that medium between light and dark, where only the greatest amount of color can be found, so that, the flesh in Titian's
            pictures, according to the best critics, is perhaps the lowest
            in its local color ever painted. This has been variously accounted for by different writers, as owing to the age of the
            pictures, time being supposed to have sunken them to their
            present low scale, &amp;c., &amp;c., all of which is insufficient to explain satisfactorily the fact, as there are even old pictures of
            Titian's time, or earlier, as light and crude as any modem
            English or French, when, if time would have done this thing
            for one, it would, being no respecter of persons, have done it
            for all. But there can be given a clear and satisfactory solution of this problem, that shall show to common sense that
            instead of its having been lime or accident that has made
            pictures which were originally bad, or indifferent, good, the
            painters who produced them really knew the Art which they
            professed and practised, more thoroughly than those who
            pretend to this knowledge in these days. Indeed, the old
            Painters had only Nature to study, from which they drew
            deep truths, and principles, such as could be safely trusted lo,
            and did universally produce results, that modems look upon
            as the offspring of a happier genius, than we are blessed
            withal; though it was the inevitable consequence of energetic
            mind, devoted to the analysis of those principles which alone
            can form a solid basis for true Art, and be learned from Nature, our true school-mistress.
         </p>
         <p>Thus much of color as we had treated in this article, before
            we made this digression, a child of twelve years of age may
            learn in a few months of teaching; and this has been spun
            out by various authors, into more volumes than would be necessary to tell of the whole rise and fall of empires, as well
            as Arts, yet this is all that modern Art has learned from the
            wonderful works of earlier Painters, together with what
            Science has done for us, and the increase of knowledge.
         </p>
         <p>In that medium degree, equally removed from the extremes
            of light and dark, which we mentioned in our first article,
            occur in nature all the most powerful colors, and no where
            else, for more light must weaken, or more dark must obscure
            them. Thence the necessity that that most difficult of substances to be imitated, human flesh, should be placed so low
            in the scale of light, as to allow all the purest color to pass
            through its plane, or the range of light which it occupies in the
            picture. This, any man may see the truth of, who has endeavored conscientiously to copy nature, or even looked attentively at such copy, when it is made.
         </p>
         <p>We now see a good reason why good old pictures are low
            in tone, not dark, or black, as too many of the specimens
            that reach our shores are, for if their lowness of tone is truly
            attained, it is so deceptive as to seem to reflect more light,
            than the lightest picture gives out.
         </p>
         <p>Such modern pictures as are an approach in lowness of
            tone to either nature or the works of true colorists, are liable
            to be what is termed leathery, and grow more and more so
            with every year after being painted; whereas the old have
            almost the tenderness of nature, which tenderness is the very
            opposite of the leathery quality; this latter quality increases
            by the darkening of the surface of the color, and is often increased by the changing of the oils. It is so common in the
            English pictures where there is an attempt to paint on a low
            key, that all kinds of vehicles are supposed to be better, as
            they seem to promise to overcome this difficulty, which they
            attribute to the use of Megilps, &amp;c. &amp;c. But it has a deeper origin. The truth is, that whenever colors are used, no
            matter how pure they be, in a picture, their tendency will be
            to change darker on the surface, thereby becoming leathery,
            for this is the inevitable quality of darker, and particularly
            the warmer colored browns, passed over lighter and left so.
            Now the opposite quality of the leathery is always produced
            by passing a lighter opaque color over a darker one. This,
            when known and well applied, will enable any one to rid his
            pictures of this quality, though the flesh be as low as that
            of Titian, and without which I believe that even he would
            have worked in vain to produce any approach to nature,
            such as he has made, this being the way of nature herself,
            and therefore the best.
         </p>
         <p>Now as human flesh occurs in this medium degree between
            light and dark, which, we have mentioned, is composed of
            the three primitive colors, in such subtle arrangement as to
            baffle all attempts of mere eye, and hand in monkey imitation, to render them intelligibly, and must yet be given before any thing can be done worthy of our opportunities, and
            what has been accomplished by others in less inteliigent
            times, let us try to follow the light which nature presents in
            the investigation of her works, and the analysis of her principles. For we cannot by studying the pictures of the old
            masters, as we can in nature, separate the layers of color
            used in their progress, nor learn the mode of their production, now when the hands that executed, and the minds that
            produced them have gone beyond the reach of our questioning, and left us nothing but the results of their labors, from
            which we barely learn that they alone, of all the professed
            disciples of Art, have understood the language even, in
            which Art must speak or remain tongue-tied, or at the best
            lisp, like a little child, but more like an aged man, that has
            reached his second childishness, and fills up the hour with
            bis empty babble.
         </p>
         <p>But I doubt not that we shall be able to show that there
            is yet a way to attain to what now makes them "the Divine
            in Art;" so conspicuous above us; and that by the simplest
            means, such as could not but have been suggested to reasoning minds, of sufficient self-dependence to throw aside all,
            that they had not themselves tested, as worthless, beginning
            anew in the true school of nature, as children who have the
            whole Art to learn, and not taking for granted any thing but
            the deductions of their own reason or experience.
            
         </p>
         <p>Now I propose to give the sketch of a process whereby a
            head may be painted, and though from the complicated nature of words, and particularly when used by one who has
            had other things than words to study, as in my case, I cannot hope to make it simple to the simple, though if it be
            well thought over, and applied with tolerable skill, will prove
            its truth in the success--at least showing its capacity for the
            grandest results. At all events, let no man condemn it until he can see a flaw in the reasoning, or has tested its truth
            or falseness, by an actual experiment--when, if he cannot
            produce a better picture by it, I fear not to declare that he
            cannot produce a good one at all.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Why Are Not the Sciences Better Understood?</div>
         <div class="biblPage">115</div>
         
         <div class="head">WHY ARE NOT THE SCIENCES BETTER UNDERSTOOD?</div>
         
         <p>Under this head it is proposed to make a simple inquiry,
            which doubtless thousands can answer with quite as little
            trouble, as it is to propound the question. But though thousands can give a ready answer to the inquiry, yet there are
            millions who cannot, and therefore, it is to them that the
            question may more properly be put--"why the Sciences are
            not better understood?" That it is a lamentable fact, that
            the phenomena of many of the simple and most practical
            things of life are not understood, no one will deny--why this
            is the case is the question. It cannot be that there is not
            sufficient interest in these phenomena; because it is well
            known that the understanding of the laws which explain
            these things are more conducive to the happiness of mankind
            than all other knowledge put together. In fact, civilization
            could not progress without it, and though thousands and
            thousands are applying the laws every day, yet they do
            not know how they do it. Every woman and child is applying some one of the laws for their comfort every day of their
            lives, yet, how few are they of this great mass of persons,
            even if the adults be taken, that can explain the reason why
            they are warmer in a woollen blanket than in a cotton one of
            equal weight?--or why a man may go into an oven, dressed
            in a woollen cloak, and remain there long enough to broil a
            beef steak, without being injured, while in any other garment he would be roasted alive--or why a white hat is cooler than a black one--or why a rough stove, gives off more
            heat than a polished one--or a black stove more than a tin
            one. Now, that these are but few of the simple questions of
            well-known facts of every day occurrence, cannot be doubted;
            but, as simple as they are, and as easily as they could be answered by any child, if once directed to the subject, there
            are thousands who never for a moment give their attention
            to the subject. But these are not the only illustrations, because there are the several branches of science, equally as
            applicable to phenomena around us.
         </p>
         
         <p>The subject of heat however is applied to such practical
            purposes, that it is singular that it should not be more understood--and particularly the laws which would explain many
            of the phenomena of heat, experienced almost every minute
            in the day. The apparent cold of iron, on taking hold of it,
            or heat of wood, is so well known, that it would be superfluous to mention it; were it not equally as apparent that a
            great majority of persons do not know why it is so. They
            know that it is so, because it gives them a painful sensation
            on a frosty morning to pick up an iron bar, while a piece of
            wood that has lain beside it, and is of the same temperature, is much warmer to handle. The simple fact of wrapping up a piece of ice in a woollen blanket to preserve it, is
            known to every porter in the country, yet how few can tell
            
            why it is that the blanket which is warmest in winter, will
            not melt ice in the summer,--or why a black or blue blanket
            would melt the ice when a white one would preserve it.
         </p>
         
         <p>These things are of so common an occurrence, that it
            would be natural to suppose every person would know
            them; yet it is far from being the case. This want of
            knowledge on these every day matters does not speak much
            for the information of those who are not in possession of it.
            The simple operation of a pump, which every boy has worked at many a time, is apparently one of the least understood. A majority of the young men, who are exceedingly well dressed, would be apt to say, "that a pump
            sucks the water up from the well"--if asked for an explanation of the operation of pumping--or if a similar enquiry
            were to be made to a young man of considerable accomplishments in a ball room, but engaged in the liquor
            trade, why it is that the syphon he uses to take liquors
            from a cask performs the operation, he would be very likely
            to say by suction, which certainly is one of the vulgar ways
            of exhausting a pipe of liquor, but nevertheless is far from
            being the true cause for that simple operation.
         </p>
         
         <p>All have more or less used the "sucker," as it is usually
            termed by boys, in raising up bricks or other smooth substances, by means of a piece of wet leather patted down on
            it. This simple operation is as equally one of the known
            laws of pneumatics as that of the atmospheric rail-road;
            and the laws which govern one would explain that of the
            other.
         </p>
         
         <p>The pressure of fifteen pounds to the square inch of the
            atmosphere, may easily be conceived to be an extraordinary
            amount of force to be applied. The pressure on the human
            body to a person not acquainted with the laws of pneumatics,
            seems to be incredible. That there should be a pressure of
            about fifteen tons on the human body, makes a person of considerable good sense look a little credulous at the idea of his
            having to shoulder such a load as that every day; and he
            would very soon begin to imagine that the burdens of this
            life were great indeed. But if in addition to this, he were
            told that on a rainy day, when the "atmosphere was so heavy
            and thick," that two or three tons of atmospheric pressure
            were taken off his shoulders, he would he very likely to say,
            "Come--come, Mr. Philosopher, that is putting it on, and
            taking it off rather too thick. What! on a rainy day the atmosphere lighter than on a bright sun-shining day? See
            here, sir, can you tell how many beans five blue beans make,
            if shook up in a bag?" Now as ridiculous as all this appears, it nevertheless is true.
         </p>
         
         <p>Many young persons have this impression on their mind,
            and unfortunately have such a particular desire to be accomplished gentlemen, to be familiar with the name of Signora
            Pico, and others of the opera--or the last new step in the
            Polka dance, and other amusements of the sort, that they
            would not know these simple every day things, because they
            are not fashionable.
         </p>
         
         <p>It would be idle to attempt to illustrate this subject as
            fully as it would permit, as it would occupy too much space.
            And the cases that have been cited are only such as are of
            such simple use, that it is much to be wondered at, that
            they cannot be as thoroughly explained by any young man,
            as can the tune of the last new opera, the steps in a quadrille, or the latest cut of the Imperial or Moustache of some
            recently imported German or French Count. If this were
            the case, it would be a source of great credit to the young
            men generally; but unfortunately it cannot be done.
         </p>
         
         <p>The love of some of the frivolities of the day, have more
            attractions than the useful sciences; whether it is that the
            name of science conveys to the mind of the young man the
            idea of something very abstruse, requiring minds like those of
            Bacon, Galileo, Newton and Franklin, to explore their mysteries, it is difficult to say; but it is very natural to suppose
            that something of this kind must deter them from the enquiry, or else they would make a venture to read such works as
            
            <span class="person" id="dbrewster">Brewster</span>'s Optics, 
            <span class="person" id="narnott">Arnott</span>'s Physics, and hundreds of other
            volumes, which would not only be more valuable to them
            than most reading that they could undertake, but would be
            equally as pleasing; for it is an absurdity to suppose that
            science has no pleasures, because all the phenomena in nature can be explained by her laws; and how much more
            gratifying it must be to any person to be able to explain the
            causes of these phenomena. Most truly, the satisfaction of
            being able to set a person right, who has stumbled into
            the error that ice is formed at the bottom of the river, and
            then rises up to the surface to be dovetailed together, would
            be more pleasing, as well as more to the credit of the person,
            than being able to correct a false step at a cotillion.
         </p>
         
         <p>This error is not an imaginary case, but one of real occurence, from a person who possesses as much good sense as
            the majority of young men, and occupies as respectable a position. But it is a case, and not unlike thousands to be met
            with every day, manifesting as much ignorance upon practicable subjects as to their laws as this. Not knowing these
            things, does not presuppose want of capacity to understand
            them; but a want of proper appreciation for their acquisition. In the cases mentioned there has been no attempt to
            select such as it is required that a person should be able to
            answer, because if that were the case he could easily learn
            by heart the usual modes of explaining their phenomena;
            but it has been to direct the attention to palpable cases of
            ignorance, not only of these things, but the application of the
            laws governing them. They should be known. The laws
            of mechanism, heat, hydraulics, hydrostatics and pneumatics,
            as well as of optics, and in fact all phenomena of nature, should be as well understood ns that of any species of
            learning knowu. Every person can appreciate this knowledge. There is a tangible form to it, by which, through
            life, it can be made available in more ways than one to promote happiness. While the same may not be said of the
            advantages from reading the best of 
            <span class="person" id="wscott">Scott</span>'s, or other novels
            and romances that can be found. They may afford some
            pleasure to excite the mind, and leave pleasing recollections
            of such characters as Ivanhoe and Rebecca; but they never
            can give as much pleasure as would be derived from the
            knowledge of these laws. Besides the pleasure of being able
            to explain these phenomena, it has the great advantage of
            leading to many useful inventions. On the subject of heat
            alone, there is field enough yet to exhaust the mind of some
            halt a dozen Davy's, in applying it to the most advantage for
            manufacturing purposes, and that of warming houses. For
            it is a fact that there is double the quantity of fuel used in
            houses to warm them, that is required, owing to the simple
            circumstance of not knowing how to use it. Fuel generally
            is but half consumed, and even of that which is consumed, a
            great portion of it is lost, owing to the bad arrangement of
            radiation. Enquiries into this matter may be made by any
            one--and though a Davy or Farraday might be able to discover the mode of economising fuel sooner than a mere superficial reader of the subject, yet it does not follow that
            they may not turn the knowledge to good account, with a
            possibility of making an improvement on the mode of using
            fuel to generate steam, or for warming houses. In chemistry the application of its principles are so universal, that
            nothing is touched but is governed by its laws. The bread
            
            that is partaken of at each meal, has to be made by as fixed
            laws of chemistry, as that of preparing gases--or the boiling
            of potatoes by equally as well known chemical laws; yet of
            the millions who eat of the bread and potatoes, if they
            were told that there was a science in boiling the potatoes,
            they would be likely to think it rather too "small potatoe"
            a science, for them to condescend to learn its laws. It would
            not be genteel to know how a potatoe was boiled, or why it
            changed from a nasty hard vegetable, to a delicate bread-like
            substance, by simply putting it into boiling water. But
            though it might not be genteel, it would certainly be very
            creditable, and perhaps detract none the less from any person's claims to gentility to be in possession of such an amount
            of knowledge. In fact, the elementary principles of physics
            should be more thoroughly studied in the schools, and forced
            upon the mind of the child, that he may, on coming to maturity, feel more interest in the subject. As it is now, most
            young men have no inclination that way. The name of science has too much of the abstruse about it to attract the attention; and the extravagant notions of gentility, which the
            great mass of the young men in the city have, of patronizing
            the operas and Pinteux--and the young and old and junior
            bachelor's balls, or getting a red flannel shirt on to run after
            an engine or hose cart, have become a serious evil to them.
            Their love of these amusements, without a proper cultivation
            of the mind, has had the tendency to lower very much the
            estimated intelligence among them; though in dress, and
            general appearance, they betray all the accomplishments of
            very learned gentlemen, and it is not until you put to them
            any of the simple questions of natural philosophy that it is
            discovered they are not what they appear to be, that all
            is not gold that glitters--and that a tailor has made the more
            pleasing part of them.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">C. L. BARRITT.</span>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Great Tower of Tarudant</div>
         <div class="biblPage">117</div>
         
         <div class="head">THE GREAT TOWER OF TARUDANT.</div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY 
            <span class="person">ROBERT OLIVER</span>.
         </div>
         
         <p>So Arphaxad proceeded with a step that constantly grew bolder and more vigorous. He
            removed the most faithful officers of the king, and supplied their places by
            creatures of his own--evil spirits whom his magic had clothed with the form and
            flesh of humanity. He issued all orders, heard all complaints, judged all causes, and
            in fine assumed all the royal functions, which he exercised without deigning even to
            consult the king. Upon the latter, indeed, he at length dared to lay a spell,
            under the influence of which the monarch shut himself up in the interior of his
            palace, and spent his whole time in studying books of magic and in practising incantations, the mode of performing which, the Egyptian had pretended to
            teach him; but in these he never could succeed, for the spell of the crafty magician
            so besotted his brain that he understood little of what he read, and remembered not
            one half of the purposely obscure and complicated instructions he had
            received.
         </p>
         
         <p>But though reduced to this pitiable state, Abdallah yet loved, and had faith in the
            Egyptian, for so strongly was he charmed, that he did not perceive his own condition,
            but still believed himself a king, and thought that bis industrious vizier merely relieved him of the toils and cares of government, that he
            might have leisure for loftier and more agreeable pursuits. Neither were the people
            dissatisfied, for though they now never saw their king, they doubted not that his
            retirement was owing to his intense devotion to the affairs of the kingdom; and
            so long as those were well administered, they cared little what passed within the
            palace.
         </p>
         
         <p>Emboldened by impunity, Arphaxad allowed his ambition full play. He proclaimed his
            intention of building in the very centre of the city of Tarudant, a tower that should exceed in size and magnificence all that the world had ever seen. And the people shouted and applauded the undertaking, as one that would
            confer great glory on the nation. 
            Nor was their approbation lessened, when they were called upon to labor at the
            work, and to contribute of their gold and silver and precious stones towards its
            embellishment; lor the Egyptian persuaded them that inconceivable benefits would
            flow from its erection. So, cheerfully they commenced the building, not dismayed,
            though a tenth part and that the fairest of their city was demolished to make room
            for the foundation. Cheerfully they labored, willingly they contributed of their wealth, and rapidly rose the tower. Story after story was added,
            each more magnificent than the other, until at length so great a height was reached, that the workmen on the top could barely be discerned from the
            ground.
         </p>
         
         <p>The work went briskly on. Multitudes of supernaturally stout and active genies toiled side by side with human laborers, and architects of more than
            mortal craft guided the progress of the structure. Materials became scarce, and first
            the great wall of Tarudant, and then its chief houses and those of the
            provincial cities were thrown down to support them, and finally the royal palace
            itself was demolished, with the exception of the single apartment to which the king
            had of late confined himself.'
         </p>
         
         <p>Still the people were called upon, and still the people came to labor. More and more of their riches was demanded, and yet it was freely given. Higher,
            higher rose the tower, piercing far above the clouds, and seeming to enter the very heavens. The supply of stones was not yet sufficient. The public works which had conferred such prosperity upon Tarudant, the canals, roads, bridges, and aqueducts were despoiled, and their granite and
            marble added to the mighty edifice.
         </p>
         
         <p>At length it was finished, and wonderful indeed was the work. Prodigious in breadth
            as well as height, superb with many-hued marbles, with the finest porphyry, the most transparent alabaster, glowing with gold and gems, and brilliant
            with silver, brass, and ivory. Immediately on its completion, Arphaxad dismissed
            the human laborers, and accompanied only by his attendant genies, of whom he had
            gathered an innumerable host, entered the tower and shut himself up therein.
         </p>
         
         <p>And now the people, having nearly spent their strength, and entirely exhausted their
            treasure in the building of this tower, looked up at it with pride and exultation,
            and waited for the blessings that the Egyptian had promised should flow from it. They waited in vain. Nothing came, nothing descended. Still they waited,
            still in vain. They began to murmur, for they lacked bread, having neglected to till
            their lands while working for the magician, and having parted with every thing
            wherewith they might have bought bread in other countries. Their murmurs swelled to
            complaints and reproaches, not unmingled with curses. They called loudly upon
            the Egyptian, who answered not, for he was busied with his incantations in the highest story of the tower, where their mightiest shouts were heard only as the gentlest whispering of the west wind. Maddened to desperation,
            they at length assaulted the building, each man catching up a stone and hurling
            it against the great brazen gates. They flew open, and the multitude rushed in. When
            a fifth part had entered, the gates closed again with a tremulous roar, crushing
            many who were pressing for admittance.
         </p>
         
         <p>The multitude found themselves in a vast circular hall, the floor of which was of
            rough rocks, and the lofty sides cased with broad plates of gold, highly burnished, but without figure or inscription. The ceiling of sculptured ivory, at
            a height beyond the reach of a strongly shot arrow, rested on columns of green
            marble, around the upper part of whose shafts immense serpents were lazily twining,
            their hideous heads swaying to and fro, up and down, and uttering occasionally thick hisses, accompanied by a gush of breath so pestiferous
            that no man could breathe it a moment and live. The eyes of these serpents glared
            with a vigilant ferocity, though the rest of their bodies seemed immersed in languid
            indolence, and from those dreadful orbs shone forth the only light which
            illumined the hall, a light so dim and strange, that when the people first entered,
            they could see nothing but their own palpitating forms.
         </p>
         
         <p>Stupidly they stared upwards, saying not a word, for the poisonous fumes from above tainted even the air below, producing a drowsy feeling in those who
            inhaled it. At length, some bolder or more impatient than the rest broke the silence,
            shouting, "Come, here is gold, let us take it and buy bread!"
         </p>
         
         <p>And they all rushed to the sides of the hall and attempted to tear off the golden
            plates; but they could not, for the 
            smooth surface afforded nothing to take hold of, and besides their strength was
            weakened by hunger and benumbed by the foul vapors they were breathing. They soon
            desisted, and sought to quit the tower, but there was no outlet save the brazen
            gates, and those defied their utmost efforts. In despair they flung themselves upon the rocky floor and remained heavily slumbering until midnight, when
            they were roused by the intolerable thirst produced by the hot and stifling air.
            They looked up, but there was no light. The serpents were asleep, and their eyes
            shot forth no gleams. Then amid the thick darkness, all with one voice gasped forth, "Water, water, give us water or we die!"
         </p>
         
         <p>Suddenly laughter sounded through the tower, scornful, fiendish laughter, and then
            again all was still. The serpents awoke, and for a moment swung their heads about uncertainly, then fixed them pointing downwards, and opening wide
            their mouths, hissed forth floods of waters strong and many, athwart whose
            rushing foam, danced with fearful glee the lurid light of their infernal eyes.
            Frantically the multitude drank, but not with pleasure, for the water was bitter and
            of a sickish warmth. It continued flowing down upon them, and rising, until it
            reached their knees, then their waists, and presently their armpits. They struggled, shrieked, and begged for mercy, but the water came pouring down, until
            it was twenty cubits deep, where the last strong swimmer sunk exhausted, and
            again horrible laughter pealed throngh the tower, mingled with the triumphant hissing
            of the serpents and the gentle dashing of the calming waters.
         </p>
         
         <p>Meantime the people without the tower finding that they could not again force open
            the brazen gates, retired to a little hill some way off and held a consultation. It suddenly occurred to them that they yet had a king, who once was good,
            and wise and brave, and they were astonished that they had even for a moment
            forgotten him. Great indeed must have been the delusion which could blot out all remembrance of the kind and gallant Abdallah. The multitude resolved immediately to seek his protection from the evils in which they
            had been involved by their reliance upon the false Egyptian. "To the king! To the
            king!" they shouted-- "he will deliver us--he will destroy the magician!"
         </p>
         
         <p>In a body therefore they hurried to the royal palace, and there being now no guards or officers of state to prevent intrusion, they reached without
            difficulty the presence of the king. They found the poor monarch in a dismantled,
            dirty apartment, the sole remnant of his superb ancestral palace. He was
            reclining on a couch of ivory, adorned with brazen figures, which had once been
            gilded so skilfuly as not to be distinguishable from pure gold. But these were now
            rusted over with dingy verdigris, while the ivory itself was so broken and decayed, that had it not been patched here and there with pieces of bone it
            would not have upheld the body of the king. Little, however, was required to uphold
            that body. So emaciated, so woe-begone was it, that emirs who for years had waited on the royal person, scarcely recognized their sovereign. His eyes were sunken in his head, his beard was enormously long and matted
            together, and his whole appearance squalid with the accumulated dust and filth of
            years. He was wrapped in a loose black robe fantastically striped with scarlet and purple, but so tattered and dirty that its texture and hues
            were scarcely discernible. Before him on the couch lay a roll of parchment inscribed
            with mystic characters, on which his eyes were bent with an expression of painful anxiety. At his side was an earthen vessel containing a quantity of
            dried fish, stale and mouldy, and at the foot of the couch a fountain of muddy water
            lazily weltered forth from between the jaws of a sculptured leopard.
         </p>
         
         <p>Abdallah did not seem conscious of the approach of his subjects, but continued
            steadfastly gazing on the magical book. They stood for a time contemplating him,
            unable to speak, for their hearts were very full. At length an old vizier,
            mastering his tears and sobs, with trembling voice exclaimed--
         </p>
         
         <p>"Look up, O king, look up and behold thy faithful people who have come to thee in
            their great distress--have come to thee for refuge and relief."
         </p>
         
         <p>The king Feebly raising his head, with difficulty opened his mouth and replied:--"Why do ye trouble me in my studies? Seek Arphaxad the Egyptian. He will do
            what ye require." And sinking back upon his couch with a painful sigh, he again
            fixed his bleared eyes upon the parchment roll.
         </p>
         
         <p>But the people groaned, and cried, "Alas, O King! It is from this accursed magician
            that
            all our miseries flow."
         </p>
         
         <p>Again Abdallah looked up, and with a sadly bewildered expression
            demanded, "Why, what hath he done? Governs he not well and wisely?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"Come forth, and see with thine own eyes, O king!"</p>
         
         <p>They lifted the monarch to his feet, and would have led him out, but he was so
            feeble that he could not stand. They held him up tenderly, and one of the emirs
            turning to the people, said, "Run, some of you, and fetch water from the
            fountain that is beside the tomb of the Santon Sidi Edris --it hath virtue to heal the
            king's mind and give his body strength."
         </p>
         
         <p>Swift young men started away as he spoke, and quickly came back with a jar full of
            water from the holy fountain. The emirs took it and washed the king, and trimmed his
            beard, and put upon him new garments of cloth of gold in place of the filthy
            black robe striped with scarlet and purple. They gave him also of the water to drink
            and fed him with bread and figs, so that he seemed like a new man, being w onderfully refreshed. The spell that bound him so long lost its power. He
            was restored to his right mind and to his wonted health; strength returned to his
            limbs, fire to his eyes, color to his cheeks. He stood among his emirs again like
            their king, and all the people shouted when they looked upon his face, for hope,
            long absent, began to swell their shrunken hearts.
         </p>
         
         <p>Then a horse was brought to the king, a young horse, strong and full of fire, on
            which he mounted and was led to a neighboring hill, whence he could view the
            condition of bis capital. When he beheld its desolation he was struck with such
            amazement that he could not speak. But at length finding his voice, he demanded, "Who
            hath done this? What enemy hath ravaged my city?" All the people answered, "Arphaxad the Egyptian. He hath done this." "Where is he?" asked the king.
            "Behold!" cried they, pointing to the tower.
         </p>
         
         <p>Abdallah looked, and his amazement was greater than before. Putting
            spurs to his horse he rode forwards, followed by all the people, until he came in
            front of the great brazen gates of the tower, when he stopped and gazed upon the
            wondrous structure. Deep stillness pervaded the edifice; there was no sign of
            life or habitation about it, except that from the upper part there was gushing forth
            on every side a thick black smoke which rose in slow whirls till they met above
            the tower's top, when they mingled in one vast spiral column that went steadily up
            till it seemed to reach the sky. There it spread into a dense cloud, that darkened the heavens and kept the blessed sunlight from ever shining on the
            godless fabric. Birds of gigantic size and monstrous shape, some with twenty
            wings and some with seven heads, but all with plumage of the brightest green, were
            flying about the wreathing column, now and then dashing into the smoke and
            soaring swiftly up into the cloud, or with their vast wings partly folded suffering themselves to sink down till they almost touched the tower,
            But these strange creatures made no sound, and seemed to be idly enjoying the smoke,
            rather than seeking after prey.
         </p>
         
         <p>Presently the king commanded the trumpets to be sounded, and with a loud voice
            called upon Arphaxad to throw open the gates and come forth. Thrice he repeated this
            summons, and at the third time there was a peal as of thunder far up in the air.
            The people huddled-together and looked eagerly to see what would follow. A door flew
            open in the middle of the tower, high above their heads, and disclosed the huge
            form of the Egyptian sheathed in armor of brass set with emeralds. His face
            could be seen only at moments, because of the smoke that swept in eddies round his
            head; but its expression was of wrath and disdain.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Who is it that makes this turmoil at my gates?" he de- manded in a voice that sounded
            like an echo of the thunder.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Who is it, audacious wretch? It is the king thy master. Come down, open these
            gates, and humbly throw thyself at his feet, if thou wouldst avoid the punishment of thy monstrous guilt."
         </p>
         
         <p>The magician laughed scornfully. "I know not of whom you speak. I have no king, I
            acknowledge no master. I had forgotten the very existence of the miserable mortal who
            styles himself such. But if you wish the gates opened, your wish shall be
            granted."
         </p>
         
         <p>So speaking, he disappeared within the tower, whose great gates suddenly flew open
            and let forth a flood of black and stinking water, bearing along in its impetuous
            flow the corpses of those who had perished in the circular hall. So mighty and
            swift was the flood that it swept away and
            drowned many of the people, and nothing but the speed of his horse saved the
            king. The good steed bore him to a hill not far off, where he stopped and looked back
            at the terrible tower. But there was no time for delay; as the waters subsided a host of hideous black genies sallied forth, chasing and slaying
            the frightened multitude. A squadron of them mounted on pale horses and headed by Arphaxad himself pursued the king, who fled eastwardly towards Mount
            Atlas. On the edge of the desert he was overtaken, and the genies were about to
            seize him, when a mighty blast of wind swept down from the mountains, and passing by
            the monarch struck his pursuers with such force that they were all thrown upon
            the ground, from which none rose alive, except their leader the magician, who
            bruised and astonished fled fearfully back to his tower.
         </p>
         
         <p>Returning thanks to Allah for this timely interposition, which by showing that he
            was under divine interposition, had wonderfully raised his spirits from the consternation produced by the dreadful scenes he had witnessed, Abdallah
            held on his way across the desert, though quite uncertain whither he should go, or what he should expect. But something whispered to his soul that
            eastward, in Mount Atlas, and there only, he would find the means to redeem his kingdom and overthrow its proud oppressor.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">(To be Continued.)</div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">American Prose Writers, No. 5, Henry T. Tuckerman</div>
         <div class="biblPage">119</div>
         
         <div class="head">AMERICAN PROSE WRITERS. 
            NO. V. 
            HENRY T. TUCKERMAN.
         </div>
         
         <p>As a descriptive limner and critical essayist, the fidelity and elegance of Mr.
            
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span>'s pen, have procured for him a large class of admirers, even among those
            upon whom his vigorous independence of thought is more or less thrown away. His
            bold paper on 
            <span class="person" id="pbshelley">Shelley</span>, proved, by the attention it excited, that he possessed far
            stronger characteristics of mind, than were to be found in the Elia-like felicity of
            style which constituted his first claim to popularity. Unlike 
            <span class="person" id="wirving">Washington Irving</span>,
            who, by his melodious combinations of words, frequently satisfies the reader for exceeding diffuseness of ideas, Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span>'s quiet beauty of
            language, and delicate imagery, often so delight the mind, that we forget for
            the moment, the noble thoughts which they garbed; and it is not until we have
            gratified our sense of harmony, that we fully discern the vigorous ideas which have
            been thus conveyed to the intellect. Just as in listening to the music of
            Bellini, we are first struck with its exceeding tenderness, and not until we have
            bathed our very souls in sweetness, do we realize its mighty suggestiveness.
         </p>
         
         <p>As an essayist, Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span> is almost without a rival. His tales, considered merely as tales, are, we think, less successful. They abound in graphic
            description and in beautiful language, but they are only sketches. Actions, events,
            the commonplace-ism of outward life, which make up so much of the vraisemblance
            of a fate, are not his forte. Opinion, sentiment, the great truths of spirit-life,
            and their application to the daily wants of humanity,--these are the subjects
            around which his mind and heart find their true occupations. No one looks with
            gentler eye upon his kind; in no heart is the fountain of sympathy more generous in
            its outpourings. But he seeks to do good to man, not by beguiling him from
            himself with some well-constructed fiction, but rather by bringing him to the
            well-spring of truth, that he may drink and live.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Isabel of Sicily" was evidently designed to embody the results of the author's
            observations during a residence upon that beautiful island. To avoid the egotism
            usually found in a traveller's journal, Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span> has woven a light web of
            romance, and upon that embroiders his facts, thus adopting a precisely opposite
            course from that of most writers. To its somewhat injudicious title, may be attributed its want of immediate popularity in this country, while
            running through two editions in England. They who disdain to suffer their
            intellect to dally with any thing but truth, are deterred from looking into a
            work bearing so fanciful a name, while the inveterate devourer of fiction is lamentably disappointed, because the anticipated novel is not a story of
            Italian passion. Yet no one can look into the book a second time, without being struck with the acuteness, the clearness of perception, and the
            high-toned philosophy of its accomplished author.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>The "Italian Sketch-book" is free from this trifling defect of mere mechanical form, and at an earlier period of our literary history, when there were more readers and fewer writers, would have instantly secured to its author an
            enviable reputation. We say fewer writers, not because Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tucker</span>man has been eclipsed among the many; but simply because writing has now become a
            trade, and, like all other trades, it is so overstocked, that trickery of all sorts
            is necessary to secure a clique of readers for each aspirant after fame, while
            the true author, disdaining the petty arts of the mere popularity-seekers, is often unheard amid the din of noisy declaimers.
         </p>
         
         <p>But, as we said before, it is as the essayist, and especially the critical essayist,
            that Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span> occupies his true position.
         </p>
         
         <p>"We confess a partiality for the essay. In the literature of our vernacular tongue
            it shines conspicuous, and it is environed with the most pleasing associations. The
            essay is to prose literature, what the sonnet is to poetry; and, as the narrow limits of the latter have enclosed some of the most beautiful poetic imagery, and finished expressions of sentiment, within the compass of versified
            writing, so, many of the most chaste specimens of elegant periods, and of animated
            and embellished prose, exist in the form of essays. * * * A volume of essays subserves the purpose of a set of cabinet pictures, or a portfolio of miniature drawings; they are the multum in parvo of literature; and,
            perused, as they generally are, in moments of respite from ordinary occupation,
            turned to on the spur of mental appetite, they not unfrequently prove more efficient
            than belles-lettres allurements of greater pretension."
         </p>
         
         <p>Such are Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span>'s remarks upon the essay in his beautiful paper on the
            "Characteristics of 
            <span class="person" id="clamb">Lamb</span>." He has done much towards proving his own assertions, and illustrating his own apt comparison, for not only has he written the
            most finished essays, but his hand has also framed the most Shakesperian sonnets
            ever penned on this side of the great waters. His "Rambles and Reviews" is a book to
            be left lying on one's table,--to be taken up in those moods of the mind, when,
            wearied with the petty details of common-place outer life, we seek refreshment at the
            well-spring of poetic truth. The sketches of Italian life and scenery are at once
            graphic and suggestive. They are like Claude Lorraine pictures, not only truthfully drawn and colored, but also possessing that
            indescribable charm of atmosphere, which seems to transport one instantly to the very
            scene depicted.
         </p>
         
         <p>Yet, if we were called on to rescue any one portion of Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span>'s prose works from destruction, we should certainly lay hold of his "Thoughts on the
            Poets." Never did the true spirit of poetry find a nobler exponent. If any one
            doubts this, let him only read the essay on 
            <span class="person" id="ogoldsmith">Goldsmith</span>, full of a fine discriminating sense of the truthfulness and simplicity which made "poor
            
            <span class="person" id="ogoldsmith">Goldsmith</span>" so winning as a friend, so delightful as a writer; then let him turn to
            the criticism on 
            <span class="person" id="apope">Pope</span>, contained in the same volume. Compare the appreciating warmth with which the critic speaks of the poet, who
         </p>
         
         <p>"Cherished throughout his whole life an earnest faith in one better nature; who
            realized the universal beauty and power of Love; who rejoiced in the exercise of all
            those tender and noble sentiments which are so much more honorable to man than the
            highest triumphs of mind--
         </p>
         <p>Compare this with his clear and critical perception of 
            <span class="person" id="apope">Pope</span>,
            
         </p>
         
         <p>"The bright enamel of whose rhymes is like a frozen lake, over which we glide like a skater before the wind, surrounded by a glittering landscape of
            snow."
         </p>
         
         <p>The hallowed mystery of a gentle mind, diseased beyond all leech-craft,--the
            thrilling picture of a soul full of love and truth, o'ertasking its powers until it
            found only darkness in the infinite,--the melancholy image of a spirit framed but
            to fine issues, yet yielding its tones to the rude touch of appetite, were never more delicately and powerfully depicted than in Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span>'s
            criticisms on 
            <span class="person" id="wcowper">Cowper</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="pbshelley">Shelley</span>, and 
            <span class="person" id="rburns">Burns</span>. Each of those gifted minds could say
         </p>
         
         <p>"My spirit's bark Is driven Far from the shore, far from the trembling throng
            Whose sails were never to the tempest given
         </p>
         
         <p>but few, even of their most ardent admirers, could have afforded so
            discriminating and philosophic an extenuation of the errors which the brightness of
            their fame made visible to the world.
         </p>
         
         <p>Whether he portrays characters like these, or points us to the more sparkling fancy
            of 
            <span class="person" id="tmoore">Moore</span>, uttering itself in song,-the chivalric muse of 
            <span class="person" id="tcampbell">Campbell</span>, breathing its
            trumpet-voiced appeal in measured, but heart-thrilling tones,--the fierce and
            passionate spirit of 
            <span class="person" id="valfieri">Alfieri</span> proclaiming its powerful will in Tuscan language
            but in Runic verse, he ever hears the low breathed moaning of that oracle which dwells in the sanctuary of the poet's heart. Himself a true poet, in the
            highest and loftiest sense of the term, he knows how to interpret the dark
            sayings of humanity.
         </p>
         
         <p>Should it be supposed that the interest of these essays may depend much upon the associations connected with their subject, and that therefore they
            afford no fair test of Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span>'s powers, we would refer to his "
            Lyrical Poetry," and his "Thoughts on Music," as evidences of his poetic taste
            and sensibility, while, for vigor of thought, elegance of diction,
            and aptness of illustration, we can find nothing finer in our literature, than the 
            "Philosophy of Travel," 
            <span class="footnote" id="n001">
               <span class="footnoteLink">1</span>
               <span class="footnoteText">Published in the Democratic Review.</span>
            </span> and "New
            England Philosophy." 
            <span class="footnote" id="n001">
               <span class="footnoteLink">1</span>
               <span class="footnoteText">Published in the Democratic Review.</span>
            </span> The
            latter, especially, is remarkable for its close analysis of, and its unanswerable
            arguments against those modes of thinking and acting, which would subject the
            warm impulses of the generous heart to the cold dictation of the calculating
            head.
         </p> 
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">E.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         <div class="biblTitle">City Amusement</div>
         <div class="biblPage">120</div>
         
         <div class="head">CITY AMUSEMENTS.</div>
         
         <p>It is a matter of astonishment, that among all the benevolent
            enterprises of the day, no society has yet been formed for the purpose of inquiring into and bettering the amusements of the people. It is a subject of vast
            importance, and one worthy of commanding the attention of reformers and
            philanthropists. The school-room, the church and the press, undergo a continual
            supervision by legal and self-constituted committees, to see that the public mind be
            not corrupted by improper aliment. But the Theatre, the Circus, and other places
            of public amusement, are shunned, as though good people could be contaminated by
            breathing even their names. Yet the minds of the young are more powerfully affected
            in their amusements, than in their studies, and deeper impressions are made upon their hearts in the unguarded relaxation of places of recreation, than while listening to wearisome lectures or long doctrinal
            sermons. Unhappily, the theatre has been so managed for many years in this city, that
            a man or woman of delicate sensibilities could not visit it. But those who have
            the good of their fellow-beings at heart are not allowed to indulge in squeamish feelings; and a virtuous motive will preserve the garments of the
            adventurer from contagion, even in passing through the rabble rout of Comus. It is therefore a duly which good men owe to society to overlook the
            amusements of the people, and when they cannot abolish a pernicious amusement, they
            must strive to improve it.
         </p>
         
         <p>It seems to be quite impossible to extinguish the love of dramatic representations. It is one of the earliest temptations which beset youth; and the entire
            management of the theatre being in the hands of unprincipled and mercenary
            managers, the stage has become a prolific source of corruption to
            our young men. But it should not be so; and it is the duty of the conservators of our
            morals to see that the abuses of the stage, as well as the abuses of the school-room,
            be abolished. It is by no means unusual to hear our preachers
            denounce the theatre, without ever having been inside of one; and pronounce anathemas against practices which never had an existence. Of course, those whom it
            is intended to benefit by such means only laugh at the ignorance of their
            instructors, and persevere in their wicked courses. Our city preachers and
            teachers should go the rounds of our public places of amusement, that they might suggest suitable remedies for their evils, if any exist. Our foreign
            missionaries inquire diligently into the practices of the heathen among whom they are sent, and become very learned in all the enormities of pagan
            worship; they could not combat successfully
            with their evil influences unless they thoroughly understood their origin;
            neither can our domestic missionaries contend with the vices which it is their aim to
            overcome, unless they thoroughly understand them.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Bishop of London is reported to have made, recently, a visit in disguise, in
            company with other benevolent men, to the lowest haunts of the metropolis; that, by
            seeing the actual condition of the lower orders, he might be able to act
            intelligently in his endeavors to reform them. This is the only way in which any
            good can be done by moral reformers. Let those who declaim against theatres go to the
            theatres, and learn with their own eyes what it is that is offensive in dramatic
            representations. Many, we have no doubt, would be struck with the fine morality of
            the plays, the purity of the dialogue, the correct deportment of the actors, and the
            forcible lessons of life which the stage presents even in its lowest and most degraded condition; and they would doubtless be astonished that an
            amusement of so refined a nature, and so capable of conveying moral impressions,
            should suffer from the denunciations of religious men. But let them leave the stage, and turn to the filthy coffee-rooms and punchrooms of the lobbies, where abandoned men and women mingle freely together, where
            every inducement to licentiousness and debauchery is held out to the young, as if on
            purpose to counteract any good impression which the stage may have made,--and
            they would no longer wonder that the Theatre was denounced by the professedly
            virtuous; but they might well wonder why these filthy holes should be appended to
            the theatre, while the lecture-room, the concert-room, and all other places of
            amusement, are free from them. The reason is very obvious. In the time of Charles the
            Second, the stage, in common with every other department of art, was highly immoral; and religious preachers of every denomination, but mainly puritans, launched their loudest invectives against it, as well they
            might; and the feeling against the stage with us has been inherited from these
            puritans, and exists now among their descendants as rankly as with them, even
            when the cause which gave it birth has ceased to exist for nearly a century. None of
            the indecent plays of Charles the Second's time have been represented in our theatres
            for fifty years past; but the literature of that period, which was tinctured
            with the same moral qualities that disgraced the stage, is still preserved in our
            libraries, and we have no doubt that every clergyman's bookcase in the city contains
            more objectionable reading than is presented on the stage during a year. The truth is, that the greater number of acting plays are as moral and prosy
            as an afternoon sermon; for before a play can be put upon the English stage it must
            be approved by the Chamberlain, who blots out every coarse expression and every
            scene of doubtful morality; and as we produce no plays of our own, we present only
            those that the English licensers nave pronounced fit for the people.
         </p>
         
         <p>But we still keep up the hereditary cry against the immoralities of the
            stage; and one state in the Union forbids by law any dramatic representation within
            her borders, when the stage has become almost as moral as the pulpit. Indeed, a good moral is an essential part of every stage performance, without which no play can be successful. No other species of
            amusement demands this; yet the stage is still called immoral, religious people are
            forbidden to frequent the theatre, and only the reckless and abandoned have courage
            to visit it, and it is to suit their tastes, because they form the chief
            supporters of the stage, that the objectionable places which we have hinted at have an existence. But let the theatre be visited by respectable people, men
            of refined tastes and good morals, and the punch-rooms and coffee-rooms
            would soon be abolished, and the people would have what they continually seek--a
            place of amusement where they might derive some moral profit, while indulging in the relaxation from the cares of business which is necessary to preserve a healthy tone in the moral and physical system.
         </p>
         
         <p>The upper classes, as the rich are called, feel the want of a place of public
            amusement, though they have a thousand resources which the poor lack, and they are striving to establish an Italian opera house for their peculiar
            enjoyment; and one of our morning papers, that holds the theatre in such
            abhorrence as to exclude all dramatic advertisements from its columns, professes to be in ecstasies with the measure. But the Italian opera, in its very
            highest condition, is only the recreation of Sybarites; it appeals only to the animal sensations, but makes no aim at the heart, which the lowest
            order of dramatic entertainments professes to do. If half the exertions which are
            bestowed in attempts to estab-j lish an Italian opera in this city, were made in
            behalf of the theatre to establish it on a proper basis, a place of amusement would be furnished for the people which would be acceptable and profitable to all classes. An Italian opera never can succeed in this
            city. If it cannot in London and Paris without the aid of government or government
            officials, how can it be supported here, where its patrons are fewer and its
            expenses higher?
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="hwalpole">Horace Walpole</span>, in one of his letters to Sir Horace Mann, writes,--
         </p>
         
         <p>"We have got another opera, which is liked; there was to have been a vast elephant, but the just Directors, designing to give the audience the full weight
            of one for their money, made it so heavy that at the Prova it broke through the
            stage. It was to have carried twenty soldiers, with Monticelli on a throne in the
            middle. There is a new subscription begun for next year, thirty subscribers at two hundred pounds each. Would you believe that I am one? You need not
            believe it quite, for I am but half an one; Mr. Conway and I take a share
            between us."
         </p>
         
         <p>This was in the last century, to be sure, but it is by simi-lar means that the Italian Opera is supported now in London; and unless the much
            talked-of "upper ten thousand'' are willing to subscribe in this munificent manner
            for the amusement of each other, which we doubt exceedingly, an Italian opera
            can never flourish among us.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="head">The Fine Arts</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts</div>
            <div class="biblPage">121</div>
            
            <div class="head">THE PENNSYLVANIA ACADEMY OF FINE ARTS.</div>
            
            <p>Considering that this institution has only been in operation thirty-nine years, it
               has succeeded in accumulating an amount of bad pictures that would seem almost
               incredible, were it not that sincere conviction may be purchased for a quarter of
               a dollar. There seems to have existed a kind of chemical affinity, by which
               all the worst specimens of Art which came within the sphere of its attraction were
               drawn irresistibly toward it. If this hypothesis be a correct one, we can only
               wish that its power of enticement had extended to some more northerly cities.
               Institutions of this kind seem to be the threads around which all the bad taste hitherto held in solution in general society hastens to crystallize
               itself. They are the ravens sent by Providence to supply mediocrity with bread
               in the shape of patronage.
            </p>
            
            <p>We hardly know whereto begin noticing some few of the many atrocities perpetrated
               here in the holy name of Art; but perhaps the fairest way of settling the
               precedence will be by the amount of canvass which each artist has expended. Perhaps, were we to take the aggregate amount of Mr. Sully's canvasses, we should find that he had displayed more of this liberal
               enthusiasm than any other gentleman whose "works" are here exhibited, but we doubt
               not buthe will be willing to yield the foremost place to Mr. West, both because he (Mr. W.) was president of the Royal Academy, and because he has
               sacrificed by far the largest single canvass upon the altar of professional
               ambition. "West's celebrated picture of Death on the Pale Horse," as it is
               styled in the panegyrical catalogue, is painted upon a canvass
               twenty-five feet long by fourteen and a half feet wide, being almost as large as
               the foresail of a pilot boat, and if in such matters, badness may be estimated by
               the acre, we should not hesitate to pronounce it the worst picture in the
               world. It would be hard to say whether it be more wanting in the imaginative or the
               mechanical qualities of a true painting. In both these respects it is below
               criticism, and it were only a waste of time to point out its most striking
               absurdities. We cannot help noticing, however, the originality
               displayed both in the conception and execution of the flash of lightning in the left of the picture. The impression conveyed by such electric displays to the mind of ordinary mortals, is that of extreme swiftness, but
               precisely the reverse effect seems to have been produced upon the President of a
               Royal Academy. The lightning in the present case wanders
               deliberately down and ends in a viscid drop, so that its general appearance is like
               what would be produced by the melting and running down of a ball of molasses candy
               which bad been reduced to that extremity upon a street-stall by a sudden
               change of weather. We cannot help imagining the exultation which must have been
               felt in England when this monstrosity was fairly rolled up and shipped to this
               country. It might almost seem that its being sent hither was the result of a plot to give British tourists an additional subject of merriment. Yet
               this trumpery has been carte l about the country in every direction and exhibited, with the connivances of those who should have known better, as a
               miracle of Art. Editors of newspapers, who are supposed ex officio to know
               every thing, pay for their tickets to such sickening shows with half a column of
               flummery, and the mass of the people forever after use this picture as a standard in measuring other pictures which have no President's name attached
               to them. In this way incalculable injury is done to the cause of true Art.
            </p>
            
            <p>Allston's "Dead man restored to life," we have never been able to admire. It
               displays none of that artist's fine qualities. The coloring is hard and niggardly,
               the grouping inefficient, and the whole looks more like an attempt to paint a large
               picture than a great one. Haydon's picture of "Christ's entry
               into Jerusalem," which hangs on another side of the room, is more in Allston's
               style of coloring than his own picture. It is chiefly interesting for the portraits it contains. We confess that we think a great crowd of people to be
               hardly a fit subject for the painter, unless, indeed, it be at such a distance
               as to preclude any attempt at individualizing particular heads. If the Artist
               paints all the heads with equal care it will either seem unnatural, because the eye
               could not take them all in at one moment, as in this picture, or it will deprive the figures of all motion and life. In Haydon's pictures all the heads in the foreground look too large.
            </p>
            
            <p>Among many pictures which are disgraceful as works of Art, there is one which is
               positively disgusting. We allude to No. 48 in the "North Gallery." The subject is
               stated in the catalogue as "Time flogging Cupid." It is, of course, by a
               French Artist, and, as we turned away from it, we could not help wishing most
               fervently that the mythology of the Greeks had made Cupid a cherub, and thus
               precluded him from becoming the subject of such an exposure.
            </p>
            
            <p>One of the worst pictures in the exhibition is by Opie, R. A. The subject is from Gil Blas. If pictures may be estimated in the same way that puns were
               by 
               <span class="person" id="clamb">Lamb</span>, who con-
               sidered that badness was one of the postulates for excellence, this
               may be ranked as facile princeps in Art. If there can be anything worse, it must be
               Mr. Sully's copy of the same painting. We can conceive of no object which Mr. S.
               could have had in selecting this for imitation, unless it might have been a
               desire to excuse in some measure the outrages of American daubers by multiplying
               the specimens of one perpetrated by an Englishman.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Directors of the Academy have learned one artifice from the picture dealers, and have given to the most flagrant violations of artistic proprieties the names of the different Great Masters, selected apparently at
               random. They seem to have entertained a peculiar spite against Salvator Rosa, the greater number being ascribed to him. Time would fail us to enumerate particularly all the wretched spoiled canvasses which the "
               Academy" have sanctioned either by their purchase or acceptance. There are a few
               good pictures here, chiefly by Flemish artists, but a foreign visitor would be
               led to imagine that there were but two or three American painters, of the works of
               some of whom the Academy had succeeded in making almost complete collections, and who compared very favorably with the great foreign masters, specimens of whose productions may be found hung side by side with
               theirs. We think that Mr. Peale showed a truly patriotic forbearance in placing his
               works in a Museum of his own, where may be seen some ten score of portraits
               all with a dab of light like a sprinkling of flour on the apex of their heads. When
               a visitor pays his money at the door of that institution, he knows what he has to
               expect. If he does not like the pictures he may look at the mastodon. At the
               Academy, if the paintings are not to his taste, he may look at--at--at--Mr. Pettrick's statue of Goethe's Mephistophiles!
            </p>
            
            <p>We have confined ourselves in this notice chiefly to the bad pictures in this
               exhibition, partly because they form by far the largest proportion, and partly
               because we think that most of them disgrace the walls where they hang. We are
               indignant that the public taste should continue any longer to be miseducated
               by such examples. If we are to have Academies of Art, let them be useful in one of
               two ways Either let them quicken the artistic perceptions of the mass of the
               people by collecting good foreign pictures, or good copies of them; or let them
               (and this is better) encourage American Art by purchasing and paying liberally for
               good pictures by native artists, especially if the Artists be un. known. Such
               institutions should lead the public taste in some measure, and the purchase of a
               picture by them should precede the verdict of popular taste, and not follow it.
               America can now point to Artists of whom Italy or Greece in their best days
               might have been proud. Why need we make a collection of tasteless failures with foreign names attached to them, while we might give employment and perhaps bread to such men as Page and Powers!
            </p>
            
            <p>The collection of pictures we have been noticing is the more disgraceful to
               Philadelphia, because there is a great deal of refined taste and judgment there, as
               well as liberal and judicious patronage. The piece of statuary by Powers and
               the picture by Leutze which we mentioned in our last, are both for a gentleman of
               Philadelphia whose private collection is as honorable to his taste as to his
               munificence.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p8">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Pardoning Governor</div>
         <div class="biblPage">122</div>
         <div class="head">THE PARDONING GOVERNOR.</div>
         
         <p>We have often seen notices of pardons by the late Governor of
            Pennsylvania, but we had no suspicion of the extent to which he had strained his mercy, until we saw the official statement of the exact number of
            convicts whom he set free before their term of confinement expired. The whole
            number of pardons granted by Governor Porter is eight hundred, of these,
            fifty-five were granted before trial. Among the pardoned were several murderers, counterfeiters, burglars, horse thieves, bigamists, incendiaries, and
            fraudulent voters. A fearful list of freedmen. Of what use are laws that must be executed by lawless men? These eight hundred rogues whom Governor Porter
            set free, the great part of them beyond doubt to rob and murder again, had been
            convicted at great expense to the state; and the neighborhoods
            which they had infested, had no doubt looked upon themselves as happily rid of
            dangerous members: but the expense must all be incurred again by the state, and
            throats must be cut, and houses fired again, because the governor, one
            weak-minded or dishonest man to whom the people gave power over their lives and
            fortunes, chose to have it so. Another Governor is the very opposite of Governor
            Porter, either very honest or very hard hearted, and will grant no pardons under
            any circumstances, and convicts who had been accidentally condemned must suffer years of confinement, because the Governor (the one man again) will have
            it so.
         </p>
         
         <p>What absurdity to talk of justice, when the execution of the law depends upon the
            whim of an individual! If one Governor may pardon eight hundred convicts, why may not
            some other Governor hereafter make a general jail delivery and pardon all convicts. If Governor Porter may pardon fifty-five indicted criminals before trial, what is there to prevent some other Governor releasing all
            offenders before trial? Nothing could more plainly show the folly of the majority
            of the whole people making a law, and then giving one man the power to render it
            null, than the exposure of Governor Porter's suspicious mercy. The Americans are
            strangely reckless of power: having it in their own hands, and having never felt
            the want of it themselves, nor suffered much from its abuse by others, they give it
            away as though it were little worth. They give it to their rulers as though their
            rulers were angels, and could not use it improperly. They are credulous to a
            degree passing belief. It never seems to have occurred to the people of the United
            States, that their executive officers could do wrong; to think so would be a reflection upon the people themselves, for the officers, are they not
            taken from the people? But the conduct of Governor Porter of Pennsylvania has caused
            a suspicion in some minds that the State Executive enjoys too much power, and a
            proposition has already been introduced into the Pennsylvania legislature requiring the consent of the Senate to a pardon by the
            Governor. In the most democratic state in the Union, Massachusetts, the advice and consent of the Governor's council is necessary to a pardon.
         </p>
         
         <p>Governor Porter must be a singularly weak-headed man, or the courts in Pennsylvania
            must be strangely corrupt, to allow of eight hundred men being sent wrongfully to
            prison. We flatter ourselves that we are governed by our own laws, but we are
            mainly governed by the whims of one man to whom we give power to render null and void
            all our laws. An elective monarchy is certainly an improvement upon an
            hereditary monarchy, but it is only an improvement, and a slight one too; our
            people are almost as far from believing that all power rests with them, and that they have power to govern themselves, as the subjects of Nicholas or
            Queen Victoria.
         </p>
         
         <p>We do not condemn governor Porter; he may have been moved by merciful considerations
            in setting the rogues free that the court had condemned to imprisonment; but he or
            the judiciary of the state must have been strangely wanting in
            honesty or capacity, or so great a number of men c[o]uld not have been convicted
            unjustly, or unjustly set set at liberty.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Original Poetry</div>
         <div class="head">Original Poetry.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">Gabrielle</div>
            <div class="biblPage">123</div>
            <div class="head">GABRIELLE.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>How I loved thee, dearly loved thee,
               
               <br></br>None can tell,
               
               <br></br>But the heart that still adores thee,
               
               <br></br>Gabrielle!
               
               <br></br>Thou hast left me, ay deceived me,
               
               <br></br>Know I well;
               
               <br></br>But I never can forget thee,
               
               <br></br>Gabrielle.
               
               <br></br>In the quiet midnight hour
               
               <br></br>Thou art nigh:
               
               <br></br>In my dreams thy gentle power
               
               <br></br>Flitteth by:
               
               <br></br>And upon my fevered brain
               
               <br></br>Thy holy spell
               
               <br></br>Cometh like an olden strain
               
               <br></br>We loved so well.
               
               <br></br>Though unknown and unregretted
               
               <br></br>I may fade,
               
               <br></br>I shall never cease to love thee,
               
               <br></br>Faithless maid;
               
               <br></br>For my pathway, lone and dreary,
               
               <br></br>Through life's cell,
               
               <br></br>By thy smile was made leas dreary,
               
               <br></br>Gabrielle.
               
               <br></br>On my grave, when I am gone,
               
               <br></br>Drop a tear
               
               <br></br>For the heart with anguish torn
               
               <br></br>Now with'ring here;
               
               <br></br>When departed, think of him
               
               <br></br>Who loved so well,
               
               <br></br>And if then thine eyes should dim,
               
               <br></br>Gabrielle?
               
               <br></br>For that tear thy spirit lover,
               
               <br></br>Fleet and fast,
               
               <br></br>Round thy footsteps e'er shall hover
               
               <br></br>Till the last;
               
               <br></br>And with music's sweetest numbers,
               
               <br></br>Holy swell:
               
               <br></br>Angels bright shall guard thy slumbers,
               
               <br></br>Gabrielle.
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">February, 1845.</div>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">S. A. W.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Wife of Lot</div>
            <div class="biblPage">123</div>
            <div class="head">THE WIFE OF LOT.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">"And the sun was risen upon the earth when Lot entered Zoar. 
               <br></br>"But his wife looked
               back from behind him, and she became a pil- 
               <br></br>lar of salt.
               
               <br></br>Genesis.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>"Arise, and flee hence, and turn not back!"
               
               <br></br>The angel to the godly patriarch said--
               
               <br></br>"Tarry thou not for kindred, herd, nor flock!"
               
               <br></br>And Lot arose and forth the city fled
               
               <br></br>Onward to Zoar. And clinging to his side
               
               <br></br>Were they on whom as yet no blemish lay,
               
               <br></br>And the true wife--the true, and oh! how tried!
               
               <br></br>With lingering footstep followed on the way.
               
               <br></br>Alas for her, sad mother! whose torn heart
               
               <br></br>Felt love's strong chain to these her being bind;
               
               <br></br>Yet clave to them, her being's other part--
               
               <br></br>To them, the doomed, that she had left behind.
               
               <br></br>And Lot sped onward, while the sandy plain
               
               <br></br>Gleam'd 'neath their hurrying feet. But Zarah turned--
               
               <br></br>And lo! on Sodom fell the fiery rain,
               
               <br></br>And the far mountains heaved, and wildly burned,
               
               <br></br>And from their summits fiercely hurled their blaze,
               
               <br></br>As hurls high Jove his thunderbolts in ire;
               
               <br></br>Lighting the roofs, till 'neath her frenzied gaze
               
               <br></br>The city flamed like one vast funeral pyre.
               
               
               <br></br>And oh! the agony that rent her breast,
               
               <br></br>While from her eyes the heart's warm torrent burst--
               
               <br></br>To know the forms her arms maternal pressed,
               
               <br></br>Were ashes there beneath yon pile accursed.
               
               <br></br>"Alas!" she wildly cried, "here would I die!
               
               <br></br>Mine eyes may look no more on all I cherish!
               
               <br></br>Too much for life henceforth were memory!
               
               <br></br>Since they are saved, with these, oh! let me perish!"
               
               <br></br>Oh! mourning mother! long upon the plain
               
               <br></br>She stood--her watch in tearful anguish keeping;
               
               <br></br>Till the warm blood congealed within each vein,
               
               <br></br>And all to stone she turned with bitter weeping.
               
            </div>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">MARY E. HEWITT</span>.
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle"></div>
         <div class="head">THE LECTURE ROOM.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Lecture Room</div>
            <div class="biblPage">123</div>
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">MR. HUDSON</span>'S LECTURE ON HAMLET.
            </div>
            
            <p>The new lecturer on 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> had been gazetted from Boston as something of a
               lion, in which respect we cannot help considering that he had been very ill
               classified. His eye, manner, eagerness, and especially the avidity with which
               he pounces upon a truth as if he would tear out the very heart of the mystery,
               characterize him as belonging to the ornithological part of creation--a hawk or
               vulture, rather than a lion. He has none of the paces of the lion, nothing of
               the roar loud and continuous, or low and dulcet--for your lion, your literary lion,
               as wisely remarked by Bottom, is very apt to degenerate into the sucking dove.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span> was expected to make a sensation. He had made a sensation in
               Boston--would the canes and gloves of New York respond? This is, as a question, by
               no means necessarily to be answered in the affirmative. Civilization and
               intelligence, we are told, are always proportioned to the density of the
               population, and New York being huge and metropolitan, it must be considered that
               what is a thirty-two pounder in the provinces is a mere pop-gun here, by the sheer
               force of mathematical accumulation. Hence it follows that New York can bear a
               celebrity from any other part of the country, with great equanimity, while the
               reverse movement has frequently called to mind the frog in the fable. Whatever Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span> maybe elsewhere, in New York he is simply a man, a
               cultivated man, originally of strong mind and vigorous perception, with these rare
               natural faculties strengthened by judicious reading. Here let him appear what
               he is, and he will be welcome. Anything extrinsic is "leather and prunella." There
               are one or two points of manner about Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span> that, we might as well state it at
               once, however telling they may be elsewhere, can be dispensed with to advantage here. Such are some of the unutterable chokings, the ineffable grins, and the foolish apology which preceded the lecture.
               His own laugh at one point betrayed him--at a peculiarly abdominal utterance of
               the word practical, during which he tied up his own muscles to relax those of
               the company. If the thing is to be done in this way, let it be so advertised.
               
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> through a horse collar might draw upon the Park audiences, but the
               divines, the lawyers, the literateurs, who graced the Society Library on
               Monday evening, can dispense with the wrigglings and grins with which Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>, like the early Methodists, delivers his conceptions. We are not at all
               disparaging Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>, which we should be, on the contrary, if we took these
               painful and ludicrous twistings for any thing natural or harmonious with the mind
               within.
            </p>
            
            <p>In our view of a lecture on Shakspeare, we are about to pay Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span> a high and
               deserved compliment, by saying that his lecture, in tone and thought, might have
               been written by
               the poet 
               <span class="person" id="rhdana">Dana</span>. There was the same inward depth and command
               of the outer world, the same profound constructiveness and freedom from mere
               dogmatism. The separate thoughts may not have been original--that is, uttered for
               the first time, a very shabby definition of originality, by the way) but there
               was the innate strength of mind to grasp and mould them into one consistent
               whole. The thinking was of the right manly sort, stopping at no half-way house of
               decencies, but going forth right to the end of the journey, fall who might by
               the way. Many a bleeding victim was left by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span> prostrate on
               the path. Poor Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="wpaley">Paley</span> with his plausible morals, an army of
               pretenders, who seem rather than are, and a score of politicians. The latter
               received their death wound from a gun resting on the shoulder of Polonius. We
               shall not readily forget the miserable demagogue whose secret is to find out the tendencies of the mass, and put himself in the van--"a trick
               requiring only long legs, a short head, and no heart at all." This was one of Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>'s points which told well, and by the way, seeing how much he himself
               gains from this harmless stage effect, he might have spared the poor actors the gird he put in, in the Ophelia scene--other sayings were as good, but the rapid succession of short, close, sinewy sentences, have driven
               them from our memory. We remember one happy illustration, referring to the noisy pretenders, and the silence of true greatness. "We hear the
               crackling of burning straw, but not the rays of the sun in heaven." These are words
               that savor not at all of the mountebank. The pointed antithetical character of
               the politician, would have done honor to 
               <span class="person" id="sbutler">Butler</span> and the best of the old Character Writers. The analysis of the character of Hamlet was ingenious, and if
               not convincing, it was at least well defended by a numerous light infantry of
               brilliant truths. The ground taken was that Hamlet feigned insanity, and so
               closely that he was subject to all the laws of the real melancholy. The most that
               can be done with Hamlet is to take some theory as a nucleus, like the thread of the
               sugar manufacturer, for the crystallization of a whole world of truth and
               philosophy. The sarcasm with which that "code of Chesterfieldianism," the instructions to Laertes, was toppled over, was righteously expended,
               and the depth of feeling for Ophelia, was an earnest to us of what we may expect in
               the lecturer's development of the great Shakspearian female life.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p12">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Concert Room</div>
         <div class="biblPage">124</div>
         <div class="head">THE CONCERT ROOM.</div>
         
         <p>"Musical Criticism."--Under this head, the editor of the Evening Mirror, comments
            with much indignation upon some remarks made by us a week or two ago, upon a young
            vocalist: he also informs us that we have been most shockingly
            mangled by the Brooklyn Daily Advertiser. Now this we are really sorry for, as we
            both respect and esteem its excellent editor, Dr. 
            <span class="person" id="wknorthall">Northall</span>, for many reasons.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have not seen his remarks, but we are acquainted with their import, and we feel
            ourselves compelled to say, that considering the very near relationship in which the
            doctor stands to the young lady in question, those remarks, though perfectly
            natural, were impolitic and in bad taste.
         </p>
         
         <p>In answer to the editor of the Mirror, we must reiterate what we have before said,
            that his musical opinions are of no value; they would not even serve as make weight
            to a doubting mind. His criticisms, as criticisms, are without meaning: being a mere string of strained similies, far-fetched images, irrelevant
            rhapsodies, which, though expressed by a strange mixture of quaintness and bombast,
            flippancy and earnestness, bear no internal evidence that they spring either from a knowledge or a love of the subject in discus- sion.
         </p>
         
         <p>The editor of the Mirror has earned, by his after supper lucubrations, the honorable
            title of Operatic Puffer; he has worked hard for the distinction and has justly
            gained it, but what benefit his labors have conferred upon the cause of music it would be impossible to discover. He has endeavored to foster a false standard of taste, by exalting (O power of imagination!) merely good
            talent into superior genius; he has encouraged negligence and slovenliness in every department, by indiscriminate commendation. This may be called good
            nature, but it is not justice, and such a course of conduct cannot command the
            respect of any one.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our course must of necessity be entirely opposite to this. We do not write to
            elevate the individual at the expense of the Art, but we are striving to raise the
            Art by preserving it and its professors in a course of integrity.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our remarks upon Miss Northall, are designated by the editor of the Mirror, as
            injudicious, flippant, and ill-natured. This is a charge he is by no means justified
            in making. We might, with equal justice, accuse him of dishonorable motives in writing up Pico at the expense of Borghese; or we might say
            that he puffed up the Opera concern, day after day, for the sole purpose of gaining
            the artists' gratuitous services at a "complimentary concert." We do not say this,
            but he has given us a right to do so, by wilfully misconstruing our intentions. We have done him the justice to believe him honest in his
            intentions, and we have a right to expect the same consideration from him.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have always endeavored to assist the young, but we conscientiously believe, that
            confirming them in their faults, whatever they may be, by indiscriminate and fulsome flattery, such as "one of a brilliant constellation of talent," &amp;c.,
            &amp;c., is not an act of friendship, but on the contrary, an unkind and wilful deviation from the truth, entailing upon the author well merited
            contempt for his mendacity, and upon the subject, a long account of falsely raised
            expectations, and a sad history of blighted hopes. Under this conviction, we
            have chosen the sterner course; we may wound and offend --though never
            intentionally, at first, but we shall soon be understood, and we do not fear the
            result.
         </p>
         
         <p>Gratuitous Services at Charitable Concerts.--We have neither space nor time this
            week, to enter upon this subject as largely as we could wish. We will simply define
            the duty the professor owes to the public, when once his name is announced in
            the bills as a gratuitous performer. Having allowed the beneficiary the attraction of
            his name (however small that attraction may prove to be) he should consider that
            he has made an engagement which he is bound in honor to fulfil, not only to the
            letter, but in the spirit. How very rarely such obligations are observed, we well
            know. We will mention two of recent occurrence, illustrating forcibly how the letter and the spirit of such engagements are
            observed.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the benefit concert at the Transfiguration Church, Madame Pico was announced to
            sing. She did not appear. What was to compensate for the absence of the chief attraction? Was not this violating the letter of the engagement. A most
            exquisite septett by Hummel was to be performed, Mr. W. A. King taking the
            piano-forte. Mr. King could get no perfect rehearsal of the piece, but he was assured
            that the persons appointed to play it, had played it frequently before. He was
            compelled to be satisfied. In the evening, when the time came for its performance,
            there was no one to play the horn part. There were two horn players pre
            sent, Messrs. Whoening and Nidds, both efficient, we suppose, or their reputation is false. They both refused steadily, the former,
            mark this well! knowing it well, having played it before, and seemed quite
            indifferent to the painful situation in which Mr. King was placed. All this time the
            Director was hurrying the performance on, saying in an audible
            voice, "go on, go on--never mind, play it without the horn,--we can't stay here all
            night." Mr. King, however, very justly refused, and finally Mr. Groenvelt, much to
            his honor as a man and a musician, undertook to play as much of the horn part as
            possible upon the clarionette. The piece was hurried on by the conductor, Signor
            Rapetti, in a very indecent manner, his impatience to retire being evident to
            the audience. The septett was beautifully played, under all these disadvantages, and was beyond a doubt the only worthy performance of the evening. Even
            if the gentlemen hornplayers were not engaged to play in the septett, under the circumstances, their feelings both as men and as musicians should have
            induced them, for the honor of their art, to afford their necessary aid. But to some
            men art has no other signification than cash.
         </p>
         
         <p>The violation of the spirit of the agreement rests either with the performers or the
            conductor.
         </p>
         
         <p>The second instance occurred only last Saturday evening, at the Benefit Concert of
            the Italian Opera. After allowing the names to appear in the advertisements, in the large posters and small programmes, (a cheap way to gain notoriety)
            when the audience was assembled, excuses were sent from Madame Arnoult, Miss Northall, Signor De Begnis and Valtellina. Being in fact the sum total of the "brilliant constellation," as the Mirror would say. These excuses were received by the audience with derision and contempt as they
            deserved, and we should be glad if the public would mark their just disgust at such conduct upon their next public performance.
         </p>
         
         <p>Madame Otto, Miss De Luce, and a Miss Sobienski, and Signor Sanquirico, appeared, we
            understand, but of their performances we cannot speak, as the customary compliment
            of tickets was withheld from us.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p13">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Drama</div>
         <div class="biblPage">125</div>
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>Olympic Theatre.--A new Burlesque, entitled "Joe Miller and his men," was produced at this theatre last week. It is a travestie upon the
            celebrated melo-drama of the Miller and his Men. The incidents are identically the
            same, but the dialogue is done into doggrel, full of point, wit, and humor. The
            actors throughout make a signal failure in their conception of the ger us of
            burlesque. Instead of acting burlesque with an intensity of seriousness, and thus heightening the absurdity, they render nonsense still more nonsensical,
            and thus miss the point entirely.
         </p>
         
         <p>The scenery throughout the evening was extremely beautiful. Mr. Bengough has the eye and the feeling of a true artist, with an admirable power of elaborating
            his ideas. The piece was of course put upon the stage in excellent style, but it will
            not succeed.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Leader of the Orchestra should content himself with playing the music set down for him, and cease indulging in such very questionable "fun."</p>
         
         <p>Chatham Theatre.--This establishment re-opened on Monday last. During the recess it
            has been entirely repainted, newly decorated, and a new stage has also been laid down. It is now, certainly, the most elegant theatre in the city.
         </p>
         
         <p>We hate imposition in every way--playing an old piece (the Vagrant) with
            a new name, is a gross imposition. "True Blue" is a nautical, patriotic,
            not-to-be-believed drama, Americanised from the English, in which one Yankee tar does
            battle with an incalculable number of Britishers, and whips them all to nothing.
            Sundry very equivocal speeches are made, which had much better be omitted.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Freer is not at home as the Sailor. Mr. Winans is very droll, but somewhat too
            broad
            in his acting. Miss Orville, who has a fine voice and is an elegant dresser,
            was encored in a very pretty song, "When the moon on the lake is beaming," and
            received a shower of bouquets from her admirers.
         </p>
         
         <p>"The Devil in Paris" is postponed for the present.</p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s7">
         <div class="biblTitle">New Illustrated Works</div>
         <div class="head">NEW ILLUSTRATED WORKS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Devotional Family Bible</div>
            <div class="biblPage">125</div>
            <p>The Devotional Family Bible, by the Rev. 
               <span class="person" id="afletcher">Alexander Fletcher</span>, A. M., author of the Guide to Family Devotion, Scripture History, &amp;c., containing the Old and New Testaments, with explanatory notes, practical observations,
               copious marginal references, &amp;c., every part embellished with a highly finished engraving on steel, including views of the principal; laces mentioned in Scripture, from drawings taken on the spot. New York, R. Martin A Co.,
               26 John street. Part 1st. Price 25 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>We believe this to be the cheapest and most elegant edition of the Bible which has been published in this country. The paper and letterpress are both of
               the highest order, and the embellishments, though copied from pictures which are almost universally known, are executed in a style of art to make them acceptable, even to those who already possess copies of them from other
               sources. The view's to be given in future numbers, from drawings by Catherwood and
               Bartlett, will constitute the chief pictorial value of this splendid edition of the
               Bible. We have always regarded any efforts of the imagination, whether executed
               by the pen or pencil, as sadly out of place on the page of Holy Writ, and we should,
               therefore, look with as little favor upon the Moses, by Sir Joshua Reynolds, in this initial number, as upon the devotional reflections appended to each
               page, by the Reverend editor. The majority of Bible readers think differently, we
               believe, and to them the reflections and the embellishments of this edition, will
               be alike acceptable, while the real illustrations, the actual views of
               Bible-places, will be acceptable to all. Our remarks are intended to apply
               solely to the principle of Scriptural illustrations, and not to the merits of those
               referred to, which are of the highest excellence per se, and quite beyond the reach
               of criticism at this day.
            </p>
            
            <p>We cannot claim any particular national credit for the excellence of this work, for
               the greater part of it is of foreign manufacture. It is not, however, a whit the less
               valuable on that account. The paper is manufactured in this country, expressly for
               the work, and several of the forth-coming designs will be from the burin of Smillie,
               who stands at the very head of landscape engravers of the present day. Altogether, it is a work of great beauty, and we trust that the enterprising
               publishers will find a profitable sale for it, as we have little doubt of their
               doing.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Apocrypha, we understand, will be published in a separate part, but uniform with
               the others, so that subscribers may take it, or not, at their discretion.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Literary Notices</div>
         <div class="head">LITERARY NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Reply to Part of the Bishop's Statement</div>
            <div class="biblPage">125</div>
            <p>A REPLY TO PART OF THE BISHOP'S STATEMENT. By 
               <span class="person" id="jjay">John Jay</span>, one of the counsel
               originally employed by the presenting Bishops. Stanford &amp; Swords, 139
               Broadway.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have no expectation that Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jjay">Jay</span>'s pamphlet will be the last which the unhappy
               trial of Bishop Onderdonk will call forth, but it is the last one that we shall
               notice in our Journal. The Bishop and his friends appear to have acted with little
               wisdom In giving notoriety to the particulars of his singular case. It is greatly to
               be lamented that the public mind should have been so disturbed by the controversies
               growing out of this trial; it was a matter which concerned the Episcopal Church alone, and the seemingly deep interest which the public have evinced in regard to it, arises from a pure love of gossip, heightened by the
               supposed immoralities which were to be revealed. The harm done to the community by
               filling the minds of the young with filthy details of scandalous transactions, and
               exciting their passions by the bitter personalities of men who are looked upon as
               heralds of peace, is greater, we fear, than the good which many Bishops will be
               likely to effect in many years.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jjay">Jay</span>'s pamphlet was called out by a rather direct insinuation against him, in
               one of the Bishop's communications to the public, which he could not well let go unnoticed. His reply is temperate, respectful and dignified. He has certainly succeeded in freeing himself from any charge of improper
               conduct or motives in the part he took towards procuring the presentment of the Bishop; or in procuring witnesses after the presentment had been made.
               It seems to be a difficult matter, according to Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jjay">Jay</span>'s Statement, to please the
               Bishop and his friends. They complain as loudly against those who neglected to
               make charges against him as against those who did. Considering Use vantage ground
               which Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jjay">Jay</span> occupies, we cannot
               but commend the forbearance and christianlike spirit which induced the
               exceedingly moderate and forgiving tone of his reply. It would have been better for
               all parties, if all who have felt themselves bound to come before the public with their views and facts had maniested the same spirit.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Age</div>
            <div class="biblPage">126</div>
            
            <p>The Age. A Satire pronounced as a Valedictory Poem before the New York Society of
               Literature, at its Second Anniversary, January 23, 1845. By 
               <span class="person" id="awheeler">Alfred Wheeler</span>. C.
               Shepard, 191 Broadway.
            </p>
            
            <p>"In presenting the following Poem," says Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="awheeler">Wheeler</span> in his preface,
               "the author regrets that neither time nor opportunity has been afforded for such
               corrections and additions as would, in his humble judgment, add much to its merit."
               Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="awheeler">Wheeler</span> has done himself an injustice by putting forth his Satire without first
               making the additions hinted at, for which, we suppose, the " New York Society of
               Litera ture" must be held accountable. All the satirical parts of Mr. Wheeler's "Satire" appear to have been left out, for we have not been able
               to discover anything that bears a resemblance to satire in a very careful reading which we gave it; and the "personal friends" who urged
               its publication before the necessary additions could be made which its title
               calls for, showed but little discretion in their friendship for the satirist. The
               freedom of the press has put an end to satire. When men have the privilege to abuse
               wrong-doers in plain prose, there is no inducement to insinuate abuse against them under the cover of assumed names in rhyme. The open blackguardism in
               which editors of newspapers and their correspondents indulge, makes all satire in
               rhyme appear extremely weak and unpalatable. But the vices of the age which
               are every day held up to derision in all manner of ways, cannot possess much zest when slightly alluded to in ten-syllable verses, after the manner of
               the satirists of the last century.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="awheeler">Wheeler</span> satirizes the stage in the following verses, which we extract as a
               specimen of his manner:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>"Now turn we, in our plaudits of the age,
               
               <br></br>To scan the beauties of the modern stage.
               
               <br></br>I mean not living beauties, who amuse
               
               <br></br>Themselves and us with powder, chalk, and rouge;
               
               <br></br>But the refinement and legitimacy
               
               <br></br>Which make the drama now so rich and racy.
               
               <br></br>Time was when men of genius there were needed,
               
               <br></br>To act the parts which else would pass unheeded;
               
               <br></br>But now, 'twill answer if they're almost fools--
               
               <br></br>Besides, they make the most efficient tools.
               
               <br></br>Thus tragedy and comedy are scarce,
               
               <br></br>For both are blended in the vulgar farce;
               
               <br></br>And once, 'twas thought, that they who judged the play,
               
               <br></br>Around the boxes sat in bright array--
               
               <br></br>That honor we've accorded to the pit,
               
               <br></br>With whom all jest and bombast pass for wit;
               
               <br></br>And as they like the mimic rage or tears,
               
               <br></br>So they reward with hisses or with cheers.
               
               <br></br>The best of every play is never seen--
               
               <br></br>That which is hid from us behind the screen;
               
               <br></br>When Hamlet and the Ghost sit tete-a tete,
               
               <br></br>Or Richard dead becomes intemperate;
               
               <br></br>Or when Othello rants at Desdemona
               
               <br></br>Because she didn't die the way he'd shown her."
               
            </div>
            
            <p>It is some time since we read the Rosciad, but we think we may safely aver that it
               contains nothing like this.
            </p>
            
            <p>The "New York Society of Literature" has made us acquainted with this new
               satirist, and the satirist has introduced us for the first time to an acquaintance
               with the "New York Society of Literature." We shall of course hear from the society
               and the satirist again.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">My Own Story; or the Autobiography of a Child</div>
            <div class="biblPage">126</div>
            
            <p>MY OWN STORY; or the Autobiography of a Child. By 
               <span class="person" id="mhowitt">Mary Howitt</span>. D. Appleton &amp; Co., 200 Broadway.
            </p>
            
            <p>This volume completes the series of "Tales for the People and their Children,"
               written by Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="mhowitt">Howitt</span>. It is womanly, gentle, and gossipping; full of little
               pathetic episodes, and sketches of in-door humble life. Those who have read the
               other books of the series, will of course read this; and in reading it will hardly
               fail to derive as much profit and enjoyment as the others have imparted.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Columbian Lady's and Gentleman's Magazine for March</div>
            <div class="biblPage">126</div>
            
            <p>THE COLUMBIAN LADY'S AND GENTLEMAN'S MAGAZINE for March. Israel Post, 3 Astor
               House.
            </p>
            
            <p>The pictorial illustrations of this number of the Columbian are a mezzotint by
               , from Hilton's picture of the Raising of Lazarus, and a line engraving by
               Jewett and Rolph, from a design by J. L. Morton of General Putnam's Escape at Horse
               Neck. There is a plate of ladies' fashions for March, neatly colored, which we
               suppose is not considered an illustration, it being chiefly valuable for the information it contains, and not for any novel ideas on the aesthetics
               of dress. One of the best papers in the Magazine is by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span>, forming No. 5 of a series called "Thoughts on the Poets." The subject of
               the present paper is 
               <span class="person" id="tgray">Gray</span>, for whom Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="httuckerman">Tuckerman</span> evinces a strong
               fellow-feeling, and a very thorough appreciation of his character and
               genius.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">Dunigan's Illustrated Edition of the Holy Bible</div>
            <div class="biblPage">126</div>
            
            <p>Dunigan's Illustrated Edition of the Holy Bible, according to the Douay and
               Rheimish Versions.
            </p>
            
            <p>Nos. 21, 22, and 23, of this finely illustrated edition of the Roman Catholic
               version of the Scriptures, contain three elegantly designed and engraved family
               records for births, deaths, and marriages. The scroll work shows a better taste and
               a higher degree of knowledge in this kind of design, than we have before seen in an American publication.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">Observations on the Best Means of Presesrving the Teeth</div>
            <div class="biblPage">126</div>
            
            <p>Observations on the best means of Presesrving the Teeth. By 
               <span class="person" id="levett">M. Levett</span>, Dentist,
               264 Broadway.
            </p>
            
            <p>A neat little pamphlet, with very plain and simple directions for keeping the
               teeth in order.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Brigand</div>
            <div class="biblPage">126</div>
            
            <p>The Brigand. By 
               <span class="person" id="gprjames">G. P. R. James</span>, Farmer and Daggers, 30 Ann st.
            </p>
            
            <p>This, we believe, is Cour de Leon, one of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="gprjames">James</span>'s popular novels;
               it will probably be found quite equal, under its new title, to a new novel by the
               same author.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">Twenty-Fourth Annual Report of the Bloomingdale Asylum
               for the Insane, for the year 1845
            </div>
            <div class="biblPage">126</div>
            
            <p>TWENTY-FOURTH ANNUAL REPORT OF THE BLOOMINGDALE ASYLUM FOR THE INSANE, FOR THE
               YEAR 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>The condition of the inmates of this well known Institution are so pleasantly set
               forth in this report, that the term unfortunate hardly seems applicable to them.
               The following short extract in regard to their social condition at the Asylum
               sounds very unlike an account of the insane.
            </p>
            
            <p>"On one evening of each week a party assembles in the family parlor,
               for the purpose of social intercourse. The officers and from fifteen to twenty of
               the patients, both ladies and gentlemen, are generally present. The ordinary
               refreshments of evening parties, are served on these occasions. Balls are
               occasionally given, at which a greater number of the patients assemble than at the parties. At the last entertainment of this description there were
               about thirty of each sex, which does not materially differ from the number ordinarily in attendance. The festivities ot the evening afforded very general satisfaction. There was cheerfulness wiihout extreme hilarity, gaiety without boisterousness, and a pervading disposition to
               participate in the enjoyment--to please and to be pleased.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p23">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Intelligence</div>
         <div class="biblPage">126</div>
         <div class="head">MUSICAL INTELLIGENCE.</div>
         
         <p>We call the attention of our readers to the advertisement of Mr. George Loder's
            Grand Classical Concert, which takes place at the Apollo Saloon this evening, Feb.
            22d. It will be without doubt the finest concert of the season, and every lover of music should consider it a duty to attend.
         </p>
         
         <p>A host of talent is at present in New Orleans. Ole Bull, the Seguins, Frazer, with
            Van Praag, Borghese, and Perozzi, Henry Phillips, the Slomans, And a Madame Hammerskold (who both as pianist and vocalist is spoken of by the New Orleans papers at something very great), and some others.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Henry Phillips is said to have made a very profitable speculation of hit tour
            through the States. He will return here in the spring, give a few concerts, perhaps, and return to England to be present at the various Grand Musical Festivals, which would all be imperfect without him.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have one item of news which will, we are sure, be highly acceptable to our
            musical friends. The French Opera will be here about July. That most charming person and sweet singer, Mademoiselle Calve, will be the leading vocalist.
            Grand Opera will be performed, such as Meyerbeer's Robert le Diable, Les Huguenots,
            Auber's Gustave, Herold's Zampa, &amp;c. &amp;c. It is, however, said, and we
            regret to hear it, that Mons. and Madame Lecourt will not be of the company. We may
            be able to report something more definite in a week or two. The performance will be,
            we believe, at the Park theatre.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p24">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Broadway Carnival</div>
         <div class="biblPage">126</div>
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY CARNIVAL.</div>
         
         <p>During the last week this famous thoroughfare presented an appearance
            of gaiety, which few streets in any city of the world could have equalled. If Boz had
            been looking from the windows of the Carlton House, he would have received a very
            different impression of the Broadway temperament, from what he did when he made his
            notes in regard to that avenue. He would have had no occasion to lament the
            absence of organ grinders or ballad singers, for his ears would have been filled with
            the merriest chimes of bells that he ever listened to. The bells that clanged in the
            ears of Toby Veck were
            dumb bells, compared with the lively jingling little rattlers that filled
            the air with music in Broadway, the last week. All the world, but especially the
            dressed-up part of it, the women and children, treated itself to a sleigh ride. Why should it not? It was less expensive than walking. A glorious ride in a
            scarlet sleigh, emblazoned with fanciful devices, covered with buffalo robes and
            drawn by twenty milk-white horses, each one wearing gay trappingc of little bells,
            cost only sixpence. Whole shoals of infants and nursery maids dashed along in
            the highest glee, shouting and clapping their hands from the very farthest verge of
            up-towndom, somewhere in the neighborhood of the Croton reservoir, down to the
            bowling-green, where they were whirled round in a style to break the heart of a Jehu
            lor envy. The sleighing was not only very fine, and the weather very tempting, but
            people knew that it was the last for the season, and so they went to work to
            make the most of it; and really we cannot conceive how more could have been made out
            of it.
         </p>
         
         <p>Where all the bells came from, all the fine sleighs, all the buffalo robes, all the
            prancing horses, all the fine ladies, all the feathers, all the satins, all the
            red-cheeked children, all the pretty nurses, all the laughter, the good humor, the
            sunshine, the men, the bustle, and the merriment, we cannot pretend to guess. In the dull month of February, they were miraculous. Let no foreign traveller ever give his impressions of New York, until he has seen sleighing in
            Broadway. There is nothing like it for fun and jollity in the world. The Carnival
            is a Connecticut fast-day in comparison.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         <div class="biblTitle">Notices to Readers and Correspondents</div>
         <div class="biblPage">127</div>
         
         <p>Notices to Readers and Correspondents.-- We have the pleasure of announcing to our
            readers, that hereafter, 
            <span class="person" id="eapoe">Edgar A. Poe</span> and 
            <span class="person" id="hcwatson">Henry C. Watson</span>, will be associated with the Editorial department of our Journal. Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="hcwatson">Watson</span>, will have entire
            control of the Musical department of the paper, and will give to it the full benefit
            of his well known abilities.
         </p>
         
         <p>The illustration which we had intended for this week's paper, a highly popular subject, which would have pleased all, and offended none, unfortunately
            was spoiled in the cutting, and we have none other to take the place which we had
            intended it should occupy. We shall guurd against such accidents in future.
         </p>
         
         <p>A very good natured gentleman, an editor himself, called at our office to tell Mr.
            
            <span class="person" id="jbisco">Bisco</span>, that he thought we had faults. We have not heard of a more sensible thing
            since we commenced our editorial career. To relieve this gentleman's mind from any
            anxious doubts that he may entertain in regard to our perfections, we hasten to
            assure him that we have faults, very great ones too, which he has probably never
            discovered, though we endeavor to hide them, so that others shall not see them. This
            may be hypocrisy, but we believe that this gentleman considered it a fault in us,
            that we find fault with others. This would be a very serious fault if it were
            done in mere wantonness, or from ill nature, but when fault is found professionally,
            there should be no more blame attached to the finder, than to a physician who informs
            a patient that his liver is diseased. We have never troubled ourselves to hunt up
            mistakes, but aimed solely to point out errors of principle in the works which we
            have noticed, and by this rule we shall always be guided. Personalities will always
            be avoided in our columns, but the perpetrator of a false principle in literature or
            art, must, of course, be made the object at which the battering-ram of criticism is directed. But this can be done with a sole view to demolish the
            principle, without any intent of injuring the person.
         </p>
         
         <p>We published, a month ago, an account of a new discovery in the art of reproducing
            engravings, and called attention to a specimen produced by the new process, which we
            had received from London, and hung up in our office. The Mirror of Tuesday evening,
            reprints the article, and gives credit for it to the Britannia, and at the same time
            states that a specimen had been published by the Art-Union of this city. The article
            in the Mirror appeared first in the Art-Union, a monthly Magazine, published in
            London, in which Magazine the specimen alluded to first appeared. The American
            Art-Union of this city has not published any specimen, as a matter of course. We make this explanation simply because the American Art-Union has some
            twenty-five hundred subscribers, who might be looking for their copy of the
            "specimen," and attach blame to the officers of the institution for neglecting to
            send it to them. The Art-Union, the London Art-Union, and the American Art-Union, are
            three very distinct affairs, but a similarity of names leads to very frequent
            mistakes by our press, when alluding to them.
         </p>
         
         <p>The "Crossing's Sweeper," is very much to our mind, and creditable to the author's
            heart and talents; but parts of it are so marred by mere neglect, that we cannot
            publish it in its present state, although strongly tempted to do so.
         </p>
         
         <p>The editor of the Philadelphia Sun has misunderstood our remarks on the Magazines:
            we certainly bear them no ill will, and do not see how they can possibly interfere
            with our own circulation. We thought that we paid them a very high compliment in
            saying that they were the best, I almost the only patrons of our native writers. We
            are extremely happy to learn that 
            <span class="person" id="grgraham">Graham</span> paid 
            <span class="person" id="jfcooper">Cooper</span> fifteen hundred dollars in
            seventeen months, and that 
            <span class="person" id="lagodey">Godey</span> keeps almost as many ladies in his pay as the
            Grand Turk; but we have heard of writers, whose articles are certainly equal to
            any thing of 
            <span class="person" id="jfcooper">Cooper</span>'s that we have seen in Graham, to whom that munificent publisher
            pays nothing.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s6">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">127</div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">MENDELSSOHN'S LOBGESANG.</div>
            
            <p>Mr. GEORGE LODER respectfully announces to the public of New York that his
               CLASSICAL CONCERT will take place at the Apollo Rooms, on February 22d, 1844.
               (Washington's Birthday,) when will be produced, for the first time in America,
               the
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">LOBGESANG, OR HYMN OF PRAISE, 
               <br></br>Allegro Maestoso e Vivace--Allegretto Agitato--Adagio
               
               <br></br>Religioso. 
               <br></br>Chorus--"All men, all things, praise the Lord." 
               <br></br>Solo--"Praise ye
               the Lord," .... Mrs. E. Loder 
               <br></br>Solo--"Sing ye praise, all ye redeemed,' . . Sig
               Antognini. 
               <br></br>Chorus--"All ye that cried unto the Lord," .... 
               <br></br>Duetto--"I waited for
               the Lord," . Mrs. E. Loder, and Miss E. Watson. 
               <br></br>Solo--"The sorrows of death are
               closing," ... Sig Antognini. 
               <br></br>Chorus--"The Night is departing," .... 
               <br></br>Duetto--"I
               sing of thy loving kindness," . . Mrs. E. Loder and 
               <br></br>Sig Antognini. 
               <br></br>Grand
               Chorus--"The Nations offer to the Lord." 
               <br></br>PART II. 
               <br></br>Overture--"Zauberflote," . . .
               . . Mozart. 
               <br></br>New Canzonetta--"La Veglia," (canzone del Conte Pepoli) 
               <br></br>Jules
               Benedict..............Miss De Luce. 
               <br></br>OFFERTORIUM, 
               <br></br>For Voice and Violin Solo . .
               . Mrs. E. Loder and Sig Rapetti. 
               <br></br>Chorus and Orchestra, composed by Vieuxtemps, for
               the opening of the 
               <br></br>church of St. Renacle, Ververs, Belgium. 
               <br></br>New Song--"The
               Soldier's Glory," composed and sung by Sig. Antognini. 
               <br></br>Aria--"Cujus Animum," Mr.
               Salmonski..................Rossini. 
               <br></br>Overture--"Des Deux
               Journee,"....................Cherubini. 
               <br></br>DIRECTOR.............................MR.
               GEORGE LODER.
            </div>
            
            <p>Tickets for sale at the various Music Stores.</p>
            
            <p>TICKETS ONE DOLLAR--Family Tickets, to admit five persons, Three Dollars.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">FAMILY GROUPS</div>
            
            <p>TAKEN by Mons. EDOUART in an unique style peculiarly his own, which has been patronized by the Crowned heads of Europe and the most distinguished families of America. Mons. E. begs to observe that his
               likenesses are true to nature, and that the manner he disposes of the figures
               constituting his Family Group has always elicited the highest commendation from eminent artists of both hemispheres. The large number of groups in his
               possesion (which are for sale,) evince his natural talent.
            </p>
            
            <p>A collection of 150,000 likenesses with autographs ap, ended, preserved in books
               and large groupings of distinguished characters, are testimonials of his unrivalled
               skill. Those who wish to leave mementos to posterity should not lose the present
               opportunity. A call at his exhibition room (free) will satisfy all that these works are entirely unique and capable of resisting the destructive
               influences of time.--His Fireside Group-, representing the members of families united, which union must be of short duration, separations occuring by
               marriage, change of location and demise, can be faithfully preserved in the works
               of Mons. Edouart, thus affording mementos to those remaining, of time past, and to
               posterity, of ancestors long since departed.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mons. E. leaves for Europe in a short lime. An early visit from patrons at No. 285
               Broadway, near Granite Buildings, is solicited and will receive immediate
               attention, or attendance at the family residence if required.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISBROW'S RIDING SCHOOL,</div>
            
            <p>NO. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette Places. New York.</p>
            
            <p>Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Evening, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS: 
               <br></br>Lecture Lessons. Exercise Riding. 
               <br></br>16 Lessons.........$15 00 1
               Month........................$12 00 
               <br></br>10 "................10 00 20
               Rides.........................10 00 
               <br></br>4 "5 00 10 "........................6 00
               
               <br></br>Single Lessons.............2 00 Single Rides.......................0 75 
               <br></br>Road "
               ...................2 50 12 Lessons...................$9 00
            </div>
            
            <p>N. B.--Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">Evening Class 
               <br></br>12 Lessons ....... $ 9 00 20 Rides..................$10 00
               
               <br></br>Single " .....................1 00 Single Ride.................. 0 75
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">RULES:</div>
            
            <p>1. All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.</p>
            
            <p>2. One hour allowed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.</p>
            
            <p>3. One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.</p>
            
            <p>4. Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 3 P. M.</p>
            
            <p>5. Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.</p>
            
            <p>6. No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladies.</p>
            
            <p>A card of address is requested rievious to commencing.</p>
            
            <p>N. B. Gentlemen keeping their hordes at this establishment, will have the
               privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering and regret, and should not
               be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
            </p>
            
            <p>The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow's professional
               skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of Dental Surgery, and an
               accomplished and skillful operator, we most cheerfully certify to the ease and
               safety with which Dr. B. performs the various and important operations, so
               essential to the usefulness, durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo. Hon. John B. Dawson, La. 
               <br></br>Joshua Herrick, Me. John H.
               Lumpkin, Geo. 
               <br></br>James Irvin, Pa. J. Thompson, Miss.
            </div>
            
            <p>Dr. A. G. Bigelow's Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">CHARLES PERABEAU,</div>
            <div class="ab"> Professor of Music, 
               
               <br></br>No. 9 Whitehall Street, New York.
               
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">MARTIN'S SPLENDIDLY ILLUSTRATED FAMILY BIBLE.</div>
            
            <div class="head">THE DEVOTIONAL FAMILY BIBLE,</div>
            
            <p>EACH PART EMBELLISHED WITH A SPLENDID ENGRAVING, SUCH AS USUALLY SELLS AT A
               DOLLAR EACH. Price only 25 Cents a Part.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE DEVOTIONAL FAMILY BIBLE, by the REV. 
               <span class="person" id="afletcher">ALEXANDER FLETCHER</span>, A.M., Author of the
               GUIDE TO FAMILY DEVOTION, SCRIPTURE HISTORY, &amp;c., containing the OLD AND NEW
               TESTAMENTS, with different Readings, Marginal References, and Reflections, each
               Part embellished with a HIGHLY FINISHED ENGRAVING, on Steel, from subjects by the
               Great Masters, together with a Series of VIEWS of the principal places mentioned in
               Scripture,
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">From Drawings made on the spot by F. Catherwood &amp; W. H. Bartlett, Esqs. 
               <br></br>R.
               MARTIN &amp; CO. 26 John St.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div> 
            <div class="ab">NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW
               YORK.
            </div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH'S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing,
               guaranteed to all (old and young) in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms--Five
               Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course of instruction,
               including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Stationery. Payable at the
               commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours--9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen, and from 11 to 1
               o'clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale "Goldsmith's Gems or Penmanship," elegantly bound. Price Five
               Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith's Gems of Pennmanship.--The Chirographic art is much more important to
               mankind than it is generally considered, and Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">Goldsmith</span> may well claim to be
               considered at its head. The volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and
               higher proofs of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">From the New York Express.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith's Gems of Penmanship.--We have seen the original, as executed by his own
               hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more wonderful display of the power of
               that little instrument which is said to be "more potent than the sword," we never
               witnessed before.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person" id="tkeightley">KEIGHTLEY</span>'S HISTORICAL WORKS.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF GREECE.--By 
               <span class="person" id="tkeightley">Thomas Heightley</span>, with notes and additions
               by G. Toulman Smith, in one volume.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF ROME- By the same author, with notes and additions in
               the same manner, in one volume.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF THE ROMAN EMPIRE--Being a continuation of the History of Home. By
               the same autnor. In one volume.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF ENGLAND--From the Invasion of Julius Caesar to the close of the
               reign of George IV. By the same author, with notes and additions as above. In two
               volumes. Published by
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John St.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY</div>
            
            <p>AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway, Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny's
               Jewelry Store,) awarded the Medal, four first Premiums, and two "Highest Honors,"
               at the Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
               the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
            </p>
            
            <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones at other
               places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on the score of
               economy.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B.--Imported German Cameras, also French and American Instruments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polishing
               materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received promptly attended
               to.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE AMERICAN REVIEW.</div>
            
            <p>A WHIG JOURNAL OF POLITICS, LITERATURE, ART AND SCIENCE. Edited by
               
               <span class="person" id="ghcolton">Geo. S. Colton</span>, and published monthly at 118 Nassau St. New York, and
               by Wiley A Putnam 161 Broadway, and 6 Waterloo Place, Recent Street, London,--at
               Five Dollars per anum in advance--Single Nos. fifty cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is the aim of this Review--discarding all national and sectarian influence --to
               harmonize in a kindlier acquaintanceship the different sections of the country; to set forth more clearly the inexhaustible resources of our territory;
               to elevate the morals of the people: to withstand pusillanimity at home, and
               indignities abroad; to promote American science, and diffuse throughout the land a
               higher order of taste in letters and the Arts. Though established ostensibly on
               partisan grounds, the Review proposes to itself no mere party triumph--but the
               moral, social and literary welfare of the commonwealth.
            </p>
            
            <p>The following is from the origional Prospectus issued at Washington by the Whig
               Members of the Twenty-Seventh Congress:
            </p>
            
            <p>"Earnestly approving of the plan of such a national organ, long needed and of manifest importance, the undersigned agree to contribute for its pages, from time to time, such communications as may be requujte to set forth, and
               defend the doctrines held by the united Whig Party of the Union.
               <span class="person" id="gpmarsh">--Geo P. Marsh</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="ddbarnard">D.
                  D. Barnard
               </span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jringersoll">J. R. Ingersoll</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="ejmorris">E. Joy Morris</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="tlclingman">T. L. Clingman</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jmberrien">J. McPheison Berrien</span>,
               
               <span class="person" id="dwebster">Daniel Webster</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="rcwinthrop">Robert C. Winthrop</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="tbking">Thomas Butler King</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="hfish">Hamilton Fish</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jpkennedy">J. P.
                  Kennedy
               </span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jcollamer">J. Collamer</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jjhardin">John J. Hardin</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="wsarcher">Wm. S. Archer</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="rchoate">Rufus Choate</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="ahstephens">Alexander H.
                  Stephens
               </span>."
            </p>
            
            <p>In addition to these, a number of writers have been enlisted for its various other
               departments, so that every number, besides strong political articles, will contain
               about 80 pages of Literary Miscellany in History, Biography, Criticism, Fiction, Poetry. Statistics, Science and the Arts, three or four Engravings of
               the most finished--the likenesses of men eminent in the present or past age, will be
               given in the course of the year. No pains will be spared, or means left unemployed,
               to make it the first of American periodicals.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">HUNT'S MERCHANTS' MAGAZINE</div>
            
            <div class="ab">AND COMMERCIAL REVIEW.</div>
            
            <p>BY 
               <span class="person" id="fhunt">FREEMAN HUNT</span>, Editor and Proprietor. Published Monthly, at 142
               Fulton Street, New York--at Five Dollars per annum, in Advance.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE MERCHANTS' MAGAZINE and COMMERCIAL REVIEW, embraces every subject connected with Commerce, Manufactures and Political Economy, as
               follows:--Commercial Legislation; Commercial History and Geography; Mercantile Biography; Descriptive, Statistical and Historical Accounts, of the various commodities which form the subject of Mercantile transactions;
               Port Charges; Tariffs: Customs and Excise Regulations; Commercial Statistics of
               the United States and the different countries of the world, with which we have
               intercourse, including their Physical Character, Population, Productions, Exports,
               Imports, Seaports. Monies, Weights, Measures Finance and Banking Associations, ana
               Enterprises connected with Commerce, embracing Fisheries, Incorporated Companies,
               Railroads, Canals, Steamboats, Docks, Post Offices, &amp;c.; Principles of Commerce, Finance and Banking, with Practical and Historical Details and
               Illustrations; Commercial Law,and Mercantile Law Reports, and Decisions of Courts in the United States and Europe, including Insurance, Partnership,
               Principal and Agent, Bills of Exchange, Sale, Guaranty. Bankruptcy, Shipping and
               Navigation, &amp;c., and whatever else shall tend to develope the resources of the
               country and the world, and illustrate the various topics bearing upon Commerce and
               Commercial Literature.
            </p>
            
            <p>It has been, and will continue to be, the aim of the Editor and Proprietor of the Merchants' Magazine, to avoid every thing of a party,
               political, or sectional bias or bearing, in the conduct of the work --opening its pages to the free and fair discussion of antagonistic doctrines
               connected with the great interests of Commerce, Agriculture, Manufactures and the
               Currency.
            </p>
            
            <p>Complete sets of the Merchants' Magazine, embracing eleven semi-annual volumes, of
               about 600 large octavo pages each, bringing it down to December, 1844, inclusive, may be obtained at the Publisher's Office, 142 Fulton-street,
               New-York, at the subscription price.
            </p>
            
            <p>Publishers of newspapers, in the United States, by giving this advertisement two
               or three insertions, and remitting Two Dollars to the Proprietor, will be entitled
               to the Magazine for one year.
            </p>
            
            <p>Office of Merchants' Magzine, January 1st, 1845.</p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p26">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Prospectus of the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">128</div>
         
         <div class="head">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal. To be Published every Saturday.</div>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals
            now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of original matter,
            consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature, Domestic and Foreign
            Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific Intelligence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can be procured, and
            drawings and plans of all new public buildings that have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to
            this department, and no pains spared to make it worthy ol patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the best writers in the country; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened
            through which true-hearted men may "let loose their thoughts," will be the means of
            drawing out some of the slumbering talent amongst us which has not yet been seen
            afloat on the surface of our periodical literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures,
            that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate. It will be
            printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octave form of 16 pages, double
            columns.
         </p>
         
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum--Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.</p>
         
         <p>A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.</p>
         
         <p>All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor or the Broadway
            Journal, and all letters on business to
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.</div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <p>John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.</p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      <div class="note" id="n001">
         <a href="/#/issues/18450222/">Published in the Democratic Review.</a>
      </div>
   </div>
</div>