<div>
   <div class="issueId">18451011</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 2,    NEW YORK, SATURDAY, OCTOBER 11, 1845.    NO. 14
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>Edited by EDGAR A POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau-st.
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Beauty in Shadow</div>
         <div class="biblPage">203</div>
         <div class="head">Beauty in Shadow.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>I mark a sadness on thy brow,
            
            <br></br>Not meet in one so fair as thou;
            
            <br></br>And as I hear thy accent now,
            
            <br></br>There’s sorrow in each tone;—
            
            <br></br>O! sure thou hast not felt the chain,
            
            <br></br>The venom of love’s shaft—the pain,
            
            <br></br>That from a dream, forever vain,
            
            <br></br>Leaves life’s sad waking lone!
            
            
            <br></br>Like some sweet waters poured to waste,
            
            <br></br>With few to see, with none to taste,
            
            <br></br>Do thy heart’s precious fountains haste
            
            <br></br>To desert sands and seas?
            
            <br></br>Oh! flowers thy hope in friendless sky,
            
            <br></br>Beneath no fond, imploring eye—
            
            <br></br>Or, like some harp, that hangs on high,
            
            <br></br>Among forgotten trees?
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">W. GIlMORE SlMMS</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Ms. Found in a Bottle</div>
         <div class="biblPage">203</div>
         <div class="head">Ms. Found in a Bottle.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Qui n’a plus qu’un moment a vivre
            
            <br></br>N’a plus rien a dissimuler-Quinault—Alys.
         </div>
         
         <p>Of my country and of my family I have little to say.
            Ill usage and length of years have driven me from the
            one, and estranged me from the other. Hereditary wealth
            afforded me an education of no common order, and a contemplative turn of mind enabled me to methodize the
            stores which early study very diligently garnered up.—
            Beyond all things, the works of the German moralists
            gave me great delight; not from any ill-advised admiration of their eloquent madness, but from the ease with
            which my habits of rigid thought enabled me to detect
            their falsities. I have often been reproached with the
            aridity of my genius; a deficiency of imagination has
            been imputed to me as a crime; and the Pyrrhonism of
            my opinions has at all times rendered me notorious. Indeed, a strong relish for physical philosophy has, I fear,
            tinctured my mind with a very common error of this
            age—I mean the habit of referring occurrences, even the
            east susceptible of such reference, to the principles of
            that science. Upon the whole, no person could be less
            liable than myself to be led away from the severe preeincts of truth by the ignes fatui of superstition. I have
            bought proper to premise thus much, lest the incredible
            tale I have to tell should be considered rather the raving
            of a crude imagination, than the positive experience of
            a mind to which the reveries of fancy have been a dead
            tetter and a nullity.
         </p>
         
         <p>After many years spent in foreign travel, I sailed in
            the year 18—, from the port of Batavia, in the rich and
            Populous island of Java, on a voyage to the Archipelago 
            of the Sunda islands. I went as passenger—having no
            other inducement than a kind of nervous restlessness
            which haunted me as a fiend.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our vessel was a beautiful ship of about four hundred
            tons, copper-fastened, and built at Bombay of Malabar
            teak. She was freighted with cotton-wool and oil, from
            the Lachadive islands. We had also on board coir, jaggeree, ghee, cocoa-nuts, and a few cases of opium. The
            stowage was clumsily done, and the vessel consequently
            crank.
         </p>
         
         <p>We got under way with a mere breath of wind, and
            for many days stood along the eastern coast of Java,
            without any other incident to beguile the monotony of
            our course than the occasional meeting with some of the
            small grabs of the Archipelago to which we were bound.
         </p>
         
         <p>One evening, leaning over the taffrail, I observed a
            very singular, isolated cloud, to the N. W. It was remarkable, as well for its color, as from its being the first
            we had seen since our departure from Batavia. I watched it attentively until sunset, when it spread all at once
            to the eastward and westward, girting in the horizon
            with a narrow strip of vapor, and looking like a long
            line of low beach. My notice was soon afterwards attracted by the dusky-red appearance of the moon, and
            the peculiar character of the sea. The latter was undergoing a rapid change, and the water seemed more than
            usually transparent. Although I could distinctly see the
            bottom, yet, heaving the lead, I found the ship in fifteen
            fathoms. The air now became intolerably hot, and was
            loaded with spiral exhalations similar to those arising
            from heated iron. As night came on, every breath of
            wind died away, and a more entire calm it is impossible
            to conceive. The flame of a candle burned upon' the
            poop without the least perceptible motion, and a long
            hair, held between the finger and thumb, hung without
            the possibility of detecting a vibration. However, as the
            captain said he could perceive no indication of danger,
            and as we were drifting in bodily to shore, he ordered
            the sails to be furled, and the anchor let go. No watch
            was set, and the crew, consisting principally of Malays,
            stretched themselves deliberately upon deck. I went below—not without a full presentiment of evil. Indeed,
            every appearance warranted me in apprehending a Simoom. I told the captain my fears; but he paid no attention to what I said, and left me without deigning to
            give a reply. My uneasiness, however, prevented me
            from sleeping, and about midnight I went upon deck.—
            As I placed my foot upon the upper step of the companion-ladder, I was startled by a loud, humming noise,
            like that occasioned by the rapid revolution of a millwheel, and before I could ascertain its meaning, I found
            the ship quivering to its centre. In the next instant, a
            wilderness of foam hurled us upon our beam-ends, and,
            rushing over us fore and aft, swept the entire decks from
            stem to stern.
         </p>
         
         <p>The extreme fury of the blast proved, in a great measure, the salvation of the ship. Although completely water-logged, yet, as her masts had gone by the board, she
            rose, after a minute, heavily from the sea, and, stagger-
            
            ing awhile beneath the immense pressure of the tempest,
            finally righted.
         </p>
         
         <p>By what miracle I escaped destruction, it is impossible
            to say. Stunned by the shock of the water, I found myself, upon recovery, jammed in between the stern-post
            and rudder. With great difficulty I gained my feet, and
            looking dizzily around, was, at first, struck with the idea
            of our being among breakers; so terrific, beyond the wildest imagination, was the whirlpool of mountainous and
            foaming ocean within which we were engulfed. After a
            while, I heard the voice of an old Swede, who had shipped with us at the moment of our leaving port. I hallooed to him with all my strength, and presently he came
            reeling aft. We soon discovered that we were the sole
            survivors of the accident. All on deck, with the exception of ourselves, had been swept overboard;—the captain and mates must have perished as they slept, for the
            cabins were deluged with water. Without assistance,
            we could expect to do little for the security of the ship,
            and our exertions were at first paralyzed by the momentary expectation of going down. Our cable had, of course,
            parted like pack-thread, at the first breath of the hurricane, or we should have been instantaneously overwhelmed. We scudded with frightful velocity before the sea,
            and the water made clear breaches over us. The framework of our stern was shattered excessively, and, in almost every respect, we had received considerable injury;
            but to our extreme joy we found the pumps unchoked,
            and that we had made no great shifting of our ballast.—
            The main fury of the blast had already blown over, and
            we apprehended little danger from the violence of the
            wind; but we looked forward to its total cessation with
            dismay; well believing, that, in our shattered condition,
            we should inevitably perish in the tremendous swell
            which would ensue. But this very just apprehension
            seemed by no means likely to be soon verified. For five
            entire days and nights—during which our only subsistence was a small quantity of jaggeree, procured with
            great difficulty from the forecastle—the hulk flew at a
            rate defying computation, before rapidly succeeding flaws
            of wind, which, without equalling the first violence of
            the Simoom, were still more terrific than any tempest I
            had before encountered. Our course for the first four
            days was, with trifling variations, S. E. and by S.; and
            we must have run down the coast of New Holland.—
            On the fifth day the cold became extreme, although the
            wind had hauled round a point more to the northward.—
            The sun arose with a sickly yellow lustre, and clambered
            a very few degrees above the horizon—emitting no decisive light. There were no clouds apparent, yet the wind
            was upon the increase, and blew with a fitful and unsteady fury. About noon, as nearly as we could guess,
            our attention was again arrested by the appearance of the
            sun. It gave out no light, properly so called, but a dull
            and sullen glow without reflection, as if all its rays were
            polarized. Just before sinking within the turgid sea, its
            central fires suddenly went out, as if hurriedly extinguished by some unaccountable power. It was a dim,
            silver-like rim, alone, as it rushed down the unfathomable
            ocean.
         </p>
         
         <p>We waited in vain for the arrival of the sixth day—
            that day to me has not arrived—to the Swede, never did
            arrive. Thenceforward we were enshrouded in pitchy
            darkness, so that we could not have seen an object at
            twenty paces from the ship. Eternal night continued to
            envelop us, all unrelieved by the phosphoric sea-brilliancy to which we had been accustomed in the tropics. We
            observed too, that, although the tempest continued to 
            rage with unabated violence, there was no longer to be
            discovered the usual appearance of surf, or foam, which
            had hitherto attended us. All around were horror, and
            thick gloom, and a black sweltering desert of ebony.—
            Superstitious terror crept by degrees into the spirit of the
            old Swede, and my own soul was wrapped up in silent
            wonder. We neglected all care of the ship, as worse
            than useless, and securing ourselves, as well as possible,
            to the stump of the mizen-mast, looked out bitterly into
            the world of ocean. We had no means of calculating
            time, nor could we form any guess of our situation. We
            were, however, well aware of having made farther to
            the southward than any previous navigators, and felt
            great amazement at not meeting with the usual impediments of ice. In the meantime every moment threatened to be our last—every mountainous billow hurried to
            overwhelm us. The swell surpassed anything I had
            imagined possible, and that we were not instantly buried
            is a miracle. My companion spoke of the lightness of
            our cargo, and reminded me of the excellent qualities of
            our ship; but I could not help feeling the utter hopelessness of hope itself, and prepared myself gloomily for that
            death which I thought nothing could defer beyond an
            hour, as, with every knot of way the ship made, the
            swelling of the black stupendous seas became more dismally appalling. At times we gasped for breath at an
            elevation beyond the albatross—at times became dizzy
            with the velocity of our descent into some watery hell,
            where the air grew stagnant, and no sound disturbed the
            slumbers of the kraken.
         </p>
         
         <p>We were at the bottom of one of these abysses, when
            a quick scream from my companion broke fearfully upon
            the night. “See!” see!” cried he, shrieking in my
            ears, “Almighty God! see! see!” As he spoke, I became aware of a dull, sullen glare of red light which
            streamed down the sides of the vast chasm where we
            lay, and threw a fitful brilliancy upon our deck. Casting
            my eyes upwards, I beheld a spectacle which froze the
            current of my blood. At a terrific height directly above
            us, and upon the very verge of the precipitous descent,
            hovered a gigantic ship of, perhaps, four thousand tons.
            Although upreared upon the summit of a wave more
            than a hundred times her own altitude, her apparent
            size still exceeded that of any ship of the line or East
            Indiaman in existence. Her huge hull was of a deep
            dingy black, unrelieved by any of the customary carvings
            of a ship. A single row of brass cannon protruded from
            her open ports, and dashed from their polished surfaces
            the fires of innumerable battle-lanterus, which swung to
            and fro about her rigging. But what mainly inspired us
            with horror and astonishment, was that she bore up under a press of sail in the very teeth of that supernatural
            sea, and of that ungovernable hurricane. When we first
            discovered her, her bows were alone to be seen, as she
            rose slowly from the dim and horrible gulf beyond her.
            For a moment of intense terror she paused upon the giddy pinnacle, as if in contemplation of her own sublimity,
            then trembled and tottered, and—came down.
         </p>
         
         <p>At this instant, I know not what sudden self-possession
            came over my spirit. Staggering as far aft as I could, I
            awaited fearlessly the ruin that was to overwhelm. Our
            own vessel was at length ceasing from her struggles,
            and sinking with her head to the sea. The shock of the
            descending mass struck her, consequently, in that portion
            of her frame which was already under water, and the inevitable result was to hurl me, with irresistible violence,
            upon the rigging of the stranger.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>As I fell, the ship hove in stays, and went about; and to
            the confusion ensuing I attributed my escape from the
            notice of the crew. With little difficulty I made my
            way unperceived to the main hatchway, which was partially open, and soon found an opportunity of secreting
            myself in the hold. Why I did so I can hardly tell. An
            indefinite sense of awe, which at first sight of the navi,
            gators of the ship had taken hold of my mind, was perhaps the principle of my concealment. I was unwilling
            to trust myself with a race of people who had offered, to
            the cursory glance I had taken, so many points of vague
            novelty, doubt, and apprehension. I therefore thought
            proper to contrive a hiding-place in the hold. This I did
            by removing a small portion of the shifting-boards, in
            such a manner as to afford me a convenient retreat between the huge timbers of the ship.
         </p>
         
         <p>I had scarcely completed my work, when a footstep in
            the hold forced me to make use of it. A man passed by
            my place of concealment with a feeble and unsteady
            gait. I could not see his face, but had an opportunity of
            observing his general appearance. There was about it
            an evidence of great age and infirmity. His knees tottered beneath a load of years, and his entire frame quivered under the burthen. He muttered to himself, in a
            low broken tone, some words of a language which I could
            not understand, and groped in a corner among a pile of
            singular-looking instruments, and decayed charts of navigation. His manner was a wild mixture of the peevishness of second childhood, and the solemn dignity of
            a God. He at length went on deck, and I saw him no
            more.
         </p>
         
         <p>A feeling, for which I have no name, has taken possession of my soul—a sensation which will admit of no
            analysis, to which the lessons of by-gone time are inadequate, and for which I fear futurity itself will offer me
            no key. To a mind constituted like my own, the latter
            consideration is an evil. I shall never—I know that I
            shall never—be satisfied with regard to the nature of my
            conceptions. Yet it is not wonderful that these conceptions are indefinite, since they have their origin in sources so utterly novel. A new sense—a new entity is added
            to my soul.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is long since I first trod the deck of this terrible
            ship, and the rays of my destiny are, I think, gathering
            to a focus. Incomprehensible men! Wrapped up in meditations of a kind which I cannot divine, they pass me
            by unnoticed. Concealment is utter folly on my part, for
            the people will not see. It was but just now that I
            passed directly before the eyes of the mate—it was no
            long while ago that I ventured into the captain’s own
            private cabin, and took thence the materials with which
            I write, and have written. I shall from time to time
            continue this journal. It is true that I may not find an
            opportunity of transmitting it to the world, but I will
            not fail to make the endeavour. At the last moment I
            will enclose the MS. in a bottle, and cast it within the
            sea.
         </p>
         
         <p>An incident has occurred which has given me new
            room for meditation. Are such things the operation of
            ungoverned Chance? I had ventured upon deck and
            thrown myself down, without attracting any notice,
            among a pile of ratlin-stuff and old sails, in the bottom
            of the yawl. While musing upon the singularity of my
            fate, I unwittingly daubed with a tar-brush the edges of
            a neatly-folded studding-sail which lay near me on a
            barrel. The studding-sail is now bent upon the ship,
            and the thoughtless touches of the brush are spread out
            into the word DISCOVERY.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have made many observations lately upon the structure of the vessel. Although well armed, she is not, I
            think, a ship of war. Her rigging, build, and general
            equipment, all negative a supposition of this kind. What
            she is not, I can easily perceive—what she is I fear it is
            impossible to say. I know not how it is, but in scrutinizing her strange model and singular cast of spars, her
            huge size and overgrown suits of canvass, her severely
            simple bow and antiquated stern, there will occasionally
            flash across my mind a sensation of familiar things, and
            there is always mixed up with such indistinct shadows
            of recollection, an unaccountable memory of old foreign
            chronicles and ages long ago.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have been looking at the timbers of the ship. She
            is built of a material to which I am a stranger. There
            is a peculiar character about the wood which strikes me
            as rendering it unfit for the purpose to which it has been
            applied. I mean its extreme porousnses, considered independently of the worm-eaten condition which is a consequence of navigation in these seas, and apart from the
            rottenness attendant upon age. It will appear perhaps
            an observation somewhat over-curious, but this wood
            would have every characteristic of Spanish oak, if Spanish oak were distended by any unnatural means.
         </p>
         
         <p>In reading the above sentence a curious apothegm of
            an old weather-beaten Dutch navigator comes full upon
            my recollection. “It is as sure,” he was wont to say,
            when any doubt was entertained of his veracity, “as
            sure as there is a sea where the ship itself will grow in
            bulk like the living body of the seaman.”
         </p>
         
         <p>About an hour ago, I made bold to thrust myself among
            a group of the crew. They paid me no manner of attention, and, although I stood in the very midst of them all,
            seemed utterly unconscious of my presence. Like the
            one I had at first seen in the hold, they all bore about
            them the marks of a hoary old age. Their knees trembled with infirmity; their shoulders were bent double
            with decrepitude; their shrivelled skins rattled in the
            wind; their voices were low, tremulous and broken;
            their eyes glistened with the rheum of years; and their
            gray hairs streamed terribly in the tempest. Around
            them, on every part of the deck, lay scattered mathematical instruments of the most quaint and obsolete con struction.
         </p>
         
         <p>I mentioned some time ago the bending of a studdingsail. From that period the ship, being thrown dead off
            the wind, has continued her terrific course due south,
            with every rag of canvass packed upon her, from her
            trucks to her lower studding-sail booms, and rolling every
            moment her top-gallant yard-arms into the most appalling hell of water which it can enter into the mind of man
            to imagine. I have just left the deck, where I find it
            impossible to maintain a footing, although the crew
            seem to experience little inconvenience. It appears to
            me a miracle of miracles that our enormous bulk is not
            swallowed up at once and forever. We are surely doomed
            to hover continually upon the brink of Eternity, without
            taking a final plunge into the abyss. From billows a thousand times more stupendous than any I have ever seen,
            we glide away with the facility of the arrowy sea-gull;
            and the colossal waters rear their heads above us like
            demons of the deep, but like demons confined to simple
            threats and forbidden to destroy. I am led to attribute
            these frequent escapes to the only natural cause which
            can account for such effect.—I must suppose the ship to
            be within the influence of some strong current, or impetuous under-tow.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have seen the captain face to face, and in his own
            cabin—hut, as I expected, he paid me no attention. Although in his appearance there is, to a casual observer,
            nothing which might bespeak him more or less than man
            —still a feeling of irrepressible reverence and awe mingled with the sensation of wonder with which I regarded him. In stature he is nearly my own height; that is,
            about five feet eight inches. He is of a well-knit and
            compact frame of body, neither robust nor remarkably
            otherwise. But it is the singularity of the expression which reigns upon the face—it is the intense, the
            wonderful, the thrilling evidence of old age so utter, so
            extreme, which excites within my spirit a sense—a sentiment ineffable. His forehead, although little wrinkled,
            seems to bear upon it the stamp of a myriad of years.—
            His gray hairs are records of the past, and his grayer
            eyes are Sybils of the future. The cabin floor was thickly strewn with strange, iron-clasped folios, and mouldering instruments of science, and obsolete long-forgotten
            charts. His head was bowed down upon his hands, and
            he pored, with a fiery unquiet eye, over a paper which I
            took to be a commission, and which, at all events, bore
            the signature of a monarch. He muttered to himself, as
            did the first seaman whom I saw in the hold, some low
            peevish syllables of a foreign tongue, and although the
            speaker was close at my elbow, his voice seemed to reach
            my ears from the distance of a mile.
         </p>
         
         <p>The ship and all in it are imbued with the spirit of
            Eld. The crew glide to and fro like the ghosts of buried
            centuries; their eyes have an eager and uneasy meaning;
            and when their figures fall athwart my path in the wild
            glare of the battle-lanterns, I feel as I have never felt before, although I have been all my life a dealer in antiquities, and have imbibed the shadows of fallen columns at
            Balbec, and Tadmor, and Persepolis, until my very soul
            has become a ruin.
         </p>
         
         <p>When I look around me I feel ashamed of my former
            apprehensions. If I trembled at the blast which has
            hitherto attended us, shall I not stand aghast at a warring of wind and ocean, to convey any idea of which the
            words tornado and simoom are trivial and ineffective!
            All in the immediate vicinity of the ship is the blackness of eternal night, and a chaos of foamless water;
            but, about a league on either side of us, may be seen, indistinctly and at intervals, stupendous ramparts of ice,
            towering away into the desolate sky, and looking like
            the walls of the universe.
         </p>
         
         <p>As I imagined, the ship proves to be in a current; if
            that appellation can properly be given to a tide which,
            howling and shrieking by the white ice, thunders on to
            the southward with a velocity like the headlong dashing
            of a cataract.
         </p>
         
         <p>To conceive the horror of my sensations is, I presume,
            utterly impossible; yet a curiosity to penetrate the mysteries of these awful regions, predominates even over my
            despair, and will reconcile me to the most hideous aspect
            of death. It is evident that we are hurrying onwards to
            some exciting knowledge—some never-to-be-imparted secret, whose attainment is destruction. Perhaps this current leads us to the southern pole itself. It must be confessed that a supposition apparently so wild has every
            probability in its favor.
         </p>
         
         <p>The crew pace the deck with unquiet and tremulous
            step; but there is upon their countenances an expression
            more of the eagerness of hope than of the apathy of despair.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the meantime the wind is still in our poop, and, as
            we carry a crowd of canvass, the ship is at times lifted
            bodily from out the sea——Oh, horror upon horror!
            the ice opens suddenly to the right, and to the left, and
            we are whirling dizzily, in immense concentric circles,
            round and round the borders of a gigantic amphitheatre,
            the summit of whose walls is lost in the darkness and
            the distance. But little time will be left me to ponder
            upon my destiny—the circles rapidly grow small—we
            are plunging madly within the grasp of the whirlpool—
            and amid a roaring, and bellowing, and thundering of
            ocean and of tempest, the ship is quivering, oh God!
            and—going down.
         </p>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Edgar A. Poe</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Stanzas</div>
         <div class="biblPage">206</div>
         <div class="head">Stanzas.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Oh! lay not her loveliness under the sod,
            
            <br></br>When life’s silver chord shall have parted;
            
            <br></br>The frame of the lute when the music’s with God—
            
            <br></br>The gentle girl now broken-hearted!
            
            
            <br></br>Would ye that the worms of the valley should prey
            
            <br></br>On the lips once like roses above her?
            
            <br></br>Or rather the Fire King waft her away,
            
            <br></br>Forever, in free air, to hover?
            
            
            <br></br>Then of amber and wood of the sandal-tree rear
            
            <br></br>All fragrant the funeral pyre:
            
            <br></br>For sure there is nothing of darksome or drear
            
            <br></br>In the shadowless Spirit of Fire!
            
            
            <br></br>Oh! beautiful he is, and hath not his peers
            
            <br></br>In the elements—he is their master!
            
            <br></br>To him give her blighted bloom dew’d with our tears,
            
            <br></br>And he, though he burn, will not blast her!
            
            
            <br></br>She shall scorch, like the lily she looks, in his breath;
            
            <br></br>But paly, and pure, and perfuming,
            
            <br></br>His arms shall her beauty unhlemished enwreath,
            
            <br></br>And even refine whilst consuming.
            
            
            <br></br>Ye will find that, when clouds which conceal her unfold,
            
            <br></br>She hath fled in her rich robes of burning!
            
            <br></br>But glean from the smouldering pile and when cold
            
            <br></br>Give the ashes a splendid inurning!
            
            
            <br></br>And oft as the evening star chastens the blush
            
            <br></br>Of sunset that brightens beneath her,
            
            <br></br>Ye will deem it her heart, which its soft fires flush,
            
            <br></br>That palpitates in the pure ether!
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">William Gibson, U. S. N.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Duc de L'Omelette</div>
         <div class="biblPage">206</div>
         <div class="head">The Duc De L'Omelette.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">And stepped at once into a cooler clime.—Cowper.</div>
         
         <p>Keats fell by a criticism. Who was it died of “The
            Andromache?"
            <span class="footnote" id="n001">
               <span class="footnoteLink">1</span>
               <span class="footnoteText">Montfleury. The author of the Parnasse Réformé makes him
                  thus speak in Hades:—“L'homme done qui voudrait savoir ce dont
                  Je suis mort, qui'l ne demande pas si’l fut de fievre ou de podagre
                  on d'autre chose, mais qu'il entende que ce fut de 'L'Andromache.’"
               </span>
            </span>Ignoble souls!—De L’Omelette perished of an ortolan. L'histoire en est brère. Assist me, Spirit of Apicius!
         </p>
         
         <p>A golden cage bore the little winged wanderer, enamored, melting, indolent, to the Chaussée D'Antin, from
            its home in far Peru. From its queenly possessor La Bellissima, to the Due De L’Omelette, six peers of the empire conveyed the happy bird.
         </p>
         
         <p>That night the Due was to sup alone. In the privacy
            of his bureau he reclined languidly on that ottoman, for
            which he sacrificed his loyalty in outbidding his king,—
            the notorious ottoman of Cadet.
         </p>
         
         <p>He buries his face in the pillow. The clock strikes!
            Unable to restrain his feelings, his Grace swallows an
            olive. At this moment the door gently opens to the
            sound of soft music, and lo! the most delicate of birds
            is before the most enamored of men! But what inexpressible dismay now overshadows the countenance of
            the Due?—“Horreur!—chien!—Baptiste —I’oiseau!
            ah, bon Dieu! cet oiseau modeste que tu as deshabillé de
            ses plumes, et que tu as servi sans papier!" It is superfluous to say more:—the Due expired in a paroxysm
            of disgust.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Ha! ha! ha!”, said his Grace on the third day after his decease.</p>
         
         <p>“He! he! he!”, replied the Devil faintly, drawing
            himself up with an air of hauteur.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Why, surely you are not serious,” retorted De L’Omelette. “I have sinned—c'est vrai—but, my good sir,
            consider!—you have no actual intention of putting such
            —such—barbarous threats into execution.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“No what?” said his majesty— "come, sir, strip!”
            “Strip, indeed!—very pretty i’ faith!—no, sir, I shall
            not strip. Who are you, pray, that I, Due De L’Omelette, Prince de Foie-Gras, just come of age, author of
            the ‘Mazurkiad,’ and Member of the Academy, should
            divest myself at your bidding of the sweetest pantaloons
            ever made by Bourdon, the daintiest robe-de-chambre ever put together by Rombert—to say nothing of the taking
            my hair out of paper—not to mention the trouble I should
            have in drawing off my gloves?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Who am I?—ah, true! I am Baal-Zebub, Prince of
            the Fly. I took thee, just now, from a rose-wood coffin
            inlaid with ivory. Thou wast curiously scented, and labelled as per invoice. Belial sent thee,—my Inspector
            of Cemeteries. The pantaloons, which thou sayest were
            made by Bourdon, are an excellent pair of linen drawers, and thy robe-de-chambre is a shroud of no scanty dimensions.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Sir!” replied the Due, “I am not to be insulted with
            impunity!—Sir! I shall take the earliest opportunity of
            avenging this insult!—Sir! you shall hear from me! In
            the meantime au revoir!”—and the Due was bowing
            himself out of the Satanic presence, when he was interrupted and brought back by a gentleman in waiting.—
            Hereupon his Grace rubbed his eyes, yawned, shrugged
            his shoulders, reflected. Having become satisfied of his
            identity, he took a bird’s eye view of his whereabouts.
         </p>
         
         <p>The apartment was superb. Even De L’Omelette pronounced it bien comme il faut. It was not its length nor
            its breadth,—but its height—ah, that was appalling!—
            There was no ceiling—certainly none—but a dense whirling inass of fiery-colored clouds. His Grace’s brain reeled as he glanced upwards. From above, hung a chain
            of an unknown blood-red metal—its upper end lost, like
            the city of Boston, parmi let nues. From its nether extremity swung a large cresset. The Due knew it to be a
            ruby; but from it there poured a light so intense, so still,
            to terrible, Persia never worshipped such—Gheber never
            imagined such—Mussulman never dreamed of such when,
            drugged with opium, he has tottered to a bed of poppies,
            his back to the flowers, and his face to the God Apollo.
            The Due muttered a slight oath, decidedly approbatory.
         </p>
         
         <p>The corners of the room were rounded into niches.—
            Three of these were filled with statues of gigantic proportions. Their beauty was Grecian, their deformity
            Egyptian, their tout ensemble French. In the fourth
            niche the statue was veiled; it was not colossal. But
            then there was a taper ankle, a sandalled foot. De L’Omelette pressed his hand upon his heart, closed his eyes,
            raised them, and caught his Satanic Majesty—in a blush.
         </p>
         
         <p>But the paintings!—Kupris! Astarte! Astoreth!—a
            thousand and the same! And Rafaelle has beheld them!
            Yes, Rafaelle has been here; for did he not paint the——?
            and was he not consequently damned? The paintings!
            —the paintings! O luxury! O love!—who, gazing on
            those forbidden beauties, shall have eyes for the dainty
            devices of the golden frames that besprinkle, like stars,
            the hyacinth and the porphyry walls?
         </p>
         
         <p>But the Duc’s heart is fainting within him. He is not,
            however, as you suppose, dizzy with magnificence, nor
            drunk with the ecstatic breath of those innumerable
            censers. C'est vrai que de toutes ces choses il a pense
            beaucoup—mais! The Due De L’Omelette is terrorstricken; for, through the lurid vista which a single uncurtained window is affording, lo! gleams the most
            ghastly of all fires!
         </p>
         
         <p>Le pauvre Duc! He could not help imagining that
            the glorious, the voluptuous, the never-dying melodies
            which pervaded that hall, as they passed filtered and
            transmuted through the alchemy of the enchanted window-panes, were the wailings and the howlings of the
            hopeless and the damned! And there, too!—there!—
            upon that ottoman!—who could he be?—he, the petilmaitre—no, the Deity—who sat as if carved in marble,
            et qui sourit, with his pale countenance, si amérement?
         </p>
         
         <p>Mais il faut agir,—that is to say, a Frenchman never
            faints outright. Besides, his Grace hated a scene—De
            L’Omelette is himself again. There were some foils
            upon a table—some points also. The Due had studied 
            under B——; il avail tue ses six homines. Now, then,
            il peut s'échapper. He measures two points, and, with
            a grace inimitable, offers his majesty the choice, Horreur! his Majesty does not fence!
         </p>
         
         <p>Mais il joue!—how happy a thought!—but his Grace
            had always an excellent memory. He had dipped in the
            “Diable” of the Abbe Gualtier. Therein it is said “que
            le Diable n’ose pas refuser un jeu d'écarte."
         </p>
         
         <p>But the chances—the chances! True—desperate: but
            scarcely more desperate than the Duc. Besides, was he
            not in the secret?—had he not skimmed over Père Le
            Bran?—was he not a member of the Club Vingt-un?—
            “Si je perds," said he, “je serai deux fois perdu—I
            shall be doubly damned—votla tout! (Here his Grace
            shrugged his shoulders) Si je gagne, je reviendrai à
            mes ortolans—que les cartes soient préparées!”
         </p>
         
         <p>His Grace was all care, all attention—his Majesty all
            confidence. A spectator would have thought of Francis
            and Charles. His Grace thought of his game. His Majesty did not think; he shuffled. The Duc cut.
         </p>
         
         <p>The cards are dealt. The trump is turned—it is—it
            is—the king! No—it was the queen. His Majesty curs-
            ed her masculine habiliments. De L’Omelette placed
            his hand upon his heart.
         </p>
         
         <p>They play. The Duc counts. The hand is out. His
            Majesty counts heavily, smiles, and is taking wine. The
            Duc slips a card.
         </p>
         
         <p>"C'est à rous à faire," said his Majesty, cutting. His
            Grace bowed, dealt, and arose from the table en presentant le Roi.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>His Majesty looked chagrined.</p>
         
         <p>Had Alexander not been Alexander, he would have
            been Diogenes; and the Duc assured his antagonist in taking leave, “que s'il n'eut pas été Be L’Omelette il n'aurait point d’objection d’etre le Diable."
         </p>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Littleton Barry</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">To Constance</div>
         <div class="biblPage">208</div>
         <div class="head">To Constance.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Forgive me, Lady, if I bring to bear
            
            <br></br>Upon my case, a fable of old times;
            
            <br></br>Since Poesie did ne’er such beauty wear
            
            <br></br>As in the breathing of those antique rhymes.
            
            <br></br>Love was Ideal then, and Fancy dress’d,
            
            <br></br>Some mortal form in attributes divine;
            
            <br></br>She was the Deity all men confessed,
            
            <br></br>And bowed down soul and reason at her shrine.
            
            <br></br>Where shall we find such passion now? ah! where?
            
            <br></br>Are not those vain, though sweet, delusive lays?
            
            <br></br>Love and Romance grow strangers year by year,
            
            <br></br>’Till rare their meeting in these actual days.
            
            <br></br>But sometimes there is found amidst the throng
            
            <br></br>A being aged in care, with heart still young,
            
            <br></br>Who still finds truth in the wild dreamer’s song,
            
            <br></br>Like ivy, clinging, where in youth he clung.
            
            <br></br>These are but few, yet rarer still we find
            
            <br></br>The God-like cause, that makes such thoughts to be;
            
            <br></br>I might have liqed and perished cold and blind
            
            <br></br>To all such bliss, had it not been for thee.
            
            
            <br></br>FABLE.
            
            <br></br>“Thou art, like me, but common earth—then why
            
            <br></br>Shouldst thou so rich in rarest odors be?”
            
            <br></br>This was the modest and the wise reply:—
            
            <br></br>“I nursed the Rose—its sweetness lives with me!”
            
            <br></br>So I, who am but common clay, have caught
            
            <br></br>From thy bright Presence some of its pure light;
            
            <br></br>As great a change is in my being wrought,
            
            <br></br>As brings the sun to the down-winged night.
            
            <br></br>I am of thee poor counterfeit, alas!
            
            <br></br>Grafting thy virtues on a worthless tree;
            
            <br></br>Yet from my heart their glory shall not pass,
            
            <br></br>But hallow, like the Rose, their sanctuary.
         </div>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">W.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Falling Star</div>
         <div class="biblPage">208</div>
         <div class="head">The Falling Star.</div>
         
         <p>It was deep midnight, and no moon shone, but the thousand stars of heaven looked down upon the sleeping
            earth, and kept their watch for her. A fair girl knelt by 
            the bed of the dying minstrel—she was his sister. She
            had tended him for many days with an untiring love—she
            would not that an alien eye should catch his latest look,
            or menial hand minister to his latest earthly want. For
            many hours she had not left his side, but kneeling there,
            with one hand clasped in her upraised hands, she gazed
            alternately from him to the vast heaven, searching its
            inmost depths with an untiring ken, as if she would tear
            from out its mystic heart the secret of a fate so interwoven
            with hers. But no sign came, and she turned and wept.
            Oh! the deep agony of that young heart! It was an unalloyed sorrow, which admitted of no earthly consolation. They were alone—these two young hearts—and
            other tie had none. All they had loved were in the
            grave, and they awoke one day as from a trance, and
            looked around and cried out for a friend, but they found
            none, and from that day they were one heart. They were
            both beautiful, and genius had been their heritage, and
            grew alike in both, only that hers was much less bold
            than His, for that it had received its tone from her sweetgentleness, mixed with deep reverence for his more reasoning mind—as the gazer on water sees some bright star
            reflected on its bosom, and sees they are alike, save that
            the image is more shadowy, which is but caused by the
            properties of that in which it shows. So wrapt were
            they in each other, that the outer world had no charm for
            them, saving its humanities; the follies of fashion and
            the frivolities of life were unknown to them. They had
            drawn around them a magic circle, in which nought save
            what was bright and beautiful dare enter. Day after day
            did they gather wisdom from the pages of the mighty
            dead, and as the old world opened to their ardent minds,
            the present faded as a dream. They loved to dwell upon
            some tale of rare affection, of deep devotion, or self-immolation at the shrine of duty—instances of which the
            Past has in perfection, gilded perhaps by the romance a
            lapse of time never fails to bestow, but still unaffectedly
            human. And when they rose from their labor of love,
            they felt the deep effect which lessons of exalted virtue
            ever impress on reflecting minds. They impart a dignity to life which is unobserved in the every-day world,
            and link the heart to its kind by the noblest sentiments
            that nature can evince. They were the Philanthropists
            of the closet, unbounded in their sympathy, but from their
            sensibility and refinement, all unfit to mingle with the
            coarser spirits of the world. What excited their benevolence in a mass would most probably cause disgust in the
            individual, and they would turn away heart-sick to find
            the world not what they thought it. They would mourn
            for the suffering million, but the leprous wretch in the
            filthy hovel would be a loathed and hideous object in their
            eyes. Such is the difference between the theoretical and
            the practical Christian—the one refines and gives out
            Utopian theories to the world, which never are adopted,
            benefitting no one, though not the less noble in their aim,
            —the other seeks out Misery in its home, and bars out
            hungering Famine from the starving wretch; and though
            the means of assistance may be small, the never-failing
            font of Sympathy skins over the wounds it cannot radically heal. They saw that the world was beautiful, and
            were content to breathe the odor of its flowers, without
            distilling the poison from their hearts. They were dreamers, and had they been separate, such feelings would
            have craved the sympathy of some kindred heart, and
            they might have loved; but they were all in all to each
            other; their feelings were so knit, so interwoven, that
            the approach of any other sentiment seemed to threaten a
            disruption of the tie, and they sensitively and gladly
            shrank back into the gentle and unreserved commune of
            their own pure thoughts. They were orphans, and friendless,—they were alone, and loving! And now the sister
            knelt by the side of her dying brother! That was her
            grief;—for him her tears flowed fast, and the visible silence was broken by deep and fervent prayers. But the
            fever raged with unabated violence,—he muttered wild
            words, which conjured up the vision of a thousand happy hours, and caused a fresh burst of grief from the
            spirit-broken girl. The malady was evidently approaching its crisis; every moment the stillness became more
            awful. She longed to call for some one to share her
            watch, yet could not for a moment tear herself from the
            couch. He had breathed hardly until now, but now she
            missed the sound—it had sunk to a child’s breathing—
            and faint and frequent throbbed the pulses at his heart:—
            the eye which had been glaring and restless became fixed;—she longed to scream, but the voice seemed frozen
            at her heart, More feebly still he breathed; an expres-
            
            sion of agony was on his brow; his hand relaxed its
            grasp, and with one deep sigh his features faded into a
            quiet smile; his spirit seemed to have left its earthly
            home! Throwing her despairing eyes to heaven, she
            shrieked, “Oh, God, have mercy!”—And a bright star
            fell!
         </p>
         
         <p>But he recovered, and a week hence was seated on a
            couch, with that fair girl nestling at his feet. *	*	*
            ****	*	*	*	* * I "have been a grievous
            trouble to thee, Marian! Thine eye is as bright, thy
            smile as sweet, but thy cheek is pale, and thy hands have
            shrunk to thinness. And I fear that in my sadness, I may
            have spoken harsh words to thee, or have been wilful and
            fretful, or wishful and exacting; but now I crave your
            pardon, dearest, and throw myself upon your love for your
            forgiveness." “Hush! hush!” said Marian, as she placed
            her hand upon his mouth—“dear Ernest, most wrongfully
            do you accuse yourself;—both gentle and patient were
            you during all your sufferings; no murmur fell from your
            lips; no repining—no impatience—and every office I performed for you was more than repaid by the look of love
            and thankfulness with which it was received.” “But—”
            “Nay, hear me. If I have lost the ruddiness of health
            from off my cheek and its fullness from my form, it was
            not caused by watching and waiting upon your couch,
            but by the ever present fear that you might be taken from
            me. It tortured me through the day, and affrighted me
            in the night. I could not fly from the thought. I read it
            in the setting sun—in the flickering taper—and as the
            stars came out, and faded as the night wore on, each
            seemed to bear upon it a ray of mystic recognition of
            your embodied spirit.” “I have but faint remembrance
            of the past. I know the days—though cheered by sight
            of you—seemed endless.” “’Twas strange, too, Earnest;
            throughout the day you would appear strangely unsettled; a feverish restlessness seemed to pervade your 
            frame; but as the night came on this was superseded by
            a calmness, trance-like, nay, almost deathly, that made
            my blood stagnate in every vein—at those times, with a
            a philosophy which failed me utterly in the day, I would
            speculate upon the possibility of your death—and all at
            once I seemed to cease to be a being of the earth—the
            mystic line was spoken, and my mind was cognizant of
            the immaterial elements. Countless bright shapes peopled the circumambient air—if shapes they could be called that were without a form or substance. I was in the
            heart of Nature, and I saw how the progress of decay
            was but a preface to another birth—a state of being in
            which soul was all—I was conscious of an elevation of
            mind, an expansion of intellect, which rendered the deepsought, stored-up knowledge of a thousand generations
            of men, but as a grain of sand to the earth’s gross bulk—
            and I saw that those of earth who approached nearest
            to the imagination of a state of being which in truth
            surpasses all that the powers of imagination can conjure up, were those who in the earnestness of a beneficent nature sought out the Humanities from Wisdom’s
            page, and blending both, saw nature through the heart
            and mind—neither with the misjudging warmth of the
            enthusiast, nor the fact-deducing coldness of the philosopher—but offering at her shrine the uttermost attainable refinement of intellect, warmed by the Spirit of angelic Love! I saw through the world, man yearning unceasingly to rise, the soul warring with its human-being clay, and striving ever to sever from it—the pale
            student in his midnight study, burying the recollection
            of the miseries of the by-gone day, forgetting the want
            of friends, the cold repulse, the unappreciation, the
            want of sympathy, the hungering morrow, in his absorbing love of the truth—the haughty statesman retiring from the admiring crowd, and seeking consolation
            in seclusion from those aspiring but baseless hopes that
            sought to raise the herd from its desperate besotted
            state,—repaid by revilement, scorn, and disbelief, by
            that very class he sought to benefit;—and, seeking in that
            solitude deep commune with his own heart, he sought to
            work out, from the philosophy of the past and the sad
            experience of the present, a state of mind in which the
            desire of dispensing happiness should be of itself sufficient compensation apart and independent of the reception of the benefit by the object of it. Thus deeply pondering and in secret, the quiet came upon his soul and
            he became of us. I cannot describe to you the nameless
            feeling that possessed me at those times—there was a
            consciousness of existence, without its cares; of knowledge without the blindness of prejudice which ever accompanies our earthly wisdom. I felt that I was apart
            from the world, yet of it; for that sympathy which pervades all nature, which binds heart to heart, and is the
            medium through which human sensations and affections
            are felt alike and conveyed throughout the universe now
            and forever, was acting upon my spirit with a mighty
            force; my nature was etherealized, and I was in an impalpable though sentient link of that wondrous harmonizer of creation, Sympathy or Love! And you were there,
            my brother;—our spirits met in that bright star with
            which we have so oft imagined that our fates were inseparably connected.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Stay, Marian, dearest, thou dost remember me, that
            as I lay upon my bed of sickness, I had a dream of a
            most terrible and strange import. I know that for days
            I lay unconscious of all, save of an intolerable and raging fever, that seemed to dry up all moisture in my
            blood and brain. I seemed to breathe hot air, which, in
            its passage, dried up my tongue, and parched and cracked my livid lips. Day and night revolved, but Time
            seemed to have stayed its course. Each day, as it broke,
            brought with it an increasing but nameless terror, which,
            ever and anon, like unto ice-strings made each trembling
            nerve; and, though the fury of a thousand fires leaped
            through each vein, my heart felt chill. On that night
            which caused thee so much terror, this harassing feeling
            was upon me, and grappled me with a giant’s hand; nor
            could I fortify myself against it, for my mind seemed to
            have lost the power of connecting ideas of any kind;—all
            was vagueness and dread. As the night wore on, the increasing stillness added a new terror to my mind. Methought I lay chained and immovable in the midst of a
            vast sandy plain, over which the hot sun was vertical—
            throughout the day, from morn till night, he poured his
            fierce beams upon my seething skin, until I felt it crack
            and gape like the parched earth; and when the sun had
            set, the moon’s rays and the beams of the golden stars
            seemed to have fire that scorched my brain to madness.
            There was no rest for me, night nor day—my fevered
            tongue could not give out my agony. And I was alone in
            my suffering—when suddenly a mighty form approached.
            It was of a grave but beautiful aspect—and on its brow
            there was a calm that chilled at once my burning blood.
            It seemed as if it had never known a youth, nor could
            know age—it was not the calm of thought, nor the passiveness of overwhelming grief, but I felt at once that it
            was the cold, eternal calm of Death. Nearer it came on,
            and my soul recoiled at its approach. Nearer, still near
            er—it had gained my feet, when in a moment the cells of
            memory gave up their treasured store. Father, mother,
            friends came flocking around me—our happy home and
            childish sports; each happy hour, that in its passage bore
            a pleasant thought; snatches of old wild melodies, and
            all the thousand things that endeared and made a joy of
            life, rushed forth to keep the dreaded terror off,—but in
            vain! It paused not in its career—it raised its hands
            above me—a cold sweat stood upon my brow—I strove to
            speak, but no sound came forth—and struggled to arise, 
            but the mighty spell withheld me, and I was sinking fast, 
            Slowly the withering hand descended towards my heart, 
            —already did I feel its grasp stilling the pulse of life,— 
            my soul paused, wavering, ere it took its flight, when on 
            the still night air the deep and fervent prayers of thy innocent heart arose, and from the orbed heaven rushed
            forth a radiant form, and stood between me and my dreaded foe”—
         </p>
         
         <p>“My brother! I saw that star fall!"</p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Henry C. Watson</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Critical Notices</div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Broken Vow and Other Poems</div>
            <div class="biblPage">210</div>
            <div class="ab">The Broken Vow and Other Poems. By Amanda M. Ed-
               
               <br></br>mond. Boston: Gould, Kendall &amp; Lincoln.
            </div>
            
            <p>An octavo of more than 320 pages, beautifully printed
               on fine paper, “embellished” with six expensive steel engravings (including a portrait of the authoress,) and
               showily as well as substantially bound.
            </p>
            
            <p>The name—Amanda-M. Edmond—is quite unknown to
               us: although if we may judge from the number of poems
               contained in the volume (110) the fair poetess must have
               been for several years before the public. Perhaps, however, she may have employed a nom-de-plume, or written 
               altogether anonymously. We do not remember having
               before seen any one poem of the collection. They are by
               no means impressive. The subjects, generally, are such
               as find favor in boarding-schools. Many of the pieces
               are on abolition topics. Some of them, from their character, have no right to the title of poem, and should not
               have been included in the volume: we refer to such
               things as “Washing-Day” and “Illi cui Carmina applicent"—mere doggrel. In the minor merits Miss Edmond
               is not particularly deficient. Her English, her versification, and her imagery, are at least respectable—but in
               the virtues of the Muse—in the loftier and distinctive attributes, we are pained to say that she is totally wanting. We look in vain throughout her volume for one
               spark of poetic fire. In justice, we cull what we consider the best specimen of her powers:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>THE MOON.
               
               <br></br>Beautiful moon! oh, how I love to hail
               
               <br></br>Thy glorious coming in the eastern sky,
               
               <br></br>When starry gems along thy pathway lie,
               
               <br></br>Trembling and turning in thy presence pale;
               
               <br></br>Brightest adorner of Night’s pensive brow,
               
               <br></br>Fairest of all her radiant jewels, thou!
               
               <br></br>Wreathing with light the fleecy cloud that veils
               
               <br></br>With its thin mantle, for a little space,
               
               <br></br>The full-orbed lustre of thy beaming face—
               
               <br></br>Casting thy splendor on the sleeping dales,
               
               <br></br>Fields, woods and waters that beneath thee rest,
               
               <br></br>With Night’s dark shadows on thy peaceful breast—
               
               <br></br>Oh, I do love thee! but the most, sweet moon,
               
               <br></br>In the still hour of midnight’s sacred noon;
               
               <br></br>Calm then are spirits that with day have striven,
               
               <br></br>And Earth's repose seems kin to that of Heaven!
            </div>
            
            
            <p>We have said that the English of Miss Edmond is generally respectable; but in the very first sentence of the
               Preface there is an ambiguity which, in a second edition,
               should be cleared up. “A poetical contribution” says
               the poetess, “offered to the public, presupposes in the
               author the existence of the true spirit of song.” Now a
               poetical contribution, so offered, presupposes in the author only about the ten thousandth part of what Miss Edmond (no doubt through mere grammatical inadvertence)
               has maintained it to presuppose. The “poetical contribution” presupposes in the author not the existence but
               the conviction of the existence, of “the true spirit of
               song”—and here there is about the same difference as
               between Peter Schlemil and his Shadow.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">Oracles from the Poets: A Fanciful Diversion for the Drawing-Room</div>
            <div class="biblPage">210</div>
            <div class="ab">Oracles from the Poets: A Fanciful Diversion for the
               
               <br></br>Drawing-Room. By Caroline Grilman. New-York:
               
               <br></br>Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            </div>
            
            <p>This is the third edition of a book which has been exceedingly popular, and justly so. Nothing could be better adapted for the amusement of an evening party.—
               The game is composed of fourteen questions with sixty
               answers each, numbered. The Oracle, for example, demands of a gentleman—“What is the personal appearance of her who loves you?” The gentleman answers
               with any number from 1 to 60—say 20. Turning to 20,
               the oracle reads as follows, from Washington Allston:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Every thought and feeling throw
               
               <br></br>Their shadows o’er her face,
               
               <br></br>And so are every thought and feeling joined,
               
               <br></br>’Twere hard to answer whether thought or mind
               
               <br></br>Of either were the native place.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>The volume is beautifully printed and bound, and forms
               a most appropriate present.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XXV: Table-Talk</div>
            <div class="biblPage">210</div>
            <div class="ab">Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No.
               
               <br></br>XXV. Table-Talk. By William Hazlitt. Second
               
               <br></br>Series Part I.
            </div>
            
            <p>Of the first series of the Table-Talk we spoke so fully
               in a previous number, that it will be needless to say anything of the second—which is, of course, a continuation.
               In lieu of any comments from ourselves, therefore, we
               make a quotation of some length, on a topic of deep interest treated as only Hazlitt could treat it:
            </p>
            
            <p>Capacity is not the same thing as genius. Capacity may be
               described to relate to the quantity of knowledge, however acquired;
               genius to its quality and the mode of acquiring it. Capacity is
               a power over given ideas or combinations of ideas; genius is the
               power over those which are not given, and for which no obvious
               or precise rule can be laid down. Or capacity is power of any
               sort: genius is power of a different sort from what has yet been
               shown. A retentive memory, a clear understanding is capacity,
               but it is not genius. The admirable Crichton was a person of prodigious capacity; but there is no proof (that I know of) that he
               had an atom of genius. His verses that remain are dull and sterile. He could learn all that was known or any subject; he could
               do anything if others could show him the way to do it. This was
               very wonderful; but that is all you can say of it. It requires a
               good capacity to play well at chess; but alter all, it is a game of
               skill, and not of genius. Know what you will of it, the understanding still moves in certain tracks in which others have trod
               before it, quicker or slower, with more or less comprehension and
               presence of mind. The greatest skill strikes out nothing for itself,
               from its own peculiar resources; the nature of the game is a thing
               determinate and fixed; there is no royal or poetical road to checkmate your adversary. There is no place for genius but in the indefinite and unknown. The discovery of the binomial theorem
               was an effort of genius: but there was none shown in Jedediah
                Buxton’s being able to multiply 9 figures by 9 in his head. If he
               could have multiplied 90 figures by 90 instead of nine, it would
               
               have been equally useless toil and trouble.
               <span class="footnote" id="n002">
                  <span class="footnoteLink">2</span>
                  <span class="footnoteText">The only good thing I ever heard come of this singular man’s
                     faculty of memory was the following. A gentleman was mention-
                     ing his having been sent up to London from where he lived to see
                     Garrick act. When he went back into the country, he was asked
                     what he thought of the player and the play. “Oh!” he said, “he
                     did not know; he had only seen a little man strut about the stage,
                     and repeat 7956 words.” We all laughed at this, but a person in
                     one corner of the room, holding one hand to his forehead, and
                     seemingly mightily delighted, called out, “Ay, indeed! And
                     Pray, was he found to be correct?” This was the supererogation
                     of literal matter-of-fact curiosity. Jedediah Buxton’s counting the
                     number of words was idle enough; but here was a fellow who
                     wanted some one to count them over again to see that he was cor-
                     rect.“The force of dulness could no farther go!"
                  </span>
               </span>He is a man of capacity who possesses considerable intellectual riches: he is a man
               of genius who finds out a vein of new ore. Originality is the
               seeing nature different from all others, and yet as it is in itself.
               It is not singularity or affectation, but the discovery of new and
               valuable truth. All the world do not see the whole meaning of
               any object they have been looking at. Habit blinds them to some
               things; short-sightedness to others. Every mind is not a guage
               and measure of truth. Nature has her surface and her dark recesses. She is deep, obscure, and infinite. It is only minds on
               whom she makes her fullest impressions that can penetrate her
               shrine or unveil her Holy of Holies. It is only those whom she
               has filled with her spirit that have the boldness or the power to reveal her mysteries to others. But nature has a thousand aspects,
               and one man can only draw out one of them. Whoever does this,
               is a man of genius. One displays her force, another her refinement, one her power of harmony, another her suddenness of contrast, one her beauty of form, another her splendor of color. Each
               does that for which he is best fitted by his particular genius, that
               is to say, by some quality of mind into which the quality of the
               object sinks deepest, where it finds the most cordial welcome, is
               perceived to its utmost extent, and where again it forces its way
               out from the fulness with which it has taken possession of the
               mind of the student. The imagination gives out what it has first
               absorbed by congeniality of temperament, what it has attracted
               and moulded into itself by elective affinity, as the loadstone draws
               and impregnates iron. A little originality is more esteemed and
               sought for than the greatest acquired talent, because it throws a
               new light upon things, and is peculiar to the individual. The
               other is common; and may be had for the asking, to any
               amount.
            </p>
            
            <p>The value of any work is to be judged of by the quantity of
               originality contained in it. A very ltttle of this will go a great
               way. If Goldsmith had never written anything but the two or
               three first chapters of the Vicar of Wakefield, or the character of
               a Village Schoolmaster, they would have stamped him a man of
               genius. The Editors of Encyclopedias are not usually reckoned
               the first literary characters of the age. The works, of which they
               have the management, contain a great deal of knowledge, like
               chests or warehouses, but the goods are not their own. We should
               as soon think of admiring the shelves of a library; but the shelves
               of a library are both useful and respectable. I was once applied
               to in a delicate emergency, to write an article on a difficult subject
               for an Encyclopedia, and was advised to take time and give it a
               systematic and scientific form, to avail myself of all the knowledge
               that was to be obtained on the subject, and arrange it with clearness and method. I made answer that as to the first, I had taken
               time to do all that I ever pretended to do, as I had thought incessantly on difierent matters for twenty years of my life;
               <span class="footnote" id="n003">
                  <span class="footnoteLink">3</span>
                  <span class="footnoteText">Sir Joshua Reynolds being asked how long it had taken him to
                     do a certain picture, made answer, “All his life.”
                  </span>
               </span>that I had
               no particular knowledge of the subject in question, and no head
               for arrangement; and that the utmost I could do in such a case
               would be, when a systematic and scientific article was prepared, to
               write marginal notes upon it, to insert a remark or illustration of
               ray own (not to be found in former Encyclopedias) or to suggest a
               better definition than had been offered in the text. There are two
               sorts of writing. The first is compilation; and consists in collecting and stating all that is already known of any question
               in the best possible manner, for the benefit of the uninformed
               reader. An author of this class is a very learned amanuensis of
               other people’s thoughts. The second sort proceeds on an entirely
               different principle. Instead of bringing down the account of
               knowledge to the point at which it has already arrived, it professes to start from that point on the strength of the writer’s individual reflections; and supposing the reader in possession of
               what is already known, supplies deficiencies, fills up certain
               blanks, and quits the beaten road in search of new tracts of observation or sources of feeling. It is in vain to object to this last
               style that it is disjointed, disproportioned, and irregular: It is
               merely a set of additions and corrections to other men’s works, or
               to the common stock of human knowledge, printed separately.
               You might as well expect reasoning in the notes to a book. It
               skips all the trite, intermediate, level common-places of the subject,
               and only stops at the difficult passages of the human mind, or
               touches on some striking point that has been overlooked in previous editions. A view of a subject, to be connected and regular,
               cannot be all new. A writer will always be liable to be charged
               either with paradox or common-place, either with dulness or affectation. But we have no right to demand from any one more than
               he pretends to. There is indeed a medium in all things, but to
               unite opposite excellences is a task ordinarily too hard for mortality. The man who succeeds in what he aims at, or who takes
               the lead in any one mode or path of excellence, may think himself
               very well off. It would not be fair to complain of the style of an
               Encyclopedia as dull, as wanting volatile salt; nor of the style of
               an Essay because it is too light and sparkling, because it is not a
               caput mortuvm. So it is rather an odd objection to a work that it is
               made up entirely of “brilliant passages”—at least it is a fault that
               can be found with few works, and the book might be pardoned for
               its singularity. The censure might indeed seem like adroit flattery, if it were not passed on an author whom any objection is sufficient to render unpopular and ridiculous. I grant it is best to
               unite solidity with show, general information with particular ingenuity. This is the pattern of a perfect style; but I myself do not
               pretend to be a perfect writer. In fine, we do not banish light
               French wines from our tables, or refuse to taste sparkling Champagne when we can get it, because it has not the body of Old Port.
               Besides, I do not know that dulness is strength, or that an observation is slight, because it is striking. Mediocrity, insipidity, want
               of character, is the great fault. Mediocribus esse poctis non Dii, non
               homines, non concessére columna. Neither is this privilege allowed
               to prose-writers in our time, any more than to poets formerly.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is not then acuteness of organs or extent of capacity that constitutes rare genius, or produces the most exquisite models of art,
               but an intense sympathy with some one beauty or distinguished
               characteristic in nature. Irritability alone, or the interest taken
               in certain things, may supply the place of genius in weak and
               otherwise ordinary minds. As there are certain instruments fitted
               to perform certain kinds of labor, there arc certain minds so framed
               as to produce certain chéf-d'æuvres in art and literature, which is
               surely the best use they can be put to. If a man had all sorts of
               instruments in his shop, and wanted one, he would rather have
               that one than be supplied with a double set of all the others. It
               he had them all twice over, he could only do what he can do as it
               is, whereas without that one perhaps he cannot finish any one work
               he has in hand. So if a man can do one thing better than any
               body else, the value of this one thing is what he must stand or fall
               by, and his being able to do a hundred other things merely as well
               as any body else, would not alter the sentence or add to his respectability; on the contrary, his being able to do so many other things
               well would probably interfere with and encumber him in the execution of the only thing that others cannot do as well as he, and so
               far be a drawback and a disadvantage. More people in fact fail
               from a multiplicity of talents and pretensions, than from an absolute poverty of resources. I have given instances of this elsewhere Perhaps Shakspeare’s tragedies would in some respects
               have been better, if he had never written comedies at all; and
               in that case his comedies might well have been spared, though
               they might have cost us some regret. Racine, it is said, might
               have rivalled Molière in comedy; but he gave up the cultivation
               of his comic talents to devote himself wholly to the tragic Muse.—
               If, as the French tell us, he in consequence attained to the perfection of tragic composition, this was better than writing comedies
               as well as Molière and tragedies as well as Crebrillon. Yet I count
               those persons tools, who think it a pity that Hogarth did not succeed better in serious subjects. The division of labor is an excellent principle in taste as well as mechanics. Without this, I find
               by Adam Smith, we could not have a pin made to the degree of
               perfection it is. We do not, on any rational scheme of criticism,
               inquire into the variety of a man’s excellences, or the number of
               his works, or his facility of production. Venice Preserved is sufficient tor Otway’s fame. I hate all those nonsensical stories about
               Lopez de Vega, and his writing a play in the morning before
               breakfast. He had time enough to do it alter. If a man leaves
               behind him any work which is a model in its kind, we have no
               right to ask whether he could do any thing else, or how he did it,
               or how long he was about it. All that talent which is not necessary to the actual quantity of excellence existing in the world, loses
               its object, is so much waste talent, or talent to let. I heard a sensible man say, he should like to do some one thing better than all
               the rest of the world. Why should a man do more than his part?
               The rest is vanity and vexation of spirit. We look with jealous
               and grudging eye at all those qualifications which are not essential; first because they are superfluous, and next, because we suspect they will be prejudicial. Why does Mr. Kean play all those
               harlequin tricks of singing, dancing, fencing, &amp;c.? They say, “It
               is for his benefit.” It is not for his reputation. Garrick, indeed,
               shone equally as well in comedy and tragedy. But he was first,
               not second-rate in both. There is not a greater impertinence than
               to ask if a man is clever out of his profession. I have heard of
               people trying to cross examine Mrs. Siddons. I would as soon try
               to entrap one of the Elgin Marbles into an argument. Good nature
               and common sense are required from all people; but one proud
               distinction is enough for any one individual to possess or to aspire
               to!
            </p>
            
            <p>Of course we admire all this—it is pointedly put—but
               we assent to only about one half of it.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">History of the War in France and Belgium</div>
            <div class="biblPage">212</div>
            <div class="ab">History of the War in France and Belgium, in 1815;
               
               <br></br>Containing Minute Details of Quatre-Bras, Ligny,
               
               <br></br>Wavre, and Waterloo. By Captain W. Siborne, Sec-
               
               <br></br>retary and Adjutant of the Royal Military Asylum;
               
               <br></br>constructor of the “Waterloo Model” first Amer-
               
               <br></br>ican from the Second London edition. With Plans of
               
               <br></br>the Battles and Maps. Philadelphia: Lea and Blan-
               
               <br></br>chard.
            </div>
            
            <p>A beantifully printed volume of nearly 650 pages.
               Captain Siborne, it is well understood, had access, through
               his staff appointment, as well as through private interest, to the most authentic sources of information, and his
               work was looked for with the greatest interest in England, as one that would settle a great many disputed
               points in reference to the Waterloo campaigns. Since
               the issue of the book, much has been said against it—
               but a very great deal more in its favor, and we ure inclined to side with its supporters. An unmistakeable
               air of candor pervades every page, and the accuracy of
               detail seems to be self-demonstrated. The manner is exceedingly good.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">Historical Sketch of the Second War between the United States of America and Great
               Britain
            </div>
            <div class="biblPage">212</div>
            <div class="ab">Historical Sketch of the Second War between the United
               
               <br></br>States of America and Great Britain, declared by Act
               
               <br></br>of Congress, the 18M of June 1812, and Concluded by
               
               <br></br>Peace, the 15th of February 1815. By Charles J. In-
               
               <br></br>gersoll. In Three Volumes. Vol. I. Embracing the
               
               <br></br>Events of 1812-13. Philadelphia: Lea aud Blan-
               
               <br></br>chard.
            </div>
            
            <p>A volume of more than 500 pages octavo. It is rather
               a series of vivid pictures on the subject of the late War,
               than an Historical Sketch of it. Force and novelty
               abound, and we are never permitted to doubt the honesty
               of the narration, but there is a slight tinge of the whim- sical about the book which
               may operate, in the first in
               to prevent a very general appreciation of its merits—which are undoubtedly great. By way of exemplifiing our meaning we quote a brief passage from an account
               of Timothy Pickering.
            </p>
            
            <p>His reputation was that of a consistent upright man, who lived
               and died firm to the conviction he cherished; hard but honest.
               On a great field day debate in 1841, on the Loan Bill, when the
               House, in committee of the whole, gave six weeks to those speeches for political capital at home and abroad, which are among the
               ways and means of free countries with a free press—much preferable to more serious combats—Mr. Pickering, in the course of his
               harangue, looking through his spectacles full in the chairman’s
               face, said, with great emphasis, swinging his long arm aloft, that
               he stood on a rock. “I stand on a rock’, said he “from which all
               democracy”—then raising his voice and repeatrng it—“not all
               democracy and hell to boot, can move me—the rock of integrity and
               truth."
            </p>
            
            <p>“These things are more honored in the breach than in
               the observance”—by silence than by historical record.
               The passage, too, will afford some idea of Mr. Ingersoll’s style which, like Mr. Pickering’s character, is
               “hard but honest”—as well as (more definitely) of his
               mere English, which is loose and uncouth to a very reprehensible degree. Take, for instance, the first paragraph of the volume:
            </p>
            
            <p>In this historical sketch I shall endeavor to submit the truth in
               an account of the contest between Great Britain and the United
               States of America, declared by Act of Congress, approved the 18th
               of June, 1812. It enacted that war was already declared to exist
               between the United Kingdoms of Great Britain and Ireland, and
               the Dependencies thereof, and the U. S. of America and their territories; and that the President of the U. S. was thereby authorized
               to use the whole land and naval force of the U. S., to carry the
               same into effect, and to issue to private armed vessels of the U, S.,
               commissions, or letters of marque and general reprisal, in such
               form as he should think proper, and under the seal of the U. S.
               against the vessels, goods and effects of the government of the said
               United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland and the subjects
               thereof.
            </p>
            
            <p>Here a “contest” is “declared.” Whether the “thereby” in “thereby unauthorized” refers to the territories,
               the war, or the act, it is difficult to determine. “The
               same” is equally ambiguous as regards its reference, and
               it seems to be the “Seal of the U. S.” which is set
               “against the vessels, goods and effects” off the British.
               The whole paragraph is awkward in the extreme.
            </p>
            
            <p>But happily the value of the book does not depend upon
               trifles such as these. It gives a plain, discerning and evidently faithful view of the events of the war, and will be
               received with favor by all who are competent to decide
               upon the worth of an historical treatise.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">Ollendorf's New Method of Learning to Read, Write and Speak the German Language</div>
            <div class="biblPage">212</div>
            <div class="ab">Ollendorf's New Method of learning to read, write,
               
               <br></br>and speak the German Language; to which is added
               
               <br></br>a Systematic Outline of the Different Parts of Speech,
               
               <br></br>their Inflection and Use, with full Paradigms and a
               
               <br></br>Complete Table of the Irregular Verbs. By J. G. Ad-
               
               <br></br>ler, A. B. New-York: D. Appleton&amp; Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>The New Method of Ollendorf affords, unquestionably, the best means of studying the German. In no other grammar do we obtain so much information, so luminously given. His great merit is that he does not plunge
               in medias res res, but begins at the beginning. He presupposes no knowledge on the part of the beginner. Other
               German grammarians take for granted, among other gratuities, an intimate cognizance of the English. The
               work before us is especially rich, too, in its system of
               idiomatic instruction—and in every respect is invaluable.
               We speak feelingly on this subject; for we have felt the
               
               thousand difficulties and ambiguities of other grammars,
               which have been written by good Germanists, certainly,
               but, at the same time, by indifferent metaphysicians._
               To instruct, demands a thorough metaphysical educa-
               tion.
            </p>
            
            <p>We shall speak of this volume at length hereafter.—
               In the meantime we cordailly recommend it. It is admirably gotten up—printed with accuracy in large type,
               and neatly bound.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">Norman's New-Orleans and Environs</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">Norman's New-Orleans and Environs: Containing a
               
               <br></br>Brief Historical Sketch of the Territory and State of
               
               <br></br>Louisiana, and the City of New-Orleans, from the
               
               <br></br>Earliest Period to the Present Time: Presenting a
               
               <br></br>Complete Guide to all Subjects of General Interest in
               
               <br></br>the Southern Metropolis, with a Correct and Improved
               
               <br></br>Plan of the City, Pictorial Illustrations of Public
               
               <br></br>Buildings, etc. etc. New-Orleans: B. B. Norman.
            </div>
            
            <p>We give the full title to show the design of the work;
               which is all that it professes to be—and a little more.—
               A very excellent and satisfactory volume, of about 200
               pages duodecimo, neatly bound. There is a fine steel
               frontispiece of New-Orleans. Mr. Norman proposes to
               issue, on the first of next month, a map of the city to
               accompany the book now published.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Prince and the Pedlar</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">The Prince and the Pedler. A Novel. By Miss Ellen
               
               <br></br>Pickering, Author of “Nan Darrell," etc. New-York:
               
               <br></br>E. Ferrett, &amp; Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>Miss Pickering has written some of the most praiseworthy and popular novels of the day; and “The Prince
               and the Pedler is one of her best.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Modern Standard Drama</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">The Modern Standard Drama. Edited by Epes Sargent,
               
               <br></br>New York: William Taylor, No. 2 Astor-House.
            </div>
            
            <p>All play-goers and play-readers should be careful to
               take this series, as it is issued. It is an exceedingly neat
               and accurate one. We have seen nothing of the kind so
               good. The plays already published are Ion, Fazio, The
               Lady of Lyons, Richelieu, The Wife, and The Honeymoon—the latter to be out this day, (Saturday). The editor’s well-known taste, especially in dramatic matters,
               should answer for the fidelity and for the success of his
               labors.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">Pictorial History of the World</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">Pictorial History of the World. By John Frost, L. L.
               
               <br></br>D.. Philadelphia: Walker &amp; Gillis. New-York: Wil-
               
               <br></br>liam H. Graham.
            </div>
            
            <p>No. 9 is issued. To be completed in 30 numbers, at 25
               cents.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Knickerbocker</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <p>The Knickerbocker for October is unusually good, but
               we are too much pressed for space to do more, just now.
               than recommend to the especial attention of our readers
               the papet entitled “Who are our National Poets?”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Westminster Review</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <p>The Westminster Review for September has been reprinted by Messrs. Leonard Scott &amp; Co., and contains its
               usual amount of valuable matter:—among other things,
               a review of Humboldt’s “Kosmos”—a review of “Sybil”—and a paper on “Shaksperian Criticism and Acting.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Southern Lit. Messenger</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <p>The Southern Lit. Messenger for October contains a
               very condemnatory and in our opinion a very just review
               of “Poems by William W. Lord.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Democratic Review</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <p>The Democratic Review for October has a fine mezzotint of Cave Johnson, and one of the most exciting stories
               We ever read, “The Monomaniac,” by Mrs. E. F. Ellet.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of American Books: No. VI</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">Wiley &amp; Putnam’s Library of American Books. No VI.
               
               <br></br>Wanderings of a Pilgrim under the Shadow of Mount
               
               <br></br>Blanc. By George B. Cheever, D. D.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">History of France from the Earliest Period to the Present Time</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">History of France from the Earliest Period to the Pre-
               
               <br></br>sent Time. By M. Michlet, Professeur-suppléant à la
               
               <br></br>Faculté des Lettres, etc. Translated by G. H. Smith,
               
               <br></br>F. G. S. No. 5. New York: D Appleton dfCo.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Cyclopedia of Several Thousand Practical Receipts</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">A Cyclopedia of Several Thousand Practical Receipts,
               
               <br></br>etc. By Arnold James Cooley. No 5. New York: D.
               
               <br></br>Appleton &amp; Co.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Plea for Social and Popular Repose</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">A Plea for Social and Popular Repose; Delivered be-
               
               <br></br>fore the Literary Societies of the University of the
               
               <br></br>City of New York. By D. D. Barnard.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p25">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Songs of Our Land, and Other Poems</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <div class="ab">The Songs of our Land, and other Poems. By Mary E.
               
               <br></br>Hewitt. Boston: William D. Ticknor &amp; Co. For
               
               <br></br>sale by Langley.
            </div>
            
            <p>We have received these five last publications at too
               late a period to do more than announce them this week.
               To Mrs. Hewitt’s beautiful book, in especial, we shall attend very particularly in our next.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="head">The Fine Arts.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p26">
            <div class="biblTitle">National Gallery at the Rotunda</div>
            <div class="biblPage">213</div>
            <p>National Gallery at the Rotunda.—We proceed
               to picture No. seven, the second of the Series:—we
               might say the second page of the History. In this it is
               evident that society has already made great strides towards civilization. The hunter has long passed away,
               and the shepherd is making room for the husbandman.—
               The locality is nearly, but not quite the same, as in the
               last picture; we have still the “boulder” promontory in
               the distance, but we have shifted our ground, and have
               moved to the right, and further from the river. Before
               us stands a group of glorious trees—primeval giants of
               the forest—beneath whose mighty arms
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>The ground was never trenched by spade,
               
               <br></br>And flowers spring up unseen.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>On the left rises a gentle hill, on which a ploughman is
               seen driving his share into the mellow earth, while in
               the middle distance on the bank of the river, stands an
               eminence crowned with a Druid’s Temple. At the foot,
               on a rock, we see a growing little town. White sails
               are on the sea, an on the shore we see and antique vessel on the stocks. Everything gives indication of an active people, yet all are not busy with the ruder cares of
               life, for the refining arts—Music and Painting—have already dawned. Beneath the shade of the mighty trees,
               we see maidens wreathed with flowers, dancing gaily
               and gracefully to the shepherd’s pipe, and on a huge
               stone (a rustic bridge) in the foreground, an embryo
               painter scrawls his first attempt at the pictorial art.—
               Near him his mother plies the busy spindle, while seated close at hand, an old man traces in the dust a geometrical figure, indicating the beginning of the abstruser
               sciences.
            </p>
            
            <p>The contemplation of this charming production carries
               us back to our boyish dreams of rural felicity all is
               beauty and joy, and but for the presence of an armed
               man, passing through the ravine up to the front of the
               picture, we might suppose it an illustration of the Poet’s
               “Golden Age.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The painter has chosen, with great propriety, the Druidical circle, as the rude temple of the earliest worshippers, while the volumes of smoke which issue from it in-
               
               dicate that living victims heap the altars of a sanguinary
               God.
            </p>
            
            <p>It were tedious to enumerate the thousand little objects
               which attract our attention, and the many delicate tints,
               of which words can convey no idea. As well might we
               attempt to give a description of the exquisite transitions
               of sound in a fine musical composition, as the delicate
               gradations of color from the full green of the foreground,
               to the faint blue haze of the distant landscape. We feel
               that it would be almost hypercritical to pick out faults in
               this composition, and yet the station we have assumed
               calls upon us to display our judgment, by finding fault,
               otherwise the public may conclude that we are no critics.
               Well, gentle readers, we will make an effort to gratify
               you, by wishing that the sheep in the middle ground
               were of an “improved breed,” as they make the shepherd appear too tall.
            </p>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">W.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            <div class="biblTitle">To All Lovers of the True and Beautiful in Art</div>
            <div class="biblPage">214</div>
            <p>To all lovers of the true and beautiful in art we recommend a visit to the Ivory Christ, brought from Italy by
               C. Edwards Lester, our Consul at Genoa, and now being
               exhibited in Broadway opposite the Park. This figure
               (it cannot properly be called a statue) is the work of an
               Italian Monk, an educated man, but with little knowledge of art. A deep enthusiasm—an overwhelming passion to do justice to the intellectual and physical character of the God-man, seems to have been in this case at
               once the instigation and the instruction. The material
               is the tusk of an antique elephant—a tusk of enormous
               size. Much of it had to be cut away on account of its carious condition, and yet the figure is 32 inches long, (we
               believe) and 8 inches broad through the shoulders:—all
               this solid—the arms are wrought from separate pieces.
            </p>
            
            <p>The first point noticeable in this Christ is the intellectuality of its expression. All other representations of the
               Saviour make him merely benevolent, dignified, meek,
               self-sustained, and beautiful in feature. In this, mind—
               genius—predominates. The whole face is eminently intellectual.
            </p>
            
            <p>The second thing to be observed is the absolute truth
               of the entire design. The figure depends from the cross
               precisely as the human form would depend under the circumstances. The moment chosen is that immediately
               succeeding death. We are made to fancy that the last
               sigh has just issued from his lips—on which is now fading a divine smile. We can see, nevertheless, that
               the death has been agonizing. The contraction of
               the muscles, more particularly about the calves, toes
               and lumbar regions, are absolute in the truth of their
               expression. In anatomy the whole figure is perfect. We
               doubt if a better model of the human frame is to be found
               anywhere. The work altogether is of a very high order
               of genius.
            </p>
            
            <p>In our next we shall endeavor to do justice to the inimitable Sortie du Bain—De Kuyper’s—now to be seen at
               the Society Library. We have no patience with those
               who decry it.
            </p>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">P.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Department</div>
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div> 
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p28">
            <div class="biblTitle">Trinity Church Organ</div>
            <div class="biblPage">214</div>
            <p>Trinity Church Organ.—Having been favored, by
               the kindness of Richard Upjohn, Esq., the gifted architect
               of Trinity Church, with an elegant drawing of the front
               elevation of the new Organ which will shortly be erected in that noble edifice, we are enabled this week to afford a similar gratification to our readers, by presenting
               them with a fine engraving on steel of the same, executed by James Duthie.
            </p>
            
            <p>In order to render this the more interesting and intelligible, we have procured from Dr. Edward Hodges, who
               first planned, and now has the oversight and superintendence of the construction of the interior of the ponderous
               instrument, the following particulars concerning its dimensions and intended contents.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of the beautiful and appropriate design of the organ front and
               subjacent screen, harmonizing as it does with the imposing effect
               of the interior of the building, I need not say anything; the drawing will speak for itself. The whole is to be of oak, and much of
               it has already been executed in a most thoroughly substantial and
               workmanlike manner.
            </p>
            
            <p>The height of the screen to the level of the floor of the organ
               loft is 14 feet 5 inches; above which the Organ will tower 38 feet
               farther; making a total elevation of nearly 53 feet.
            </p>
            
            <p>The width of the organ front is 24 feet, but as the floor will be
               trussed out about 4 feet on each side as well as towards the nave,
               the width of the organ-loft will be 34 feet—thus affording abundant room for an effective choir, should it be finally resolved to place
               the choir at that (the wrong) end of the church. This gallery or
               organ-loft will be surrounded, on three sides, by latticed work to a
               considerable altitude, as seen in the drawing.
            </p>
            
            <p>The only way to give a just idea of the nature and extent of
               an Organ, is by stating its leading divisions (e. g. an Organ of
               two, three, or more ranks of keys,) enumerating the stops, and giving the magnitudes of the largest pipes connected with each department, to which all the rest are adjusted in a well known proportional order. Simply to state the number of stops and the
               number of pipes pertaining to each, can communicate no accurate or satisfactory information; for, as the magnitudes in descending the scale increase in geometrical progression, it may happen that a dozen pipes in one organ may require and occupy as
               much room as a thousand pipes in another, or in another part of
               the same instrument. We cannot estimate the power or effect of
               an organ, therefore, by the number of its pipes; any more than
               we could that of a ship of war merely by learning the number of
               guns she carries, without ascertaining whether they are four
               pounders or Paixhan sixty-fours. Suffice it then to add here, for
               the sake of those who have no technical acquaintance with the
               subject, that the lengths of the pipes intended for the Trinity organ vary from nearly thirty feet to something less than an inch,
               and the diameters from three feet to the size of a small goose-quill.
            </p>
            
            <p>A custom has obtained amongst organists and organ-builders
               of naming the pipes and the notes which bear the denomination
               of the letter C in various octaves of the great scale, by the convenient designation of a round number of feet, not precisely accurate as to the actual admeasurement, but near the truth. Thus we
               speak of 2 feet C, of 4 feet C, See. (each octave doubling the foregoing;) and when we come to the bottom, of 32 feet C, although,
               it the pipe be of larger diameter it may not exceed 28 or 29 feet.
               One cause of this has probably been the successive changes of
               pitch, to accommodate modern orchestral instruments; which changes, until a very recent period, were invariably towards the sharper or more acute limit of the scale of musical sounds. And, of
               course, organ-builders have been nothing loath to fall into the prevailing fashion in (his respect, seeing that when the pitch had ascended but a single semitone (and it has been supposed to have
               varied thrice as much,) it lessened the magnitude, the weight, and
               the cost of any given instrument by at least as much as a twentieth part of the whole. At present a check seems to have been
               put upon this innovating tendency, and the pitch may be considered as settled. The public, however, ought to be made aware of the
               fact that fraud can be practised in this particular, and that the pitch
               of an organ is not an affair of so small consequence as some persons would represent it to be.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is deception of another species not seldom exercised with
               regard to this complex instrument. Certain organ-builders, coming to the knowledge of the fact that in the hands of ignorant and
               unskilful organists, the note G G# in the extreme bass was seldom
               put in requisition, affected to consider that note as useless, and so
               omitted it; although, upon an ordinary G G organ this arrangement excluded the largest pipe but one iu every stop. And this 
               
               <div class="figure">
                  <div class="head">The Organ of Trinity Church
                     New-York.
                  </div>
               </div>
               
               practice (which originated, as candor requires me to confess, in
               England,) has continued to our day. Many such organs are still
               built, and advertised for sale—the compass being with audacious
               effrontery stated to be from G G upwards, without any mention
               tion made of this most important deficiency. But as long as good
               people are satisfied to order and purchase organs without any reference to persons competent to afford them professional advice on
               the subject, they must remain content to be duped.
            </p>
            
            <p>Thus much being premised, the following description may possibly become tolerably intelligible even to those who have not
               been initiated in the mysteries of the organ-craft:
            </p>
            
            <p>The Organ for Trinity Church, then, is to consist of four distinct
               departments, having three ranks of manual keys, and one of pedals, or keys for the feet. The manuals pertain to the Swell, the
               Great Organ, and the Choir Organ, respectively. The Swell is an
               organ of 4 ft.; (that, being, as before explained, the size of the
               longest pipe); the Choir Organ, (seen in front, projecting from the
               gallery,] an 8 ft. organ; the Great Organ, 16 ft.; the Pedal Organ,
               32 ft.
            </p>
            
            <p>Little more remains than to give an enumeration of the stops,
               which are to be grouped right and left of the keys, as exhibited in
               the following diagram.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">1	Clarion.
               
               <br></br>2	Trumpet.
               
               <br></br>3	Hautboy.
               
               <br></br>4	Stopped Diapason.
               
               <br></br>5	Double Stopped Diapason.
               
               <br></br>6	Dulciana.
               
               <br></br>7	Open Diapason.
               
               <br></br>8	Principal.
               
               
               <br></br>-----  
               
               
               <br></br>LEFT.                                           RIGHT.
               
               <br></br>Swell.                                          Choir Organ:
               
               <br></br>1                                               22 23
               
               <br></br>2 3                                             24 25 26 
               
               <br></br>4 5 6                                           27 28
               
               <br></br>7 8
               
               <br></br>9
               
               
               <br></br>Couplers.                                       Great Organ.
               
               <br></br>10                                              29 30
               
               <br></br>11 12                                           31 32 33
               
               <br></br>13 14 15                                        34 35
               
               <br></br>16 17                                           36 37 38
               
               <br></br>18                                              39 40
               
               <br></br>19 20                                             
               
               <br></br>                                                Swell Bass.
               
               <br></br>Pedals.                                         40 42    
               
               <br></br>21
               
               <br></br>                                                Bellows.
               
               <br></br>                                                43
               
               
               <br></br>-----
               
               
               <br></br>9 Cornet (5 ranks.)
               
               <br></br>10 Great Organ and Swell at octaves.
               
               <br></br>11 do. do. and do. at unison.
               
               <br></br>12 Great Organ and Choir, do.
               
               <br></br>13 Choir and Swell at octaves.
               
               <br></br>14	Pedals and Choir Organ.
               
               <br></br>15 Choir and Swell.
               
               <br></br>16	Pedals and Great Organ, 16 ft.
               
               <br></br>17 Do. and do.	8 ft. 
               
               <br></br>18 Pedals and Swell Bass.
               
               <br></br>19 Pedals, 32 ft.
               
               <br></br>20 Pedals, 16 ft.
               
               <br></br>21	Double Diapason.
               
               <br></br>22 Bassoon (half stop.)
               
               <br></br>23 Clarionet (half stop.)
               
               <br></br>24 Stopped Diapason.
               
               <br></br>25 Dulciana.
               
               <br></br>26	Principal.
               
               <br></br>27 Flute.
               
               <br></br>28	Fifteenth.
               
               <br></br>29	Trumpet.
               
               <br></br>30 Clarion.
               
               <br></br>31	Sesquialtera (3 ranks.)
               
               <br></br>32 Twelfth.
               
               <br></br>33	Mixture (3 ranks.)
               
               <br></br>34	Fifteenth.
               
               <br></br>35	Large Flute.
               
               <br></br>36	Principal.
               
               <br></br>37	Stopped Diapason.
               
               <br></br>38	Principal.
               
               <br></br>39	Open Diapason.
               
               <br></br>40	Open Diapason.
               
               <br></br>41	Dulciana.
               
               <br></br>42	Serpent.
               
               <br></br>43	Wind.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>The compass or extent of the organs, respectively, is as follows:
               Of the Swell, four octaves and a half, or fifty-four keys; of the
               Choir organ, the same, although at an octave lower pitch, the latter ending at fin alt., the other at f in altissimo; of the Great Organ. five octaves and a half, or sixty-six keys; and of the Pedals,
               two octaves, or twenty-five keys. In connexion with this latter
               department there is this peculiarity, that the stop consists of thirtyseven pipes, and can be drawn so as to play two octaves from 32 ft.
               C, or two octaves from 16 ft. upwards; or both together. The stops
               called “Swell Bass” are also, properly speaking, pedal stops, although they can be acted upon by the manual keys also, so as to
               afford a great variety of effect.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">The number of pipes can now be easily ascertained.
               
               <br></br>Swell,	13	ranks	of 54	pipes each,	-	-	702
               
               <br></br>Choir Organ, 6	“	of	54	“	“	-	-	324
               
               <br></br>Great Organ, 16	“	of	66	“	“	-	-	-	1056
               
               <br></br>Swell Bass, 2	“	of	25	“	“	-	-	-	50
               
               <br></br>Pedals, -	37
               
               <br></br>                                     2169
            </div>
            
            
            <p>The Swell is constructed upon the plan which I first introduced
               in England about twenty years ago, and a full description of which
               I drew up and published in the "Quarterly Musical Magazine &amp;
               Review," vol. 8, No. xxxii., 1826. It may be briefly described as
               resembling in principle the ordinary refrigerator. It consists of
               three distinct boxes or cases, through each of which (when closed)
               the sound has to pass ere it reaches (he ear. Thus the most delicate effects, in the way of expression, are capable of being produced, by the gradual removal or interposition of obstacles to the
               transmission of sound.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Pedal keys likewise are as yet comparatively new in this
               country, being of brass. These I likewise introduced in England a
               year or two prior to my new swell, and described in No. xxxii of
               the periodical just mentioned. They must gradually make their
               way into extensive use, as they afford great facilities to the player,
               enabling him to do a great deal more with one foot than wa3 before
               at all practicable, and thus setting the other at liberty for the command of the swell.
            </p>
            
            <p>The number of coupling stops in the organ is, I believe, almost
               if not altogether unprecedented. They will conduce to almost interminable varieties of combinations. It would be a wearisome
               task to attempt to calculate them. There will, therefore, be great
               room for the exhibition of taste and skill in their adaptation to specific purposes of accompaniment, &amp;c.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Henry Erben is the contractor, and the work has already
               made very considerable progress, nearly all the machinery of the
               organ being in a state of forwardness, at his spacious and wellfurnished factory in Centre street. The workmen employed deserve great credit for the masterly manner in which they have acquitted themselves hitherto in the construction of this unique instrument; and if the voicing of the pipes (not commenced) shall
               prove as satisfactory as the mechanism unquestionably is, the public may expect to hear an organ which will add to the attractions
               of this great city.
            </p>
            
            <p>I am afraid that my description will be found tediously long;
               but, like the witty Frenchman who apologized to his friend for
               sending him so long a letter, I must say that I had not time to
               write it shorter.
            </p>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">E. H.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p29">
            <div class="biblTitle">Ole Bull's Second Concert</div>
            <div class="biblPage">215</div>
            
            <p>Ole Bull’s Second Concert.—We attended the second
               concert of this artist, having received from him at length,
               though unsolicited, the courtesy of the usual free admissions. No concert of his in this city has ever been so
               poorly attended. The vast area of the Tabernacle contained not more than from five to six hundred listeners of
               all sorts. We copy the programme of the evening:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">                     PART I.
               
               <br></br>1.	Grand	Overture,.......................................Full	Orchestra.
               
               <br></br>2.	Song,..................................................Mr.	Duffield.
               
               <br></br>3.	Sicillia a	e Tarrentella, composed and performed by Ole Bull.
               
               <br></br>4. Song,.................................................Miss	Northall,
               
               <br></br>5. Norges Fjelde, Mountains of Norway, Fanta-
               
               <br></br>   sia, composed and performed by.....................Ole Bull,
               
               <br></br>                         PART II.
               
               <br></br>1. Song,..................................................Mr.	Duffield,
               
               <br></br>2. Carnival of Venice, composed by Paganini,
               
               <br></br>         and performed by...............................Ole Bull,
               
               <br></br>3.	Song,.................................................Miss	Northall.
               
               <br></br>4.	Polacca Guerriera, composed and performed by....Ole Bull.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>Mr. Duffield comes to us from the Western country,
               and the only recommendation we have seen of his talent
               is copied from some Westem paper, and concludes with
               
               something to this effect:—“He never sings the song
               “Fifty years ago” without receiving demonstrations of
               delight from a buck-eyed auditory.” This is praise considerable, but we do not think it will weigh much with
               our Northern people. Mr. Duffield has a light, pleasing
               and melodious voice, but of its compass and power we
               were unable to judge, for his intonation was so faulty,
               and his manner so cold and uncultivated, that we rarely
               heard the true quality of his organ. However, the indications were sufficient to warrant the opinion, that, with
               careful and hard study, he may become an ornament to
               his profession. His last song was “Stand to your guns.”
               It requires great descriptive powers, a vast deal of energy, and a most powerful voice. Mr, Duffield, at present,
               lacks all these qualifications, and consequently the song
               was a failure. He took the tempo of the song nearly one
               half too slow; at least, the conductor, Mr. Hill, lead the
               song off too slow, and the singer followed—but presently
               Mr. Duffield, by a variety of expressive gestures, intimated his wish that the time should be increased; the conductor took the hint, and communicated the same to the
               band, which ultimately consented to accede to their united wishes.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of Miss Northall we spoke last week, and we saw no
               reason on this occasion to alter our opinion then expressed. She has a most beautiful voice, and we should be
               delighted to find that she cultivated it to advantage, for
               she is quite young yet, and has, we hope, many years in
               prospective which may yield her high honor and large
               profit. In her last song, with orchestral accompaniments, it was really painful to hear how the conductor
               labored with hands and feet to impress the tempo upon
               the band, and it was equally painful to observe what very
               little success attended his efforts.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of Ole Bull we have much to say, both in praise and
               in condemation. We cannot but admire his adagio performances; they are full of passion and sentiment. His
               allegros are brilliant and forcible, and his scherzos are
               piquant and striking; but with all these undoubted excellences, there is mingled so much of trickery and what
               is termed professional “gaggery,” that the beauties are
               often clouded, and sometimes quite obscured. Many of
               his peculiarities are undoubtedly the natural impulse of
               his genius, which is nothing if not wildly eccentric; but
               there are others which display no other intention than to
               tickle the ears, without appealing to the mind.
            </p>
            
            <p>Ole Bull was wretchedly accompanied; we really felt
               for him. He tried all he could to lead the conductor by
               gesture and cue, but they were mostly at difference, and
               the band differed from both, producing confusion worse
               confounded.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p30">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Musical Convention</div>
            <div class="biblPage">216</div>
            
            <p>The Musical Convention had its sitting this week at
               the Tabernacle. The only object of the Convention, as far
               as we can learn, is to procure a large sale for Boston Music books—from which we especially pray to be preserved
               —and to exalt a few little men into falsely magnified
               positions, before a portion of the public. Why did not
               the Boston Convention stay in Boston?
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p31">
         <div class="biblTitle">Editorial Miscellany</div>
         <div class="biblPage">216</div>
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>
         
         <p>The New-York Mirror has been much enlarged, and
            in some respects greatly improved—although we regret
            the necessity of the brevier in place of the bold bourgeois
            —and although we miss the original and racy editorials
            of Willis. In newspaper not less than in theatrical management we think the * system is a bad one.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. or Mrs. Asterisk honored us lately with half a column which we have been sadly at a loss to comprehend.
            Can any of our readers help us out?
         </p>
         
         <p>Poe-lemical.—In the last number of the Broadway Journal, the
            critical and learned editor reiterates his opinion of Mr. Simms,
            whom he considers the “best novelist that this country has, upon
            the whole produced.” Mr. Poe seems to have quite an original
            and peculiar standard of judging of the merits of men and books.
            Success is the common measure of talent, not only in regard to the
            productions of literary men, but in business also, in works of art
            or of usefulness; and in all the varied pursuits of life. It is the
            victory that confers fame on the hero, father than brave bearing,
            and manly courage on the battle-field. We are too apt to look at
            results merely, and to honor and praise the successful, rather than
            the meritorious man. In business, the millionare, into whose lap
            fortune has poured her treasures, and to whose prosperity the winds
            of heaven have seemed subservient, gains with his wealth the reputation of being wiser and shrewder than his competitors, who
            may perhaps have struggled harder, and reasoned better, and yet
            been thwarted in their efforts beyond avoidance or control. And
            in literature, also, the popular man, is the great man,—the author
            who sells best—who is most read—and oftenest quoted,—he is the
            man whom the people will honor in spite of all the critics. But
            then one class of philosophers tell us that the judgment of the million is always wrong—that the great majority of men, blinded by
            passion, and swayed by prejudice, are wholly incapable of deciding
            in matters of taste or morals, in politics or religion. On the other
            hand, there are many "learned Thebans,” who as strenuously
            maintain that the voice of the multitude is the voice of truth and
            God; and that in all cases it is the duty of the minority to acquiesce in the verdict of the people. Here, we take it, is the great
            rock on which politicians, moralists, and critics split and separate.
            Leaving this primal question as undecided as it is likely to remain
            until the “World’s Convention” shall eradicate from human nature all the causes which lead to differences in the opinions of men,
            we are inclined to believe that it is above the power of any single
            critic—or of all the critics in the country combined, to convince
            the world that William Gilmore Simms is a better novelist than
            Cooper, or Brockden Brown. He is certainly less known and read
            at home and abroad. We doubt if the copy-right of all Mr.
            Simms’ collected works would bring as good a price in America
            or England, as the "Norman Leslie” of Fay, or the "Sketch
            Book” of Irving. But our surprise at Mr. Poe’s estimate is somewhat diminished, when, on turning to another article, we find him
            speaking of our old friend, “Christopher North,” as “the ignorant
            and egotistical Wilson!” and adding, that, “with the exception
            of Macaulay and Dilke, and one or two others, there is not in
            Great Britain a critic who can be fairly considered worthy the
            name!" This is indeed, “bearding the lion in his den;” and as
            Mr. Poe is preparing to publish an edition of his "Tales" in
            England, (omitting the story of the Gold Bug, we suppose,) he can
            expect but little mercy from the Amir-biting reviews of the Lockharts and Fonblanques, those bull-dogs of the English press. It is,
            however, a matter of some pride that we have, at least, one critic,
            who is brave and Quixotic enough to attack any wind-mill, either
            in Europe or America, however formidable it may appear; and
            our good wishes go with our valiant neighbor.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. (or Mrs.) Star suggests here first, (if we are not
            mistaken) that success is (or is not) the test of merit, and
            secondly, that it is not (or is). Are we right in this interpretation? No doubt of it.
         </p>
         
         <p>The separation of our passage about Mr. Simms from
            its context, brings about a total misrepresentation of our
            ideas.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Simms is “better known” than Brockden Brown.</p>
         
         <p>Putting the author of “Norman Leslie” by the side of
            the author of the “Sketch-Book,” is like speaking of
            “The King and I”—of Pop Emmons and Homer—of a
            Mastodon and a mouse. If we were asked which was
            the most ridiculous book ever written upon the face of
            the earth—we should answer at once, “Norman Leslie.”
         </p>
         
         <p>We are not “preparing to publish” our Tales in Eng
            
            land; we leave such manoeuvres to
            those who are in the habit of bowing
            down to the Golden Calf of the British
            opinion. Our book, to be sure, has been
            re-published in England—long ago—
            but we had nothing to do with its republication, Should we ever think of
            such a thing, however, we should undoubtedly give The “Bug” a more prominent position than it even occupies at
            present. We should call the book “The
            Gold-Bug and Other Tales”—instead
            of “Tales,” as its title stands. However highly we respect Mr. Willis’ talents, we feel nothing but contempt for
            his affectations.
         </p>
         
         <p>But we have a curiosity to solve the
            anonymous of the * The star-dust
            theory is exploded—but can any one
            tell us which is the very smallest of
            all the stars to be found in the “Milky
            Way”?
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">217</div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PAINE &amp; BURGESS</div>
            
            <div class="ab">HAVE JUST PUBLISHED
               
               <br></br>THE CITIZEN OF a REPUBLIC, by
               
               <br></br>Ansaldo Ceba. 1 vol. 12 mo. “A book
               
               <br></br>of rare and condensed thoughts, like dia-
               
               <br></br>monds finely polished and richly set.”
            </div>
            
            <p>The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli,
               2 vols. 12 mo. “The charmed records of
               the classic city of the Arno, by the master
               spirit of his age.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The Challenge of Barletta, a Romance of
               the Times of the Medici. 1 vol. 12 mo. “A
               gem gathered from the jewelled mines of
               Italian Romance.”
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">WILL PUBLISH SOON,
               
               <br></br>The Autobiography of Alfieri.
               
               <br></br>Melodies, by Gen. Geo. P. Morris.
               
               <br></br>The Artist, Merchant and Statesman. 2
               
               <br></br>vols. 12 mo. By C. Edwards Lester.
               
               <br></br>Prairiedom; or Texas and New Estrama-
               
               <br></br>dura. By a Southerner. 1 vol. 12 mo.
               
               <br></br>A New Work on Greece. By G. A. Per-
               
               <br></br>dicari, U. S. Consul at Athens. 2 vols. 12
               
               <br></br>mo.
               
               <br></br>Rambles by Land and Water, or Notes of
               
               <br></br>Travel in Cuba and Mexico. By B. M.
               
               <br></br>Norman, author of Rambles in Yucatan, etc.
               
               <br></br>1 vol. Illustrated.
               
               <br></br>Fanny Forrester’s First Book of Sketches.
               
               <br></br>Man in the Republic. By C. Matthews.
               
               <br></br>32 mo. Gilt. A new and carefully revised
               
               <br></br>edition.
               
               <br></br>The Prince. By Machiavelli.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">161 Broadway, September, 1845.</div>
            
            <div class="head">WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'S
               Library OF CHOICE READING.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">“BOOKS WHICH ARE BOOKS.”</div>
            
            <p>THE PUBLISHERS of the Library of Choice
               Heading beg leave to call attention to the following clarification of the books published in the
               series by which it will appear that novelty, variety,
               and standard merit have always been preserved,
               and the promise of the original prospectus faithfully,
               kept. It was proposed to publish "the best books of
               Travels, Biographies, works of Classic Fiction— 
               where the moral is superior to the mere story, with
               out any sacrifice of the interest—occasional choice 
               volumes of Poetry, Essays, Criticism. Contributions
               to History, and generally such single volumes, written by men of genius as will equally delight the 
               scholar and the general reader.” The books already
               issued and ready for immediate publication may be
               arranged as follows:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">BOOKS OF TRAVELS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">EOTHEN, OR TRACES OF TRAVEL BROUGHT
               
               <br></br>home FROM THE EAST.
               
               <br></br>FRENCH IN ALGIERS. By Lady Duff
               
               <br></br>Gordon.
               
               <br></br>THE CRESCENT AND THE CROSS—2 vols. By
               
               <br></br>Warburton.
               
               <br></br>Sir Francis HEAD'S BUBBLES FROM THE
               
               <br></br>BRUNNEN.
               
               <br></br>BECKFORD'S ITALY, SPAIN, PORTUGAL, AND
               
               <br></br>VISIT TO THE MONASTERIES OF ALCO-
               
               <br></br>BACA AND BATALHA—in press.
               
               <br></br>NOTES ON A JOURNEY THROUGH FRANCE
               
               <br></br>AND ITALY. By Hazlitt—in runs.
            </div>
            
            <p>These will be followed by Sir Francis Head’s
               Rough Notes of a Journey across the Pampas;—
               Waterton’s Wanderings in South America; Miss
               Rigby’s Letters from the Baltic; Henry Nelson
               Coleridge’s Six Months in the West Indies, and
               Thackeray’s Notes of a Journey from London to
               Cairo, and others—forming altogether one of the
               most original and select collections of books of travels ever published.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">CLASSIC FICTION.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">MARY SCHWEIDLER, THE AMBER WITCH
               
               <br></br>The most interesting Trial for Witchcraft ever 
               
               <br></br>published.
               
               <br></br>UNDINE AND SINTRAM AND HIS COMPAN-
               
               <br></br>IONS. From the German of La Motte Fouque. 
               
               <br></br>THE DIARY OF LADY WILLOUGHHY
               
               <br></br>HEADLONG HALL AND NIGHTMARE. ABBEY 
               
               <br></br>ZSCHOKKE’S TALES. Translated by Parke God-
               
               <br></br>win.
               
               <br></br>THE CROCK OF GOLD. By Martin Farquhar
               
               <br></br>Tapper.
               
               <br></br>HEART AND THE TWINS. By Marlin Farquhar
               
               <br></br>Tupper.—in press.
            </div>
            
            <p>Under this department will be included the choicest
               new works of fiction as they issue from the press
               and choice translations from the writers of the Continent. The following have been already announc
               ed: Mrs. INCHBALD'S Nature and Art; Tales from
               TIECK and Hoffman, the White Lady and Peter
               Schlemihl; The Life and Adventures of Peter Wilkins, a Cornish Man; Melincourt and Crotchet Castle, by the author of Headlong Hall.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">ILLUSTRATIONS OF ENGLISH LITERATURE
               
               <br></br>LEIGH HUNTS IMAGINATION AND FANCY
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT’S DRAMATIC WRITERS OF THE
               
               <br></br>AGE OF ELIZABETH.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT’S CHARACTERS OF SHAKSPEARE
               
               <br></br>WILSON’S GENIUS AND CHARACTER OF 
               
               <br></br>BURNS.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT’S LECTURES ON THE COMIC WRI-
               
               <br></br>TERS—in press.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT’S LECTURES ON THE ENGLISH
               
               <br></br>POETS—in PRESS
            </div>
            
            <p>The works of Hazlitt in this department, the
               most eloque t commentator on English Literature,
               will be followed by various writings of Campbell,
               Wilson, COLERIDGE, SOUTHEY, Ellis and others.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">BIOGRAPHY AND GENERAL LITERATURE.
               
               <br></br>LEIGH HUNT’S INDICATOR AND COMPANION— 2 vols.
               
               <br></br>HOOD’S PROSE AND VERSE—2 vols.
               
               <br></br>CHARLES LAMB'S ESSAYS Of ELIA.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT'S TABLE TALK—2d seriәs, 2 vols.
               
               <br></br>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF BENVENUTO CELLINI
               
               <br></br>—IN PRESS.
            </div>
            
            <p>A complete collection of the writings of Hazlitt
               and Leigh Hunt will form part of the senes to be
               published at short intervals; Walter Satage Lan
               dor's writings: De Quincet’s (the English opium
               eater) Miscellaneous Writings; names Smith's Rejected Addresses and the Poems and Ballads of Box
               Gualtier.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">OLD ENGLISH LITERATURE.
               
               <br></br>BASIL MONTAGU’S SELECTIONS FROM TAY-
               
               <br></br>LOR. SOUTH, BARROW. FULLER, &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>CHARLES LAMB’S SPECIMENS OF OLD ENG-
               
               <br></br>LISH DRAMATISTS WHO LIVED ABOUT 
               
               <br></br>THE TIME OF SHAKSPEARE.
            </div>
            
            <p>These, the most perfect collections of the kind
               ever published, will form the introduction in prose
               and verse to a series of the old English writers,
               including Sir Thomas More, Herbert, Fuller,
               Sir Thomas Browse, Milton, Selden, Bacon and
               others.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">AMERICAN SERIES.
               
               <br></br>Of the “Library of American Books, the fol-
               
               <br></br>lowing have already been issued:
               
               <br></br>JOURNAL OF AN AFRICAN CRUISER, EDITED
               
               <br></br>BY NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE.
               
               <br></br>LETTERS FROM ITALY. BY J T. HEADLEY.
               
               <br></br>THE WIGWAM AND THE CABIN. BY W. GIL-
               
               <br></br>MORE SIMMS. 
               
               <br></br>BIG ABEL AND THE LITTLE MANHATTAN, 
               
               <br></br>BY CORNELIUS MATHEWS.
               
               <br></br>WANDERINGS OF THE PILGRIM UNDER THE
               
               <br></br>SHADOW OF THE JUNGFRAU, BY GEORGE
               
               <br></br>B, CHEEVER, D. D.—Just ready.
            </div>
            
            <p>The following are in press:—Western Clearings,
               by Mary Clavers (Mrs. Kirkland); Wanderings
               of a Pilgrim under the Shadow of the Jungfrau by
               George B. Cheever; Views and Reviews in American History, Literature, and Fiction, a Miscellany,
               by W. Gilmore Simms; The Forest and the Prairie
               by James hall, author of the Border tales; a new
               volume, by Nathaniel Hawthorne; The Old English Library. by W. N. Jones; and other productions
               of American authors.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Gurney's
               PREMIUM DAGUERRIAX GALLERY,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">189 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.</div>
            
            <p>PICTURES taken at this Establishment
               are not excelled in this country—so say
               his numerous patrons. The public are invited to call and judge for themselves. O2
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MESSRS. HARPER &amp; BROTHERS</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PUBLISH THIS DAY,
               
               <br></br>Elements of Morality and Polity.
               
               <br></br>BY PROF. WHEWELL.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS valuable new production, from the pen of
               one if the most eminent scholars of the age,
               exhibits, in a most lucid, exact, and elegant style,
               the great principles of moral, political, and ecclesiastical science in a far more complete and methodical manner than has ever met been presented to the
               Public. In offering this great work to the American
               reader, the publisher begs leave to introduce it as
               the commencement of a new and a tractive series
               of sterling books, to be issued by them, under the
               general designation of
               HARPER’S NEW MISCELLANY;
               the volumes of which will be legibly printed, in
               duodecimo, on fine paper, and
               Bound, in extra Muslin Gilt—Price
               Fifty Cents a Volume,
               and issued at short intervals. To render accessible
               to the million, the fullest advantages of popular instruction in the various divisions of human knowledge, is the design of the above series. It is apparent in the present day, that books of intrinsic value
               are demanded by the people. Formerly the popular taste preferred mainly works of mere amusement
               —the great body of readers now seek them as vehicles of general knowledge books of a more permanently valuable caste—devoted to some of the
               departments of science, or general literature. A
               new race has sprung up, glowing with the first
               energies of youth, requiring more expanded ideas
               of the world in  which they live, and a more reliable
               and well-digested knowledge of the men. and the
               events of other times and countries. A class of
               books expressly adapted to this demand, it is the
               aim of the publishers to supply; and at a price so
               exceedingly cheap that every person of ordinary
               taste and advantages may thus become possessed
               of a
               Complete Library of the Best Literature of the Age.
            </p>
            
            <p>In this collection it is intended to include the best
               productions in every department of knowledge;
               popular philosophical treatises on topics of universal interest; the most compact and brilliant historical books; valuable biographical memoirs; modern
               voyages and travels, &amp;c.; together with scientific
               and other collateral divisions; in the selection of
               all which, the most careful discrimination will be
               observed A mere glance over the wide domain of
               our English literature will exhibit much yet unexplored and uncultivated, from which might be gathered the fruits of a rich, luxuriant harvest; besides
               which, the ever-teeming issues of the European
               press open a vast revenue of literary wealth, from
               which the above collection may be liberally supplied. Original productions from American writers
               will also occasionally be introduced. In submitting,
               therefore, the esteemed work of Prof. Whewell
               as a kind of first fruits of their "New Miscellany,”
               the publishers deem it only necessary to add, that
               their arrangements for carrying forward the enterprise being of the most complete and efficient kind,
               they confidently rely upon their efforts being met
               with a ready response from the entire reading community.
            </p>
            
            <p>This, they venture to believe, will be insured to
               their Miscellany, no less from the intrinsic value
               of the collection, than from its unparalleled economy; each volume being elegantly produced, bound
               IN HANDSOME AND SUBSTANTIAL STYLE. FITTED WITHOUT FARTHER EXPENSE FOR PERMANENT PRESERVAtion in the library; the whole series being issued
               in uniform binding, while the price of each volume
               will be only Fifty Cents—far below the cost of
               any similar series of books yet published in this,
               are, it is believed, any other country.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES.</div>
            <p>—THOMAS H.—CHAMBERS,
               (formerly Conductor to Dubois and Stodart),
               No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment
               if the latest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes,
               of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared
               to guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch,
               and External Finish, and to elude in any climate,
               a liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano
               Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always
               on hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PENMANSHIP.</div>
            
            <p>Reopening of Goldsmiths Writing
               ACADEMY, 289 Broadway. LA Farge Buildings corner of Reade Street. Terms reduced to
               THREE DOLLARS, AND NO EXTRA CHARGE.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the
               citizens of New York and Brooklyn, that his rooms
               are now open, during the day and evening, for Pupuils and Visiters. Mr. G's specimens of
               PENMANSHIP
               has received the First Premium Five Years, from
               the American Institute, and he guarantees to all in
               TEN easy AND INTERESTING EXERCISES,
               a free and elegant style of writing that the pupils
               cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale at the Academy GOLDSMITH'S GEMS
               OF PENMANSHIP.
            </p>
            
            <p>Ladies’ Class meets daily at 11 o’clock. Gentle
               men’s day and evening. See Circular. s18
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. F. BROWNE &amp; CO.
               MANUFACTURER OF THE
               IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION HARP,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years with Erard.</div>
            
            <p>J. F. BROWNE respectfully informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has established
               himself for the manufacture
               and importation of these very beautiful instruments, at
                                       281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET.
            </p>
            
            <p>His arrangements are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices,
               thereby saving purchasers the high duties
               imposed by Tariff on these Instruments.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. F. Browne would observe, these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
               with all the modern improvements of
               London and Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy of tone, fineness of touch, and perfectness
               of mechanism. Particular care is taken
               to fit them for the extremes of climate in this country, in which respect they will
               be found far superior to any of European manufacture, imported in the usual way.
            </p>
            
            <p>These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and professional talent in
               Europe; among the latter, he would mention
               N. C. Boscha, who invariably selects from this establishment.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. F. Browne begs to offer the opinions of some of the first professional talent in
               this country.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:--Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making
               a professional use of your Harps, and of
               testing their qualities, it affords me pleasure to certify, that in point of tone,
               workmanship, and above all, a solidity that stands proof
               against the inconstancy of our trying climate, they have in all cases given me the
               most entire satisfaction.
                  January, 1845.	                                                 I am yours, CHARLES
               THIBAULT, No. 40 Beach St., N. Y.
            </p>
            
            <p>Dear Sir:--I write to express the delight I experienced in performing on one of your
               Harps at Sig. Casella’s Concert in this city.—
               The mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly superior to any harp I
               have heard for many years. I remember my old
               Master, Boscha, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no
               other. Yours most truly, H. G. TRUST.
               Philadelphia, March 4th, 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:--I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make
               I performed on at the St. George’s Society
               Concert, is, in brilliancy of tone, touch, and elegance of workmanship, the finest
               I ever played on. This will apply to all your Harps.
               The grand six and a half Gothic Double action, is a most splendid instrument. Yours,
               with respect, ELIZABETH SLOMAN.
                   New York, January 16th, 1845.	                                 A pupil of N.C.
               Boscha
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:--Having at your request closely scrutinized your double-action
               Harps, I find they possess the best qualities of the first makers in Europe combined. That in the ease of touch, by which the
               most brilliant tone is obtained in perfection and
               ease of modulation, they are superior to any I have used; their elegance of exterior
               must gratify the most refined taste. Your new
               Grand Gothic six and a half octave, is the most splendid effort of art yet produced
               in the musical world; it will give me great pleasure
               in recommending your Harps at every opportunity.	Yours Truly, HENRY HORN
                   January 12th, 1845.	                                           An eminent professor,
               and Member of the Royal Academy.
            </p>
            
            <p>These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
               show the estimate of persons every wav capable of
               making a correct decision. J. F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the
               Society of Arts, Philadelphia for his splendid
               improvements in this delightful Instrument.
            </p>	
            
            <p>Harps from 300 to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.</div>
            
            <p>B.B MINOR, Proprietor. Published monthly,
               at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            </p>
            
            <p>The MESSENGER has been established since
               1835, has a large subscription list, and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office
               of the “Broadway Journal,"  135 Nassau street.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JUST PUBLISHED BY H. G. DAGGERS,</div>
            <div class="ab">30 Ann
               
               <br></br>Street, New York.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE COTTON LORD By Mrs. Stone A Ro
               mance of the Rich and Poor, written by a lady of
               brilliant talents. 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>FRANKENSTEIN, by Mrs. Marry W. Shelley,
               wife of the illustrious poet. “It is among the most
               exciting and terrible of modern romances."—Tri
               bune. 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>LAWRIE TODD, by John Galt, with an original
               preface by the original Lawrie Todd, viz: Grant
               Thorburn, Esq. “Mr. Thorburn’s Preface is worth
               more than the price asked for the novel." 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE NUN: or, Life in a Convent. By one of
               the Sisterhood “A terrible exposition of the secret
               practices of Roman Catholics.’’ 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>POOR JACK. By Captain Marryatt, author of
               Midshipman Easy, Peter Simple, &amp;c. 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B. All of the above will be sent for One Dol
               lar to any person ordering them through Postmasters, who are by law authorized to remit money to
               publishers. Any Postmaster ordering the above
               shall be presented with either novel he may select.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">ÆOLIAN ATTACHMENT.</div>
            
            <p>HERMANN'S SARONI, Professor of Music, 116
               Leonard street, New York, teaches the Piano
               Forte, with or without Coleman's celebrated At
               tachment.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANOFORTES</div>
            <p>-H. WORCESTEB, NO. 139
               THIRD AVENUE, Corner of 14th Street, res
               pectfully informs his friends and the public, that he
               has a good assortment of Piano Fortes, in Rosewood
               and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons
               wishing to purchase will find it to their advantage
               to call and examine before purchasing elsewhere.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BEETHOVEN'S MOUNT OF OLIVES AND
               the SEVEN SLEEPERS
            </div>
            <p>-During the week of
               the American Musical Convention —The sublime
               Oratorio of the Mount of Olives, by the immortal
               Beethoven, and the Seven Sleepers, by Dr. Lowe,
               will be performed at the Tabernacle, on Thursday
               evening, the 9th October next, under the direction of
               MR. GEORGE LODER.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Chorus and Orchestra will be full and effective, and the solo parts will be sustained by resident
               talent
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. H. C. TIMM will preside at the Organ.</p>
            
            <p>Tickets, 50 cents each, may be obtained on and
               after Thursday next, at the principal music stores
               Subscribers will receive three tickets for one dollar
               as usual.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">HENRY MEIGGS, 446 Broadway.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">G. H. DERWORT, PROFESSOR OF SINGING.</div> 
            
            <p>Guitar and Piano Forte, has opened a class
               for Young Ladies, from 7 to 10 years of age, among
               whom are three of his own daughters, whom he
               proposes to thoroughly instruct in the art of Singing.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr Derwort’s system is the result of many years'
               observation and experience, during which he has
               successfully taught in Germany, London, and New
               York. His method cannot fail to impart to his pupils a clear perception and a thorough knowledge
               of the grammatical principles of music with the
               ability to harmonize any simple given melody.
            </p>
            
            <p>Parents and guardians are invited to call at his
               Rooms, 427 Broadway, when every inquiry will be
               answered.
            </p>
            
            <p>Terms $20 per annum, payable quarterly in ad
               vance. Lessons three times a week.
            </p>
            
            <p>Private instruction as heretofore.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER</div>
            <p>-JAMES
               PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near
               Elm. A Large Stock of the finest instruments al
               ways on hand. Terms moderate. FOR SALE—A
               Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a great
               bargain for cash.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">WEDDING, VISITING, &amp; PROFESSIONAL.
               CARDS,
            </div>
            <div class="ab">engraved and printed at VALEN-
               
               <br></br>TINE'S, 1 Beckman street—Lovejoy's Hotel.
            </div>
         </div>
         
           
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. BALLARD, PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Singing, and Flute, No. 135 8pring street.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">CARD OF REMOVAL.</div>
            <p>—MR. W. A. KING,
               Professor of Music and Teacher of the PianoForte and Organ, has Removed to the First House
               above Twenty-Fifth Street on the Rail-Road (4th
               Avenue)
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div>
         <div class="note" type="headnote">Our First Volume.—A few copies of
            the first volume of the Broadway Jonrnal are for sale at the office, either in
            numbers or neatly bound.
         </div>
         
         <div class="head">AGENTS.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>M. Baullemet, Mobile, Ala.
            
            <br></br>Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O.
            
            <br></br>D. M. Dewey, Rochester, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>W. E. Russell, Schenectady, N. Y
            
            <br></br>Levi Willard, Troy, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>G. Jones, Albany. N. Y.
            
            <br></br>S. F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore, Md.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.
            
            <br></br>Thos. H. Peade, New-Haven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>J. C. Morgan, New-Orleans.
            
            <br></br>W. W. Kingslev, New-London, Ct.
            
            <br></br>G. N. Beesley, Utica, N Y.
            
            <br></br>H. B. Strang, Peekskill, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Haliburton &amp; Dudley Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Peter Cooke, Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>H. Eaten, Providence, R. I.
            
            <br></br>Safford &amp; Park, Norwich. Ct.
            
            <br></br>John Tomlin, P. M. Jackson, Tenn.
            
            <br></br>S. Hart, Sen., Charleston, 8. C.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      <div class="note" id="n001">
         <a href="/#/issues/18451011/p4">Montfleury. The author of the Parnasse Réformé makes him
            thus speak in Hades:—“L'homme done qui voudrait savoir ce dont
            Je suis mort, qui'l ne demande pas si’l fut de fievre ou de podagre
            on d'autre chose, mais qu'il entende que ce fut de 'L'Andromache.’"
         </a>
      </div>
      
      <div class="note" id="n002">
         <a href="/#/issues/18451011/p9">The only good thing I ever heard come of this singular man’s
            faculty of memory was the following. A gentleman was mentioning his having been sent up to London from where he lived to see
            Garrick act. When he went back into the country, he was asked
            what he thought of the player and the play. “Oh!” he said, “he
            did not know; he had only seen a little man strut about the stage,
            and repeat 7956 words.” We all laughed at this, but a person in
            one corner of the room, holding one hand to his forehead, and
            seemingly mightily delighted, called out, “Ay, indeed! And
            Pray, was he found to be correct?” This was the supererogation
            of literal matter-of-fact curiosity. Jedediah Buxton’s counting the
            number of words was idle enough; but here was a fellow who
            wanted some one to count them over again to see that he was correct.“The force of dulness could no farther go!"
         </a>
      </div>
      
      <div class="note" id="n003">
         <a href="/#/issues/18451011/p9">Sir Joshua Reynolds being asked how long it had taken him to
            do a certain picture, made answer, “All his life.”
         </a>
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>