<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450614</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. I.     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JUNE 14, 1845.     NO. 24.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.
         
         <br></br>Single Copies 6 1/4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau-St-
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Premature Burial</div>
         <div class="head">THE PREMATURE BURIAL.</div>
         
         <p>There are certain themes of which the interest is all-absorbing, but which are too entirely horrible for the purposes of legitimate fiction. These the mere romanticist must eschew, if
            he do not wish to offend, or to disgust. They are with propriety handled, only when the severity and majesty of Truth sanctify and sustain them. We thrill, for example, with the most
            intense of “ pleasurable pain,” over the accounts of the Passage of the Beresina, of the Earthquake at Lisbon, of the
            Plague at London, of the Massacre of St. Bartholomew, or of
            the stifling of the hundred and twenty-three prisoners in the
            Black Hole at Calcutta. But, in these accounts, it is the fact
            —it is the reality—it is the history which excites. As inventions, we should regard them with simple abhorrence.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have mentioned some few of the more prominent and august calamities on record; but, in these, it is the extent, not
            less than the character of the calamity, which so vividly impresses the fancy. I need not remind the reader that, from
            the long and wierd catalogue of human miseries, I might have
            selected many individual instances more replete with essential
            suffering than any of these vast generalities of disaster. The 
            true wretchedness, indeed—the ultimate woe—is particular,
            not diffuse. That the ghastly extremes of agony are endured
            by man the unit, and never by man the mass—for this let us
            thank a merciful God!
         </p>
         
         <p>To be buried while alive, is, beyond question, the most terrific of these extremes which has ever fallen to the lot of mere 
            mortality. That it has frequently, very frequently, so fallen, 
            will scarcely be denied by those who think. The boundaries
            which divide Life from Death, are at best shadowy and vague.
            Who shall say where the one ends, and where the other begins? We know that there are diseases in which occur total
            cessations of all the apparent functions of vitality, and yet in
            which these cessations are merely suspensions, properly so
            called. They are only temporary pauses in the incomprehensible mechanism. A certain period elapses, and some unseen |
            mysterious principle again sets in motion the magic pinions and
            the wizard wheels. The silver cord was not forever loosed,
            nor the golden bowl irreparably broken. But where, meantime, was the soul?
         </p>
         
         <p>Apart, however, from the inevitable conclusion, a priori,
            that such causes must produce such effects—that the well
            known occurrence of such cases of suspended animation must
            naturally give rise, now and then, to premature interments—
            apart from this consideration, we have the direct testimony of
            medical and ordinary experience, to prove that a vast number
            of such interments have actually taken place. I might refer
            at once, if necessary, to a hundred well authenticated instances.
            One of very remarkable character, and of which the circumstances may be fresh in the memory of some of my readers,
            occurred, not very long ago, in the neighboring city of Baltimore, where it occasioned a painful, intense, and widely extended excitement. The wife of one of the most respectable 
            citizens—a lawyer of eminence and a member of Congress— 
            was seized with a sudden and unaccountable illness, which 
            completely baffled the skill of her physicians. After much suffering she died, or was supposed to die. No one suspected,
            indeed, or had reason to suspect, that she was not actually
            dead. She presented all the ordinary appearances of death.
            The face assumed the usual pinched and sunken outline. The
            lips were of the usual marble pallor. The eyes were lustreless. There was no warmth. Pulsation had ceased. For
            three days the body was preserved unburied, during which it
            had acquired a stony rigidity. The funeral, in short, was
            hastened, on account of the rapid advance of what was suppos ed to be decomposition.
         </p>
         
         <p>The lady was deposited in her family vault, which, for three
            subsequent years, was undisturbed. At the expiration of this
            term, it was opened for the reception of a sarcophagus;—but,
            alas! how fearful a shock awaited the husband, who, personally, threw open the door. As its portals swung outwardly
             back, some white-apparrelled object fell rattling within his arms.
            It was the skeleton of his wife in her yet unmouldered shroud.
         </p>
         
         <p>A careful investigation rendered it evident that she had revived within two days after her entombment—that her struggles within the coffin had caused it to fall from a ledge, or
            shelf, to the floor, where it was so broken as to permit her escape. A lamp which had been accidentally left, full of oil,
            within the tomb, was found empty; it might have been exhausted, however, by evaporation. On the uppermost of the
            steps which led down into the dread chamber, was a large fragment of the coffin, with which it seemed that she had endeavored to arrest attention, by striking the iron door. While
             thus occupied, she probably swooned, or possibly died, through
            sheer terror; and, in falling, her shroud became entangled in
            some iron-work which projected interiorly. Thus she remained, and thus she rotted, erect.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the year 1810, a case of living inhumation happened in
            France, attended with circumstances which go far to warrant
            the assertion that truth is, indeed, stranger than fiction. The
            heroine of the story was a Mademoiselle Victorine Lafourcade,
            a young girl of illustrious family, of wealth, and of great personal beauty. Among her numerous suitors was Julien Bossuet, a poor litterateur, or journalist, of Pans. His talents
            and general amiability had recommended him to the notice of
             the heiress, by whom he seems to have been truly beloved;
            but her pride of birth decided her, finally, to reject him, and to
            wed a Monsieur Renelle, a banker, and a diplomatist of some
            eminence. After marriage, however, this gentleman neglected, and. perhaps, even more positively ill-treated her. Having
            passed with him some wretched years, she died,—at least her
            condition so closely resembled death as to deceive every one
            who saw her. She was buried—not in a vault—but in an ordinary grave in the village of her nativity. Filled with despair, and still inflamed by the memory of a profound attachment, the lover journeys from the capital to the remote province in which the village lies, with the romantic purpose of disinterring the corpse, and possessing himself of its luxuriant tresses.
            He reaches the grave. At midnight he unearths the coffin,
            opens it, and is in the act of detaching the hair, when he is arrested by the unclosing of the beloved eyes. In fact, the lady
            had been buried alive. Vitality had not altogether departed;
            
            and she was aroused, by the caresses of her lover, from the lethargy which had been mistaken for death. He bore her frantically to his lodgings in the village. He employed certain
            powerful restoratives suggested by no little medical learning.
            In fine, she revived. She recognized her preserver. She remained with him until, by slow degrees, she fully recovered
            her original health. Her woman’s heart was not adamant, and
            this last lesson of love sufficed to soften it. She bestowed it
            upon Bossuet. She returned no more to her husband, but concealing from him her resurrection, fled with her lover to
            America. Twenty years afterwards, the two returned to
            France, in the persuasion that time had so greatly altered the
            lady's appearance that her friends would be unable to recognize
            her. They were mistaken, however; for, at the first meeting,
            Monsieur Renelle did actually recognize and make claim to his
            wife. This claim she resisted; and a judicial tribunal sustained her in her resistance; deciding that the peculiar circumstances, with the long lapse of years, had extinguished,
            not only equitably but legally, the authority of the husband.
         </p>
         
         <p>The “ Chirurgical Journal ” of Leipsic—a periodical, of
            high authority and merit, which some American bookseller
            would do well to translate and republish—records, in a late
            number, a very distressing event of the character in question.
         </p>
         
         <p>An officer of artillery, a man of gigantic stature and of robust health, being thrown from an unmanageable horse, received a very severe contusion upon the head, which rendered him
            insensible at once; the skull was slightly fractured; but no
            immediate danger was apprehended. Trepanning was accomplished successfully. He was bled, and many other of the ordinary means of relief were adopted. Gradually, however, he
            fell into a more and more hopeless state of stupor; and, finally, it was thought that he died.
         </p>
         
         <p>The weather was warm; and he was buried, with indecent
            haste, in one of the public cemeteries. His funeral took place
            on Thursday. On the Sunday following, the grounds of the 
            cemetery were, as usual, much thronged with visiters; and,
            about noon, an intense excitement was created by the declaration of a peasant that, while sitting upon the grave of the officer, he had distinctly felt a commotion of the, earth, as if occasioned by some one struggling beneath. At first little attention was paid to the man’s asseveration; but his evident terror, and the dogged obstinacy with which he persisted in his 
            story, had, at length, their natural effect upon the crowd.
            Spades were hurriedly procured, and the grave, which was
            shamefully shallow, was, in a few minutes, so far thrown open
            that the head of its occupant appeared. He was then, seemingly, dead; but he sat nearly erect within his coffin, the lid of
            which, in his furious struggles, he had partially uplifted.
         </p>
         
         <p>He was forthwith conveyed to the nearest Hospital, and
            there pronounced to be still living, although in an asphytic
            condition. After some hours he revived, recognized individuals of his acquaintance, and, in broken sentences, spoke of his
            agonies in the grave.
         </p>
         
         <p>From what he related, it was clear that he must have been 
            conscious of life for more than an hour, while inhumed, before 
            lapsing into insensibility. The grave was carelessly and loosely 
            filled with an exceedingly porous soil; and thus some air was 
            necessarily admitted. He heard the footsteps of the crowd 
            overhead, and endeavored to make himself heard in turn. It was
            the tumult within the grounds of the cemetery, he said, which 
            appeared to awaken him from a deep sleep—but no sooner
            was he awake than he became fully aware of the awful horrors
            of his position.	
         </p>
         
         <p>This patient, it is recorded, was doing well, and seemed to 
            be in a fair way of ultimate recovery, but fell a victim to the 
            quackeries of medical experiment. The galvanic battery was 
            
            applied; and he suddenly expired in one of those ecstatic par-
            oxysms which, occasionally, it superinduces.
         </p>
         
         <p>The mention of the galvanic battery, nevertheless, recalls to
            my memory a well known and very extraordinary case in point,
            where its action proved the means of restoring to animation a
            young attorney of London who had been interred for two days.
            This occurred in 1831, and created, at the time, a very profound sensation wherever it was made the subject of converse.
         </p>
         
         <p>The patient, Mr. Edward Stapleton, had died, apparently,
            of typhus fever, accompanied with some anomalous symptoms
            which had excited the curiosity of his medical attendants.
            Upon his seeming decease, his friends were requested to sanction a post mortem examination, but declined to permit it. As
            often happens when such refusals are made, the practitioners
            resolved to disinter the body and dissect it at leisure, in private. Arrangements were easily effected with some of the
            numerous corps of body-snatchers with which London abounds;
            and, upon the third night after the funeral, the supposed corpse
            was unearthed from a grave eight feet deep, and deposited in
            the operating chamber of one of the private hospitals.
         </p>
         
         <p>An incision of some extent had been actually made in the
            abdomen, when the fresh and undecayed appearance of the
            subject suggested an application of the battery. One experiment succeeded another, and the customary effects supervened, with nothing to characterize them in any respect, except,
            upon one or two occasions, a more than ordinary degree of
            life-likeliness in the convulsive action.
         </p>
         
         <p>It grew late. The day was about to dawn; and it was
            thought expedient, at length, to proceed at once to the dissection. A student, however, was especially desirous of testing
            a theory of his own, and insisted upon applying the battery to
             one of the pectoral muscles. A rough gash was made, and a
            wire hastily brought in contact; when the patient, with a
            hurried but quite unconvulsive movement, arose from the table,
            stepped into the middle of the floor, gazed about him uneasily
            for a few seconds, and then—spoke. What he said was unintelligible; but words were uttered; the syllabification was dis tinct. Having spoken, he fell heavily to the floor. 
         </p>
         
         <p>For some moments all were paralyzed with awe—but the
             urgency of the case soon restored them their presence of
             mind. It was seen that Mr. Stapleton was alive, although in
            a swoon. Upon exhibition of ether he revived and was rap idly restored to health, and to the society of his friends—from
            whom, however, all knowledge of his resuscitation was withheld, until a relapse was no longer to be apprehended. Their
            wonder—their rapturous astonishment—may be conceived.
         </p>
         
         <p>The most thrilling peculiarity of this incident, nevertheless,
            is involved in what Mr. S. himself asserts. He declares that
            at no period was he altogether insensible—that, dully and confusedly, he was aware of every thing which happened to him,
            from the moment in which he was pronounced dead by his
             physicians, to that in which he fell swooning to the floor of
             the Hospital. “ I am alive” were the uncomprehended words
             which, upon recognizing the locality of the dissecting-room,
             he had endeavored, in his extremity, to utter.
         </p>
         
         <p>It were an easy matter to multiply such histories as these
            —but I forbear—for, indeed, we have no need of such to es tablish the fact that premature interments occur. When we
             reflect how very rarely, from the nature of the case, we have
             it in our power to detect them, we must admit that they may
            frequently occur without our cognizance. Scarcely, in truth,
            is a graveyard ever encroached upon, for any purpose, to any
            great extent, that skeletons are not found in postures which
            suggest the most fearful of suspicions.
         </p>
         
         <p>Fearful indeed the suspicion—but more fearful the doom! It may be asserted, without
            hesitation, that no event is so ter
            
            ribly well adapted to inspire the supremeness of bodily and of
            mental distress, as is burial before death. The unendurable
            oppression of the lungs—the stifling fumes from the damp
            earth—the clinging of the death garments—the rigid embrace
            of the narrow house—the blackness of the absolute Night—
            the silence like a sea that overwhelms—the unseen but palpable presence of the Conqueror Worm—these things, with
            thoughts of the air and grass above, with memory of dear
            friends who would fly to save us if but informed of our fate,
            and with consciousness that of this fate they can never be informed—that our hopeless portion is that of the really dead—
            these considerations, I say, carry into the heart, which still
            palpitates, a degree of appalling and intolerable horror from
            which the most daring imagination must recoil. We know of
            nothing so agonizing upon Earth—we can dream of nothing
            half so hideous in the realms of the nethermost Hell. And
            thus all narratives upon this topic have an interest profound; an
            interest, nevertheless, which, through the sacred awe of the
            topic itself, very properly and very peculiarly depends upon
            our conviction of the truth of the matter narrated. What I
            have now to tell, is of my own actual knowledge—of my own
            positive and personal experience.
         </p>
         
         <p>For several years I had been subject to attacks of the singular disorder which physicians have agreed to term catalepsy,
            in default of a more definitive title. Although both the immediate and the predisposing causes, and even the actual diagnosis,
            of this disease, are still mysteries, its obvious and apparent
            character is sufficiently well understood. Its variations seem
            to be chiefly of degree. Sometimes the patient lies, for a day
            only, or even for a shorter period, in a species of exaggerated
            lethargy. He is senseless and externally motionless; but the
            pulsation of the heart is still faintly perceptible; some traces
            of warmth remain; a slight color lingers within the centre of
            the cheek; and, upon application of a mirror to the lips, we
            can detect a torpid, unequal, and vacillating action of the lungs.
            Then again the duration of the trance is for weeks—even for
            months; while the closest scrutiny, and the most rigorous
            medical tests, fail to establish any material distinction between
            the state of the sufferer and what we conceive of absolute
            death. Very usually, he is saved from premature interment
            solely by the knowledge of his friends that he has been previously subject to catalepsy, by the consequent suspicion excited, and, above all, by the non-appearance of decay. The
            advances of the malady are, luckily, gradual. The first manifestations, although marked, are unequivocal. The fits grow
            successively more and more distinctive, and endure each for
            a longer term than the preceding. In this lies the principal
            security from inhumation. The unfortunate whose first attack
            should be of the extreme character which is occasionally seen,
            would almost inevitably be consigned alive to the tomb.
         </p>
         
         <p>My own case differed in no important particular from those
            mentioned in medical books. Sometimes, without any apparent cause, I sank, little by little, into a condition of hemi-syncope, or half swoon; and, in this condition, without pain, without ability to stir, or, strictly speaking, to think, but with a
            dull lethargic consciousness of life and of the presence of
            those who surrounded my bed, I remained, until the crisis of
            the disease restored me, suddenly, to perfect sensation. At
            other times I was quickly and impetuously smitten. I grew
            sick, and numb, and chilly, and dizzy, and so fell prostrate at
            once. Then, for weeks, all was void, and black, and silent,
            and Nothing became the universe. Total annihilation could
            be no more. From these latter attacks I awoke, however,
            with a gradation slow in proportion to the suddenness of the
            seisure. Just as the day dawns to the friendless and houseless beggar who roams the streets throughout the long deso-
            
            late winter night—just so tardily—just so wearily—just so
            cheerily came back the light of the Soul to me.
         </p>
         
         <p>Apart from the tendency to trance, however, my general
            health appeared to be good; nor could I perceive that it was
            at all affected by the one prevalent malady—unless, indeed, an
            idiosyncrasy in my ordinary sleep may be looked upon as superinduced. Upon awaking from slumber, I could never gain,
            at once, thorough possession of my senses, and always remained, for many minutes, in much bewilderment and perplexity;—the mental faculties in general, but the memory in
            especial, being in a condition of absolute abeyance.
         </p>
         
         <p>In all that I endured there was no physical suffering, but of
            moral distress an infinitude. My fancy grew charnal. I
            talked “ of worms, of tombs and epitaphs.” I was lost in
            reveries of death, and the idea of premature burial held continual possession of my brain. The ghastly Danger to which
            I was subjected, haunted me day and night. In the former,
            the torture of meditation was excessive—in the latter, supreme. When the grim Darkness overspread the Earth, then,
            with very horror of thought, I shook—shook as the quivering plumes upon the hearse. When Nature could endure
            wakefulness no longer, it was with a struggle that I consented
            to sleep—for I shuddered to reflect that, upon awaking, I
            might find myself the tenant of a grave. And when, finally,
            I sank into slumber, it was only to rush at once into a world
            of phantasms, above which, with vast, sable, overshadowing
            wings, hovered, predominant, the one sepulchral Idea.
         </p>
         
         <p>From the innumerable images of gloom which thus oppressed me in dreams, I select for record but a solitary vision.
            Methought I was immersed in a cataleptic trance of more
            than usual duration and profundity. Suddenly there came an
            icy hand upon my forehead, and an impatient, gibbering
            voice whispered the word “ Arise!” within my ear.
         </p>
         
         <p>I sat erect. The darkness was total. I could not see the
            figure of him who had aroused me. I could call to mind neither the period at which I had fallen into the trance, nor the
            locality in which I then lay. While I remained motionless,
            and busied in endeavors to collect my thoughts, the cold
            hand grasped me fiercely by the wrist, shaking it petulantly,
            while the gibbering voice said again:
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Arise! did I not bid thee arise?”</p>
         
         <p>“ And who,” I demanded, “ art thou?”</p>
         
         <p>“ I have no name in the regions which I inhabit,” replied
            the voice mournfully; “ I was mortal, but am fiend. I was
            merciless, but am pitiful. Thou dost feel that I shudder.—
            My teeth chatter as l speak, yet it is not with the chilliness of
            the night—of the night without end. But this hideousness
            is insufferable. How canst thou tranquilly sleep? I cannot
            rest for the cry of these great agonies. These sights are more
            than I can bear. Get thee up! Come with me into the outer
            Night, and let me unfold to thee the graves. Is not this a
            spectacle of woe?—Behold!"
         </p>
         
         <p>I looked; and the unseen figure, which still grasped me by
            the wrist, had caused to be thrown open the graves of all mankind; and from each issued the faint phosphoric radiance of
            decay; so that I could see into the innermost recesses, and
            there view the shrouded bodies in their sad and solemn slumbers with the worm. But, alas! the real sleepers were fewer,
            by many millions, than those who slumbered not at all; and
            there was a feeble struggling; and there was a general sad
            unrest; and from out the depths of the countless pits there
            came a melancholy rustling from the garments of the buried.
            And, of those who seemed tranquilly to repose, I saw that a
            vast number had changed, in a greater or less degree, the
            rigid and uneasy position in which they had originally been
            entombed. And the voice again said to me, as I gazed:
         </p>
         
         
         
         <p>“ Is it not—oh, is it not a pitiful sight?”—but, before I
            could find words to reply, the figure bad ceased to grasp my
            wrist, the phosphoric lights expired, and the graves were closed with a sudden violence, while from out them arose a tumult of despairing cries, saying again—“Is it not—oh, God!
            is it not a very pitiful sight?"
         </p>
         
         <p>Phantasies such as these, presenting themselves at night,
            extended their terrific influence far into my waking hours.—
            My nerves became thoroughly unstrung, and I fell a prey to
            perpetual horror. I hesitated to ride, or to walk, or to indulge
            in any exercise that would carry me from home. In fact I
            no longer dared trust myself out of the immediate presence of
            those who were aware of my proneness to catalepsy, lest, falling
            into one of my usual fits, I should be buried before my real
            condition could be ascertained. I doubted the care, the fidelity of my dearest friends. I dreaded that, in some trance of
            mere than customary duration, they might be prevailed upon
            to regard me as irrecoverable. I even went so far as to fear
            that, as I occasioned much trouble, they might be glad to consider any very protracted attack as sufficient excuse for getting rid of me altogether. It was in vain they endeavored to
            reassure me by the most solemn promises. I exacted the
            most sacred oaths, that under no circumstances they would
            bury me until decomposition had so materially advanced as
            to render farther preservation impossible. And, even then,
            my mortal terrors would listen to no reason—would accept no
            consolation. I entered into a series of elaborate precautions.
            Among other things, I had the family fault so remodelled as
            to admit of being readily opened from within. The slightest
            pressure upon a long lever that extended far into the tomb
            would cause the iron portals to fly back. There were arrangements also for the free admission of air and light, and
            convenient receptacles for food and water, within immediate
            reach of the coffin intended for my reception. This coffin was
            warmly and softly padded, and was provided with a lid, fashioned upon the principle of the vault-door, with the addition
            of springs so contrived that the feeblest movement of the body
            would be sufficient to set it at liberty. Besides all this, there
            was suspended from the roof of the tomb, a large bell, the
            rope of which, it was designed, should extend through a hole 
            in the coffin, and so be fastened to one of the hands of the 
            corpse. But, alas! what avails the vigilance against the Destiny of man? Not even these well contrived securities sufficed 
            to save from the uttermost agonies of living inhumation, a 
            wretch to these agonies foredoomed!
         </p>
         
         <p>There arrived an epoch—as often before there had arrived
            —in which I found myself emerging from total unconsciousness into the first feeble and indefinite sense of existence.—
            Slowly—with a tortoise gradation—approached the faint gray
            dawn of the psychal day. A torpid uneasiness. An apathethetic endurance of dull pain. No care—no hope—no effort.
            Then, after long interval, a ringing in the ears; then, after
            a lapse still longer, a pricking or tingling sensation in the extremities; then a seemingly eternal period of pleasurable
            quiescence, during which the awakening feelings are struggling into thought; then a brief re-sinking into non-entity;
            then a sudden recovery. At length the slight quivering of an
            eyelid, and immediately thereupon, an electric shock of a
            terror, deadly and indefinite, which sends the blood in torrents
            from the temples to the heart. And now the first positive effort to think. And now the first endeavor to remember. And
            now a partial and evanescent success. And now the memory 
            has so far regained its dominion that, in some measure, I am
            cognizant of my state. I feel that I am not awaking from ordinary sleep. I recollect that I have been subject to catalepsy. And now, at last, as if by the rush of an ocean, my shuddering spirit is overwhelmed by the one grim Danger—by the
            one spectral and ever-prevalent Idea.
         </p>
         
         <p>For some minutes after this fancy possessed me, I remained
            without motion. And why? I could not summon courage
            to move. I dared not make the effort which was to satisfy
            me of my fate—and yet there was something at my heart
            which whispered me it was sure. Despair—such as no other
            species of wretchedness ever calls into being—despair alone
            urged me, after long irresolution, to uplift the heavy lids of
            my eyes. I uplifted them. It was dark—all dark. I knew
            that the fit was over. I knew that the crisis of my disorder
            had long passed. I knew that I had now fully recovered the
            use of my visual faculties—and yet it was dark—all dark—
            the intense and utter raylessness of the Night that endureth
            for evermore.
         </p>
         
         <p>I endeavored to shriek; and my lips and my parched tongue
            moved convulsively together in the attempt—but no voice issued from the cavernous lungs, which, oppressed as if by the
            weight of some incumbent mountain, gasped and palpitated,
            with the heart, at every elaborate and struggling inspiration.
         </p>
         
         <p>The movement of the jaws, in this effort to cry aloud, showed me that they were bound up, as is usual with the dead. I
            felt, too, that I lay upon some hard substance; and by something similar my sides were, also, closely compressed. So
            far, I had not ventured to stir any of my limbs—but now I violently threw up my arms, which had been lying at length,
            with the wrists crossed. They struck a solid wooden substance, which extended above my person at an elevation of not
            more than six inches from my face. I could no longer doubt
            that I reposed within a coffin at last.
         </p>
         
         <p>And now, amid all my infinite miseries, came sweetly the
            cherub Hope—for I thought of my precautions. I writhed,
            and made spasmodic exertions to force open the lid: it would
            not move. I felt my wrists for the bell-rope: it was not to be
            found. And now the Comforter fled forever, and a still sterner Despair reigned triumphant; for I could not help perceiving
            the absence of the paddings which I had so carefully prepared
            —and then, too, there came suddenly to my nostrils the strong
            peculiar odor of moist earth. The conclusion was irresistible.
            I was not within the vault. I had fallen into a trance while
            absent from home—while among strangers—when, or how, I
            could not remember—and it was they who had buried me as a
            dog—nailed up in some common coffin—and thrust, deep, deep,
            and forever, into some ordinary and nameless grave.
         </p>
         
         <p>As this awful conviction forced itself, thus, into the innermost chambers of my soul, I once again struggled to cry aloud.
            And in this second endeavor I succeeded. A long, wild, and
            continuous shriek, or yell, of agony, resounded through the
            realms of the subterrene Night.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Hillo! hillo, there!” said a gruff voice in reply.</p>
         
         <p>“ What the devil's the matter now I” said a second.</p>
         
         <p>“ Get out o’ that!” said a third.</p>
         
         <p>“ What do you mean by yowling in that ere kind of style,
            like a cattymount?” said a fourth; and hereupon I was seized and shaken without ceremony, for several minutes, by a
            junto of very rough-looking individuals. They did not arouse
            me from my slumber—for I was wide awake when I screamed
            —but they restored me to the full possession of my memory.
         </p>
         
         <p>This adventure occurred near Richmond, in Virginia. Accompanied by a friend, I had proceeded, upon a gunning expedition, some miles down the banks of James River. Night
            approached, and we were overtaken by a storm. The cabin of
            a small sloop lying at anchor in the stream, and laden with
            garden mould, afforded us the only available shelter. We
            made the best of it, and passed the night on board. I slept in 
            
            one of the only two berths in the vessel—and the berths of a
            sloop of sixty or seventy tons, need scarcely be described.
            That which I occupied had no bedding of any kind. Its extreme width was eighteen inches. The distance of its bottom
            from the deck overhead, was precisely the same. I found it a
            matter of exceeding difficulty to squeeze myself in. Nevertheless, I slept soundly; and the whole of my vision—for it
            was no dream, and no nightmare—arose naturally from the
            circumstances of my position—from my ordinary bias of thought
            —and from the difficulty, to which I have alluded, of collecting my senses, and especially of regaining my memory, for a
            long time after awaking from slumber. The men who shook
            me were the crew of the sloop, and some laborers engaged to
            unload it. From the load itself came the earthy smell. The
            bandage about the jaws was a silk handkerchief in which I had
            bound up my head, in default of my customary nightcap.
         </p>
         
         <p> The tortures endured, however, were indubitably quite
            equal, for the time, to those of actual sepulture. They were
            fearfully—they were inconceivably hideous; but out of Evil
            proceeded Good; for their very excess wrought in my spirit an
            inevitable revulsion. My soul acquired tone—acquired temper. I went abroad. I took vigorous exercise. I breathed 
            the free air of Heaven. I thought upon other subjects than
            Death. I discarded my medical books. “ Buchan ” I burned. I read no “ Night Thoughts ”—no fustian about churchyards—no bugaboo tales—such as this. In short, I became a
            new man, and lived a man's life. From that memorable night.
            I dismissed forever my charnal apprehensions, and with them
            vanished the cataleptic disorder, of which, perhaps, they had
            been less the consequence than the cause.
         </p>
         
         <p>There are moments when, even to the sober eye of Reason,
            the world of our sad Humanity may assume the semblance of
            a Hell—but the imagination of man is no Carathis, to explore
            with impunity its every cavern. Alas! the grim legion of
            sepulchral terrors cannot be regarded as altogether fanciful—
            but, like the Demons in whose company Afrasiab made his
            voyage down the Oxus, they must sleep, or they will devour
            us—they must be suffered to slumber, or we perish.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Letter to the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="head">LETTER TO THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <p>My Dear Journal,</p>
         
         <p>You know my boy Bob? I mean that great double jointed
            fellow whose countenance is concealed in a matting of beard
            and whiskers; the same of whom somebody- remarked that he
            seemed to place great confidence in capillary attraction. He
            is gone. Like Absalom his own hair has ruined him—and like
            Absalom’s father, I can exclaim, “ my son! my son!”
         </p>
         
         <p>The circumstances are these. For a long time he has been
            nursing his beard, and kept a small Dutch looking-glass before
            him, which, when no customer claimed his attention, he was
            ever combing, brushing, and making the most extraordinary
            serio-ludicrous faces that can be imagined. A little drawer
            under the counter was constantly supplied with candle-ends—
            not gathered, as I in my simplicity supposed from motives of
            economy; but to grease his whiskers withal.
         </p>
         
         <p>At length, matters began to grow serious. Ho could not be
            induced to give attention to any but the female customers,
            The men bought their wares elsewhere; and even the women
            seemed to think him dangerous. Miss Sally Jones said he
            was a good likeness of Orson—and Mrs. Gollyhoggin, being
            in an interesting state of health, and entering the shop just as
            Bobby was turning around towards the counter, was so much
            alarmed that the major threatened to sue mo for damages.
         </p>
         
         <p>Resolved to bear this no longer, I ordered him to shave.
            
            The next morning he did not appear in the shop, and upon inquiry I found that he was gone. In the hope of finding some
            clew to the place of his retreat, I examined his chamber and
            found various books and papers belonging to a set of fellows
            calling themselves Barbati, or some such outlandish name, of
            whom my poor deluded boy was, it seems, the secretary.
         </p>
         
         <p>It appears by the record of their proceedings, which were
            deemed of sufficient importance to be noted in a journal, that
            they had a Constitution; and I send you a copy of it, word for
            word.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Since the known paths to distinction have become crowded
            to such a degree that those who toil up the dangerous steep
            are almost all, sooner or later, precipitated into the abyss of
            oblivion, which every where opes its unsatiate jaws for its
            prey; it is the part of the wise to hew out some new road that
            may lead to glory with less labor and with less hazard.
         </p>
         
         <p>Moved by these considerations, we have maturely pondered
            the interesting theme. We have considered the great in their
            eminence—we have seen every eye upturned to admire them,
            and every hand eagerly outstretched to catch what might fall
            from them—wc have seen even the intellectual immunditia of
            these demigods garnered as treasures and preserved as holy
            things—wc have seen exhibited as relics of inestimable value,
            the absurdities of Demosthenes—the coxcombry of Alexander
            the truisms of Franklin—and the bloodguiltiness of Draco, the
            more deserving of execration that it was entailed upon posterity. Nay, we have known even the insane ravings of our own
            most contemptible political Jehus, to be listened to with all the
            reverence formerly paid to the paltering trivialities of a Delphic
            oracle. We are taught to admire the King of Macedon as a
            groom—to read with intense interest that one great man delighted in crumpets, and another luxuriated on cauliflowers—that one
            was born with teeth, and another had a hitch in his gait.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have considered all these things and determined to be
            great—not, however, by toiling up the rugged steep. We will
            rise to notoriety by an easy, well graduated road. Spencer,
            Petersham, Nash and Brummel have built themselves monuments of wearing apparel; and Stultz has achieved nobility by
            the same easy path. Mesmer, Dee, Nostradamus, Law, Perkins, Gall, Lavater,
            <span class="anchor" id="a001">
               <a href="#n001"> Link </a>
            </span> still live as the fathers, grandfathers and
            great grandfathers of quackery—and Sam Patch is not dead—
            he who suggested the startling proposition that “ some things
            can be done as well as other things”—and died to prove it—
            whereby he liveth.
         </p>
         
         <p>We too, will become great; and by a simple and easy pro-
            cess—we will, by our beards! Fiat.
         </p>
         
         <p>We do therefore combine and unite ourselves into a Society
            to be intituled
         </p>
         
         <p>Capricornorum Barbatorum SOCIETAS 
            <span class="anchor" id="a002">
               <a href="#n002"> Link </a>
            </span> which name is
            never to be known but to the initiate; the letters C. B. S.
            alone being given to the admiring world.
         </p>
         
         <p>On public occasions, and at all meetings of the C. B. S.
            each member shall wear a broad ribbon at his left button-hole,
            whereon shall be plainly embroidered the letters S. B. C. S.
            meaning Socius Barbatus Capricornorum Societatis, 
            <span class="anchor" id="a003">
               <a href="#n003"> Link </a>
            </span>
            which shall be known to the members only.
         </p>
         
         <p>The beards of all the members shall be of one length and
            fashion, to be fixed by law.
         </p>
         
         <p>The President, by way of distinction, shall wear no beard.</p>
         
         <p>At the meetings it shall be the duty of the society first to
            debate on the subject of beards, their antiquity, history, ex
            
            pression, cultivation, and their influence, physical and moral,
            on society in general—2nd. To eat stewed oysters.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Resolved that the thanks of this society be presented to
            Athanasius Wollop, Esq. the high-minded honorable Principal of Appletree Academy for his unparalleled exertions in preparing this Constitution, and that the members of this society
            take every means of recommending his school to the public.”
         </p>
         
         <p>It appears by the record of these proceedings, that a warm
            contest arose on that part of the Constitution which relates to
            the President’s beard. The leader of one party alleged that
            to prevent the President from wearing a beard would invest
            him with a power fraught with danger to the permanence of
            the institution. Another objected to the proposed regulation on
            the ground that it was a vested right and therefore unconstitutional.
         </p>
         
         <p>Here five members sprang to their feet, and the chairman
            caught the eye of Mr. Wiggles—
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Wiggles wished to know what gentlemen meant by a
            vested right. If it meant a right to wear a vest, then all men
            except savages and brutes, were entitled to it. Indeed he
            himself, simple and unpretending as he stood there, had seen
            a monkey wear a vest—yes—and a coat—and even a pair of
            breeches! He would maintain this right to the utmost of his
            poor abilities. “ What sir,” said Mr. Wiggles, “ deprive a
            man of a right to wear a vest!”
         </p>
         
         <p>Major Peter Perks rose to say that the able and eloquent
            harangue made by the honorable gentleman who spoke last,
            was predicated—
         </p>
         
         <p>Interrupted by Mr. Wiggles who denied that his remarks
            had been predicated. He would consider it personal if such
            a thing were insinuated in regard to him.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Perks would pass over the language used by the gentleman, because it was founded upon a misapprehension. He
            meant to say that a vested right was not a right to wear a vest.
            It was a right which every man had to do what he likes with
            his own property. For example, said Mr. P. if a man chooses
            to invest his money in stocks, or cravats, or collars, has he not
            a right to do so, and then to burn them if he thinks proper?—
            The first named article is bought and sold; for people buy and
            sell stocks by thousands of pounds worth at a time; and who
            will be so bold as to deny their right. Now, sir, though it is
            clear that every man has a right to his vested rights, yet this
            must not be understood as applying to the case of a President.
            It is well known that man is prone to abuse power; and as so
            high an officer as a President is more obnoxious to this vice
            than any one else, so it should not only be denied to him, but
            he should also be deprived of his rights—nay, more sir, of
            his vested rights. I am, sir, a people’s man—a friend of the
            people—and therefore opposed to giving any power to any
            body—and if it should ever happen that I have the honor to
            be elected President of the United States, I’ll let the people
            see what my views are. If any man should propose to give
            me or any one else any power, I’ll hang him, sir.” [Loud cheers.
         </p>
         
         <p>The resolution was finally adopted.</p>
         
         <p>Mr. Tips proposed that all beards should be perfumed; but
            it was rejected on the ground that the natural odour was the
            best. Mr. Tiberius Gracchus Riggs—puer emunctae naris—
            rose in behalf of those whose beards had not yet grown. He
            thought it unreasonable that they should be fined for not wearing a beard; provided due diligence was shown to be used in
            shaving and oiling.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Tiffy thought that the question “ whether a beard could
            or could not be made to grow on a gentleman’s chin,” was not
            to be discussed here. It would be unjust to make a law that did
            not apply alike to all. Every member must have a beard,
            whether he could or not. It was democratic.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Mr. Riggs thought this a very absurd proposition—and said
            that he would not pay the fine; nor would he withdraw from
            the society. He had as much right to membership as any
            body; and he would render inoperative (so far as it concerned
            himself,) all laws which did not suit him; and take the benefit
            of these which were agreeable to him.
         </p>
         
         <p>When he (Mr. Riggs joined the society, he did it with the
            purpose and with the expectation of deriving from it the
            greatest possible advantage—but this end would not be attained if he was to be subjected to any inconveniences. He
            intended to gain—not to lose. If the society were to resolve
            itself into a committee of the whole and attempt to levy the
            fine, he (Mr. R.) would boldly enter into the contest, and do
            such deeds of noble daring, that the raging tempest would
            pause to hear the tale and the whole earth would tremble at his
            name.
         </p>
         
         <p>These extracts will suffice to exhibit the character and designs of the Society. I trust, sir, that you will give them to
            the public, with such observations of your own as may tend to
            bring to their senses the Socii Capricornorum Barbatorum Soc.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">  Yours,
            
            <br></br>PATER HAEDI.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Woman--The Hareem</div>
         <div class="head">WOMAN—THE HAREEM.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Thus in the ever-closed hareem,
            
            <br></br>As in the open Western home,
            
            <br></br>Sheds womanhood her starry gleam
            
            <br></br>Over our being's busy foam.
            
            <br></br>Through latitudes of varying faith,
            
            <br></br>Thus trace we still her mission sure,
            
            <br></br>To lighten life, to sweeten death,
            
            <br></br>And all for others to endure.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">R. M. Milnes.</div>
         
         <p>On entering a strange country, its women are the first objects
            of interest to the moralist as well as to the epicurean; to the
            former, because the education of a people, and the framework
            of its society, depend mainly upon maternal and domestic character: to the latter, because almost every grace and chaim of
            daily life is owing to her influence, or interwoven with her
            being—“ On a dit, qu’il y a de la femme dans tout ce qu’on
            aime.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Among the lower classes of all nations, especially in the
            country, the life and habits of women approximate more or less
            to that of men in an inverse proportion to their civilisation. As
            they share with the ruder sex their labors, hardships, and daily
            occupation, among savage tribes almost the only distinction
            between the sexes is physical. It is of the Moslem woman of
            the middle and upper classes that I am now about to speak,
            and I do so with a diffidence proportioned to such mysterious
            matters.
         </p>
         
         <p>Difficult a study as woman presents in all countries, that difficulty deepens almost into an impossibility in a land where even
            to look upon her is a matter of danger or of death. The seclusion of the hareem is preserved in the very streets by means
            of an impenetrable veil; the well-bred Egyptian averts his
            eyes as she passes by; she is ever to remain an object of
            mystery; and the most intimate acquaintance never inquires
            after the wife of his friend, or affects to know of her existence.
            <span class="anchor" id="a004">
               <a href="#n004"> Link </a>
            </span>
            This very mystery, however, piques the often-baffled inquirer;
            and between Europeans, who have become almost Egyptian,
            and Egyptians who have become almost European, one is able
            to obtain some information even on this delicate subject.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Eastern woman seems as happy in her lot as her European sister, notwithstanding the plurality of wives in which her
            lord indulges, or ventures upon. In her “ public opinion’s law”
            there is no more disparagement in occupying the second place
            as a wife, than there is in Europe as a daughter. The manners of patriarchal ages remain in Egypt as unchanged as its
            monuments; and the people of Cairo think as little of objecting to a man's marrying a second wife, as those of Memphis of
            questioning the legitimacy of Joseph. The Koran, following
            the example of the Jewish doctors, only allows four wives to
            each Mussulman, and even of this limited allowance they seldom avail themselves to its fullest extent. Some hareems 
            
            contain two hundred females including wives, mothers-in-law,
            concubines, and the various slaves belonging to each; but
            these feminine barracks seem very different from what such
            establishments would be in Europe. In the hareem there is
            as much order and decorum as in an English quaker’s home:
            it is guarded as the tiger guards his young; but its inmates
            consider this as a compliment, and fancy themselves neglected
            if not closely watched. This cause for complaint seldom occurs, for the Egyptian has no blind confidence in the strength
            of woman’s character, or woman’s love. He holds to the
            aphorism of Mahomet in this matter, “ if you set butter in
            the sun it will surely melt;” and considers it safer, if not
            more glorious, to keep her out of the reach of temptation, than
            to run the chance of her overcoming it when exposed to its
            encounter.
         </p>
         
         <p>Born and brought up in the hareem, women never seem to
            pine at its imprisonment: like cage-born birds, they sing among
            their bars, and discover in their aviaries a thousand little pleasures invisible to eyes that have a wider range. To them, in
            their calm seclusion, the strifes of the battling world come
            softened and almost hushed; they only hear the far-off murmur of life’s stormy sea, and, if their human lot dooms them
            to their cares, they are as transient as those of childhodd.
         </p>
         
         <p>Passing through the secluded suburbs of Cairo, I once found
            myself near one of the principal hareems; I paused by the dull,
            dark wall, over which the palm-tree waved, and the scent of
            flowers and the bubbling of fountains stole; and there I listened to the sweet laughter of the Odalisques within. This was
            broken by snatches of untaught song, to which the merry unseen band joined chorus, and kept time by clapping hands, on
            which their jewelled bracelets tinkled. It was a music of
            most merry mirth; and as I pictured to myself the gay group
            within, I wondered whether they deserved all that pity from
            their European sisters which they so little appreciate. An
            English lady, visiting an Odalisque, inquired what pleasure her
            profusion of rich ornaments could afford, as no person except
            her husband was ever to behold them: “ and for whom,” replied the fair barbarian, “ do you adorn yourself? is it for other
            men?”
         </p>
         
         <p>I have conversed with several European ladies who had
            visited hareems, and they have all confessed their inability to
            convince the Eastern wives of the unhappiness or hardship of
            their state. It is true that the inmate of the hareem knows
            nothing of the advantages of the wild liberty (as it seems to
            her) that the European woman enjoys: she has never witnessed the domestic happiness that crowns a fashionable life, or the
            peace of mind and purity of heart that reward the labors of a
            London season; and what can she know of the disinterested
            affection and changeless constancy of ball-room belles, in the
            land where woman is all free. Let them laugh on in their happy ignorance of a better lot, while round them is gathered all
            that their lord can command of luxury and pleasantness: his
            wealth is hoarded for them alone; he permits himself no
            ostentation, except the respectable one of arms and horses;
            and the time is weary that he passes apart from his home and
            his hareem. The sternest tyrants are gentle there; Mehemet
            Ali never refused a woman’s prayer; and even Ali Pasha was
            partly humanized by his love for Emineh. In the time of the
            Mamelukes, criminals were led to execution blindfolded, because if they had met a woman and could touch her garment,
            they were saved, whatever was their crime. Thus idolized,
            watched, and guarded, the Egyptian woman’s life is, nevertheless, entirely in the power of her lord, and her death is the inevitable penalty of his dishonor. No piquant case of crim. con.
            ever amuses the Egyptian public: the injured husband is his
            own judge and jury; his only “ gentlemen of the long robe”
            are his eunucbs; and the dagger or the Nile the only damages.
            The law never interferes in these little domestic arrangements.
         </p>
         
         <p>Poor Fatima! shrined as she was in the palace of a tyrant,
            the fame of her beauty stole abroad through Cairo. She was
            one amongst a hundred in the hareem of Abbas Pasha, a man
            stained with every foul and loathsome vice; and who can wonder, though many may condemn, if she listened to a daring
            young Albanian, who risked his life to obtain but a sight of her?
            Whether she did listen or not, none can ever know, but the
            eunuchs saw the glitter o the Arnaut’s arms, as he leapt from
            her terrace into the Nile and vanished in the darkness. The
            following night, a merry English party dined together on board
            of Lord E-----’s boat, as it lay moored off the Isle of Rhoda;
            conversation had sunk into silence, as the calm night came on;
            a faint breeze floated perfumes from the gardens over the starlit Nile, and scarcely moved the clouds that rose from the
            chibouque; a dreamy languor seemed to pervade all nature,
            and even the city lay hushed in deep repose—when suddenly
            a boat, crowded with dark figures among which arms gleamed,
            shot out from one of the arches of the palace; it paused under the opposite bank, where the water rushed deep and
            gloomily along, and for a moment a white figure glimmered
            amongst the boat’s dark crew; there was a slight movement,
            and a faint splash—and then the river flowed on as merrily as
            if poor Fatima still sang her Georgian song to the murmur of
             its waters.
         </p>
         
         <p>I was riding one evening along the banks of the Mareotis;
            the lowland, half swamp, half desert, was level as the lake;
            there was no sound except the ripple of the waves along the
            far extended shore, and the heavy flapping of the pelican’s wings,
            as she rose from the water’s edge. Not a palm-tree raised its
            plumy head; not a shrub crept along the ground; the sun was
            low, but there was nothing to cast a shadow over the monotonous waste, except a few Moslem tombs with their sculptured turbans: these stood apart from every sign of life, and even
            of their kindred dead, like those upon the Lido at Venice. As
            I paused to contemplate this scene of desolation, an Egyptian
            hurried past me wiih a bloody knife in his hand; his dress was
            mean and ragged, but his countenance was one that the father
            of Don Carlos might have worn; he never raised his eyes as
            he rushed by; and my groom, who just then came up, told me
            he had slain his wife, and was going to her father’s village to
            denounce her.
         </p>
         
         <p>My boat was moored in the little harbor of Assouan, the old
            Syene, the boundary between Egypt and Ethiopia; opposite,
            lies Elephantina, the “ isle of flowers,” strewed with ruins,
            and shaded by magnificent palm-trees; the last eddies of the
            cataract of the Nile foam round dark red granite cliffs, which
            rise precipitously from the river, and are piled into a mountain
            crowned by a ruined Saracenic castle. A forest of palm-trees
            divides the village from the quiet shore on whose silvery sands
            my tent was pitched. A man in an Egyptian dress saluted me
            in Italian, and in a few moments was smoking my chibouque,
            and sipping coffee by my side: he was very handsome; but
            his faded cheek and sunken eye showed hardship and suffering, and he spoke in a low and humble voice. In reply to my
            question, as to how a person of his appearance came into this
            remote region, he told me that he had been lately practising
            as a surgeon in Alexandria; he had married a Levantine girl,
            whose beauty was to him as “ la faccia del cielo:"he had
            been absent from his home, and she had betrayed him. On
            his return, he met her with a smiling countenance; in the
            evening he accompanied her to a deep well, whither she went
            to draw water, and, as she leant over it, he threw her in. As
            he said this, he paused, and placed his hands upon his ears, as
            if he still heard her dying shriek. He then continued: “ I
            have fled from Alexandria till the affair is blown over: I was
            robbed near Siout, and have supported myself miserably ever
            since, by giving medical advice to the poor country people: I
            shall soon return, and all will be forgotten. If I had not
            avenged myself, her own family, you know, must have done
            so.” And so this woman-murderer smoked on, and continued
            talking in a low and gentle voice till the moon was high; then
            he went his way, and I saw him no more.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">From the Crescent and the Cross.</div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Niblo's Garden</div>
         <p>Niblo’s Garden.—This favorite and delightful place of amusement opened last week. The performances are of a light and
            pleasing character, in admirable accordance with the genius of the
            place. The company is good, numbering among its members
            Messrs. Chippendale, Sefton, &amp;c., &amp;c.—Miss Taylor, Miss Mathews, Mrs. Watts and others. In the dancing department, Miss
            Partington and Celeste are well known and highly popular, while
            too young debutantes, Misses Deloriel and Nathalie are striving for
            popular favor. They are singularly pretty, light, graceful and wellformed; they dress beautifully, and give promise in their style of
            dancing, of much future excellence. The band is excellent; Mr.
            Marks wielding the baton with his accustomed firmness and grace.
         </p>
         
         <p>The house has been well filled every night, and if novelties are
            produced, we feel sure that this will prove a profitable season to
            Mr. Niblo.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Mr. Barton</div>
         <p>Mr. Barton, the well-known flutist, has arrived in this city, after
            a tour of extraordinary success through the Southern States. 
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="biblTitle">An Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy</div>
            <p>An Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy, No. 4: Harper &amp;
               Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>Though the present number of this excellent work is less
               profusely illustrated with cuts than those that have preceded it.
               it is the most valuable of all, being occupied chiefly with the
               subject of food, of which it treats very fully and discreetly.
               Something like thirty pages of the two last numbers are occupied by matter relating to domestic servants, which is mainly
               calculated to produce more harm than good in this country.
               The author of this department of the Encyclopaedia has entered
               into the ethics and aesthetics of servitude with great gravity,
               and a marvellously elevated tone of thought. He begins his
               essay, paragraph 1432, in this impressive manner:
            </p>
            
            <p>Domestic servants are a class in society no less essential to its
               welfare and convenience than the equivalent in subsistence and
               money which, for service done, that class receives, is essential
               to the well-being of each individual belonging to it.
            </p>
            
            <p>We doubt whether this has been written by a gentleman who
               has ever had the honor, personally, to officiate as a domestic
               servant of any kind, although in his description of what a servant should be, he manifests a very minute acquaintance with
               the duties of a foot-boy, scullion, &amp;c. His picture of a nurse
               is particularly edifying; he has drawn the character of a more
               perfect monster than can be found in any novel:
            </p>
            
            <p>In person a nurse should have no striking peculiarity or deformity; no habitual tricks with the features, such as squinting or grimaces; no defect in the articulation, such as lisping
               and stammering; no singularity or vulgarity in the tone or accent; for such peculiarities always brings into exercise the imitative propensities of childhood. In stature the middle size is, for
               a nurse, preferable to either extreme of tall or short; the one
               often causing deficiency in activity, the other in muscular power.
               The constitution of a nurse maid should be sound. Tendencies
               to humors of any kind, to consumption, to rheumatism, or even
               being liable to frequent headaches, would detract from the personal fitness of an individual for the duties of the nursery. In
               age the nurse should be neither very old, nor very young; were
               she old, she might possibly be very deficient in activity and
               temper; were she too young, she might want consideration and
               judgment. In disposition, she should be cheerful even to liveliness, yet, withal, gentle. Boisterous gayety in the nurse would
               be almost as injurious to her infant charges as a temper of irritability and violence. In the situation and duties of a nurse
               there is much to try the temper; and it is not reasonable to expect that it should be always unruffled: still, no one is fit for
               the charge of children who cannot control in herself any violent
               expression of irritation.
            </p>
            
            <p>In personal habits the nurse should be scrupulously correct.
               Cleanliness and neatness are not to be dispensed with in the
               individual who is to lay the foundation of good habits in the
               objects of her superintendence. Deficiency in such habits can,
               in her, only arise from indolence; and if this defect be inculcated in childhood, by the force of her example, it may, being the 
               parent of so many other vices, blight the promise given in the 
               first years of life of the exercise of future mental vigor.
            </p>
            
            <p>But, after all, no personal nor acquired qualification in the
               nurse can be put in competition with the all-important requisite
               of vigorous, effective, and virtuous principles.
            </p>
            
            <p>Here is a greater amount of high qualities required in a
               nurse than would be exacted from a Prime Minister, or a Chief 
               Justice. Turning to the table of wages, we find that the pay 
               of such an angel as is described above, varies from twenty to
               thirty pounds per annum, while the dress required for such an
               admirable form, every article of which is particularly named,
               (petticoats 12s, body linen 6s, &amp;c.&amp;c.,) amounts to £7.8.0 sterling per annum.
            </p>
            
            <p>The duties of each servant are very fully detailed; we select
               the article on a “ footman,” as a sample, from which it will be
               seen that his office is by no means a sinecure.
            </p>
            
            <p>He must rise early, and endeavor to get some of the roughest
               part of his work done before his breakfast, and before he is required to appear in the breakfast-room. In order to preserve
               the cleanliness of his clothes, he should be provided with a complete overall suit, made of materials that will easily brush clean
               or bear washing. Covered over with these, he brushes the
               clothes of the gentlemen of the family, then cleans and polishes their boots and shoes, which the night before, if wet or damp,
               he had placed at a proper distance from the fire, to dry them
               gradually: an attention which enables him afterwards to give
               them a finer polish. These done and set ready to convey to
               their owners, he then cleans the knives and forks, wipes them,
               and puts them away till wanted. After this he washes and
               cleans himself previously to the preparations for the family
               breakfast table. After laying the cloth and placing the required
               number of cups, saucers, plates, &amp;c., he puts the heater into the
               kitchen fire, sees that water is boiling, and the supplies of
               bread, butter, &amp;c. ready, and then is prepared for the summons
               for the urn. His own breakfast time is regulated by that of the
               family, the footman in some houses taking breakfast with the
               other servants, and in others in his own pantry on the remains
               of the family breakfast.
            </p>
            
            <p>After the footman has himself breakfasted,washed and replaced
               in the china closet whatever has been used of china at the breakfast table, together with the plate, waiters and trays, he must direct his attention to the cleaning of candlesticks (see “ Cleaning”), trimming of lamps, (see “ Artificial Illumination,”), put ting them in right places in his pantry till they are wanted.—
               The mahogany furniture in the dining-room or library he must
                rub daily , and twice weekly he ought to wash away any spots
                it may have acquired, restoring afterward the polish it may have
                lost, by any of the means mentioned under “ Cleaning.” Some
                of the windows he should clean weekly, availing himself of
                periods of the day when the occupants of the rooms are absent
                from them. Afterward returning to the pantry, he should set
               himself to prepare something or other for the dinner table;
               either to rub the plate, to wipe the glass, &amp;c., until it be time to
               prepare for the luncheon. During this part of the day he should
               be in such a dress as is not inconsistent with his employments,
               nor yet unfit for him to appear in if summoned by bells to the
               parlor or to the hall door. A colored cotton or plain cloth jacket and white linen apron are usually worn by footmen while engaged as above described. The parlor luncheon being generally called for about one o’clock, he must have the tray set ready;
               when carried into the parlor, and properly arranged, he will
               usually be at liberty to get his own dinner, which is generally
               ready at this period of the day. When his mistress requires it,
               the footman should be ready to attend her, either with the carriage, or to follow her if she walks out. For this latter part of
               his morning’s duty, he should be neatly dressed; his clothes and
               hat should be well brushed; his shoes and stockings and gloves
               clean. A dirty looking footman is a disgrace rather than a
               credit to a family. In giving directions to the coachman he
               should be quick and accurate; nor is it altogether needless to
               remark that, even in his announcing rap at the doors of the
               parties on whom his lady calls, there is a propriety to be observed as to its measure and degree; if too loud and long, it disturbs
               a whole neighborhood; if too insignificant, it may be deficient
               in respect to his lady. In following her during her walks, he
               should preserve a steady decorum of manner, and be observant
               and ready in case any emergency should make his aid necessary
               to her.
            </p>
            
            <p>Waiting at table is one of the most important parts of his employments, and requires more skill and attention from him, if
               unaided by others, than when he is one among many attendants.
               Here, any neglect of his other duties will be apparent, and the
               censure must fall on him alone. Knives, forks, plate, and
               glass will all tell of his industry or of his negligence.
            </p>
            
            <p>The general deportment of a footman, while waiting at dinner, should bo quiet and quick, but not hurried or bustling: he
               should tread lightly, change plates, knives,, &amp;.c. without clatter,
               and should speak as little as possible, and never in a raised tone
               of voice, unless it be necessary in answering questions. He
               should hand everything with the left hand, and to the left of the
               person he is assisting to anything. The tablecloth, in removing, should have each side and ends lightly thrown together, and
               be carried out of the room, and laid aside until a convenient
               opportunity for shaking it and folding it up. On formal occasions, the tablecloth is left, and long slips down each side art
               used, and removed when dinner is over. It should be wrapt up
               in the folds previously made, and placed carefully in the tablelinen press. Dinner over, and the dessert and wine properly
               placed on the table, the footman retires to his own pantry to
               wash glasses, &amp;c.., and to put everything once more in its right 
               
               place. Then he prepared for taking up coffee and tea; puts the
               urn heater into the fire; places teacups, &amp;c., on the board; and
               sets cakes, bread and butter, milk, &amp;c. on his waiter, ready to
               carry to the drawing-room when required. At night he closes
               all window-shutters and locks up doors; carries up bed candles;
               takes the slippers to his master; and, lastly, collects, as far as
               he can, all small articles of plate, such as teaspoons, which are
               in constant dispersion during the day in most houses; counts
               all over; locks it up or places it in security—and thus closes
               his daily business.
            </p>
            
            <p>To place candles properly in the candlesticks, though not
               strictly a branch of cleaning generally, completes this part of
               the footman’s work. Candles should be placed perfectly straight
               in the candlestick; any inclination from the perpendicular being
               not only disagreeable to the eye, but causing the tallow or wax
               to run wastefully down the sides, because the heat of the flame
               acts more powerfully on one side of the candle than on the other. The same effect is produced by dirt or soil on the surface
               of the candle, as also causing an irregular action of the heat.
               If the nozzle of the candlestick be too large for the candle, a
               small fold of paper must be put round the candle, not so wide
               as to be visible when the candle is placed in it. The wick of
               the candles, if they have not been previously lighted, should 
               be just set fire to and blown out. For this, when they are 
               wanted, they will light the more easily.
            </p>
            
            <p>In trimming candles which have been previously in use, it is 
               desirable to pare off the top, so far as to form again the conical 
               shape into which they had been originally moulded. The object
               of this is to prevent that surplus of melted tallow, caused by
               the heating of so large a circumference of tallow, and which
               the wick cannot at first consume, from flowing down the sides
               of candles, wasting as well as disfiguring them.
            </p>
            
            <p>Candle ends, mould as well as wax, ought to be used upon
               save-alls by the servants, and not put into the box of scrapings,
               to add to the perquisites of those whose office it is to clean the
               candlesticks.
            </p>
            
            <p>For these trifling services and every day accomplishments,
               the footman receives from 10 to 25 pounds per annum, which 
               will not be considered too much when it is seen that he must
               have the nanners of a perfect gentleman, and the gallantry of
               an old chevalier, besides being six feet in his stockings, and the
               owner of good teeth and broad shoulders.
            </p>
            
            <p>But the most interesting of all to a great part of American
               readers, will be the description and list of duties assigned to a 
               “ maid of all work,” that kind of servant being the most common in American families.
            </p>
            
            <p>First, she must be an early riser; before her mistress gets
               up, her kitchen, parlor, and hall should be properly cleaned (see
               art. “ Cleaning,”), and she herself washed and neatly dressed,
               ready to attend on her mistress and prepare her breakfast, taking
               her own also about the same time. After breakfast, and after 
               washing and putting away the breakfast things, and receiving
               her mistress’s orders for the day, she should repair to the bedrooms, and proceed to clean and arrange them, as described
               above (see “ Household Duties”) From these employments it
               is probable that she may be oacasionally called away to answer
               bells; and, on such occasions, she should look to her kitchen
               fire now and then, to keep it in readiness for the cooking, to
               which she will, in a short time, have to attend. When up-stairs
               work is done, she must return to her kitchen, and set about
               preparing the dinner. In some cases, the mistress may, perhaps, assist her. It will be an advantage to the servant to have
               such an assistant and instructress who may be clever in the
               art of cooking.
            </p>
            
            <p>Before dinner is served she should again wash her hands and
               change her apron, making her dress as seemly as the nature of
               her employments permit. In a service such as the one now described, the family usually dine first, and the servant afterward,
               on the remains of the dinner. As she brings it from table she 
               should put it near the fire to keep it warm until she has time to 
               sit down to it. If she does her duty to her employer, she may
               conscientiously attend to any little circumstances that may promote her own comfort.	
            </p>
            
            <p>Her dinner over, the clearing away, scouring saucepans, 
               washing dishes, with every other necessary act of cleanliness, 
               will occupy some part of the afternoon, in the course of which 
               she must find time to make up the kitchen fire, set on the teakettle, and sweep up the kitchen hearth. Her work completed, 
               she again washes herself and changes her dress; she is then 
               
               ready to wait upon her mistress at tea, and to attend in any oth-
               er way to her comfort.
            </p>
            
            <p>The evening is occupied with closing doors and windows,
               and arranging the bedrooms for the night.
            </p>
            
            <p>Besides the daily routine, she must contrive to bring into each
               day some portion of the weekly cleaning. Her kitchen should
               be scoured twice a week, on Wednesday and Saturday; the parlour swept every other morning; the hall washed; bedrooms
               swept, and carpets taken up and shaken on Tuesday and Friday; plate cleaned on Wednesday and Saturday; block tin kitchen utensils, plated candlesticks, and brass work on Thursday
               (see “ Cleaning".) Once a fortnight or once in three weeks,
               the floors of bedrooms should be scoured (see “Scouring”.) marks
               on painted wainscots washed off, windows cleaned, &amp;c.
            </p>
            
            <p>If the washing be done in the house, the above routine will be
               occasionally broken into for a few days, though probably she
               will be allowed some assistance at the washtub, and will find
               her mistress ready to take on herself some portion of the lighter business of starching and getting up the fine linen.
            </p>
            
            <p>The young lady who performs these duties well, and is moreover virtuous, cheerful and good looking, may hope for seven
               pounds per annum, and tea and sugar.
            </p>
            
            <p>The whole of the article on domestic servants is very pleasant reading, if not very profitable on this side of the Atlantic,
               and the description of a gentleman’s household reads like a
               chapter from a fashionable novel.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">An Explanatory and Phonographic Pronouncing Dictionary</div>
            <p>As Explanatory and Phonographic Pronouncing Dictionary
               of the English Language: To which is added a Vocabulary
               of Greek, Latin, Scripture, Christian, and Geographical Names,
               with their Pronunciation; together with a Collection of Words
               and Phrases from Foreign Languages, often met with in the
               Works of English Writers, with their Signification. Edited by
               William Bolles. New London. Published by Bolles &amp; Williams.
            </p>
            
            <p>A work such as Mr. Bolles has here given us, was certainly
               much needed—that is to say, a complete English Vocabulary
               with each word properly defined and its pronunciation distinctly exhibited. Walker’s Sheridan has been long objectionable,
               of course; for during the last fifty years the advance of literature, and more especially of science, has introduced into the
               language a vast number of words which had no existence at
               the period of the compilation of that work. It contains only
               about 33,000 words, and the Dictionary now before us includes
               no less than 85,000—“ 20,000 more than were ever offered to
               the American public in any one work”—this, too, exclusive of
               more than 20,000, Greek, Latin, Scripture, Christian, and
               Geographical proper names. Walker’s volume, moreover,
               was essentially defective in its pronunciation, from a similar
               reason—that is to say, from the lapse of time since its composition, and the important changes sanctioned by usage during
               the interval. The 100,000 words furnished by Mr. Bolles,
               are divided into syllables, with the pronunciation of each given
               phonographically according to Sheridan’s rules, but with an
               absolutely rigorous application of them. Where the usage is
               settled, it has been scrupulously followed: where not, resort
               has been had to analogy and classical authority.
            </p>
            
            <p>Sheridan's rules were as follows:</p>
            
            <p>No character should be set down in any word which is not
               pronounced. Every distinct simple sound should have a distinct character to mark it, for which it should uniformly stand.
               The same character should never be set down as the representative of two different sounds. All compound sounds should
               be marked only by such characters as will naturally and necessarily produce those sounds, upon their being pronounced
               according to their names in the alphabet.
            </p>
            
            <p>These rules are theoretically perfect, but the pronouncing
               dictionaries in use have invariably failed in carrying them into
               practice. Sheridan and Walker make no scruple, for example,
               of presenting to the eye letters for which no sound is heard.
               Mr. Bolles, in his Preface, furnishes us with some specimens
               of this error. The pronunciation of the word courteous, is, in
               Sheridan, kur'-tshus—inWalker, kur'-tshe-us—and in Bolles,
               
               kort-yus. The last is indisputably the truest both as regards
               the phonographical distinctness with which the intended
               sounds are conveyed, and the more modern and polished pronunciation of the word itself.
            </p>
            
            <p>The orthography of Dr. Johnson has been followed, in our
               opinion very properly, throughout; except “ in cases where
               custom has decidedly sanctioned a change for the better, as in
               the omission of u in the termination our and of final k, preceded by c, in words derived from the learned languages, etc.
               etc.” We quote this last passage from Mr. Bolles, because
               we fully agree with him that custom has sufficiently established the orthographies in question, however much we may be
               inclined to dispute, in many cases, the justice or propriety of
               the custom.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Bolles has admitted obsolete words when they are to
               be found in authors not obsolete, “ or when they have any form
               or beauty that may deserve revival." His reason for admitting
               them when found in authors not obsolete is, with some modification, unanswerable. “ Indeed,” he says, “ the vocabulary
               of an explanatory English Dictionary would be exceedingly
               defective, in which one should look in vain for words occurring
               in such authors as Bacon, Boyle, Shakspeare, Milton, &amp;c.,
               while their works constitute a portion of the standard literature of the language.” It should be observed, however, that
               it is only in the case of such as Bacon, Boyle, Shakspeare and
               Milton, that the lexicographist is justifiable in applying this
               rule. Innumerable obsolete words may be found “ in authors
               not obsolete,” which words, nevertheless, it would be folly
               to attempt resuscitating. We mean to say that Mr.
               Bolles’ proposition is, in his Preface, too loosely or too generally stated. In fact, that is to say in the body of his work,
               we perceive that he has confined his revivals within the proper limits—confined them to such authors as are emphatically
               standard. He has included, however, a vast number of words
               now regarded as obsolete—although we by no means think he
               has improperly included them. He promises an abridgment
               in which they will be omitted.
            </p>
            
            <p>In regard to rules of pronunciation, we cannot do better than
               quote the author’s own words, with which in the main, we
               heartily agree.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ These rules are so multitudinous, and the exceptions to
               almost all of them so numerous, that it is believed that in a
               work of this nature they tend more to embarrass than to aid
               the inquirer, and that however useful these troublesome appendages may be in works where the pronunciation is omitted
               or loosely given, they are rendered useless by the plan of this
               dictionary, in which the pronunciation of any word can be
               much more readily and certainly ascertained by a bare inspection than by a reference to rules almost smothered amid
               their own anomalies.”
            </p>
            
            <p>With these judicious views Mr. Bolles has contented himself with an introductory exposition of the principles on which
               Human Speech is founded—(a well written and altogether
               valuable paper)—some Directions to Foreigners (particularly
               the French)—and a few rules to be observed by the natives of
               Ireland and Wales, in order to attain a just pronunciation of
               English.
            </p>
            
            <p>If, upon the whole, we cannot regard this work as the most
               profoundly vague word often vaguely applied) we are at least
               disposed to consider it the most comprehensive, the most accurate, and by far the most practical—that is to say the most
               useful of its class.
            </p>
            
            <p>Its typographical execution is excellent. It is for sale, we
               understand, at the exceedingly moderate price of three dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">We Are Informed</div>
            <p>We are informed that Mr. Cornelius Matthews is not the author
               of the article in the North American Review which recently appeared in Simms' Magazine. It was signed with the initials of
               Mr. M., but Simms was himself the author.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Dramatic Authors of America</div>
            <p>The Dramatic Authors of America. By James Rees. Phila-
               delphia: G. B. Tilber &amp; Co., 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p> This is a very curious and a highly profitable little work for
               the student of American literature. It is probable that no
               other man in the country has sufficient love for the Drama to
               enable him to gather together so many forgotten facts in relation to this subject as Mr. Rees has done in this little book.
               The Dramatic Authors of America! How many could the
               most learned man among us enumerate? Perhaps a dozen.
               Very many American scholars would doubtless have to think
               a while before naming even one. Yet Mr. Rees has mustered
               a regiment here of no less than one hundred and eighty-eight,
               thirty-four of them being anonymous. Some of these authors
               have produced as many plays as Shakspeare, while a good
               many have produced but one. And yet, among the whole
               of their Dramas, there are not more than three or four that
               keep their place upon the stage. A literary gentleman remarked the other day that he did not know any body who had not
               written a word; after looking over Mr. Rees’s catalogue of
               Dramatists we could not readily remember any body who had
               not written a play. Mr. Rees evidently undertook his task
               con amore, and doubtless made his list as complete as he could,
               but he has made four omissions within our knowledge, and
               doubtless many beyond it. So that we may safely estimate
               the Dramatic Authors of the United States, or of Alleghania,
               at two hundred, and giving them three plays a piece, which
               must be within the mark, the Alleghanish Drama must amount
               to at least six hundred plays. John Neal is the anthor of a
               five act tragedy called Otheo. Mr. Edward S. Gould is the
               author of a tragedy founded on the history of Richard Cour
               de Lyon, which was successfully represented at the Park theatre
               about fifteen years since, and Cornelius Matthews is the author of a five act comedy called the Politicians, which we believe has never been produced at any theatre. Mr. Rees has
               not included either of these dramatic authors in his catalogue.
               Probably Mr. Griswold will include these and many more of
               whom the country has never heard, in his forth-coming book
               on American prose writers.
            </p>
            
            <p>Notwithstanding the complaints that we hear continually
               from the denizens of the theatre, about the decline of the legitimate drama, there seems to be a very decided love for
               dramatic compositions among our educated men as well as
               among the lower classes, from whom the theatre derives its
               principal support.
            </p>
            
            <p>The wife of a popular tragedian in New York says, that
               they always tremble when the door bell rings; expecting the
               apparition of a dramatic author with a manuscript tragedy to
               follow as a matter of course. She says that they have had a
               large chest constructed in their garret for the express purpose
               of keeping manuscript tragedies. Where there is so much
               smoke it would not be unreasonable to expect some fire;
               but the American Drama does not appear to promise sufficient
               heat to produce combustion. Mrs. Mowatt has recently “fired
               up,” to a certain extent; but whether she has produced a real
               flame or only an ignis fatuus remains to be seen. One thing is
               very certain, that no art can flourish in a country when it is
               not countenanced by the better classes of society, and it can-,
               not be denied that the theatre derives no aid, with us, from
               the learned, the wealthy, or the professedly religious. All
               classes of society read the Wandering Jew, and everything
               that comes from Dickens; doctors of low, divinity and medicine read such works and place them in their libraries; but
               these people never visit the theatre let the attraction be what it
               may. Let half-a-dozen D. Ds be seen in the pit of the Park
               Theatre, and we should not only see their congregations following them, but we should see our men and women of genius 
               
               exerting their talents for the amusement and instruction of
               such fit audiences. One of the last things that we could ever
               do would be to recommend, or countenance idle and vicious
               amusements, but no amusement which requires so great a variety of artistic excellence as the drama, ever could be vicious
               or injurious if it were countenanced by those who assume the
               office of public teachers.
            </p>
            
            <p>Whether the theatre be a disreputable place, as conducted at present, is not a point which we need debate about; the
               theatre exists and is likely to exist, and to exert an extensive influence of some kind in the commnnity, and the only
               consideration should be, with good men, whether it would be
               better to leave it to grow in its enormities, or by giving it their
               countenance, convert it into a blessing instead of a curse to the
               people. There is no objection among good people to pictures,
               none to music, none to wit and humor, none to rhetoric; but
               the drama is nothing more than these united. Instead of going
               on separate nights to witness each department of art by itself,
               in the theatre they may see them happily assembled to produce
               an effect. The fault of the false position which the drama
               holds does not lie so much with the better classes of society, as
               with the managers of theatres themselves; if these will make
               brothels and drinking houses of their theatres they have no
               right to complain when respectable people refuse to patronise
               them. The reform must begin in the theatre, and when that
               has been effected, we have no doubt that it will extend to those
               without. The appearance of so respectable a person as Mrs.
               Mowatt on the stage, we trust, will not be without a purifying
               effect upon the atmosphere of the play-house.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">New Works Lately Received</div>
         <div class="head">NEW WORKS LATELY RECEIVED.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">Vathek</div>
            <p>Vathek. With a Biographical Sketch of the Author. No. 1 of the
               New Series of the Mirror Library. Published by Morris, Willis
               &amp; Fuller, pp. 50. Price 25 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are very glad to see a new series of the Mirror Library,
               and to weleome Vathek in No. 1. The “biographical sketch
               of the author” however, is a misnomer: the gossiping recollections of Mr. Redding by no means form a biography, and we
               would be glad to see some of the productions of Beckford substituted in their place; the Memoirs of the Old Painters for
               instance. The biography of Beckford is a good subject for a
               philosophical or a fanciful writer, and it is a matter of surprise
               that none of his countrymen have yet made an attempt on
               his “life.” Mr. Redding’s recollections are very agreeable
               reading for hot weather, but he was too much impressed by
               the externals which surrounded Vathek to be able to form a
               cool judgment of his character. The book is neatly got up,
               of a size to correspond with the first series of the Mirror Library.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p26">
            <div class="biblTitle">Self</div>
            <p>Self. By the Author of “Cecil." New York: Harper Sc
               Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Cecil" was one of the most popular novels ever published
               in England, and produced, on its first appearance, scarcely
               less sensation than “ Vivian Grey," or “ Pelham,” to both
               which, however, it has a strong family resemblance. It has
               more spirit—more dash—more abandon—and infinitely more
               impudence than either: taking qualities, all of these, with the
               public. Its learning, too, was seemingly prodigious, and it was
               difficult (for this and other reasons) to believe it the work of a
               woman. Mrs. Gore was, nevertheless, well understood to be
               the author—although it has been asserted that she received aid,
               in the bespicing of the book with scraps of pedantry, from a
               well-known scholar and litterateur of London. This we do
               
               not believe—nor is there any sufficient reason for believing it.
               In the first place, had any such aid been given, it must have
               been given after the composition by Mrs. Gore, and traces of
               interpolation would have inevitably remained:—none such
               are apparent. In the second place, all the former productions
               of the authoress evince the same species of apparent erudition—an erudition which is only apparent, and carefully introduced to serve a purpose. True erudition is only certainly
               discoverable in its entire results. There is nothing in anything written by Mrs. Gore, which is not within the reach of
               any decently educated person of ingenuity, having access to
               the large libraries of London. The same thing may be said
               even of that remarkable work, “ The Doctor,” and of a great
               many other similar publications.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Self” has all the principal traits of “ Cecil,” and is, perhaps, a more entertaining book upon the whole—although its
               subject does not offer so many facilities. We recommend it
               heartily to all persons troubled with ennui.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Waverly Novels</div>
            <p>The Waverly Novels, by Sir Walter Scott: with the author’s
               latest corrections and additions. Complete in five volumes
               (3340 pages) for two dollars and fifty cents. Philadelphia:
               Carey &amp; Hart.
            </p>
            
            <p>The general title of this work, as we give it above, includes
               all necessary information respecting it. A greater amount of
               valuable and interesting reading was never furnished for the
               same money. The contents of the second volume (just
               issued) are The Heart of Mid-Lothian; The Bride of Lammermoor; The Legend of Montrose; Ivanhoe; The Monastery; and The Abbott. The New York agents are Burgess,
               Stringer &amp; Co., W. H. Graham, aud Saxton Sc Miles.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p28">
            <div class="biblTitle">Veronica</div>
            <p>Veronica; or The Free Court of Aarau. Translated from the
               German of Zschokke, by the Author of Giafar Al Barmeki.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is number 51 of Harper’s “ Library of Select Novels.”
               Zschokke, of late, has become popular in America, to an extent which neither his intrinsic merit nor his foreign reputation would appear to justify. We would not undervalue his
               genius, (if genius it can be called,) but we mean to say that
               there are numerous Germans whose works might be translated to better purpose. “ Veronica” is not the least interesting of his novels—but the author of “Giafar Al Barmeki”
               has himself written a far better original thing, and we would
               urgently advise him to leave the task of translation to those
               who have no capacity for anything else.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p11">
         <div class="biblTitle">Translation of an Ode of Sappho</div>
         <div class="head">TRANSLATION OF AN ODE OF SAPPHO.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Blest as the immortal gods is he
            
            <br></br>On whom each day thy glances shine;
            
            <br></br>Who hears thy voice of melody.
            
            <br></br>And meets thy smile so all divine.
            
            <br></br>Oh, when I list thine accents low
            
            <br></br>How thrills my breast with tender pain—
            
            <br></br>Fire seems through every vein to glow,
            
            <br></br>And strange confusion whelms my brain.
            
            <br></br>My sight grows dim beneath the glance
            
            <br></br>Whose ardent rays I may not meet,
            
            <br></br>While swift and wild my pulses dance.
            
            <br></br>Then cease all suddenly to beat.
            
            <br></br>And o’er my cheek with rapid gush,
            
            <br></br>I feel the burning life-tide dart;
            
            <br></br>Then backward like a torrent rush
            
            <br></br>All icy cold upon my heart.
            
            <br></br>And I am motionless and pale,
            
            <br></br>And silent as an unstrung lyre;
            
            <br></br>And feel, while thus each sense doth fail,
            
            <br></br>Doomed in thy presence to expire.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">MARY E. HEWITT.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p12">
         <div class="biblTitle">The New Opera at Philadelphia</div>
         <div class="head">THE NEW OPERA AT PHILADELPHIA.</div>
         
         <p>According to our expressed intention we visited Philadelphia for the purpose of being present at the performance of
            Mr. Fry’s “ Leonora.” The production of a grand Opera,
            composed by a resident American, was an event which, we believe, fully warranted some extraordinary outlay upon our
            part, in order to present to our readers a faithful account of the
            character of the work. Fully aware of all the difficulties attendant upon the production of a new Opera by a new hand,
            we went prepared for all the annoyances on the stage and in
            the orchestra, consequent upon a first performance, or rather a
            last dress rehearsal.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Chesnut Theatre was crowded in every part; the boxes
            presented an array of beauty and fashion but rarely congregated together at one time; and if the fair ladies of our sister cityare to be judged by the various specimens then before us, we
            should say that a feeling of “ brotherly love ” towards them
            would prove a dangerous experiment.
         </p>
         
         <p>The plot of the Opera is no other than Bulwer’s Lady of
            Lyons. Most of our readers are familiar with the action of
            that play. One or two characters are omitted, and Claude's
            mother in the play, is changed to Julia’s sister in the Opera.
            No other material alteration is made, if we except the change
            in the locality and the time, which are transferred from Lyons
            to Spain—from the eighteenth to the sixteenth century. The
            reader will, however, bear the first of these changes in mind,
            as the entire truthfulness and fitness of the music turns upon it.
            The characters are as follows: Leonova, daughter of Valdor,
            Mrs. Seguin; Mariana, sister of Julio, Miss F. Ince; Julio,
            a peasant, Mr. Frazer; Montalao, a gentleman of rank, Mr.
            Seguin; Valdor, a rich merchant, Mr. Richings; Alferez, a
            gentleman, Mr. Brunton. The overture consists of a maestoso movement, an agitato, and we believe, an andante movement with the usual repetitions. No one portion of the overture was striking either for its originality or its beauty. We
            listened in vain for some phrase which should develope a
            thought or suggest an idea; it was simply a succession of motivi, as applicable to one thing as to another. Much blame
            must be laid to the very defective instrumentation; no one
            subject came out clearly; the brass and wood instruments
            were used injudiciously; effects were sought after by violent
            and repeated contrasts, by phrases given to the full brass and
            echoed by the wood, headed by the piccolo-flute—now the whole
            subject would be full to repletion, and now thin to attenuation.
            We did not hear a single point in which the character of one
            of the orchestral instruments was developed. The violincelli
            were used as common basses; the violas as common fiddles;
            and the fagotti did only general work. Such is the general
            character of the instrumentation throughout the Opera.
         </p>
         
         <p>The opening chorus is a bold and spirited melody and will
            in all probability, from its familiar character, be whistled about
            the streets. Montalao’s first song is “ King Death was a rar old fallow." This song as composed by Chevalier Newkomn
            is universally known, and what could have induced Mr. Fry
            to introduce it into his Opera, unless to suggest comparison,
            we are at a loss to conceive. Comparisons will be drawn and
            to his disadvantage, for the first phrases of his version prove,
            beyond a doubt, that Newkom’s fine song was fresh in his
            memory, and suggested, if not supplied, the thought. The introduction of the chorus is, however, cleverly managed and exceedingly effective The air “ No Haughty Maiden,” has a
            most charming florid accompaniment, and is without doubt, the
            most pleasingly instrumented piece in the Opera.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the second scene, the first scena is chiefly remarkable for
            the very bad effect produced by the accompaniments of the
            
            stringed instruments with mutes (con Sordini.) The air “ Grant
            me one only hour ” is nothing, if not Bellini.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Recitative and Air, “ Ah canst thou bid me smother,”
            is certainly a very charming composition. The melody partakes somewhat of the Spanish character and is sad and impassioned. This air is thc most natural burst of genuine feeling in the opera. It was chastely and expressively sung by
            Mr. Frazer. The oboe solo which preceded the song was
            played in a most masterly and exquisite manner by Mr. Kellner.
            We must compliment this gentlemen upon his performance
            throughout; it was the only thing worthy to he remembered
            amidst the vast orchestral chaos. Mr. Kellner would do credit
            to any orchestra.
         </p>
         
         <p>The next point of consequence we arrive at, is the chorus—
            “ Who can be this youthful stranger?” The subject is decidedly clever, but it is elaborated to an absurd extent, and the
            changes towards the close are vexatious and unmeaning—a
            striving hard for something, and nothing thereby achieved.
         </p>
         
         <p>Julio’s following recitative is good and the aria is pleasing,
            but it is spun out to a ridiculous extent—the subject being repeated, with intervening symphonies, three times. This is exceeding his Italian model with a vengeance.
         </p>
         
         <p>The finale to the first act “ Oh! moment too enchanting”
            is marked Bolero, to which it bears as much resemblance as a
            Tyrolean movement can bear to a Spanish Bolero. It is very
            florid, and afforded Mrs. Seguin every opportunity for a lull
            display of her executive power.
         </p>
         
         <p>The bridesmaid's chorus which opens the second act is a
            very pretty Tyrolean. The melody is flowing, and seemed to
            catch the ear of the audience for it was warmly applauded.
            The duett between Julio and Leonora is so long, and consists
            of so many movements, that it is impossible to speak as positively of it as we could wish. The first movement we noted
            as exceedingly good—a succeeding movement as borrowed
            without reserve, and another as clever in the extreme. The
            remainder of the scene presents but little worthy of particular
            notice, if we except the voluntary upon the Seraphine which
            was remarkable only for its utter want of thought and ingenuity,
            and for the pumping effects with the pedal.
         </p>
         
         <p>The ballad by Mariana which opens the second scene is a
            very pleasing little trifle and was very well received. Miss
            Ince, though lacking a musical education, possesses a pleasing
            voice and natural simplicity of manner, which take well with
            the public.
         </p>
         
         <p>There are several pleasing melodies, and one or two creditable concerted pieces, in the remainder of this act, and in the
            last act, but, though we would willingly notice them separately, want of space compels us to draw this notice to a
            close.
         </p>
         
         <p>To bring our remarks into a small compass we should say
            that although there are some very pleasing morceaux in the
            Opera, it is, beyond a doubt, wanting in originality of thought,
            is deficient in profundity, and possesses very little, if any, dramatic action. As a Spanish Opera it must be considered an
            irredeemable failure, as the composer never knew, or entirely
            mistook the characteristics of the Spanish school. We wish
            to be correctly understood. It is generally conceded that the
            great emotions which agitate the human heart—love, hatred,
            jealousy and revenge, demand no conventional mode of expression—they owe to no rule their intensity of feeling; they
            speak in a language which is universal, and whether it be the
            Spaniard or the Englishman, the Italian or the German, these
            emotions spring right up from the heart and are dependent for
            the truthfulness of expression upon the genius or inspiration of the composer. John Barnett, to be sure, in the Mountain Sylph and Boildieu, in La Dame Blanche, have succeeded
            
            in imparting to ths larger portion of the music of these operas, 
            the distinctive characteristics of the music of the land in which
            the action of the libretto is laid. But the rule is not absolute.
            There is a rule, however, which is never departed from by
            composers of any talent—a rule so natural that it must suggest
            itself to every reflecting mind. It is, that all ballads, dances
            and simple chorusses, should be purely and entirely national.
            The national music of every country is faithfully portrayed in 
            its ballads and dances, and if these do not partake of the national character, the scene might as well be laid in Russia as
            in France, or in China as in Spain. Mr. Fry has, therefore,
            in this important feature, entirely failed. The music of Leanora has, indeed, no distinctive character—no idiosyncracy—it
            is simply music without relevancy to time or place. There is
            another and a fatal fault to be noticed; a fault which Mr.
            Fry, knowing the voices he had to write for, should not have
            fallen into.
         </p>
         
         <p>The music is too high both for the soprano and tenor. Both
            Mrs. Seguin and Mr. Frazer are taxed beyond their power
            and compass, and the effect throughout is strained and painful.
            The music, if published as written, would be beyond the compass of all but operatic singers. The Instrumentation is still
            the weakest part of the composition. We should have judged
            it to have been a very early attempt of a young writer. Want
            of clearness in design, outre effects and injudicious combinations, with a general poverty of conception, are the leading
            characteristics presented by the partition. We feel certain
            that the composer never imagined such effects as came out in
            the orchestra. A man may be an admirable theorist in the
            art of scoring, but if he has not had years of practical experience, his theories are not worth a jot—he may write a score
            that will look well, but looks go for nothing when it comes
            into the orchestra. A man never feels so childlike and helpless as when he hears his first important score performed, and
            finds bis beauties upon paper, different in every way from what
            he expected. In short, books are worthless except for general principles, and though Mr. Fry may have written a thousand scores which he has never heard, we are sure that the
            fact of hearing one of these, would have done more for his
            improvement than years of blind labor.
         </p>
         
         <p>In conclusion, while commending the perseverance which
            he has exhibited, we can only regret that he has so misapplied 
            his labors. If, instead of following a hackneyed model which
            has laid him open—and justly, too—to the charge of wholesale
            plagiarism, he had bestowed the same amount of time in
            working out a style of his own, something worthy of the labor
            might have resulted therefrom; but now, even allowing that
            Leonora becomes popular, the composer will owe at least one
            half to the school which he adopts, for in the servile imitations
            of any school, striking similarities are entirely unavoidable,
            and these similarities are almost certain to recall the prominent and popular beauties of the school or composer followed,
            and the public willingly receive the counterfeit for the sake of
            the real.
         </p>
         
         <p>We hoped that Leonora would have been the foundation of
            an American school, but it is simply a weak copy of an original which is itself too weak to bear diluting. If Mr. Fry is
            to become anything in the future, he must look with doubt upon
            those who say, that this work ranks him with the greatest
            composers of Europe. It is ignorant flattery or something
            worse. We thought it injudicious in Mr. Fry, to say the least
            of it, to inform the audience that the same amount of mental
            labor, study, &amp;c., &amp;c., was given to the production of Leonora, as the greatest composers of Europe usually bestowed upon their productions. Mr. Fry doubtless worked hard, and all
            the credit due him should be awarded; it should, however, be
            remembered that the dwarf labors, in proportion, as hard as the
            
            giant, but the result of that labor is also in proportion. Of the
            performance it would not be fair to judge hardly, for the rehearsals were altogether inadequate. Mrs. Seguin was, however, quite perfect, and her promptitude and steadiness frequently retrieved the music from inextricable confusion. Mr.
            Frazer has been harshly spoken of. This is unjust, as he endeavored to delay the performance of the Opera that he might
            perfect himself in his part. The only wonder is, how he got
            on as well as he did. His music was of immense length and
            great difficulty;—a man cannot study by steam, and therefore
            the errors of Mr. Frazer should fall upon those who hurried
            the Opera out.
         </p>
         
         <p>The performance of the orchestra was bad beyond belief;
            it would have been bad even, for sight playing, but for a performance after having rehearsed the music, we cannot condemn it too severely.
         </p>
         
         <p>The getting up, scenery, dresses, &amp;c., &amp;c., was highly cred-
            itable to the liberality of the managers.
         </p>
         
         <p>We shall recur to this Opera again, probably in our next, as
            we are now compelled to close abruptly from want of space.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Miscellanies</div>
         <div class="head">MISCELLANIES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Old Masters in England</div>
            <p>The old Masters in England.—There were imported
               into England, in the last five years, seventy thousand ancient
               paintings. The sales at auction average over one thousand
               a month of undoubted originals. During the months of April
               and May, 2920 old masters were sold at the regular auction
               marts. From these facts it is very evident that all the old
               masters do not find their way, as some people suppose, into
               the auction room of Mr. Levy.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Passionate Lover of Flowers</div>
            <p>A Passionate Lover of Flowers.—“ We want no better
               evidence of a good heart than the passionate love of flowers,”
               says the good-hearted Major Noah in his last Messenger; hut
               we do. In passing a very beautiful flower-garden in the
               neighborhood of New York, a week or two since, we made
               a similar remark to a lady, who replied, “ it’s all stuff; I was
               passing by this garden a few days since, and seeing the owner
               of it trimming her flowers, I asked her to give me a pink out
               of her border of carnations. ' I never give away my flowers,’
               was the ' good-hearted’ response of this passionate lover of
               flowers."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">We Stated Last Week</div>
            <p>We stated last week, on the authority of the Knickerbocker’s
               correspondent at Constantinople, that the author of Eothen was
               a gentleman named White: we had previously stated on the
               authority of a London newspaper that his name was Trevilian, we now learn from the author of the “ Crescent and the
               Cross,” that the author of Eothen is a gentleman bearing the
               handsome name of Kinglake. It is a new name and a good
               one, and we shall not contend with it until the arrival of the
               next steamer, when we shall probably hear of another one.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Profits of Novels</div>
            <p>The Profits of Novels.—During the last few years the
               Parisian daily press had run down so low in circulation that
               the plan of giving a novel in the feuilleton was adopted to
               attract purchasers; when the united energies of political
                writers and critics failed to interest the Parisian public, the
               aid of the novelist was invoked, and successfully, to save them
               from bankruptcy. In 1828, Lafitte bought one of the fifteen
               shares of the Constitutionnel, for Messrs. Cauchoir, Lemaire
               and Thiers, for which he paid one hundred thousand francs,
               and three years ago the whole paper was sold for five thousand
               pounds sterling, to Veron, a compeer of Thiers. The
               " Presse” adopted the plan of giving a novel, which succeeded,
               
               and then the “ Constitutionnel” engaged Eugene Sue, at the
               enormous price of one hundred thousand francs. Le Juif
               Errant was begun, and the sales of the paper rose to ten
               thousand copies daily at once.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">Improvement in Broadway</div>
            <p>Improvements in Broadway.—There is considerable
               tearing down and building up going on in our beautiful
               thoroughfare, but the only alterations that we notice likely
               to prove an improvement, are extensive excavations for the
               foundation of a hotel next to Wiley &amp; Putnam’s, to be kept
               by the famous Rathbone, of Buffalo, and the beginning of a
               club-house and racketts-court, building by Mr. Carman,
               opposite to St. Thomas’ Church, or. the shady side of Broadway. This novel building will extend through to Crosbystreet in the rear. The entrance to the Rev. Mr. Bellows’
               church will be a handsome addition in that part of the street.
               It is of red sand-stone, of the fashionable Gothic order.
            </p>
            
            <p>Among the places worth visiting in Broadway, is the shop
               of George Chester, at 392, who has some of the most
               beautiful specimens of stained glass that we have seen in any
               of our decorative warehouses.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Poetry of Europe</div>
            <p>The Poetry or Europe.—By Longfellow.—The first
               volume of this collection of poetry has just been issued. It is
               a very large book, neatly printed, with a portrait of Schiller,
               and a very indifferent ornamental title page. It includes
               none of the poetry of England, and but little of the poetry
               of France. The translations are from a great variety of
               sources, British and American. We hear that the professor
               receives three thousand dollars for editing the work.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Spread of Alleghanianism</div>
            <p>The Spread of Alleghanianism.—A new sign has recently been hung out in the upper part of Broadway, bearing
               this startling inscription:—“ The Alleghanian. Best of
               Liquors 3 cents per glass.” This is the most encouraging
               sign for the Alleghanians that we have met with. An Alleghanian “smasher” for 3 cents is cheap enough. The proprietor will reckon, as a matter of eourse, on the entire patronage of the amateurs in national nomenclature.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">The French Company</div>
            <p>The French Company also open at the Park next week. It is
               unusually strong in every respect. The opening Opera will be La
               Juive, by Helevy.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">M. Huber</div>
            <p>M Huber, a violincellist of reputation, recently from Paris, is at
               present in the city, and will give a concert as soon as the weather
               moderates its colidity.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mr. Tryon</div>
            <p>Mr. Tryon opens the New Bowery Theatre on Monday, with a
               vaudeville company.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p23">
         <div class="biblTitle">Obituary</div>
         <div class="head">OBITUARY.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">
            <span class="person">J. R. BLEECKER.</span>
         </div>
         
         <p>We are pained to record the death of this promising young
            painter, at the early age of 26. He died on the 5th inst., sifter a
            protracted illness, of consumption. His loss is mourned by a large
            circle of friends, who admired his genius, and loved him for his
            generous and manly qualities. A kinder hearted man or a warmer
            friend never lived. Most sincerely do we sympathize with his afflicted family in their bereavement. Mr. Bleecker was an amateur,
            but he has left works of a high order of merit, which give evidence
            of talents that would have placed his name among the first of
            American painters. His paintings are admirable for great delicacy
            of color, and beauty of conception, and for bold and original treatment. He had a true perception of the picturesque and humorous
            in character, and some of his efforts at their delineation were exceedingly happy. One of his last pictures, a very beautiful touch
            of melancholy nature, representing a scene in October, when the
            sky is growing cold, the clouds heavy, and the earth bare, is hung
            
            in the exhibition of the National Academy. He was a true lover
            of nature, and we shall look at his modest sketches with melancholy interest, now that his hand is cold in death.
         </p>	
         <div class="byline">r.</div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p24">
         <div class="biblTitle">Books in Press</div>
         <div class="head">BOOKS IN PRESS.</div>
         
         <p>By D. Appleton Sc Co.—Arnold’s Latin and Greek Prose and
            verse Composition, and other classical works. Michelet’s History
            of the Roman Republic. Michelet's Priest. Woman and Families.
            Sismondi’s History of Literature. Coleridge’s Literary Remains.
            Guizot’s Complete History of Civilization. Carey’s Translation of
            Dante’s Poems. Heeren's Historical Researches. Arnold’s Sermons and Miscellaneous works. Arnold’s Lectures on Modern
            History, with notes. Arnold’s History of Rome. Macfarland’s
            History of England. London Ladies’ Country Companion.—
            Carlyle’s Life of Schiller. Reid’s Dictionary of the English Language, l vol. 12mo.
         </p>
         
         <p>By Wiley &amp; Putnam.—Journal of an African Cruiser, with
            sketches of the Canaries, Cape de Verds, Liberia, Madeira, Sierra
            Leone and the West Coast of Africa, by an officer of the U. S.
            Navy. Table Talk, by William Hazlitt, Esq., second series
            The Autobiography of Heinrich Zschokke. Tales from the Ger
            man, of Heinrich Zschokke, by Parke Godwin, a complete col
            lection. Life and Adventures of Peter Wilkins, a Cornish man
            Maid Marion and Crotchet Castle, by the Author of “ Headlong
            Hall.” The Life of Talleyrand, by Thackeray. The Works of
            William Hazlitt. The Seer, or Common Places Refreshed, by
            Leigh Hunt.
         </p>
         
         <p>By Lea &amp; Blanchard, Philadelphia.—Simon’s Pathological and
            Practical Treatise on Scrofulous Diseases. Maingault’s Operative
            Surgery, by Wm. Sands Cox. Handbook of Foreign Cookery,
            containing receipts, principally French, German and Danish.
            Volume 8 of Miss Strickland’s Queens of England. Nearly
            ready—Miss Acton’s Modern Cookery, edited By Miss Sarah J.
            Hale, from the second London edition.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">RECENT AMERICAN PUBLICATIONS.</div>
         
         <p>The Club Room, a Daughter’s Love, and other Temperance
            Tales, by T. S. Arthur, 25 cts. Lives of Men of Letters and
            Science, who flourished in the time of George III, by Henry,
            Lord Brougham, 50 cts. The Sybil, or the Two Nations, by
            Benj. D’lsraeli, (Carey Sc Hart,) 25 cts. Cecil, or the Adventures
            of a Coxcomb—(H. G. Daggers.) Self, by the author of Cecil—
            (Harper &amp; Brothers)—25 cts. Time Works Wonders, a new
            Comedy, by Douglas Jerrold. Copland's Dictionary of Practical
            Medicine, Part 8 The Nevilles of Garretstown, by Charles
            Lever, No. 4. Elizabeth Thornton, or the flower and fruit of Female Piety, by S. J. Prince. The Nurse’s Manual, and Mother’s
            Medical Adviser. Hours of Meditation and Devotional Reflection
            upon the Moral and Social Duties of Life, Translated from the
            German of Heinrich Zschokke, 50 cts. (J.S. Redfield.) A collection of Psalms and Hymns for the Sanctuary, compiled by Rev.
            Geo. P. Ellis, of Charlestown, Mass. (Boston, Munroe &amp; Co.)
            Allegories and Christian Lessons for children, by T. B. Fox.—
            (Boston, Crosby &amp; Neiholls.) An Inquiry into the views, principles, services and influence of the leading men in the origination
            of the Union, by Thaddeus Allen.—(Boston, S. N. Dickinson.)
            A Scripture Catechism, containing the principles of the Christian
            Religion in the words of the Bible, for the use of Sunday Schools,
            by Rev. Ephraim Peabody.—(Boston, Crosby &amp; Nicholls.) Hebrew Tales, from the writings of the Ancient Hebrew Sages.—
            (Same.) It is all for the best, or Clark the Baker, a Tale for
            youth, by Miss Seaton.—(Boston, Ticknor &amp; Co.) Moral Tales
            for young people, by Mrs. E. Sedgwick.—(Boston, Crosby &amp;
            Nicholls.)
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">The National Magazine and Industrial Recorder, No. I.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">EDITED BY REDWOOD FISHER,
               
               <br></br>ASSISTED IN THE NATIONAL DEPARTMENT BY MR. EDWIN WILLIAMS.
               
               <br></br>Published Monthly, in Numbers of 96 pages, $5 per Annum.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE DESIGN OF THIS WORK IS TO DEVELope all the great resources of the country, as they are shown in
               its Agricultures, Manufactures and Commerce. Essays and statements
               on these great interests will be given, with notices of Manufacturing
               Towns and Villages, Internal Improvements, New Inventions, snd Statistical Details, exhibiting the progress of American industry.
            </p>
            
            <p>FROISSART’S CHRONICLES of England, France and Spain,
               with an Essay on the Character and Society of the Middle Ages. One
               vol. 4to. pp. 634. $3.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">SCARCE WORKS.</div>
            
            <p>THE BRITISH NAVAL CHROMICLE; a General and Biographical History of the Royal Navy. 20 vols. 8vo., bound, with numerous
               plates. Price $50.
            </p>
            
            <p>NILE'S WEEKLY REGISTER, (Subscriber's Copy) in 20 vols.
               8vo., bound. Price, $50.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received to all the American and English Periodicals
               and orders for books promptly executed.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">J. SMITH HOMANS,
               
               <br></br>Sun Office, comer of Fulton and Nassau Streets.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">This Day is Published,</div>
            
            <div class="head">LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING.</div>
            
            <p>NO.’S XI AND XII OF THE LIBRARY OF CHOICE
               READING, Containing the Crescent and the Cross, by Eliot Warburton, Esq. Two thick parts, 12mo. beautifully printed in large clear
               type, on fine white paper, each 50 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Eliot Warburton, who is known to be the author of these brilliantly
               sparkling papers, the “ Episodes of Eastern Travel,” which lit up our
               last November. His book (The Crescent and the Cross) must and will
               be capital.”—Vide “ Eothen,” page 179.
            </p>
            
            <p>“This delightful work is, from first to last, a splendid panorama of
               Eastern scenery, in the full blaze of its magnificence. The crowning
               merit of the book is, that it is evidently the production of a gentleman,
               and a man of the world, who has lived in the best society, and been an
               attentive observer of the scenes and characters which have passed before
               him during his restless and joyous existence. To a keen sense of the
               ludicrous, he joins a power of sketching and grouping which are happily
               demonstrated.”—Morning Post.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ We could not recommend a better book as a travelling companion
               than Mr. Warburton’s. Admirably written as is the work, and eminently graphic as are its descriptions, it possesses a yet more exalted merit
               in the biblical and philosophical illustrations of the writer.”—United
               Service Magazine.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Mr. Warburton has fulfilled the promise of his title-page. The
               Realities’ of ‘ Eastern Travel’ are described with a vividness which invest them with deep and abiding interest; while the ‘ Romantic’ adventures which the enterprising tourist met with in his course are
               narrated with a spirit which shows how much he enjoyed these reliefs
               from the ennui of every-day life.”—Globe.
            </p>
            
            <p>Published aud for sale by	         WILEY &amp; PUTNAM,
               161 Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">LONDON AND PARIS LITERARY AGENCY</div>
            
            <div class="ab">O RICH &amp; SONS.
               
               <br></br>AGENTS FOR THE PURCHASE OF BOOKS FOR
               
               <br></br>AMERICA.
               
               <br></br>Agents for the Library of Congress,
               
               <br></br>The New-York Society Library.
               
               <br></br>The Albany Institute,
               
               <br></br>The Boston Athenaeum, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>12	Red Lion Square, London.
               
               <br></br>13	Rue Pot de Per. Paris.
            </div>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich Respectfully informs his friends and fellow-citizens that he
               has formed an establishment in Paris, in connexion with his old establishment in Red Lion Square, for the purpose of furnishing BOOKS
               published on the continent without the heavy expense attending their 
               transmission through England. Each of these establishments will be
               conducted by one of his sons, under his own general superintendence.—
               This new arrangement, he trusts, will prove of signal advantage to his
               correspondents, and no exertions will be wanting to execute their orders
               on the most advantageous terms. Orders may be sent through, and
               small sums payed to Messrs. Goodhue &amp;. Co. of New-York. Two and a
               half percent will be allowed to all those who make a remittance with
               their orders.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich, having made Bibliography his special study for forty years,
               possesses a knowledge of books and editions not often to be met with,
               and will be happy to give any advice and information respecting the formation of Libraries or Collections of Books in any particular branch of
               literature or science. For information in regard to his efficiency, he
               begs to refer to Messrs. Prescott, Ticknor, Sparks, Irving, and other literary characters in the United States, to whom he is known. Intending
               to devote the remainder of his life to literary pursuits, his greatest pleasure will arise from sending rare and valuable books to his own country;
               and he trusts to live long enough to see in the United States a Library
               which may bear a comparison with the most celebrated in Europe. If
               he can live to say, “ I also assisted in its formation,” his most ardent wishes will be gratified.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich has in press—Bibliotheca Americana Nova: a Catalogue of Books relating to America, including Voyages to the South
               Seas and round the World: Part III. from 1831 to 1845, with supplement
               and index completing the work.
            </p>
            
            <p>He has also ready for the press, Bibliotheca Americana Vitus: a
               Catalogue of Books relating to America from the discovery to the year
               1700; with notes and observations: in one vol. 8 vo., of about 400 pages.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr Rich has also ready a reprint from Thevenot’s Collection of Father Marquette’s account of the discovery of the Mississippi, entitled,
               ' Decouverte de quelques Pays et Nations de l’Amerique Septentrionale.'
               Only 125 copies are printed, which will be distributed among Mr. Rich's
               friends and correspondents.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich has also purchased the remaining copies of the part relating
               to America of L'Art de Verifier les Dates; of which ten volumes in octavo by D. B. Warden, Esq., are printed, and two volumes more, completing the work, will be published during the course of the present year.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Price of the ten volumes published, - - - - 40 francs</div>
            
            <p>Complete sets of the Art de Verifier les Dates, in 44 vols. 8vo, 160 francs,
               instead of 308, the original price.
            </p>	
            
            <div class="ab">Paris, May l, 1845.	                  may24</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">SMITH'S WEEKLY VOLUME.</div>
            
            <p>A SELECT CIRCULATING LIBRARY BY THE ORIGINAL
               Editor of Wadlie’s Library. This popular periodical is regularly received at the office of the Broadway Journal. Terms, $4
               per annum, single numbers 8 cts. 	JOHN BISCO Publisher
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">                            135 Nassau st., Clinton Hall.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">VALUABLE FAMILY BOOK</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NOW PUBLISHING IN NUMBERS, PRICE TWENTY-FIVE
               
               <br></br>CENTS, TO BE COMPLETED IN TWELVE NUMBERS.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">ENCYCLOPEDIA
               
               <br></br>Of Domestic Economy.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">COMPRISIN</div>
            
            <p>SUCH subjects as are most immediately connected with Housekeeping; as, The Construction of Domestic Edifices, with the
               modes of Warming, Ventilating, and Lighting them—A description of the various articles of Furniture, with the nature of their
               Materials—Duties of Servants—A general account of the Animal
               and Vegetable Substances used as Food, and the methods of preserving and preparing them by Cooking—Making Bread—the
               Chemical Nature and the preparation of all kinds of Fermented
               Liquors used as Beverage—Materials employed in Dress and the
               Toilet—Business of the Laundry—Description of the various Wheel
               Carriages—Preservation of Health—Domestic Medicine, etc., etc.,
               etc. By Thomas Webster, F. G. S., etc.; assisted by the late
               Mrs. Parkes, author of “ Domestic Duties.”
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">EDITED BY AN AMERICAN PHYSICIAN.
               
               <br></br>ILLUSTRATED WITH NEARLY ONE THOUSAND WOODCUTS.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ The title page sufficiently indicates the wide range of topics included in this most useful Encyclopedia; and all are treated with a
               fullness which leaves nothing io be desired. It has been the object of the editor to combine science with practice, a knowledge
               of principles with the ordinary details and daily recurring duties
               of domestic life. In some departments of the work Mr. Webster
               has been assisted by a lady whose qualifications are beyond dispute, and the result of their united labors is the production of a
               volume which exhausts the subject, and defies all competition.
               The work is richly illustrated with woodcuts, adding greatly to
               its value. We strongly recommend every lady, and all others who
               are concerned in the management of domestic affairs, to make
               themselves familiar with a work, which must speedily be regarded
               as an indispensable book of reference to every housekeeper.”—
               Eclectic Review.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ It is a perfect repository of all that homely knowledge which
               is so difficult to obtain except in the hard school of experience, and
               yet so needful for getting on in this matter-of-fact world. It would
               be time and money admirably economized for housekeepers to provide themselves with this thesaurus of the way of living at the
               outset.”—Churchman.
            </p>
            
            <p>	“ We consider it one of the most useful works ever issued from
               the American press, and strongly recommend it to all heads of
               families.”—Rover.
            </p>
            	
            <p>“ This is decidedly a book for the million; it contains all that
               kind of precise information adapted to the use of families, and
               which one may seek a long time for in vain elsewhere.”—N. Y.
               Evening Gazette.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ It contains a mass of information upon a thousand points, re-
               specting which, most people find themselves sadly at fault, at
               times. It is a work which cannot fail to prove highly useful.”—
               Buffalo Advertiser.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ A complete library for every household: a work which
               every husband should buy for his wife, and every father for his
               daughter.”—N. Y. Com. Advertiser.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ The price of the whole book may be saved by the superior
               information one may get from this very number, (the second,) and
               the economy one may practise in consequence in buying a new
               arm-chair or a pattent lamp.” -Morning Next.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ A Treasury of Knowledge upon matters of which we all feel
               the importance."—Littell's Living Age.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">HARPER &amp; BROTHERS, PUBLISHERS,
               
               <br></br>82 CLIFF-STREET.NEW-YORK:
               
               <br></br>and may be obtained or the booksellers in town and
               
               <br></br>COUNTRY.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published Monthly at Richmond, Va.; Price Five Dollars per Year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835,
               has a large subscription list among the elite of the Southern Aristo
               cracy, and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the “ Broadway JournaL, 135 Nassau-at.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MANESCA’S ORAL SYSTEM OF TEACHING</div>
            
            <p>THE FRENCH LANGUAGE, pursued by his daughter, Madame
               Durand, either in class or private lessons, to Ladies and Gentlemen, at
               No. 35 Walker-street.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
            
            <p>SIR — WE WILL THANK YOU TO CAUTION
               the public against a set of imposters who are calling upon our customers, asserting that they are engaged by us in the capacity of agents.
               In several instances they have succeeded in obtaining orders. But when
               the goods are delivered great dissatisfaction has been given by the infamous and utterly base imitations. But still persisting that the cards
               are our manufacture, they too often succeed in foisting them upon the
               unsuspecting. We ourselves would strenuously caution the said parties
               that, should they persist after this notice, we will try what effect a State
               Prison will have upon them.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">We are, Sir, Your most obt’y,
               
               <br></br>J. B. CAREY &amp; CO.,
               
               <br></br>Ornamental Show Card Manufacturers, 323 Broadway.
            </div>
            
            <p>An agent wanted for New-York City. Also one for New-York State
               —whose name will be published as our authorized agent.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE,
               THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE TEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE
               FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M. daily for gentlemen, and
               from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. -Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
            
            <p>WM, A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANOFORTE,
               ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank-street, where his terms
               for giving instruction cun be ascertained.	         myl7
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <p>“PHILIP ERNST, Teacher of the Flute and Guitar, would inform the lovers of Music that he has now for sale several of the above celebrated instruments, constructed in every respect in
               accordance with those now in use at the Paris and London Royal Academies. To be seen at PHILIP ERNST’S Music Saloon, 395 Broadway,
               near Walker-st.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">(new invention.)</div>
            
            <p>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the Conservatorie at Paris,
               and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
            </p>
            
            <p>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the ‘Boehm Flute,’
               110 Fulton-St. N.Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of this 
               city the above Important Invention, which has been so enthusiastically received and generally used by the most distinguished European artists, feels happy in being able to place before them the following
               testimonial to its merits, signed by two of the most distinguished of our
               resident Artists.
            </p>
            
            <p>We hereby certify to the excellence of the Boehm Flute, as manufactured
               by Mr. J. D. Larrabee; to the beauty of its tone, the perfection of
               its tune, and the simplicity of its fingering, which renders a brilliant execution comparatively easy.
            </p>
            
            <p>Philip Ernst, (who has already introduced it
               successfully among his pupils.)
            </p>
            
            <p>John A. Kyle, Principal Flute of the Philharmonic Society, and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm
               Flute, 41 Forsyth-st. New-York.
            </p>
            
            <p>Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory, 110 
               Fulton-st. and judge for themselves.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTE8.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to)
               Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the largest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most 
               superior quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any cl mate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned
               and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <p>F. RILEY &amp; CO., No. 297 Broadway, (between
               Reade and Duane-Streets,) N. Y., Publishers of Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition to
               their own catalogue (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep
               on hand the publications of all the principal Music houses. They are 
               erecting a large Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes of a
               superior quality, will constantly be kept on hand
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>—A. H. GALE &amp; CO.’s Ware-
               Rooms, No. 289 Broadway—Manufactory Third Avenue, corner of
               13th street.
            </p>
            
            <p>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assortment
               of Rosewood and Mahogany Piano Fortes, with from six to seven octaves, embracing every variety of patterns, made in their well-known
               substantial manner, under their immediate and personal superintendence,
               by skillful and experienced mechanics, from the best seasoned materials.
            </p>
            
            <p>These instruments embrace many important improvements, which
               will recommend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of
               perfection, with the best French grand action, warranted in every respect
               by the manufacturer.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished,
                in elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
               the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
               to the ACTION, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
               upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNAM.
               
               <br></br>361 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>Manufactory, 13th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
               
               <br></br>N. B. A good second-hand piano forte for sale.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>— JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy At Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to the
               elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, corner of Cottage-Place and Bleecker-street, which he will sell as
               prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twenty
               years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two of the
               largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the best makers in
               this country or Europe, and that they contain all the real improvements
               of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
               Repaired.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">New-York, April 28d, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal-
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
               Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from
               choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the business.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,
               PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER-STREET, NEAR ELM.
               
               <br></br>A Large Stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
               
               <br></br>TERMS MODERATE.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
               work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this
               method, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
               The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises,
               scules and studies are given in such progressive order, that they enlist
               the interests of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly through those
               mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often made irksome in
               other instruction books. The time has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is only by the study of
               such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will be enabled to Read music
               with facility, and at the same time become good musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the
               rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each
               lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations from
               professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of Bertini’s
               Method overall others yet published in this country, most of them
               having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to
               give a few of the names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Boston.	
               
               <br></br>Messrs. G. J. Webb,
               
               <br></br>J.G. Maedar,	
               
               <br></br>H.T. Hoch,	
               
               <br></br>E. L. White,	
               
               <br></br>David Paine,	
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek, 	
               
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.	
               
               <br></br>New-York.
               
               <br></br>Messrs. H. C. Timm,
               
               <br></br>W. Alpers,
               
               <br></br>U. C. Hill,
               
               <br></br>F. H. Brown.
               
               <br></br>Philadelphia.
               
               <br></br>B. C. Cross,
               
               <br></br>Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
               American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197
               Washington-street, Boston.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">
            <br></br>Redding &amp; Co........................Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance,...................Philadelphia, Pa.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. Huntincton,................Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>George Jones........................Albanv, N.Y.
            
            <br></br>Thomas H Pease......................New-Haven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>L. Willard,..........................Troy.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">J.B. Winser, Printer, 138 Fulton-street.</div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      <a href="#a001"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n001">Of course we do not father the opinions of our correspondent.
         EDs. B. J.
      </div>
      
      <a href="#a002"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n002">The society of bearded goats.</div>
      
      <a href="#a003"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n003">Bearded members of the society of He goats.</div>
      
      <a href="#a004"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n004">If alluded to at all by other lips than those of her proprietor, or writ-
         ten to, it is as “ the guarded lady,”—“ the concealed jewel.”—LANE.
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>