<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">VOL. 2.</div>	
         <div class="ab">NEW YORK,</div> 
         
         <div class="ab">SATURDAY, OCTOBER 18,1845.	NO. 15.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Three Dollars per Annum. Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.</div>		
         
         <div class="ab">Edited BY EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY O. WATSON.</div>
         <div class="ab">Published at 135 Nassau-st By JOHN BISCO.</div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
                   
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div>
         <div class="head">Stanzas.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Thou hast eyes like stars, and sweetness
            <br>Which no fruit of earth supplies;
            <br>Thou hast angel grace, and fleetness,
            <br>Like some bird of upper skies;—
            <br>Let not earthly charms go higher,
            <br>Than the ones which should aspire,—
            <br>Be thy spirit like thine eyes—
            <br>As to them so lavish given,
            <br>Clothe it too in hues of heaven.
            <br>Bid it bless where now it kindles,
            <br>Let not mocking spirits say
            <br>That thy holy beauty dwindles
            <br>To a common mortal ray;—
            <br>Be the wicked speech confounded,
            <br>Take the captive thou hast wounded,
            <br>Prove that eyes, that so can slay,
            <br>Have an attribute the more
            <br>When the stricken they restore!
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">W. Gilmore Simms.</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">King Pest.
            A TALE CONTAINING AN ALLEGORY.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">The gods do bear and well allow in kings
            <br>The things which they abhor in rascal routes.
            <br>Buckhurst's Tragedy of Ferrez and Porrez.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <p>About twelve o’clock, one night in the month of October, and during the chivalrous reign of the third Edward,
            two seamen belonging to the crew of the “Free and Easy.” a trading schooner plying between Sluys and the
            Thames, and then at anchor in that river, were much astonished to find themselves seated in the tap-room of an
            ale-house in the parish of St. Andrews, London—which
            ale-house bore for sign the portraiture of a “Jolly Tar.”
         </p>
         
         <p>The room, although ill-contrived, smoke-blackened,
            low-pitched, and in every other respect agreeing with
            the general character of such places at the period—was,
            nevertheless, in the opinion of the grotesque groups scattered here and there within it, sufficiently well adapted
            to its purpose.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of these groups our two seamen formed, I think, the
            most interesting, if not the most conspicuous.
         </p>
         
         <p>The one who appeared to be the elder, and whom his
            companion addressed by the characteristic appellation of
            "Legs,” was at the same time much the taller of the
            two. He might have measured six feet and a half, and
            an habitual stoop in the shoulders seemed to have been
            the necessary consequence of an altitude so enormous.
            Superfluities in height were, however, more than accounted for by deficiencies in other respects. He was
            exceedingly thin; and might, as his associates asserted,
            have answered, when drunk, for a pennant at the mast
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>head, or, when sober, have served for a jib-boom. But
            these jests, and others of a similar nature, had evidently
            produced, at no time, any effect upon the cachinnatory
            muscles of the tar. With high cheek-bones, a large
            hawk-nose, retreating chin, fallen under-jaw, and huge
            protruding white eyes, the expression of his countenance,
            although tinged with a species of dogged indifference to
            matters and things in general, was not the less utterly
            solemn and serious beyond all attempts at imitation or
            description.
         </p>
         
         <p>The younger seaman was, in all outward appearance,
            the converse of his companion. His stature could
            not have exceeded four feet. A pair of stumpy bow-legs
            supported his squat, unwieldly figure, while his unusually short and thick arms, with no ordinary fists at their
            extremities, swung off dangling from his sides like the
            fins of a sea-turtle. Small eyes, of no particular color,
            twinkled far back in his head. His nose remained buried
            in the mass of flesh which enveloped his round, full, and
            purple face; and his thick upper-lip rested upon the still
            thicker one beneath with an air of complacent self-satisfaction, much heightened by the owner’s habit of licking
            them at intervals. He evidently regarded his tall shipmate with a feeling half-wondrous, half-quizzical; and
            stared up occasionally in his face as the red setting sun
            stares up at the crags of Ben Nevis.
         </p>
         
         <p>Various and eventful, however, had been the peregrinations of the worthy couple in and about the different
            tap-houses of the neighbourhood during the earlier hours
            of the night. Funds even the most ample, are not always everlasting: and it was with empty pockets our
            friends had ventured upon the present hostelrie.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the precise period, then, when this history properly
            commences, Legs, and his fellow Hugh Tarpaulin, sat,
            each with both elbows resting upon the large oaken table in the middle of the floor, and with a hand upon either cheek. They were eyeing, from behind a huge
            flagon of unpaid-for “humming-stuff,” the portentous
            words, “No Chalk,” which to their indignation and astonishment were scorefl over the doorway by means of
            that very mineral whose presence they purported to deny. Not that the gift of decyphering written characters—a gift among the commonalty of that day considered little less cabalistical than the art of inditing—could,
            in strict justice, have been laid to the charge of either
            disciple of the sea; but there was, to say the truth, a
            certain twist in the formation of the letters—an indescribable lee-iurch about the whole—which foreboded, in
            the opinion of both seamen, a long run of dirty weather;
            and determined them at once, in the allegorical words of
            Legs himself, to “pump ship, clew up all sail, and scud
            before the wind.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Having accordingly disposed of what remained of the
            ale, and looped up the points of their short doublets, they
            finally made a bolt for the street. Although Tarpaulin
            rolled twice into the fire-place, mistaking it for the door,
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page220"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            yet their escape was at length happily effected—and
            half after twelve o’clock found our heroes ripe for mischief, and running for life down a dark alley in the direction of St. Andrew’s Stair, hotly pursued by the landlady
            of the “Jolly Tar.”
         </p>
         
         <p>At the epoch of this eventful tale, and periodically,
            for many years before and after, all England, but more
            especially the metropolis, resounded with the fearful cry
            of “Plague!” The city was in a great measure depopulated—and in those horrible regions, in the vicinity of
            the Thames, where amid the dark, narrow, and filthy
            lanes and alleys, the Demon of Disease was supposed to
            have had his nativity, Awe, Terror, and Superstition
            were alone to be found stalking abroad.
         </p>
         
         <p>By authority of the king such districts were placed
            -under ban, and all persons forbidden, under pain of death,
            to intrude upon their dismal solitude. Yet neither the
            mandate of the monarch, nor the huge barriers erected
            at the entrances of the streets, nor the prospect of that
            loathsome death which, with almost absolute certainty,
            overwhelmed the wretch whom no peril could deter from
            the adventure, prevented the unfurnished and untenanted dwellings from being stripped, by the hand of nightly rapine, of every article, such as iron, brass, or leadwork, which could in any manner be turned to a profitable account.
         </p>
         
         <p>Above all, it was usually found, upon the annual winter opening of the barriers, that locks, bolts, and secret
            cellars, had proved but slender protection to those rich
            stores of wines and liquors which, in consideration of
            the risk and trouble of removal, many of the numerous
            dealers having shops in the neighbourhood had consented to trust, during the period of exile, to so insufficient
            a security.
         </p>
         
         <p>But there were very few of the terror-stricken people
            who attributed these doings to the agency of human
            hands. Pest-spirits, plague-goblins, and fever-demons,
            were the popular imps of mischief; and tales so bloodchilling were hourly told, that the whole mass of forbidden buildings was, at length, enveloped in terror as in a
            shroud, and the plunderer himself was often scared away
            by the horrors his own depredations had created; leaving the entire vast circuit of prohibited district to gloom,
            silence, pestilence, and death.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was by one of the terrific barriers already mentioned, and which indicated the region beyond to be under
            the Pest-ban, that, in scrambling down an alley, Legs
            and the worthy Hugh Tarpaulin found their progress
            suddenly impeded. To return was out of the question,
            and no time was to be lost, as their pursuers were close
            upon their heels. With thorough-bred seamen to clamber up the roughly fashioned plank-work was a trifle;
            and, maddened with the twofold excitement of exercise
            and liquor, they leaped unhesitatingly down within the
            enclosure, and holding on their drunken course with
            shouts and yellings, were soon bewildered in its noisome
            and intricate recesses.
         </p>
         
         <p>Had they not, indeed, been intoxicated beyond moral
            sense, their reeling footsteps must have been palsied by
            the horrors of their situation. The air was cold and
            misty. The paving-stones, loosened from their beds, lay
            in wild disorder amid the tall, rank grass, which sprang
            up around the feet and ankles. Fallen houses choked
            up the streets. The most fetid and poisonous smells
            everywhere prevailed;—and by the aid of that ghastly
            light which, even at midnight, never fails to emanate
            from a vapory and pestilential atmosphere, might be dis
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>cerned lying in the by-paths and alleys, or rotting in
            the windowless habitations, the carcass of many a nocturnal plunderer arrested by the hand of the plague in
            the very perpetration of his robbery.
         </p>
         
         <p>—But it lay not in the. power of images, or sensations,
            or impediments such as these, to stay the course of men
            who, naturally brave, and at that time especially, brimful of courage and of “humming-stuff!” would have
            reeled, as straight as their condition might have permitted, undauntedly into the very jaws of Death. Onward
            —still onward stalked the grim Legs, making the desolate solemnity echo and re-echo with yells like the terrific war-whoop of the Indian: and onward, still onward
            rolled the dumpy Tarpaulin, hanging on to the doublet
            of his more active companion, and far surpassing the
            latter’s most strenuous exertions in the way of vocal music, by bull-roarings in basso, from the profundity of his
            stentorian lungs.
         </p>
         
         <p>They had now evidently reached the strong hold of
            the pestilence. Their way at every step or plunge grew
            more noisome and more horrible—the paths more narrow
            and more intricate. Huge stones and beams falling momently from the decaying roofs above them, gave evidence, by their sullen and heavy descent, of the vast
            height of the surrounding houses; and while actual exertion became necessary to force a passage through frequent
            heaps of rubbish, it was by no means seldom that the
            hand fell upon a skeleton or rested upon a more fleshey
            corpse.
         </p>
         
         <p>Suddenly, as the seamen stumbled against the entrance
            of a tall and ghastly-looking building, a yell more than
            usually shrill from the throat of the excited Legs, was
            replied to from within, in a rapid succession of wild,
            laughter-like, and fiendish shrieks. Nothing daunted
            at sounds which, of such a nature, at such a time, and
            in such a place, might have curdled the very blood in
            hearts less irrevocably on fire, the drunken couple rushed
            headlong against the door, burst it open, and staggered
            into the midst of things with a volley of curses.
         </p>
         
         <p>The room within which they found themselves proved
            to be the shop of an undertaker; but an open trap-door,
            in a corner of the floor near the entrance, looked down
            upon a long range of wine-cellars, whose depths the occasional sound of bursting bottles proclaimed to be well
            stored with their appropriate contents. In the middle of
            the room stood a table—in the centre of which again
            arose a huge tub of what appeared to be punch. Bottles
            of various wines and cordials, together with jugs, pitchers, and flagons of every shape and quality, were scattered profusely upon the board. Around it, upon coffintressels, was seated a company of six. This company
            I will endeavor to delineate one by one.
         </p>
         
         <p>Fronting the entrance, and elevated a little above his
            companions, sat a personage who appeared to be the president of the table. His stature was gaunt and-tall, and
            Legs was confounded to behold in him a figure more
            emaciated than himself. His face was as yellow as saffron—but no feature excepting one alone, was sufficiently
             marked to merit a particular description. This one consisted in a forehead so unusually and hideously lofty, as
            to have the appearance of a bonnet or crown of flesh superseded upon the natural head. His mouth was puckered and dimpled into an expression of ghastly affability, and his eyes, as indeed the eyes of all at table, were
            glazed over with the fumes of intoxication. This gentleman was clothed from head to foot in a richly-embroidered black silk-velvet pall, wrapped negligently
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page221"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            around his form after the fashion of a Spanish cloak.—
            His head was stuck full of sable hearse-plumes, which
            he nodded to and fro with a jaunty and knowing air;
            and, in his right hand, he held a huge human thighLone, with which he appeared to have been just knocking down some member of the company for a song.
         </p>
         
         <p>Opposite him, and with her back to the door, was a
            lady of no whit the less extraordinary character. Although quite as tall as the person just described, she
            had no right to complain of his unnatural emaciation.
            She was evidently in the last stage of a dropsy; and her
            figure resembled nearly that of the huge puncheon of
            October beer which stood, with the head driven in, close
            by her side, in a corner of the chamber. Her face was
            exceedingly round, red, and full; and the same peculiarity, or rather want of peculiarity, attached itself to her
            countenance, which I before mentioned in the case of the
            president—that is to say, only one feature of her face
            was sufficiently distinguished to need a separate characterization: indeed the acute Tarpaulin immediately observed that the same remark might have applied to each
            individual person of the party, every one of whom seemed to possess a monopoly of some particular portion of
            physiognomy. With the lady in question this portion
            proved to be the mouth. Commencing at the right ear, it
            swept with a terrific chasm to the left—the short pendants which she wore in either auricle continually bobting into the aperture. She made however, every exertion to keep her mouth closed and look dignified, in a
            dress consisting of a newly starched and ironed shroud
            coming up close under her chin, with a crimpled ruffle of
            cambric muslin.
         </p>
         
         <p>At her right hand sat a diminutive young lady whom
            she appeared to patronise. This delicate little creature,
            in the trembling of her wasted fingers, in the livid hue
            of her lips, and in the slight hectic spot which tinged
            her otherwise leaden complexion, gave evident indications of a galloping consumption. An air of extreme
            haul ton, however, pervaded her whole appearance; she
            wore in a graceful and degage manner, a large and
            beautiful winding-sheet of the finest India lawn; her
            hair hung in ringlets over her neck; a soft smile played
            about her mouth; but her nose, extremely long, thin, sinnous, flexible and pimpled, hung down far below her under lip, and in spite of the delicate manner in which she
            now and then moved it to one side or the other with her
            tongue, gave to her countenance a somewhat equivocal
            expression.
         </p>
         
         <p>Over against her, and upon the left of the dropsical lady, was seated a little puffy, wheezing, and
            gouty old man, whose cheeks reposed upon the shoulders
            of their owner, like two huge bladders of Oporto wine.
            With his arms folded, and with one bandaged leg deposited upon the table, he seemed to think himself entitled
            to some consideration. He evidently prided himself
            much upon every inch of his personal appearance, but
            took more especial delight in calling attention to his
            gaudy-colored surtout. This, to say the truth, must have
            cost him no little money, and was made to fit him exceedingly well—being fashioned from one of the curiously embroidered silken covers appertaining to those
            glorious escutcheons which, in England and elsewhere,
            are customarily hung up, in some conspicuous place,
            upon the dwellings of departed aristocracy.
         </p>
         
         <p>Next to him, and at the right hand of the president,
            Was a gentleman in long white hose and cotton drawers.
            His frame shook, in a ridiculous manner, with a fit of
            what Tarpaulin called “the horrors.” His jaws, which
            had been newly shaved, were tightly tied up by a bandage of muslin; and his arms being fastened in a simi
            lar way at the wrists, prevented him from helping himself too freely to the liquors upon the table; a precaution rendered necessary, in the opinion of Legs, by the
            peculiarly sottish and wine-bibbing cast of his visage.
            A pair of prodigious ears, nevertheless, which it was no
            doubt found impossible to confine, towered away into
            the atmosphere of the apartment, and were occasionally pricked up in a spasm, at the sound of the drawing
            of a cork.
         </p>
         
         <p>Fronting him, sixthly and lastly, was situated a singularly stiff-looking personage, who, being afflicted with
            paralysis, must, to speak seriously, have felt very ill at
            ease in his unaccomodating habiliments. He was habited, somewhat uniquely, in a new and handsome mahogany coffin. Its top or head-piece pressed upon the skull
            of the wearer, and extended over it in the fashion of a
            hood, giving to the entire face an air of indescribable interest. Arm-holes had been cut in the sides, for the sake
            not more of elegance than of convenience; but the
            dress, nevertheless, prevented its proprietor from sitting
            as erect as his associates; and as he lay reclining
            against his tressel, at an angle of forty-five degrees, a
            pair of huge goggle eyes rolled up their awful whites
            towards the ceiling in absolute amazement at their own
            enormity.
         </p>
         
         <p>Before each of the party lay a portion of a skull,
            which was used as a drinking cup. Overhead was suspended a human skeleton, by means of a rope tied
            round one of the legs and fastened to a ring in the ceiling. The other limb confined by no such fetter, stuck
            off from the body at right angles, causing the whole
            loose and rattling frame to dangle and twirl about at
            the caprice of every occasional puff of wind which found
            its way into the aparment. In the cranium of this hideous thing lay a quantity of ignited charcoal, which
            threw a fitful but vivid light over the entire scene; while
            coffins, and other wares appertaining to the shop of an
            undertaker, were piled high up around the room, and
            against the windows, preventing any ray from escaping
            into the street.
         </p>
         
         <p>At sight of this extraordinary assembly, and of their
            still more extraordinary paraphernalia, our two seamen
            did not conduct themselves with that degree of decorum which might have been expected. Legs, leaning
            against the wall near which he happened to be standing,
            dropped his lower law still lower than usual, and spread
            open his eyes to their fullest extent: while Hugh Tarpaulin, stooping down so as to bring his nose upon a
            level with the table, and spreading out a palm upon
            either knee, burst into a long, loud, and obstreprons
            roar of very ill-timed and immoderate laughter.
         </p>
         
         <p>Without, however, taking offence at behaviour so excesssvely rude, the tall president smiled very graciously upon the intruders—nodded to them in a dignified
            manner with his head of sable plumes—and, arising,
            took each by an arm, and led him to a seat which some
            others of the company had placed in the meantime for
            his accommodation. Legs to all this offered not the
            slightest resistance, but sat down as he was directed;
            while the gallant Hugh, removing his coffin tressel
            from its station near the head of the table, to the vicinity of the little consumptive lady in the winding sheet,
            plumped down by her side in high glee, and pouring out
            a skull of red wine, quaffed it to their better acquain
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page222"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            tance. But at this presumption the stiff gentleman in the
            coffin seemed exceedingly nettled; and serious consequences might have ensued, had not the president, rapping upon the table with his truncheon, diverted the attention of all present to the following speech:
         </p>
         
         <p>“It becomes our duty upon the present happy occasion”—</p>
         
         <p>“Avast there!” interrupted Legs, looking very serious,
            “avast there a bit, I say, and tell us who the devil ye all
            are, and what business ye have here, rigged off like the
            foul fiends, and swilling the snug blue ruin stowed away
            for the winter by my honest shipmate, Will Wimble the
            undertaker!”
         </p>
         
         <p>At this unpardonable piece of ill-breeding, all the original company half started to their feet, and uttered the
            same rapid succession of wild fiendish shrieks which
            had before caught the attention of the seamen. The
            president, however, was the first to recover his composure, and at length, turning to Legs with great dignity,
            recommenced:
         </p>
         
         <p>“Most willingly will we gratify any reasonable curiosity on the part of guests so illustrious, unbidden though
            they be. Know then that in these dominions I am monarch, and here rule with undivided empire under the title of ‘King Pest the First.’
         </p>
         
         <p>“This apartment, which you no doubt profanely suppose to be the shop of Will Wimble the undertaker—a
            man whom we know not, and whose plebeian appellation
            has never before this night thwarted our royal ears—
            this apartment. I say, is the Dais-Chamber of our Palace,
            devoted to the councils of our kingdom, and to other sacred and lofty purposes.
         </p>
         
         <p>“The noble lady who sits opposite is Queen Pest, our
            Serene Consort. The other exalted personages whom
            you behold are all of our family, and wear the insignia
            of the blood royal under the respective titles of ‘ His
            Grace the Arch Duke Pest-Iferous'—His Grace the Duke
            Pest-Ilential’—‘His Grace the Duke Tem-Pest’—and
            ‘Her Serene Highness the Arch Duchess Ana-Pest.’
         </p>
         
         <p>“As regards,” continued he, “your demand of the
            business upon which we sit here in council, we might be 
            pardoned for replying that it concerns, and concerns 
            alone, our own private and regal interest, and is in no j
            manner important to any other than ourself. But in consideration of those rights to which as guests and strangers you may feel yourselves entitled, we will furthermore explain that we are here this night, prepared by
            deep research and accurate investigation, to examine, analyze,and thoroughly determine the indefinable spirit—
            the incomprehensible qualities and nare—of those inestimable treasures of the palate, the wines, ales, and liqueurs of this goodly metropolis: by so doing to advance
            not more our own designs than the true welfare of that
            unearthly sovereign whose reign is over us all, whose
            dominions are unlimited, and whose name is ‘Death,’”
            “Whose name is Davy Jones!” ejaculated Tarpaulin,
            helping the lady by his side to a skull of liqueur, and
            pouring out a second for himself.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Profane varlet!” said the president, now turning his
            attention to the worthy Hugh, “profane and execrable
            wretch!—we have said, that in consideration of those
            rights which, even in thy filthy person, we feel no inclination to violate, we have condescended to make reply
            to thy rude and unseasonable inquiries. We nevertheless, for your unhallowed intrusion upon our councils,
            believe it our duty to mulct thee and thy companion in
            each a gallon of Black Strap—having imbibed which to
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>the prosperity of our kingdom—at a single draught—and
            upon your bended knees—ye shall be forthwith free
            either to proceed upon your way, or remain and be admitted to the privileges of our table, according to your
            respective and individual pleasures.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“It would be a matter of utter unpossibility” replied
            Legs, whom the assumptions and dignity of King Pest
            the First had evidently inspired with some feelings of respect, and who arose and steadied himself by the table
            as he spoke—“it would, please your majesty, be a matter of utter unpossibility to stow away in my hold even
            one-fourth part of that same liquor which your majesty
            has just mentioned. To say nothing of the stuffs placed
            on board in the forenoon by way of ballast, and not to
            mention the various ales and liqueurs shipped this evening at different sea-ports, I have, at present, a full cargo
            of ‘humming stuff’ taken in and duly paid for at the
            sign of the ‘Jolly Tar.’ You will, therefore, please your
            majesty, be so good as to take the will for the deed—for
            by no manner of means either can I or will I swallow
            another drop—least of all a drop of that villanous bilgewater that answers to the hail of ‘ Black Strap.’”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Belay that!” interrupted Tarpaulin, astonished not
            more at the length of his companion’s speech than at the
            nature of his refusal—“Belay that you lubber!—and I
            say, Legs, none of your palaver! My hull is still light,
            although I confess you yourself seem to be a litte topheavy; and as for the matter of your share of the cargo,
            why rather than raise a squall I would find stowage-room
            for it myself, but”——
         </p>
         
         <p>“This proceeding,’’interposed the President, “is by no
            means in accordance with the terms of the mulct or sentence, which is in its nature Median, and not to be altered
            or recalled. The conditions we have imposed must be
            fulfilled to the letter, and that without a moment’s hesitation—in failure of which fulfilment we decree that you
            do here be tied neck and heels together, and duly drowned as rebels in yon hogshead of October beer!”
         </p>
         
         <p>“A sentence!—a sentence!—a righteous and just sentence!—a glorious decree!—a most worthy and upright,
             and holy condemnation!” shouted the Pest family alto gether. The king elevated his forehead into innumerable
             wrinkles; the gouty little old man puffed like a pair of
            bellows; the lady of the winding sheet waved her nose to
            and fro; the gentleman in the cotton drawers pricked up
            his ears; she of the shroud gasped like a dying fish; and
             he of the coffin looked stiff' and rolled up his eyes.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Ugh! ugh! ugh!” chuckled Tarpaulin without heeding the general excitation, “ugh! ugh! ugh!—ugh! ugh!
            ugh! ugh!—ugh! ugh! ugh!—I was saying," said he,
            “I was saying when Mr. King Pest poked in his marlin-spike, that as for the matter of two or three gallons
            more or less of Black Strap, it was a trifle to a tight seaboat like myself not overstowed—but when it comes to
            drinking the health of the Devil (whom God assoilzie)
            and going down upon my marrow bones to his ill-favored
            majesty there, whom I know, as well as I know myself
            to be a sinner, to be nobody in the whole world, but Tim
            Hurlygurly the stage-player—why! its quite another
            guess sort of a thing, and utterly and altogether past my
            comprehension.”
         </p>
         
         <p>He was not allowed to finish this speech in tranquilityAt the name of Tim Hurlygurly the whole assembly
            leaped from their seats.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">“Treason!" shouted his Majesty King Pest the First.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">“Treason!” said the little man with the gout.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">“Treason!” screamed the Arch Duchess Ana-Pest.</div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page223"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div class="ab">“Treason!” muttered the gentleman with his jaws lied
            <br>up.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">“Treason!” growled he of the coffin.</div>
         
         <p>“Treason! treason!” shrieked her majesty of the
            mouth ; and, seizing by the hinder part of his breeches
            the unfortunate Tarpaulin, who had just commenced
            pouring out for himself a skull of liqueur, she lifted him
            high into the air, and let him fall without ceremony into the huge open puncheon of his beloved ale. Bobbing
            up and down, for a few seconds, like an apple in a bow)
            of toddy, he, at length, finally disappeared amid the
            whirlpool of foam which, in the already effervescent liquor, his struggles easily succeeded in creating.
         </p>
         
         <p>Not tamely, however, did the tall seaman behold the
            discomfiture of his companion. Jostling King Pest
            through the open trap, the valiant Legs slammed the
            door down upon him with an oath, and strode towards
            the centre of the room. Here tearing down the skeleton
            which swung over the table, he laid it about him with so
            much energy and good will, that, as the last glimpses of
            light died away within the apartment, he succeeded in
            knocking out the brains of the little gentleman with the
            gout. Rushing then with all his force against the fatal
            hogshead full of October ale and Hugh Tarpaulin, he
            rolled it over and over in an instant. Out burst a deluge
            of liquor so fierce—so impetuous—so overwhelming—
            that the room was flooded from wall to wall—the loaded
            table was overturned—the tressels were thrown upon
            their backs—:the tub of punch into the fire-place—and
            the ladies into hysterics. Piles of death-furniture floundered about. Jugs, pitchers, and carboys mingled promiscuously in the melee, and wicker flagons encountered
            desperately with bottles of junk. The man with the
            horrors was drowned upon the spot—the little stiff gentleman floated off in his coffin—and the victorious Legs,
            seizing by the waist the fat lady in the shroud, rushed
            out with her into the street, and made a bee-line for the
            “Free and Easy,” followed under easy sail by the redoubtable Hugh Tarpaulin, who, having sneezed three or
            four times, panted and puffed after him with the Arch
            Duchess Ana-Pest.
         </p>
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">Littleton Barry.</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Unattainable.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Oft from eventide transitions
            <br>And from music’s sweet surprises,
            <br>From day-dreams and starlight visions
            <br>I can picture paradises—
            <br>Ah! if fancies might be things,
            <br>Then, of objects sublunary,
            <br>Of the whole wide world a-weary,
            <br>I would fly to realms of Fancy—
            <br>But I want the wings.
            <br>Manhood I have never bended
            <br>Save before high thrones of Beauty,
            <br>To Ideals which far transcended
            <br>Aught that could command my duty
            <br>On this darkling, desert orb.
            <br>Woman I have loved—but lightly—
            <br>Young hearts burn—but burn too brightly—
            <br>Theirs is not the flame which nightly
            <br>Souls of stars absorb!
            <br>Tremulous and transitory,
            <br>Moths in moonlight, our desires
            <br>Die, attaining not the glory
            <br>Which hath won them to its fires,—
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div><br>Glimpses of what Heaven allows:
            <br>Crowned with ever-living laurel,
            <br>Joining in Joy’s anthem choral,
            <br>Intellectual and moral
            <br>Beauty on our brows!
            <br>Oh! the consciousness convulses
            <br>That Hope faints in heavenward mounting,
            <br>Heart-beats break the heart, and pulses,
            <br>Throb on throb which we are counting,
            <br>Are but silent funeral knells,
            <br>Felt but heard not—Death is nearer,
            <br>All the while those chimes the dearer,
            <br>Nature darkening and drearer,
            <br>Till she drowns her bells.
            <br>Like to Night unstarred and noiseless,
            <br>Glooms the grave—and by its portal
            <br>Are the glimmering ghost-lights voiceless!
            <br>Know we that we are immortal?
            <br>Or is this a dream insane?
            <br>No—though dim are our discernings,
            <br>We believe that these heart-burnings
            <br>From our birth—these God-like yeaanings,
            <br>Were not given in vain.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">WILLIAM Gibson, U. S. N</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Two Sailor Monkeys.</div>
         
         <p>The first of these sailed on board a frigate, and, though
            always in scrapes, was the favorite both of cabin and
            ward-room, and indeed of every mess, except the midshipmen’s, being perhaps disliked by these young gentlemen, for the same reason that poor cousins (as a French
            author observes) are ill seen by us, to wit, for approaching them too nearly in nature.
         </p>
         
         <p>All his pranks, however provoking at the moment,
            seemed only to make him a greater favorite with the
            crew. The captain himself, who studied pug’s happiness as much as the others, and who perhaps thought he
            might be somewhat steadied by matrimony, was anxious
            to provide him with a wife.
         </p>
         
         <p>For some time the happiness of the wedded pair appeared to be complete; and the frigate sailed upon a
            summer cruise during their honeymoon. The husband,
            however, soon grew indifferent; and indifference was
            soon succeeded by disgust. This was manifested by angry looks, chatter, and even blows upon the female, persevering in her attentions.
         </p>
         
         <p>All were much disappointed and scandalized at the
            evil suceess of so promising a union.
         </p>
         
         <p>At length, however, an apparent change took place in
            the husband’s conduct, and was hailed with correspondent joy by the ship’s company. Their pleasure was,
            however, of short duration, for the traitor, having one
            fine day decoyed his wife out to the end of the fore topgallant yard, as if to shew her something at sea, and set
            down with her on the spar, slipped his paw under her
            sitting part and tumbled her overboard. I never shall
            forget the momentary horror with which this was witnessed by all, with the exception of a French captain,
            then a prisoner on board, who, turning to the second lieutenant, exclaimed, “Parbleu, Monsieur, ce drole-la a
            beaucoup de caractère.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Another sailor monkey, who came under my cognizance,
            if he did not shew so much character (or, to speak better English, so much mind) as the first, was certainly
            a beast of infinite humor. He went to sea, accompanied
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page224"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            by a bear, with a relation of mine, who was captain of a
            small sloop of war, and who professed to take them with
            a view to keeping his men in good humor. I believe it
            was to minister to his own amusement. Probably both
            objects were attained.
         </p>
         
         <p>The monkey principally extracted his fun from the
            bear. This beast, who was of a saturnine complexion,
            indulged himself much in sleeping on the sunny side of
            the deck. On these occasions the monkey would overhaul his paws and twitch out any hair which he found
            matted by tar or pitch, the suffering which to remain
            seemed to be a great scandal in his opinion.
         </p>
         
         <p>At other times he would open Bruin’s eyelids and
            peep into his eyes, as if to ascertain what he was dreaming about. The bear, irritated at such liberties being
            taken with his person, used to make clumsy attempts to
            revenge himself; but his persecutor was off in an instant. The rigging was, on these occasions, his place
            of refuge. Thither he was indeed followed by his enemy; but poor Bruin was but an indifferent top-man, and
            seldom got beyond lubber’s hole.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The monkey, on the contrary, was famous for his activity, and for some time was entitled by the sailors,
            “Deputy-captain of the fore top.” He obtained this designation from a very singular practice. Having observed the excitement produced on deck by the announcement of a sail a-head, which, as well as the chase which
            followed, seemed to be highly agreeable to him, the fore
            top became his favorite station; from whence he made
            his signals with great energy, chattering with a peculiar
            scream when any vessel was in sight, and indicating by
            signs in what direction it appeared.
         </p>
         
         <p>Pug continued to volunteer his services for some time
            in this manner, and constantly found his reward. But
            at length, upon the sloop’s getting on bad cruising ground,
            he found his employment dull, and, by way of enlivening
            it, amused himself with giving false alarms.
         </p>
         
         <p>He was started for this by the boatswain’s-mate, and
            lost his rank of deputy-captain of the fore-top. In lieu
            of which, moreover, he was new-named Monk the Marine; a denomination which he certainly knew to be opprobrious, as he resented it with grimaces, chatter, and,
            whenever he dared, with blows.
         </p>
         
         <p>Though he was fond of the excitement of a chase, he
            was not supposed to have good nerves, and those who
            had seen him in action (he was, after the first experiment, always sent below) made but an ill report of his
            steadiness under fire.
         </p>
         
         <p>This poor monkey came to a melancholy end. He had
            observed a sick lieutenant, who breakfasted after the rest
            of his mess, making his tea, and being accidentally left
            alone in the gun-room, determined to imitate him. He
            however succeeded ill in his mixture; for he infused a
            paper of tobacco which was lying on the table, into the
            pot, instead of tea, and afterwards swallowed it with its
            accompaniments of milk and sugar. This ill-imagined
            beverage produced the most fearful commotion in his inside, attended with long and loathsome vomitings; of
            which he finally died.
         </p>
         
         <p>The doctor, who was a materialist and an atheist, and
            a most quarrelsome fellow, (he had killed two brother
            officers in duels, one for only calling him Dr. Gallipot,)
            attended him with more care than we had expected;
            but the poor beast (as the purser said) was outward
            bound, and could not be recalled.
         </p>
         
         <p>The surgeon pronounced that pug died of the iliac pas
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>sion, and announced this as a reason for believing that
            man was but a better breed of monkey.<span class="anchor" id="a001"><a href="#n001"> Link </a></span></p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">To a Spirit.</div> 
         
         <div class="lg"><br>From the far-off Spirit Land,
            <br>Dost thou hail I
            <br>For thy thin and shadowy hand,
            <br>And that face so meek and bland,
            <br>And so pale,
            <br>And thy voice, so faint and lone,
            <br>And its melancholy tone,
            <br>Tell the tale.
            <br>O’er those herbless plains and drear,
            <br>Do these glide—
            <br>’Mid that voiceless atmosphere,
            <br>The shadows of the dear
            <br>That have died?
            <br>Cold, cheerless and alone,
            <br>Each to each unknown,
            <br>Side by side?
            <br>’Neath that sky so low and gray,
            <br>Like a cell—
            <br>Where the changeless twilight day
            <br>Never warms the mist away,
            <br>Do they dwell?—
            <br>Those funereal crowds,
            <br>With the grave-damp on their shrouds?
            <br>Spirit, tell!
            <br>Would a single shade obey,
            <br>Should I call?
            <br>Or, divested from this clay
            <br>And its passions, do they stray
            <br>'Neath that pall,
            <br>Unhearing and unseeing,
            <br>With a blank and vacant being.
            <br>Lifeless all?
            <br>Of the Past do they retain
            <br>Not a gleam?
            <br>Or doth a hope remain
            <br>They shall ever wake again
            <br>To that dream
            <br>Of Love, which o’er the wave
            <br>Of the Lethe of the grave
            <br>Casts its beam?
            <br>I care not. Com’st thou here
            <br>To command
            <br>A mortal to appear
            <br>In that world of doubt and fear,
            <br>The Spirit Land?
            <br>Of a life of pain I tire,
            <br>Thou art here at my desire—
            <br>Give thy hand!
            <br>Remorse I feel not now,
            <br>Nor shall feel;
            <br>There’s no brand upon the brow
            <br>(For a brother) that I bow
            <br>To thy will:
            <br>But a sell-sustaining trust
            <br>In the Merciful and Just,
            <br>Arms me still.
            <br>Tis gone—a mournful shade,
            <br>As it came,
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page225"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            <br>With its misty robe arrayed
            <br>As if smitten and dismayed,
            <br>And in shame.
            <br>What power in Mercy lies,
            <br>When an evil phantom flies
            <br>At the name!
         </div> 
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">George B Wallis.</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">A Mountain Village.</div>
         
         <p>The eastern extremity of the Taurus Mountains in
            Nassau, though little known to English tourists, would
            well repay those who might be tempted to explore it.— 
            This part of the chain presents, in its narrow pastoral
            valleys, clear purling streams, and wooded heights, scenery of the utmost beauty, differing from that nearer to
            the Rhine in its character of sylvan solitude, and perhaps
            surpassing it in variety. The district here referred to
            might he fairly included within a triangle drawn between the towns of Wiesbaden, Frankfort, and Hamburg.
         </p>
         
         <p>One of the most beautiful homes of this district is Eppstein, ten miles distant from Wiesbaden, and delightfully
            situated at the point of junction of four different valleys. 
            “This village,” says the author of An Autumn near the
            Rhine, “is one of the most wild sequestered abodes of,
            man I ever beheld. Though almost all the mountain villages in Germnny have the same feudal character in 
            their buildings and positions, I should select Eppstein in
            preference, on giving the most perfect notion of the secluded fastness of a feudal baron and his vassals. Everything here carries one back to the days of chivalry.— 
            The situation of the village, wedged in a narrow defile,
            between rocks and mountains, in the centre of a wild
            district remote from the habitations of man, and where
            nothing but the object of security could induce any mortal to pitch his camp—the solid walls and low portals
            which inclose about twenty or thirty mean houses—the 
            massive towers and donjons of the old baronial castle, 
            perched, like an eagle’s nest, on the most accessible point,
            of rock overhanging the village—the winding approach
            up the mountain half hid with brushwood—everything
            transports one back to the thirteenth or fourteenth century; and a slight stretch of imagination might people
            the scene with the grim figures of the Count Gedefroi, or
            the Count Eberhard of Eppstein and his mailed attendants, arriving under the castle turrets from an encounter
            with a neighboring knight. The village and its inhabitants have an air of uncivilized and primitive rudeness,
            which does not ill accord with the illusion.”
         </p>
         
         <p>The family of Eppstein seems nearly as old as that of
            Nassau: many of its members were chancellors of the
            empire and archbishops of Mayence. One of them crowned the Emperor Frederick Barbarossa, at Aix-la-Chapelle,
            and afterwards was made Patriarch of Jerusalem. The
            line became extinct in the sixteenth century: several of
            their monuments still exist in the village church.
         </p>
         
         <p>“The founder of the family was, of course, a hero;
            and the report of the neighborhood is, that a knight, named Eppo, hunting in the forest hard by, heard the sobs
            and lamentations of a female, whom, on penetrating into the forest, he found seated on a rock by the side of a
            cave, wiping away her tears with her long tresses, and
            Pouring forth bitter lamentations. She told him she was
            chained there by a giant, who had slain her kindred, and
            carried her away from her father’s castle. The giant
            Was absent in the forest, but returned every day to sleep
            at noon, on the summit of the mountain. Sir Eppo vow
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>ed to deliver her; and the lady entreated him to go to
             her castle in the neighborhood, and procure from the
            blind warder a magical net hanging up in the hall,
            which her father had brought as a booty from Palestine.
            The knight hastened to procure the net, and stretched it
            on the spot where the giant slept. The lady strewed it
            over with flowers—the giant lay down in it—was taken,
            and hurled from the summit of the rock by the knight
            to the valley below, of course the lady gave her hand
            to her deliverer. The knight built a castle on the rock,
            which he called Eppstein, (Eppo’s rock,) and here he
            dwelt with his bride. To prove the truth of the story,
            a whale’s rib, deposited over the gateway, is still pointed out as one of the giant’s bones.”
         </p>
         
         <p>About three miles from Eppstein, is Konigstein: the
            road whither lies through the pretty vale of Fischbach.
            “The whole landscape, the hanging woods, variously
            tinted by autumn, the jutting rocks, the sombre sequestered recesses in the glen, and the lonely stillness which
            pervades the scene, sometimes remind one of some of the
            least wild of Salvator’s romantic scenes, or of thә cool
            and lovely valleys of Gaspar Poussin.”
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Wife's Prayer.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Hear me!—Oh, hear me now!
            <br>By the red flush upon thy wasted cheek—
            <br>By the deep tracery o’er thy noble brow,
            <br>Hear me! bear with me, husband! while I speak!
            <br>I’ve marked thee day by day —
            <br>Thy hours are all of anxious, vague unrest—
            <br>Thine eye hath caught a stern, unwonted ray—
            <br>Thy lip hath lost all memory of its jest.
            <br>Thy wife sits pale beside—
            <br>Thy child shrinks back appaled from thine embrace—
            <br>Thy menials quail before thy mien of pride—
            <br>Thy very dog avoids thine altered face!
            <br>O! for poor Glory’s wreath,
            <br>Casting from thee all tenderness and gladness;
            <br>Thou track’st a phantom on, whose fiery breath
            <br>Drielh the way founts till thou thirst to madness!
            <br>My prayer is all for thee—
            <br>My life is thine! by our remembered bliss—
            <br>By all thine hours of watchful misery—
            <br>What meed hath fame to render thee for this!
            <br>If thou yet lov’st me, hear!
            <br>Now, while thy feet press onward to the goal,
            <br>Turn thee! oh! turn thee in thy stem career,
            <br>And thrust this mad Ambition from thy soul!
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">Mary E Hewitt.</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Bishop and his house-Keeper.</div>
         
         <p>In a city in the south of France, which we will not
            name at present, there lived a few years ago a bishop, a
            kind, amiable old man severe to himself, indulgent to
            others, so good and charitable that everybody loved him.
            His house was a model of propriety and hospitality; it
            was managed by an old housekeeper, Madame Pichard.
            In a bachelor’s establishment the supreme authority is
            always exercised by a lady. Madame Pichard was the
            very model of housekeepers, and everything went on admirably under her administration. Her only source of
            trouble was her husband, a drunken, quarrelsome old
            man, who at the time of our story, was carried off by a
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page226"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            dropsy produced by his excesses. A few days after his
            death the bishop went up to his housekeeper’s apartments to pay her a visit of condolence.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Well, my dear madam,” began his lordship, “I have
            called to endeavor to console you in your afflictions.
            You must not grieve too deeply: we are all mortal you
            know, and sooner or later we come to the end of our
            earthly pilgrimage; your husband’s is now ended—it
            would have been better if he had not spent so much of
            it in drinking, but still the mercy of heaven has no
            bounds.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Your lordship is very good; but, to say the truth, I
            was not thinking of my husband at all; I will not deceive you.”
         </p>
         
         <p>This was a kind of funeral oration for which the bishop was hardly prepared, and it was with no little astonishment that he replied—</p>
         
         <p>“That is not a very Christian frame of mind, I’m
            afraid; did you not love your husband?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Your lordship would not ask me that question, if you
            knew how I came to be married.”
         </p>
         
         <p>You must tell me all about it,” said the bishop, with
            the curiosity of age.
         </p>
         
         <p>“And your lordship does not know anything about my
            Augustus,” continued the housekeeper, in a melancholy
            tone.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Your Augustus, Madam Pichard? Pray explain.”</p>
         
         <p>“I was born at Boulogne, if it please your lordship.
            At fifteen they called me the village beauty, and I suppose, when eighteen, I was not much uglier ; but excuse
            me, Sir,” said the old lady, drawing back her chair, “I
            am going to tell you a love-story, and I shall only tire
            you.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Go on,” repeated the dignitary, “we are both of us
            old now, and can talk about such nonsense without any
            danger.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“There lived in the village a young man, tall, finely
            formed, with blue eyes, and curling light hair; I think I
            can see him now; all we girls used to pull caps for him; he
            was what our parents called a wild young man; his
            name was Augustus, and we all used to call him ‘ handsome Gussy.’ He soon singled me out, and when my
            father went to Paris, and my mother was out of the way,
            he was always at my side. When one gets to be an old
            woman, and has a great grown-up girl to take care of,
            one rails at lovers; but still that was the happiest time
            of my life—I remember it as if it was yesterday. I was
            proud of my Gussy, who was our village beau, and he
            soon quitted all the other girls to pay his court to me.
            All this sounds very strange to your lordship, no doubt.
            My father and mother would never have agreed to my
            marrying so wild a fellow as he was; they forbade him
            the house, but we used often to meet in secret; he would
            prowl around all day only to get a single look of me, and
            then, oh how happy and proud I was! One day, my
            father had gone to the city with a load, and I slipped
            out to try and see Augustus for a moment; we had not
            seen each other for a fortnight! I met him in the highroad. If your lordship knew what a delight it is to meet
            one’s lover, when one is just eighteen, and has been parted from him a fortnight, you would comprehend what
            one feels; I forgot father, mother, everything. We stood
            under a tree by the road-side, looking into each other’s
            eyes; we were so happy we did not even speak. A cart
            came along, it was my father’s; he saw us, sprung out,
            and began to beat me for having met Augustus against
            his orders. I am certain that if he had attacked Augus
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>tus himself, he would not have resisted; but the poor
            fellow could not bear to see me suffer, he attacked my
            father, and they fought desperately. My father caught
            up a stone, and split open Augustus’ head; he on the other hand, dealt the old man such a blow that he fell
            senseless.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Oh, run, run, Augustus!” said I, “if the police should
            catch you, you are lost!” He obeyed me, and fled, and I
            have never seen him since. My father soon came to, and
            gave me a dreadful beating. He detetmined to marry
            me off, and easily found a man to take me without any
            affection, in consideration of a good dower. When I was
            tired of being beaten every morning and night, I became
            Madam Pichard. I never loved my husband; he knew
            that my father used to beat me, and he followed his example. We wandered over the whole of France, in great
            want and misery for the most part, till your lordship’s
            kindness gave us support. That is my story.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“And what became of handsome Gussy?”</p>
         
         <p>“He thought he had killed my father, and left the village. He was a lad of courage; no doubt he enlisted;
            perhaps he is now a colonel, goneral, or count, who
            knows? unless he was killed in'battle. But I cannot believe he is dead; I have been looking for him these forty
            years; I expect every moment to hear him knock at
            the door, and see him come in with his graceful figure,
            his mild blue eyes and waving locks.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ So, then, you suppose, my good lady, that your Gussy
            is just the same now as he was then?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“So I fancy, please your lordship.”</p>
         
         <p>“Why, that is folly; your Augustus has grown old like
            other men; by this time his face must be wrinkled, his
            head bald and his figure bent double. If you were to see
            him now, you would not know him.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Oh, that’s impossible! I can’t believe that he’s so
            changed; but at any rate I should know him among a
            thousand. Put him in the middle of an army, and I’ll lay
            my life I’d recognise him at the very first.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“You are mistaken, madam; you dwell in fancy on
            the youth of twenty, not on the old man of sixty-five; and
            Augustus, himself, if he was to see you, would not know
            you. To prove this, you have both of you lived six
            months in my house without either’s ever suspecting that
            the other was—”
         </p>
         
         <p>“What? what does your lordship mean ?” asked the
            old woman anxiously.
         </p>
         
         <p>“To undeceive you, Margaret—lam your Augustus.”
            Madame Pichard sprung up from her chair, and held
            up both hands; she could not believe him.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Oh dear! is your lordship ‘ handsome Gussy?’”</p>
         
         <p>“Certainly.”</p>
         
         <p>“The handsomest young fellow in the village?”</p>
         
         <p>“Yes, Margaret, forty-five years ago.”</p>
         
         <p>“Was it you that I used to meet down in our garden?”</p>
         
         <p>“Alas! yes, Margaret.”</p>
         
         <p>“Was it you, your lordship—I mean Augustus—I mean
            your lordship, that my father hit with a stone?”
         </p>
         
         <p>The dignitary took off his scull-cap, and shewed a distinct scar on his shaven crown.</p>
         
         <p>“I can tell you all in a very few words. When I
            thought I had killed your father, I fled across the frontier.
            I took refuge in a convent; the good fathers gave me an
            education; I wanted to go back to France and claim
            your hand. When I heard of your marriage I determined
            to take orders; I abandoned the idle pursuits of my youth
            and devoted myself to study and prayer. I returned to
            France; I preached thirty years, when I was nominated
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page227"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            to the see I now occupy. You must stay with me, Margaret; we are both of us so old and so changed now that
            there is no danger in the remembrance of the past. You
            see now that your fancy was fed by mere illusion, the
            object of your first love was before your eyes, yet you did
            riot know him, nor he you. Nothing is lasting in this
            world, my child; all is vanity and vexation of spirit.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Madame Pichard contined to be the very model of a
            careful housekeeper. The servants stood in awe of her,
            and believed that she was crazy, for they often heard her
            mutter to herself when she thought she was alone,—
         </p>
         
         <p>“Oh dear! his lordship my handsome Gussy—oh dear!
            oh dear!
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <p>The editor’s temporary absence from the city, will account to our publishing friends for present neglect of several new works. These will be attended to on his return.</p>
         
         <div class="ab">Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of American Books. No.
            <br>VIII. Big Abel and The Little Manhattan. By Cor-
            <br>nelius Mathews.
         </div>
         
         <p>In our notice of this work, a week or two since, we
            promised a quotation, by way of instancing the author’s
            very peculiar style and tone. We proceed now to redeem our word, by copying some passages from the episode, or rather interlude, of the Poor Scholar and his
            Mistress. These passages are, perhaps, as idiosincratic
            as any in the volume:
         </p>
         
         <p>Turning, at a bend, they found, in the heart of the bend itself,
            the very thing they looked for, a little garden or house of refreshment. Not much of a garden; a slip of the size of a handkerchief; green, too; and a fountain (something very small in the
            way of a fountain); and bowers, ever so many of them, at least
            three in number. And here, while they were getting served by a
            nice mistress of the place, as busy in all her motions as though
            she had opened that morning, and heard a couple of hundred calling her all at once, with cream, and cakes, and fruit (Lankey’s
            part was fruit alone), there drew nearer to a bower; it was the
            centre, and pride of the garden that was waiting for them; two
            young persons, one of them very pale, the other all a-glow.
         </p>
         
         <p>Was ever a Poor Scholar's mistress in such spirits before! And
            then the way in which she took possession of the bower; if the
            green chair had been of solid gold she could’nt have treated it
            more grandly. Three rape of the knuckles, and there was a banquet—not much of a one, to be sure—but what of that! William
            bad something to say, that was clear; but such spirits as Mary’s
            —why the stoutest man living would have quailed before them,
            much less a poor scholar.
         </p>
         
         <p>“The Book’s to be printed, Will? I believe you admit that at
            last!"
         </p>
         
         <p>“To be sure it is—they’ve accepted it.”</p>
         
         <p>“A happy time of it for the printers, now! turning all your
            gentle fancies out upon the page; making your mirth laugh, your
            sorrow weep; your little men and women grow again in light,
            and take a shape to every human eye, all the wide world over!—
            Oh what dreams they’ll have the first night. They’ll not sleep a
            wink, I fear, with all your magic over!”
         </p>
         
         <p>foolish Mary!</p>
         
         <p>"And then the binder’s girls, who have the folding of them
            daintily! Many a clipping of wages will they lose this very
            week, lingering, as they should not, naughtily about that wicked
            Book!"
         </p>
         
         <p>Mary, too fanciful by half.</p>
         
         <p>“Tuesday, now! By Friday, at the latest, that little bright-eyed,
            clean-apparelled gentleman (your Book, I mean, Will) must come
            own stairs, and begin to see company! Oh for the first look at
            his sweet and cheerful face!"
         </p>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <p>In the young Scholars heart that was settled long ago.</p>
         
         <p>“The show-bills, now! All over town, speaking up, with
            fresh, clean looks! Coaxing every one to slop and read! Every
            one to hurry in and buy! and then away to taste the dainty to
            his core!”
         </p>
         
         <p>Was there ever such a foolish, thoughtless mistress to a Poor
            Scholar; all the world over?
         </p>
         
         <p>She stopped and looked at Will as though she saw a Blessed
            Spirit, stepped out from the sun, and not a mortal man. But he
            was very pale, and still had something to say, and now could
            say it.
         </p>
         
         <p>You forget Germany, Mary!” That was what he had to
            say.
         </p>
         
         <p>No: she didn’t She reccollected it perfectly well; it was in all
            the maps, upon the globes, and hung up in the windowsBut in
            this connection she didn’t reccollect it, she confessed. What was
            Germany to this?
         </p>
         
         <p>She hadn’t heard of a famous Rendering or translation out of
            that country, that was talked about, a mighty book, with such a
            power of chains, by way of binding up and riveting the reader;
            such a thrilling, enchanting, wonderful and miraculous book?
            Strange, she hadn’t heard of that I That was the Book?
         </p>
         
         <p>What, to come betwixt this Book of William’s and the light of
            day?
         </p>
         
         <p>William was pale, I said, and Mary now, too. Had those
            men who played these changeful tricks stood there, or sate within
            that bower, they must have been torn piece-meal, limb by limb, by
            little angry devils, leaping out of Mary’s eyes, a score at once,
            and many score!
         </p>
         
         <p>When they had gone forth, Big Abel and Lanky (how Poor
            William and his mistress got away, heaven, whence it came
            from, knows!), the shower was deepening, and they made quickly
            for a house not far away. And there it was. That little, tidy,
            shining palace of brick; palace it is in the spirit within;
            sitting by itself; in cleanliness and purity, and through all the
            falling rain eyeing calmly all passers-by with his little winking
            knob and bell-pull.
         </p>
         
         <p>At home? The ladies of this mansion are always at home,
            and have been any time these fifty yearsA snug parlor, everything tidy, everything in a high state of polish, everything demure
            and settled calmly in his place. The plaster-rabbits on the mantel,
            not zoologically perfect, inasmuch as the necks are movable, anil
            have no visible appurtenance to the bodies; and yet, to the mind,
            all that could be reasonably expected of rabbits under such circumstances. A little door is slided open, and out of a back room
            a nice, comfortable, smiling body—Seventy! Yes; this was the
            youngest of the two maiden sisters, Big Abel’s friends, living here.
            Pretty good for Seventy! Cheerful, quick of speech and gait, and
            cordial, too, as the days of hearty June are long. Another appearance out of the back room—Eighty! Not so tall, nor quite
            so stout, but more cheerful, quicker of motion, decidedly more
            cordial. There was a great shaking of hands, I tell you, there!
            No difference made between fair-looking Abel and the swarthy
            Lanltey—not the least) Talk! Plenty of it; and after that there
            came, out of the back room, too, a little square table, which was
            suddenly clothed (by Eighty) with a snowy cloth, and put in possession (by Seventy) of a little family of cups and saucers, then of
            a dainty pile of toast, then of a cold ham, then of a steaming pot,
            and the little table was set up in the world, and ready to do business.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Wiley &amp; Putnam’s Library of Choice Reading. No.
            <br>XXVI. Selections from the Works of Taylor, Lati-
            <br>mer, Hall, Milton, Barrow, South, Brown, Fuller and
            <br>Bacon. By Basil Montagu, Esq., M. A. First Ame-
            <br>rican from the Fifth London Edition.
         </div>
         
         <p>This is a book we may safely take on our faith in the
            good taste and discretion of the American editor. He
            has been a diligent laborer in the vineyard of old English Literature for many years; and we have no doubt
            he has a sincere pleasure in seeing the public coming
            round to the manlier standard of the earlier writers—
            These selections, we need scarcely say, are well made.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page228"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            They are from the picked greatness of English prose;
            the bounty, the vigor, the spirit and breadth of the old
            giant-race of authors, who were men and wrote for men.
            They have no fear, but a full faith in the generous fecundity of nature, and teem on every hand with expression
            and truth and life. The passages from the modern Edward Irving, given in the notes (which are to the purpose, and copious) are in a like temper, and abide the
            comparison without loss of credit to the eccentric divine.
         </p>
         
         <p>At some other day, when our pages are less crowded,
            it will give us pleasure to spread some of these choice
            selections before our readers—if they are not before us
            by a resort to the publishers, and a mastery of the whole
            feast in advance of our grudging convenience.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Praise and Principle; or For What Shall I live. By
            <br>the author of “Conquest and Self Conquest” New-
            <br>York: Harper if Brothers.
         </div>
         
         <p>If we say that this book is evidently written by a sensible, discreet, judicious woman, we indicate all its best
            properties as well as though we dwelt on it through a
            dozen pages. The style is clear and simple, the sentiments excellent and proper, and the narrative gracefully
            conducted to the end.
         </p>
         
         <p>It indicates in various passages a greater knowledge j
            of life, in its actual, out-of-door struggles, than generally
            falls to those who can write with such lady-like propriety and refinement. We have been particularly impressed
            by the naturalness and good judgment with which her
            school-boy scenes are managed: they are in an excellent
            tone, and denote in the writer quick sympathies and an
            observant eye. The nice taste of the authoress is shown,
            as might be expected, even in the selection of her mottoes: they are obviously of her own choosing. The book
            is, in a word, of a kind we are glad to see: we hope it
            will not only be—it has already been to no inconsiderable
            degree—a source of honor to its fair writer, but may be
            such in all its results as to prompt and encourage her to
            further undertakings of the same kind. Constant purchasers as such books are likely to command, and a few
            copy-rights like this, well deposited in the hands of liberal publishers, should be an estate for the gentle worne.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Littell's Living Age. No 73.</div>
         
         <p>Mr. Littell is the compiler of a valuable miscellany
            published in Boston, of generally liberal sympathies, but
            has not entirely escaped provincial preferences. This is
            shown by the apparent eagerness with which unfriendly
            notices of writers without New England are spread upon his pages from the English journals. A singular example of this occurs in the present number, where an unfavorable notice of a New-York author is picked out of
            many favorable ones, and a favorable notice of a New
            England historian is picked out of many unfavorable
            ones.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Wiley if Putnam's “Foreign Library."</div>
         
         <p>A Prospectus has been issued of this new undertaking,
            which has grown out of the popular series of books in
            “The Library of Choice Reading,” with an eye to a convenient division of the volumes for the Library. The
            Foreign Library will be published uniformly with the
            other, with equal attention to the beauty of the typography, and the excellence of the editions, and at equally
            low rates. By the publishers' announcement it will include the leading classic works of the Foreign languages,
            both ancient and modern—the latter being a new and im
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>portant feature of the undertaking—with such works of
            miscellaneous literature as may be worthy a permanent
            place in the Library. The historical works of Schiller
            are announced, Goethe’s Wilhelmmeister, Mitchell’s
            Translation of Aristophanes, &amp;c. The first numbers will
            be Bensenerto Cellini’s Memoirs, the full and elaborately
            illustrated edition of Roscoe; a valuable and delightful
            work, for its historical and personal interest, which Horace Walpole pronounced “more amusing than any novel, and of which a complete translation is included in
            the works of Goethe. We shall have more to say of the
            plan and the books hereafter.
         </p>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Fine Arts.</div>
            
            <p>We are indebted to the kindness of Mr. C. Edwards
               Lester, for permission to extract some passages, this
               week, from his forthcoming work, “The Artist, the Merchant, and the Statesman.” The quotation will speak
               for itself:—the words are those of Powers.
            </p>
            
            <p>I have endeavored in these two statues to avoid anything that
               could either by form or import offend the purest mind; and to accomplish my design better, I have left out any expression in either of them of a consciousness of their nudity. In the Eve this
               is inferred of course—" for they were naked and were not ashamed”—indeed, they knew not that they were naked. But in the
               Slave, as it is a subject of our own times, we could not suppose
               this under ordinary circumstances—but there art circumstances
               under which it might be supposed, and I selected a subject that
               would justify this.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Slave has been taken from one of the Greek Islands by the
               Turks, in the time of the Greek Revolution; the history of which
               is familiar to all. Her father and mother, and perhaps all her
               kindred, have been destroyed by her foes, and she alone preserved
               as a treasure too valuable to be thrown away. She is now among
               barbarian strangers, under the pressure of a lull recollection of
               the calamitous events which have brought her to her present state;
               and she stands exposed to the gaze of the people she abhors, and
               awaits her fate with intense anxiety, tempered indeed by the support of her reliance upon the goodness of God. Gather all these
               a Auctions together, and add to them the fortitude and resignation
               of a Christian, and no room will be left for shame. Such are the
               circumstances under which the Greek Slave is supposed to stand.
            </p>
            
            <p>Every one remembers having listened to the sound of the seashell, when we hear what the poets call "the murmur of the sea.”
               But if is not so generally known that the shell is supposed to give
               warning of the approach of a storm. I had an impression this
               superstition was confined to America; but many of my visitors
               have told me it is general throughout the world. Everybody
               knows the cause of the sound we hear in the shell, which is a
               species of ear trumpet, that magnifies feeble sounds to such a degree, that they become much more audible, and are echoed from
               the large end of the trumpet, provided the small end be shut, so
               strangely, and in such a peculiar manner as to resemble, by the
               aid of the fancy, the roar of the waves of the sea. There have
               been several beautiful pieces written on this; particularly by Dryden and Wordsworth; but none have alluded to the shell as an
               oracle of the weather. To represent this peculiar superstition (if
               indeed it be all superstition), I have made a small statue of a boy
               of a light and delicate form, and an Innocent expression, holding
               a shell to his ear with his left hand, while with the right he supports a net and the tiller of his boat. He is standing upon the
               sand, and near his feet are some small shells and sea-weed, to denote the magin of the ocean.
            </p>
            
            <p>This figure is a kind of Appolonio, but the character is modern; for I hold that artists should do honor to their own limes and
               their own religion, instead of going back to mythology to illustrate, for the thousandth lime, the incongruous absurdities and inconsistencies of idolatrous times, especially as our times and our
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page229"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               religion are lull of subjects equal in beauty, and all the qualities
               necessary to a full development ot art. Why cling to a Jupiter,
               when our Saviour affords us a greater than parallel subject?—
               Why a Hercules, while we have a Samson? Why an Apollo,
               while we have a Moses who is peculiar, and, with the exception
               of a Jupiter, more noble than them all 1 Then with the other sex
               mythology affords no Eve, no Miriam, no Virgin Mary, no Magdalen, no Rebecca, no Jeptha’s daughter, no Angels, no Michael,
               no Gabriel, no Ithuriel; and I might mention a hundred other
               characters equally adapted to sculptural and pictorial representations.
            </p>
            
            <p>I do not cite these as parallel subjects exactly, but as themes
               which may afford as fine opportunities for the display of human
               genius in art, as the ancients had in old time; and I believe in
               very many respects they are calculated to draw out a finer moral
               feeling, and, consequently, a loftier sentiment and a more exalted
               genius. This is a consideration not too commonly advanced, or
               entertained; but it should not be forgotten, that art rises in its perfection just in proportion to the purity and moral majesty of the
               subject of which the artist treats. Many a great artist has at.
               tempted a lewd theme, but he never made a great work; and there
               are no remains of ancient or modem art, I am bold to say, that
               ‘'ear with them any clear indication of lofty genius, which shock,
               At any considerable degree, the loftier and purer feelings. God,
               in His cunning wisdom, has wrought deep into the constitution
               of all things the great law, that sublimity and excellence of every
               kind are in a more or less intimate relation with purity. If you
               find anything beautiful, very beautiful, you are just as sure to
               find something pure. This is illustrated strikingly in those remains of ancient art,
               which have so long attracted the gaze, 
               and excited the admiration of mankind.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the Laocoon, which sends the cold shudder through one, years
               after he saw it first; in the stately and superb group of Niobe an
               her children, which awakens every generous and lofty emotion of
               the human soul; in the head of Brutus, which carries you back to
               the streets of Rome before her Ceasars; and in
            </p>
            
            <p>“That bending statue which delights the world,"
               where the chisel of Cleomenes has transmitted to all coming times
               the perfection of ideal beauty:—in all these great gems of antiquity, where Greece and Rome have exhausted their genius, and been
               contending for the palm of sculpture for two thousand years—there
               is loftiness, there is sublimity, there is the perfection of beauty
               And why is it so? Why have they lived and been transmitted
               from age to age? and why shall they be transmitted to future ages
               for ever?—They are pure!
            </p>	
            
            <p>I believe that we may, under the guidance of this principle, surpass the ancients in art, as far as the religion of the fishermen of Galilee surpasses the filthy dreams of their mythology. I well know
               we may fail to do it, too; and I am persuaded we shall fail, until
               we abandon their subjects, and a wretched servile imitation of
               their works.
            </p>
            
            <p>But a step further. I have seen either the originals or good casts
               of nearly all the celebrated representations of our Saviour, and,
               with a few exceptions, they portray the humility, meekness and benevolence that are supposed to have been peculiar to him; but in
               none of these, if I except the Ivory Christ of yours-cut by an unseated monk at Genoa, have lever seen that expression of mind,
               of divine gracefulness which must have been just as peculiar to
               his wonderful character. It would be enough for us to know that,
               that he were the Prince of Peace to know the one, and it is enough
               for us to know that he is the Son of God to convince us of the secondWhen we read the New Testament we are guided to a
               conclusion in which we cannot be mistaken; and I have always
               felt that Milton was the only Christian of modem writers who has
               drawn the person and the character of the Son of God with just
               conceptions of his intellect, his majesty and his grandeur, as we
               find it drawn by the simple but inspired pens of the apostles.
            </p>
            
            <p>Perhaps the statue of Christ by Thorwalsden embodies more of
               this conception than anything ever executed in marble, in
               great man seldom made a failure; and he has gone over a
               the whole empire of sculpture. There is a very touching incident
               connected with his Christ. He first made the disciples and sold
               ‘hem to his Government at Copenhagen. He then executed for
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>them his Christ, and presented it to them “without money and
               without price” to complete the group.
            </p>
            
            <p>Some have said, and others no doubt will affirm that a grand
               masculine character is inconsistent with the mildness and benevolence of the Saviour; but I do not think so. As a proof that all
               these characteristics may be written in one individual, I need only mention the bust of Washington by Houdon—where we see not
               only the highest degree of goodness and benevolence, but all the
               elements of the most grand and lofty character. I have heard
               foreigners delare, while gazing on this bust, that he was not only
               the best of men, but the wisest and most majestic of all human
               beings. His bust expresses the fulness of his character. There
               is no head among all the ancients so grand and noble; and while
               looking at it, I have often questioned myself after the following
               manner: if I wanted counsel, he is the man I would go to; if I
               wanted one to defend me, here is one with the courage and the
               prudence to do it; a confidant, who so trustworthy; a friend, who
               so constant? But there are certain qualities not to be found there.
               He was a practical man, and not a poet. I should never expect
               rhetorical eloquence from such a man, nor low wit, nor anything
               in the way of small talk.
            </p>
            
            <p>I do not cite the bust of Washington for a parallel in a similar
               work of our Saviour; but as a simple illustration of the remark
               that the milder and the sterner qualities of humanity may be all
               expressed with the same person.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
            
            <p>Grand Oratorio at the Tabernacle.—Beethoven’s
               Mount of Olives, and Dr. Loewe’s Seven Sleepers, were
               performed at the Tabernacle on Thursday evening, under
               the direction of Mr. George Loder. The vast building
               was more crowded upon this occasion than we ever remember to have seen it; there could not have been less
               than three thousand people present. This fact proves triumphantly that the name of any Society has but little to
               do with attracting people; good performances given under the direction of a competent person, and upon a scale
               of respectable magnitude, will never fail to ensure a large
               share of public patronage. The small amount of concerts of choral kind given in this city, during the few
               past years, has caused us both surprise and regret. There
               is such a vast field for entertainments of this kind, such
               an endless quantity of fine choral works, both ancient and
               modern, and so strong a feeling in favor of this class of
               music among the body of the people, that it becomes a
               matter of surprise that but one choral Society should exist in this great city. We could, however, give the key
               to this mystery, but we will leave it for some future occasion. We cannot however leave this portion of our
               subject, without congratulating our readers and the public generally, upon the establishment of this large body
               of amateurs, under the direction of Mr. Loder, for we
               have already seen the good fruits which spring from it.
               Mr. Meiggs, the projector of the concerts, deserves our
               thanks for his enterprising spirit, and the public an equal
               share for their discrimination in supporting him so liberally. May they continue to work together, to their mutual satisfaction.
            </p>
            
            <p>Beethoven’s great work, the Mount of Olives, forms a
               striking instance of the combination of the sublime and
               the beautiful. Several of the solos are exquisite in their
               melody, of a chastly, passionate and pathetic character,
               interspersed with passages of great beauty; while the
               choruses are distinguished for their singularly dramatic
               or rather descriptive qualities. The last chorus, “Hallelujah to the Father,” in grandeur and sublimity of
               thought and expression, not even Handel, in his moments
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page230"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               of highest inspiration, could hardly equal—certainly not
               excel What can be more vividly descriptive than the
               chorus of “Roman Soldiers,” “He came towards this
               Mountain,” and the following one in which the Disciples
               arә supposed to join in with the Soldiers, who cry,
               “ Here, seize him—we have found him who dares himself to call the Mighty King of Israel”? While the Disciples murmur out fearfully, “The Soldiers seek our Master; what dreadful fate awaits Him surrounded by His
               foes.” Nothing can exceed these compositions in vigor
               of thought, boldness of design, and artistical effect by
               powerful contrast.
            </p>
            
            <p>How entirely truthful is the trio, “My soul with rage
               and fury for just revenge o’erflows.” This is a bold and
               impetuous movement, indicating the feelings of the fiery
               Disciple, who would strive to avert his Master’s fate, by
               force of arms. He is answered by this mild reply, “No,
               thou shalt do no murder! the lesson of meek patience
               taught by the Son of God, is love and peace on earth,
               good will to man.” The great beauty of this movement
               can only be imagined, by getting the words deeply engraven on the heart, and then thinking them in music.
               Altogether the trio is a masterly work, and reminds us,
               in its situation and design, of that exquisite trio, “The
               flocks shall leave the Mountain,” in Handel’s charming
               Seranata, acis Galatea.
            </p>
            
            <p>The next point of beauty that we arrive at in this composition—and it is its crowning beauty—is the instrumentation. It is in this that Beethoven rises above all
               his competitors, if we except Mendelssohn Bartholdy;
               for as an instrumentalist he will, we believe, ever stand
               pre-eminent. To attempt to describe instrumentation,
               would be to strive to do that which cannot be done, but
               thus far we can say that the only instrumentation that rises to an art, is that which carries out the thought—not
               a mere accompaniment, subservient to the voice, but an
               integral portion of the idea, which without it would be
               but. the bare outline. The instrumentation is the coloring of the tone-picture—forms its lights and shadows,
               and imparts its grand effects. Of such a sort is the partition of the Mount of Olives, and without doubt it is the
               highest of its class. After our definition of instrumentation as an art, and the position we have awarded to that
               of the Mount of Olives, to say more upon the subject
               would be useless.
            </p>
            
            <p>We regret that we cannot award much praise to the
               solo singers. The music is too difficult for Mrs. Strong,
               and also for Mr. Pearson. There is a hardness about
               Mrs. Strong’s style, a want of delicate finish, and a coldness of manner, which renders her execution of such music, in a measure painful to hear. She has one peculiarity totally at variance with the style of Sacred Music:—
               we allude to her staccato method of execution. Even the
               simple turn (which by the by she uses most lavishly and
               not in the best taste) even the simple turn, we say, she
               sings staccato, and every note of every cadence is as distinctly articulated as it would be in a marked passage
               for a flute where every note is tongued. Mrs. Strong requires more portamento in her singing, which if acquired
               would produce a fine effect with her beautiful voice.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Pearson sang his music very correctly, but it ranges too high for his compass of voice. He also wants
               finish; he has a method of drawling out his notes, and a
               bad habit of broad pronunciation, which produce a style
               smacking much of the country psalm-singing. These defects could be remedied by a strong infusion of vigor and
               careful study for a purer intonation. We should be de
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>lighted to find our suggestions acted upon, for Mr. Pearson has been gifted by nature with a voice which properly trained would be a fortune to him.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. S. Pearson had not much to do, but what he did he
               did respectably. Of the chorus we cannot speak too
               highly. Never have we heard in this city so large a body of choristers so admirably well trained. To use a
               homely expression, everything went like clock-work.—
               There was no hesitation, no wavering, from the beginning to the end of the performance, including both Oratorios. The choruses we have mentioned in the Mount
               of Olives were executed in a masterly manner, not only
               as regards precision and force, but in sentiment and effect. They were subdued to a whisper—they rose to the
               crescendo, and overwhelmed our ears upon the fortissimo.
               Upon no occasion were the fugues in the Seven Sleepers
               so clearly developed; hitherto a certain degree of confusion was evident—the points did not come out distinctly—
               but on this occasion every opposing point was made out
               with remarkable fidelity and force. The Alto voices told
               out admirably, the Second Trebles were capital, and the
               Basses were remarkably prompt and efficient: nor were
               the other voices deficient in excellence, although we must
               remark that the Tenors were, for a short time, sadly out
               of tune (flat) in the first chorus in the second act of the
               Seven Sleepers.
            </p>
            
            <p>The band was better controlled than upon any other
               vocal concert ever given in this city. The accompaniments to the Mount of Olives, require the most delicate
               execution, and excessive promptness, to render them effective, and so admirably did the band perform on this
               occasion, that it appeared to every one the prominent
               beauty of the Oratorio. The Violins were excellent;
               also the wind instruments, particularly the Flutes and
               Fagotti. Indeed it is invidious to point out any portion
               for particular praise, so admirablә was the whole.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Oratorio of the Seven Sleepers has been so fully
               discussed during the last two weeks, that any remarks
               upon its merits on this occasion would be out of date.
               We will say however, that being better understood it
               was better appreciated and that it evidently gains favor
               with the public on each performance.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mrs. Strong and Mrs. S. Pearson acquitted themselves
               better in this than in the previous Oratorio. Mrs. E.
               Loder by her chaste and classical style, pure intonation,
               and emphatic enunciation, won the approbation of the
               large assembly in the part of Malchus the youngest of the
               Seven Brothers. Miss De Luce displayed her fine voice
               to great andvantage, and the other solo performers acquited themselves very creditably.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. H. C. Timm displayed his usual skill at the organ,
               bringing it in most judiciously to enforce the fortes and
               to strengthen the Bass in the Organ points.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. George Loder has added still more to his already
               extensive, and well earned reputation. He has all the
               qualities necessary for a conductor, energy, firmness, appreciation, refined taste and knowledge, and to all these
               qualifications he adds experience to direct them all. We
               congratulate him upon his successful performance.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Loder announced from the Orchestra that early in
               November, Mendelssohn's magnificent Oratorio of St.
               Paul, would be produced under his direction. We are
               glad of this for it is the greatest Sacred Composition of
               modern days.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page231"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Items.</div>
            
            <p>Worcester’s Piano Forte Manufactory.—Having
               occasion to visit this establishment a few weeks since,
               our ears were assailed, on every side, by the “busy note
               of preparation” for the autumn campaign. We saw
               around us a very large number of instruments in every
               stage of advancement, besides a formidable array finished and ready to be sent from the factory. We tried and
               examined many of the finished instruments, and feel much
               pleasure in recommending them cordially to our friends
               and the public. The seven octave pianos pleased us the
               most; they are brilliant, full toned, and substantial instruments, and would wear out a half a dozen of the more
               popular, but less carefully made pianos, the interior being considered of more consequence than the exterior by
               Mr. Worcester; although the exteriors are all carefully
               and elegantly finished.
            </p>
            
            <p>We trust that our professional friends and the purchasing public will call upon Mr. Worcester, at his factory,
               139 Third Avenue, corner of Fourteenth street, and judge
               for themselves of his instruments.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Bell Ringers, under the direction of Mr. Corbyn,
               have been literally coining money the past week in NewYork, Boston and other places. They are at present in
               this city, and all who have not heard them, would do well
               to visit them this week, as they start en route for Mexico
               in a few days, and will not return probably for two years.
            </p>
            
            <p>Wherever they go, we wish them success, for they in
               every way merit it, and our good wishes extend most cordially to their worthy director, Mr. Corbyn.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Cheney Family gave a concert on Monday last.
               We arrived too late to hear them, but we have been told
               that their performance was excellent. They should be
               encouraged.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are unable to notice Mr. Templeton’s performance
               this week, in consequence of the early hour at which we
               go to press; but we will do him ample justice in our
               next.
            </p>
            
            <p>Trinity Church Organ.—The beautiful engraving of
               this splendid instrument, which we promised our readers
               last week, will be delivered with our present number.—
               We must apologise for the delay, which was caused by
               an accident which could not be avoided in time for publication.
            </p>
            
            <p>A few fine impressions of this remarkable instrument,
               on extra sized paper, are on sale at the office, 135 Nassau
               atreet, price 12 1/2 cents, including the paper which contains the description.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have received numbers 1 and 2 of a new periodical called the Boston Musical Review, edited by G. W.
               Peck, Esq., and published by L. H. Bridgeman, 6 Water
               Street Boston. It is published every two weeks; contains one sheet of twenty-four duodecimo pages; price
               three dollars a year in advance. Musical periodicals,
               conducted with a view to the encouragement and improvement of the science, are much needed, and when
               found worthy should be liberally encouraged by the proProfession, by amateurs, and by all lovers of the Art.
               The numbers of the Boston Musical Review before us,
               contain some interesting articles, and some articles
               which had better been omitted. The essays on Musical
               expression contain some very clever writing, and display
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>fair appreciation of the subject, but we confess we have
               very little faith in the influence of Musical essays. The
               style in the first place is happily exploded, and in the
               next place the taste of those who read periodicals devoted to Music, is opposed to such a dry mode of conveying information, and tends to that style which discourses
               of passing events and things of present interest. The
               essay style may please six out of every thousand readers
               but those who would do good to any science must write
               for the mass and not for the few.
            </p>
            
            <p>With regard to its character as a science, we can
               scarcely at present form an opinion, though from what
               we have as yet seen we should think the  'Reviews’ will
               prove to be notices by no means critical. We shall,
               however, be glad to know that the work succeeds, for
               every help that is given to the cause of Music should be
               welcomed cordially.
            </p>
            
            <p>New-York Musical Convention.—We were in error
               in stating last week that this Convention was got up
               chiefly for the sale of Boston books. We were, however, only to a certain extent in error; if New-York be substituted for Boston, the sentence would contain the fact.
               Patent Music Books, of all descriptions, were crowded
               into every pew in the Tabernacle, and printed circulars
               descriptive of the extraordinary merits of each of them,
               were scattered everywhere about. We cannot for a moment doubt that if these works were properly appreciated, every man, woman and child would be accomplished
               musicians in less than no time.
            </p>
            
            <p>We had determined to report fully the proceedings of
               this Convention; but on attending its sittings, we found
               it to be, as we expected, nothing more nor less than a
               solemn humbug. We were surprised that such a farce
               could be enacted in the city of New-York, but we were
               pleased to find that no musician of eminence was present
               to sanction such a mockery. It is true that Dr. Hodges
               and Mr. Hill were present; but Dr. Hodges merely addressed the meeting, and the members of the Convention
               will not readily forget the caustic severity of that address.
               The patent-book men must have felt especially small.
            </p>
            
            <p>Well, this Convention met and propounded a list of
               questions for discussion, so trivial in themselves that they
               threw into the shade the sensibilities evolved in the arguments pro and con. We will not trouble our readers
               with the eighteen questions before the Convention, but
               we copy a clever satire, in which the questions will be
               discovered; and we assure our readers that it contains
               more common sense than was uttered during the sitting
               of this remarkable Convention:
            </p>
            
            <p>1. Resolved, That the obstacles to the advancement of Sacred
               Musie are so formidable that the least said at present about them
               the better.
            </p>
            
            <p>2. That there are many practical benefits from oratorial singing
               to psalmody, but as all persons have not musical ears, there is no
               use in specifying them now.
            </p>
            
            <p>3. That musical instruments may be of great use in religious
               edification—the tambour, triangles, sackbut, dulcimer, and big
               drum particularly.
            </p>
            
            <p>4.	That good musical performances to a certain extent depend
               on the ability to read music at sight; but that it is not judicious
               to define that extent just now, nor just to omit saying that those
               who can read without their sight are to be accounted as among the
               most skilful.
            </p>
            
            <p>5.	That the cultivation of secular music conduces to the advancement of sacred music, just as far as it is kept secret, and its
               utility is in the inverse ratio to its prevalence.
            </p>
            
            <p>6.	That some of the best ways of sustaining competent teachers
               in our churches are to allow them their own way entirely in the
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page232"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               tuition of classes—females especially—to give them good pay, and
               not allow them to chew honey dew, or drink gin slings, or Gough
               cordials, those beverages tending to injure the voice, and promote
               all manner of discords.
            </p>
            
            <p>7.	Taat churches should hold themselves, and be held by others,
               as responsible lor the maintenance of their sacred music, according to the French proverb, “aide-toi et le ciel t’aidera.”
            </p>
            
            <p>8.	That, popularly considered, the best means for diffusing musical knowledge, is to persuade all persons who have the capacity to
               learn music, to develope the organs of time and tune, and issue
               testimonials, and give small premiums to those who excel in
               whistling, singing, or cleverly attempting to do either.
            </p>
            
            <p>9.	That the principal advantage derivable from quartette choirs
               is best known to those who have experienced it.
            </p>
            
            <p>10.	That churches are benefitted by religious music, as far as
               they themselves, as well as the music, are religious; which means,
               of course, the opposite of profane; and that if this does not always
               hold good, it is owing to some fault in the instrument, the voice, or
               faith of the performer.
            </p>
            
            <p>11.	That the most excellent kind of melody is the melody of the
               heart; therefore, to effect this organ ought always to be a primary
               object of the singer or player, and that, in order to do this, it would
               be wise to write all semibreves, minims, crotchets, quavers, &amp;c.,
               heart-shaped instead of globular.
            </p>
            
            <p>12.	That good musical taste is one thing, and religious influence
               another; therefore, as they are distinct, separate, but friendly objects, they cannot in any shape or form conflict with each other.
            </p>
            
            <p>13.	That the propriety of giving public concerts of sacred music
               in a great measure depends on the popularity of the practice, the
               cash receipts derivable from them, and the degree in which musical professors acquire reputation and emolument by the practice.
            </p>
            
            <p>14.	That the best mode of teaching religious music is for every
               person to learn it himself, but to be sure and pay the professor who
               lives by it.
            </p>
            
            <p>The number of people present at the meetings during
               the “Musical Week,” might amount to (spectators included) some eighty or ninety. The Convention threaten the
               city with another meeting in the ensuing year.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
            
            <p>Mr. Murdoch.—Our readers will recollect the commendation bestowed by us on certain Shakespearian recitations at the Society Library in the spring of the present year. There were not a few persons of discrimination and taste who discerned in their deliverer, Mr. Murdoch, the elements and capabilities of a first rate performer. Their faith will be dashed or confirmed by the
               results of next Tuesday evening, at the Park. Mr. Murdoch on that occasion presents himself in Hamlet, and
               will contend for a position among the tragic actors of
               the day. In our judgment, while allowance being made
               for difference of years and opportunity, he will fall behind the greater names of his art, he will triumphantly
               overleap many performers who have borne the palm and
               made conquest of popular support.
            </p>
            
            <p>We do not name names, but we shall be glad to see
               our American taking the field against all comers; we
               are satisfied, from what we know and have seen of the
               man, that he will acquit himself honorably. He appears
               at a period when the public are, so to speak, in expectation: the tide has at length turned in favor of home talent, and they are ready to welcome any one who may
               justify their national hope. Nationality at length steps
               forward to plant its standard in Literature, in Art, and on
               the Stage. Mr. Murdoch is destined to be one of its best
               and most resolute supporters. He comes at a time when
               he is needed. It is a long day since the American stage
               has presented to the public a native-born performer, whom
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>they could receive and adopt. Unless all augury derived
               from youth, person, voice, discipline and experience prove
               false, he is destined to become not only their child, but
               their favorite, and it will give us great pleasure to see
               him measured not only by the side of competitors, heretofore, from abroad, hut keeping the field against all
               new-comers. We look for the prosperity of the drama
               here, at home. The hope of the drama is as great—greater acording to our notion — here in New-York and in
               America than anywhere on the face of the globe; and we
               venture to predict that a school of dramatic writing, and
               a succession of performers, eminently national, having
               the color of the climate and the heart of the people in
               them, will ere long appear.
            </p>
            
            <p>We look toward the drama, therefore, as a form in
               which the national spirit shall early show itself, with
               great anxiety. We are determined to watch its promise,
               and to give it every aid in our power. It is on this account that we dwell on this first appearance of Mr. Murdoch; and in his reception we expect to be furnished
               with an evidence and confirmation of our hopes. He presents such claims, and has every circumstance that can
               attract and interest the public in his favor, so clearly on
               his side, that we are sure we cannot be mistaken in predicting a reception in every way flattering to him, and
               honorable to American feeling and-pride of country.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div> 
            
            <p>If any inference may be drawn from the constant issues of the press, poetry is ascending in America to a
               popular level. We have every week occasion to notice
               some new publication of this kind, on good paper, well
               bound, and altogether elegantly set forth. We have had
               or are to have within a very short time a sample from
               almost every one of the better known female writers of
               the country. Messrs Wiley &amp; Putnam are about to incorporate poetical writings in their Library of American Books. Paine &amp; Burgess, the new and spirited publishers in John Street, are issuing a Miniature Edition of
               American Poets, in handsome style. Mr. Redfield has
               lately published a neat volume. Clarke Sc Austin are
               busy in the same direction—so that the opinion we have
               long entertained that poetry was destined to lift its fair
               front, next, in America, in new and attractive forms, will
               not be defeated by the absence of popular sympathy or
               a want of a disposition on the part of our publishers to
               further its approaches towards the public.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have called attention under the Dramatic head, to
               the appearance of Mr. Murdoch at the Park Theatre,
               next week. To that occasion we again invite the attention of our readers. The Drama is destined, we believe&gt;
               to acquire a consequence in this country greater than it
               has enjoyed among any people since the ancient Grecians. We see on every side of us many indications of
               such a result. We are not sure but that the first form
               in which our Literature is to triumphantly vindicate itself will be in that of dramatic writing. There will be
               and has been exceptions, in single productions in other
               departments: But we are not sure that the first school to
               rise will not be the dramatic. In the founding of such a
               school, good actors are as greatly needed as great writers:
               and it is on this account that we hope that every genuine American and well-wisher to the hopes of the country, will sustain trials and attempts like this of Mr. Murdoch.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page233"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">JUST PUBLISHED,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Autobiography of Viltori Alfieri—
               <br>translated, with an original essay on the
               <br>Genius and Times of Aliieri, by C. Edwards
               <br>Lester—l vol. 12 mo. Contents—Introduc-
               <br>tion, Period 1st—Infancy, embracing nine
               <br>years of vegetation. Peiiod 2d—Childhood,
               <br>embracing nine years of inueducaiion. Pe-
               <br>riod 3d—Embracing ten years of travelling
               <br>and dissipation. Period 4lh—Embracing
               <br>more than thirty years of devotion to letters.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">“In it the great Tragedian has revealed
               <br>all the secrets of his soul; the blood fell en-
               <br>thusiasm, the poetry, the music, the earnest
               <br>passions, and the wild love scenes of that
               <br>beautiful land, all breathe from its pages.
               <br>Genius with its great and tree impulses—its
               <br>strange caprices—Passion with her fury and
               <br>fires—Music with her transporting flights of
               <br>song—Tragedy, with its fearful elements—
               <br>Protean Love, with its triumphs and insane
               <br>despair,and all painted with a master’s hand”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Citizen of a Republic, by An-
               <br>saldo Ceba. 1 vol. 12 mo. “ A book of rare
               <br>and condensed thoughts, like diamonds fine-
               <br>ly polished and richly set.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli,
               <br>2 vols. 12 mo. “The charmed records ol
               <br>the classic city of the Arno, by the master
               <br>spirit of his age.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Challenge of Barletta, a Ro-
               <br>mance of the Times of the Medici. 1 vol.
               <br>12 mo. “A gem gathered from the jeweled
               <br>mines of Italian Romance.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">—NEARLY READY—
               <br>Artist, Merchant and Statesman—
               <br>Part 1st. By C. Edwards Lester.
               <br>Morris's Melodies, 32 mo. gilt.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Prairiedom, Rambles and Scrambles
               <br>in Teqas, or New Estramadura, by a South-
               <br>ron. 1 vol. 12mo.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">PAINE &amp; BURGESS,
               <br>62 John street.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">Orthophonic System of Elocution.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">MR. GEORGE VANDENHOFF
               <br>RESPECTFULLY announces than on his
               <br>return from Europe it is his intention
               <br>permanently to devote himself in the city of
               <br>New-York to
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Oratorical Instruction.
               <br>He will resume his
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Classes in Elocution,
               <br>bis Private Lectures with members of the
               <br>profession of the Church and Bar; and his
               <br>Shaksperian and Poetical Readings, in No-
               <br>vember. Mean time notes, See. may be ad-
               <br>dressed for him to the Carlton House, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Mr. G. Vandenhoff’s System of
               <br>Vocal Gymnastics,
               <br>based on the course pursued at the Orthopho-
               <br>nic Institute in Paris, and the Royal Acade-
               <br>my of Music in London (the later under the
               <br>superindence of Mr. Vandenhoff,) both of
               <br>which Mr. G. V. has had the best opportuni-
               <br>ties of personally examining—will be found
               <br>most efficacious in removing all Delects of,
               <br>Utterance, and by a due regulation of the
               <br>respiratory economy, and of the organic ac-
               <br>tion of articulation, will give power and
               <br>case to the public speaker.	ol8
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">161 Broadway, September, 1845.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'S
               <br>LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">“BOOKS WHICH ARE BOOKS.”
               <br>THE PUBLISHERS of the Library of Choice:
               <br>Reading beg leave to call attention to the fol
               <br>lowing classification of the books published in the
               <br>series by which it will appear that novelty, variety,
               <br>and standard must	have always been preserved,
               <br>and the promise of the original prospectus faithfully 
               <br>kept. It was proposed to publish the best books of
               <br>Travels, Biographies, works of Classic Fiction,
               <br>where the morally superior to the mere story, with
               <br>out any-sacrifice of the interest— occasional choice
               <br>volumes of Poetry Essays, Criticism. Contributions
               <br>to History, and generally such single volumes writ
               <br>ten by men of genius, as will equally delight the I
               <br>scholar and the general reader." The books already
               <br>issue 1 and ready for immediate publication may be
               <br>arranged as follows:
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">BOOKS OF TRAVELS
               <br>EOTHEN, OR TRACES OF TRAVEL BROUGHT
               <br>HOME FROM THE EAST.
               <br>THE FRENCH IN ALGIERS By Lady Duff 
               <br>Gordon.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div>
            <div class="ab">THE CRESCENT AND THE CROSS—2 vols. By
               <br>Warburton.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">SIR FRANCIS HEAD’S BUBBLES FROM THE
               <br>BRUNNEN.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">BECKFORD’S ITALY, SPAIN, PORTUGAL, AND
               <br>VISIT TO THE MONASTERIES OF ALCO-
               <br> BACA AND BATALHA—in press.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">notes of a journey through France
               <br>AND ITALY. By Hazlitt.—in press.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">These will be followed by Sir Francis Head’s
               <br>Rough Notes of a Journey across the Pampas;—
               <br>Waterton’s Wanderings in South America; Miss
               <br>Rigby’s Loiters from the Baltic; Henry Nelson
               <br>Coleridge’s Six Months in the West Indies, and
               <br>Thackekay’s Notes of a Journey from London to
               <br>Cano, and others—forming altogether one of the
               <br>most original and select collections of books of tra
               <br>vels ever published.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">CLASSIC FICTION.
               <br>MARY SCHWEIDLER, THE AMBER WITCH
               <br>The most interesting Trial for Witchcraft ever
               <br>published.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">UNDINE AND SINTRAM AND HIS COMPAN-
               <br>IONS. From the German of La Motte Fouque.
               <br>THE DIARY OF LADY WILLOUGHRY.
               <br>HEADLONG HALL AND NIGHTMARE ABBEY
               <br>ZSCHOKKE’S TALES. Translated by Parke God-
               <br>win.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE CROCK OF GOLD. By Martin Farqubar
               <br>Tupper.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">HEART AND THE TWINS. By Martin Farqubar
               <br>Tupper.—in press.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Under this department will he included the choicest
               <br>new works of fiction as they issue from the press
               <br>and choice translations from the wipers of the Con
               <br>tinent. The following have been already announc
               <br>ed: Mrs Inchbald's Nature and Art ; Tales from
               <br>Tieck and Hoffman, the White Lady and Peter
               <br>Schlemihl; The Life and Adventures of Peter Wil-
               <br>kins, a Cornish Man; Melincourt and Crotchet Cas
               <br>tle, by the author of Headlong Hall.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">ILLUSTRATIONS OF ENGLISH LITERATURE
               <br>LEIGH HUNT’S IMAGINATION AND FANCY
               <br>HAZLITT’S dramatic writers OF The
               <br>AGE OF ELIZABETH.
               <br>HAZLITT'S CHARACTERS OF SHAKSPEARE
               <br>WILSON’S GENIUS AND CHARACTER OF
               <br>BURNS.
               <br>HAZLITT'S LECTURES ON THE COMIC WRI
               <br>TERS—in press.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">HAZLITT'S LECTURES ON THE ENGLISH
               <br>POETS—in press.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The works of Hazlitt's this department, the
               <br>most eloquent commentator on English Literature
               <br>will be followed by various writings of Campbell
               <br>Wilson, Coleridge, SOUTHEY, Ellis and others.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">BIOGRAPHY AND GENERAL LITERATURE.
               <br>LEIGH HUNT’S INDICATOR AND COMPA
               <br>NION—2 vols.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">HOOD’S PROSE AND VERSE—2 vols.
               <br>CHARLES LAMB’S ESSAYS OF ELIA.
               <br>HAZLITT’S TABLE TALK—2d seriәs, 2 vols.
               <br>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF BENVENUTO CELLINI
               <br>—in press.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">A complete collection of the writings of Hazlitt
               <br>and Leigh Hunt will form part of the series to be
               <br>published at short intervals; WALTER SATAGE LAN
               <br>'doe’s writings; De Quincet's (the English opium
               <br>eater) Miscellaneous Writings; James Smith’s Re 
               <br>jected Addresses and the Poems and Ballads of Bon Gualtier.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Old English literature.
               <br>BASIL MONTAGU'S SELECTIONS FROM TAY
               <br>LOR, SOUTH, BARROW, FULLER, &amp;c.
               <br>CHARLES LAMB'S SPECIMENS OF OLD ENG-
               <br>LISH DRAMATISTS WHO LIVED ABOUT
               <br>THE TIME OF SHAKSPEARE.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">These, the most perfect collections of the kind.
               <br>ever published, will form the introduction in prose
               <br>and verse to a series of the old English writers
               <br>including SIR THOMAS MORE, HERBERT, FULLER.
               <br>sir thomas browne, miltion, selden, bacon and others.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">American Series.
               <br>Of the "Library of American Books," the fol
               <br>lowing have already been issued:
               <br>JOURNAL OF AN AFRICAN CRUISER, edited
               <br>BY NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE.
               <br>TALES BY EDGAR A. POE.
               <br>LETTERS FROM ITALY BY J T HEADLEY
               <br>THE WIGWAM AND THE CABIN. BY W. GIL
               <br>MORE SIMMS.
               <br>AG  ABEL AND THE LITTLE MANHATTAN
               <br>BY CORNELIUS MATHEWS.
               <br>WANDERINGS OF THE PILGRIM UNDER THE
               <br>SHADOW OF THE JUNGFRAU, BY GEORGE
               <br>B. CHEEVER, D. D.—Jut READY.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The following are in press:—Western Clearings 
               <br>by Mary CLAVERS (MRS KIRKLAND); Wanderings
               <br>of a Pilgrim under the Shadow of the Jungfrau, by
               <br>GEORGE B. CHEEVER; Views and Reviews in Ame
               <br>rican History, Literature, and Fiction, a Miscellany 
               <br>by W. Gimore Simms; The Forest and the Prairie 
               <br>by JAMES HALL, author of the Border Tales; a new
               <br>volume, by NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE; The OLD Eng
               <br>lish Library, by W.N. JONES; and other productions
               <br>of American authors.
            </div>
         </div> 		
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">GURNEY’S
               <br>PREMIUM DAGUERRIAN GALLERY,
               <br>189 BROADWAY, NEAV-YOKK.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">PICTURES taken at this Establishment
               <br>are not excelled in this country—so say
               <br>his numerous patrons. The public are in-
               <br>vited to call and judge lor themselves. O2
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div>
            <div class="ab">MESSRS. HARPER &amp; BROTHERS
               <br>PUBLISH THIS DAY,
               <br>Elements of Morality and Polity.
               <br>BY PROF. WHEWELL.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">THIS valuable new production, from the pen of
               <br>one of the most eminent scholars of the age,
               <br>exhibits, in a most lucid, exact, and elegant state,
               <br> the great principles of moral, political, and ecclcsi-
               <br> slical science in a far more complete and methodi-
               <br>cal manner than has ever yet been presented to the
               <br> public. In offering this great work to the American
               <br> reader, the publisher begs leave to introduce it as
               <br>the commencement of a new and attractive series
               <br>of sterling books, to be issued by them, under the
               <br>general designation of
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">HARPER’S NEW MISCELLANY;
               <br>the volumes of winch will be legibly printed, in
               <br>duodecimo, on fine paper, and
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Bound in extra Muslin Gilt—Price
               <br>Fifty Cents a Volume,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">and issued at short interval To render accessible
               <br>to the million, the fullest advantage- of popular in-
               <br>struction in the various divisions of human know-
               <br>ledge, is the design of the above series. It is appa-
               <br>rent in the present day, that books of intrinsic value
               <br>are demanded by the people. Formerly the popu-
               <br>lar taste preferred mainly works of mere amusement
               <br>—the great body of readers now seek them as vehi-
               <br>cles of general knowledge books of a more per-
               <br>manently valuable caste—devoted to some of the
               <br>departments of science, or general literature. A
               <br>new race has sprung up, glowing with the first
               <br>energies of youth, requiring more expanded ideas
               <br>of the world in which they live, and a more reliable
               <br>and well-digested knowledge of the men. and the
               <br>events of other times and countries. A class of
               <br>books expressly adapted to this demand, it is the
               <br>aim of the publishers to supply; and at a price so
               <br>exceedingly cheap that every person of ordinary
               <br>taste and advantages may thus become possessed
               <br>of a
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Complete Library of the Best Litera-
               <br>ture of the Age.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">In this collection it is intended to include the best
               <br>productions in every department of knowledge;
               <br>| popular philosophical treatise- on topics of univer
               <br>-sal interest; the most compact and brilliant histori-
               <br>cal books; valuable biographical memoirs; modern
               <br>voyages and travels, &amp;c.; together with scientific
               <br>and other collateral divisions; in the selection of
               <br>all which, the most careful discrimination will be
               <br>observed A mere glance over the wide domain of
               <br>our English literature will exhibit much yet unex-
               <br>plored and uncultivated, from which might be ga-
               <br>thered the fruits of a rich, luxuriant harvest; besides
               <br>which, the ever-teeming issues of the European
               <br>press open a vast revenue of literary wealth, from
               <br>which the above collections may be liberally suppli-
               <br>ed. Original productions from American writers
               <br>I will also occasionally be introduced In submitting,
               <br>therefore, the esteemed work of Prof. Whewell
               <br> as a kind of first fruits of their ‘‘New Miscellany,”
               <br>the publishers deem it only necessary to add, that
               <br>their arrangements for carrying forward the enter-
               <br>prise of being of the most complete and efficient kind,
               <br>they confidently rely upon their efforts being met
               <br>with a ready response from the entire reading com-
               <br>munity.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">This, they venture to believe, will be insured to
               <br>other Miscellany, no less from the intrinsic value
               <br>of the collection, than from its unparalleled econo
               <br>my: each volume being elegantly produced, bound
               <br>IN HANDSOME AND SUBSTANTIAL STYLE. FITTED WITH-
               <br>OUT FARTHER EXPENSE FOR PERMANENT PRESERVA-
               <br>TION in the library; the whole series being issued
               <br>in uniform binding while the price of each volume
               <br>will be only Fifty Cents—far below the cost of
               <br>any similar senes of books yet published in this,
               <br>or, it is believed, any other country.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—THOMAS II. CHAMBERS,
               <br>(formerly Conductor to Dubois and Stodart),
               <br>No. 365 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment
               <br>of the latest approved Grand Action Piano Forres,
               <br>of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared
               <br>to guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch,
               <br>and External Finish, and to endure in any climate.
               <br>liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano
               <br> Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always
               <br>on here.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">PENMANSHIP.
               <br>Reopening of goldsmiths writing
               <br>ACADEMY, 289 Broadway. La Farge Build-
               <br>ings, corner of Reade Street. Terms reduced to
               <br>THREE DOLLARS, AND NO EXTRA CHARGE.
               <br>MR. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the 
               <br>citizens of New York amd Brooklyn, that his rooms
               <br>are now open, during the day and evening, for Pu-
               <br>pils and Visiters. Mr. G's specimens of
            </div> 
            
            <div class="ab">PENMANSHIP
               <br>has received the First PREMIUM FIVE YEARS, from
               <br>a American Institute, and he guarantees to all in
               <br>TEN EASY AND INTERESTING EXERCISES,
               <br>a free and elegant style of writing, that the pupils
               <br>cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">For sale at the Academy GOLDSMITH's GEMS 
               <br>OF PEMANSHIP.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Ladies' CLASS meets daily at 11 o'clock. Gentle-
               <br>men's day and evening. See Circular. s18
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page234"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">J. F. BROWNE &amp; CO.
               <br>MANUFACTURER OF THE
               <br>IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION HARP,
               <br>By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years with Erard.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">J F. BROWNE respectfully informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has established
               himself for the manufacture
               <br>and importation of  these very beautiful instruments, at
               <br>281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">His arrangements are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices,
               thereby saving purchasers the duties
               <br>imposed by Tariff on these Instruments.
            </div>	
            
            <div class="ab">J. F. Browne would observe these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
               with all the modern improvements of
               <br>London and Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy of tone, fineness of touch, and perfectness
               of mechanism Particular care is taken
               <br>to fit them for the extremes of climate in this country, in which respect they will
               be found far superior to any of European manufac-
               <br>ture, imported in the usual way.
            </div>	
            
            <div class="ab">These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and professional talent in
               Europe; among the latter, he would mention
               <br>N.C. Boscha, who invariably selects from this establishment.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">J. F. Browne begs to offer the opinions of some of the first professional talent in
               this country.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making
               a professional use of your Harps, and of 	
               <br>testing their qualities, it affords me pleasure to certify, that in point of tone,
               workmanship, and above all, a solidity that stands proof
               <br>against the inconstancy of our trying climate, they have in all cases given me the
               most entire satisfaction.
               <br>January, l845.	I am yours, CHARLES THIBAULT, No. 40 Beach St., N. Y.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">Dear Sir:—I write to express the delight I experienced in performing on one of your
               Harps at Sig. Casella's Concert in this city.—
               <br>The mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly superior to any harp I
               have heard for many years. I remember my old	
               <br>Master, Boscha, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no
               other. Yours, most truly, H. G. TRUST.
               <br>Philadelphia, March 4th, 1841.
            </div>
         </div>		 
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make
               I performed on at the St. George's Society
               <br>Concert, is, in brilliancy of tone, touch, and elegance of workmanship, the finest
               I ever  played on. This will apply to all your Harps.
               <br>The grand six and a half Gothic Double action, is a most splendid instrument. Yours,
               with respect, ELIZABETH  SLOMAN.
               <br>New York, January 16th, 1845.	A pupil of N. C. Boscha.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir Having at your request closely scrutinized your double-action
               Harps, I find they possess the best quali-	
               <br>ties of the first makers in Europe combined. That in the ease of touch by which the
               most brilliant tone is obtained in perfection and 
               <br>ease of modulation, they are superior to any I have used: their elegance of exterior
               must gratify the most refined taste. Your new 
               <br>Grand Gothic six and a half octave, is the most splendid effort of art yet produced
               in the musical world; it will give me great pleasure 
               <br>in recommending your Harps at every opportunity.	Yours Truly, HENRY HORN.
               <br>January 12th, 1845.			 An eminent professor, and Member of the Royal Academy.
            </div>
         </div>      
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
               show the estimate of persons every way capable of
               <br>making a correct decision. J.F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the
               Society of Arts, Philadelphia, for his splendid 
               <br>improvements in this delightful Instrument. 
               <br>Harps from 300 to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div>
            <div class="ab">THE SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER
               <br>B.B. MINOR, Proprietor. Published monthly,
               <br>at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The MESSENGER has been established since
               <br>1835, has a large subscription list, and is the princi-
               <br>pal organ of Southern opinion.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the offiәe
               <br>of the 'Broadway Journal,’ 135 Nassau street.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">JUST PUBLISHED BY H. G. DAGGERS, 30 Ann
               <br>Street, New York.
               <br>THE COTTON LORD. By Mrs. Stone A Ro
               <br>mance of the Rich and Poor, written by a lady of
               <br>brilliant talents. 25 Cents.
               <br>FRANKENSTEIN, by Mrs. Mary W. Shelley,
               <br>wife of the illustrious poet.  "It is among the most
               <br>exciting and terrible of modern romances.”—TRI
               <br>bunE. 25 Cents.
               <br>LAWRIE TODD, by John Galt, with an original
               <br>preface by the original Lawrie Todd, viz Grant
               <br>Thorburn, Esq. “Mr. Thorburn's Preface is worth
               <br>more than the  rice asked for in the novel.” 25 Cents
               <br>THE NUN: or, Life in a Convent. By one of 
               <br>the Sisterhood “A terrible exposition of the secret
               <br>practices of Roman Catholics." 25 Cents.
               <br>POOR JACK. By Captain Mariyatt, author of
               <br>Midshipman Easy, Peter Simple, &amp;c. 25 Cents.
               <br>N. B. All of the above will; be sent for One Dollar to any person ordering them through
               Postmasters, who are by law authorized to remit money to
               <br>publishers. Any Postmaster ordering the above
               <br>shall be presented with either novel he may select.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">ÆOLIAN attachment.
               <br>Hermann s. SARONI, Professor of Music, 116
               <br>Leonard street, New York, teaches the Piano
               <br>Forte, with or without Coleman s celebrated At-
               <br>tachment.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—II. WORCESTEB, NO. 135
               <br>THIRD AVENUE, Corner of 14th Street, res
               <br>pectfully informs his friends and the public, that he
               <br>has a good assortment of Piano Fortes, in Rosewood
               <br>and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons
               <br>wishing to purchase will find it to their advantage
               <br>to call and examine before purchasing elsewhere.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div>
            <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES —V.F. HARRISON, 23 CANAL
               <br>Street, N. Y.
               <br>Instruments made with the most recent improve
               <br>ments, such as Iron Frames, &amp;c., with a compass
               <br>of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice
               <br>materials, and highly finished, with the most faith
               <br>ful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience
               <br>in the business.
               <br>N. B. Wanted a second hand Parlor Organ.
               <br>Piano Fortes hired by the month.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES CHEAP FOR CASH—THE
               <br>subscribers have on hand a handsome assort-
               <br>ment, 6, 6 1/2 and 7 octave, mahogany and rosewood
               <br>pianos, which they will warrant and sell low for
               <br>cash or approved paper
               <br>GLENN, RODGERS &amp; CO., Manufacturers,
               <br>152 Fulton street, East of Broadway.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">G H. DERWORT, PROFESSOR OF SINGING,
               <br>Guitar and Piano Forte, has opened a class
               <br>for Young Ladies, from 7 to lo years  of age, among
               <br>whom are three of his own daughters, whom he
               <br>proposes to thoroughly instruct in art of Singing.
               <br>Mr. Derwort’s system is the result of many  years
               <br>observation and experience, during which he has
               <br>successfully taught in Geunany, London and New
               <br>York. His method cannot fail to impart to his pu
               <br>pils a clear perception and a thorough knowledge
               <br>of the grammatical principles of music with the
               <br>ability to harmonize any simple given melody.
               <br>Parents and guardians are invited to call at 44
               <br>Rooms, 427 Broadway, when every inquiry will be
               <br>answered.
               <br>Terms $20 per annum, payable quarterly in ad
               <br>vance. Lessons three times a week.
               <br>Private instruction as heretofore.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER—JAMES
               <br>PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near
               <br>Etin. A Large Stock of the finest instruments al
               <br>ways on hand. Terms moderate. FOR SALE—A
               <br>Splendid Harp, nearly new. To he sold at a great
               <br>bargain for cash.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">WEDDING, VISITING, &amp; PROFESSIONAL
               <br>CARDS, engraved and printed at VALEN-
               <br>TINE'S, l Beckman street— Lovejoy's Hotel.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div>
            <div class="ab">J. BALLARD. PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR,
               <br>Singing, and Flute, No. 135 Spring street.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">CARD OF REMOVAL.—MR W. A KING,
               <br>Professor of Music and Teacher of the Piano-
               <br>Forte and Organ, has Removed to the First House
               <br>(above Twenty-Fifth Street on the Rail-Road (4th
               <br>Avenue)
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">Our First Volume.—A few copies of
               <br>the first volume of the Broadway Jour-
               <br>nal are for sale at the office, either in
               <br>numbers or neatly bound.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">AGENTS.
               <br>Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass.
               <br>R. G. H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct.
               <br>M. Baullemet, Mobile, Ala.
               <br>Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O.
               <br>D. M. Dewey, Rochester, N Y.
               <br>J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.
               <br>W. E. Russell, Schencetady, N. Y
               <br>Levi Willard, Troy, N. Y.
               <br>G. Jones, Albany. N. Y.
               <br>S. F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N Y.
               <br>Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore, Md.
               <br>Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.
               <br>Thos. H. Pease, New-Haven, CL
               <br>J C. Morgan, New Orleans.
               <br>W W. Kingsley, New-London, Ct.
               <br>G. N. Beesley, Utica, N Y.
               <br>H.B. Strang, Peekskill, N. Y.
               <br>Hallburton &amp; Dudley Boston, Mass.
               <br>S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass.
               <br>Peter Cooke, Hartford, Ct.
               <br>H. Eston, Providence, R. I.
               <br>Safford &amp; Park, Norwich. Ct.
               <br>John Tomlin, P. M. Jackson, Tenn.
               <br>S. Hart, Sen., Charleston, S.C.
            </div>
         </div>
         
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      <a href="#a001"> Link </a><div class="note" id="n001">From a clever jeu d’esprit published in the year 1825.</div>
      
   </div>
</div>