<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
      
      <div class="ab">VOL. 2.
         NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JULY 19, 1845.
         NO. 2.
      </div>
      
      <div class="ab">Three Dollars per Annum.
         Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
      </div>
      
      <div class="ab">EDITED BY
         EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.
      </div>
      
      <div class="ab"> Published at 136 Nassau St.
         By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">OUR NEW VOLUME.</div>
         
         <p>To the Public.—The suspension of “The Broadway
            Journal" for one week, has been occasioned by the necessity
            fofr some arrangements in which the public have no interest,
            but which, beyond doubt, will give increased value and
            efficiency to the paper.
         </p>
         <p>In commencing the Second Volume, the undersigned begs
            leave to return his sincere thanks to the numerous friends 
            who have lent him their aid in the very difficult task of
            establishing a literary and critical weekly. The success of
            the work, in the brief period of its existence, has been, he
            truly believes, beyond precedent—and from a briliiant Past,
            he looks confidently to a triumphant Future.
         </p>
         <p>The editorial conduct of “ The Broadway Journal” is under the sole charge of Edgar A. Poe—Mr. H. C. Watson,
            as heretofore, controlling the Musical Department.
         </p>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">John Bisco</span>,
            Publisher.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Masque of the Red Death.</div>
         
         <p>The “Red Death” had long devastated the country. No
            pestilence had ever been so fatal, or so hideous. Blood was
            its Avator and its seal—the redness and the horror of blood.
            There were sharp pains, and sudden dizziness, and then profuse bleeding at the pores, with dissolution. The scarlet
            stains upon the body and especially upon the face of the victim, were the pest ban which shut him out from the aid and
            from the sympathy of his fellow-men. And the whole seiz- 
            ure, progress and termination of the disease, were the inci- 
            dents of half an hour.
         </p>
         <p>But the Prince Prospero was happy and dauntless and sagacious. When his dominions were half depopulated, he
            summoned to his presence a thousand hale and light-hearted
            friends from among the knights and dames of his court, and 
            with these retired to the deep seclusion of one of his castellated abbeys. This was an extensive and magnificent structure, the creation of the prince’s own eccentric yet august
            taste. A strong and lofty wall girdled it in. This wall had
            gates of iron. The courtiers, having entered, brought furnaces and massy hammers and welded the bolts. They resolved to leave means neither of ingress or egress to the sudden impulses of despair or of frenzy from within. The abbey
            was amply provisioned. With such precautions the courtiers might bid defiance to contagion. The external world
            could take care of itself. In the meantime it was folly to
            grieve, or to think. The prince had provided all the appliances of pleasure. There were buffoons, there were improvisatori, there were ballet-dancers, there were musicians,
            there was Beauty, there was wine. All these and security
            were within. Without was the “ Red Death.”
         </p>
         <p>It was toward the close of the fifth or sixth month of his
            seclusion, and while the pestilence raged most furiously 
            abroad, that the Prince Prospero entertained his thousand  friends at a masked ball of the most unusual magnificence.
            
         </p>
         <p>It was a voluptuous scene, that masquerade. But first let
            me tell of the rooms in which it was held. There were
            seven—an imperial suite. In many palaces, however, such
            suites form a long and straight vista, while the folding doors
            slide back nearly to the walls on either hand, so that the
            view of the whole extent is scarcely impeded. Here the
            case was very different; as might have been expected from
            the duke’s love of the bizarre. The apartments were so irregularly disposed that the vision embraced but little more
            than one at a time. There was a sharp turn at every twenty or thirty yards, and at each turn a novel effect. To the
            right and left, in the middle of each wall, a tall and narrow
            Gothic window looked out upon a closed corridor which pursued the windings of the suite. These windows were of
            stained glass whose color varied in accordance with the prevailing hue of the decorations of the chamber into which it
            opened. That at the eastern extremity was hung, for examample, in blue—and vividly blue were its windows. The
            second chamber was purple in its ornaments and tapestries,
            and here the panes were purple. The third was green
            throughout, and so were the casements. The fourth was
            furnished and lighted with orange—the fifth with white—the
            sixth with violet. The seventh apartment was closely
            shrouded in black velvet tapestries that hung all over the
            ceiling and down the walls, falling in heavy folds upon a
            carpet of the same material and hue. But in this chamber
            only, the color of the windows failed to correspond with the
            decorations. The panes here were scarlet—a deep blood
            color. Now in no one of the seven apartments was there
            any lamp or candelabrum, amid the profusion of golden ornaments that lay scattered to and fro or depended from the
            roof. There was no light of any kind emanating from lamp
            or candle within the suite of chambers. But in the corridors
            that followed the suite, there stood, opposite to each window,
            a heavy tripod, bearing a brazier of fire that projected its
            rays through the tinted glass and so glaringly illumined the
            room. And thus were produced a multitude of gaudy and
            fantastic appearances. But in the western or black chamber
            the effect of the fire-light that streamed upon the dark hangings through the blood-tinted panes, was ghastly in the extreme, and produced so wild a look upon the countenances
            of those who entered, that there were few of the company
            bold enough to set foot within its precincts at all.
         </p>
         <p>It was in this apartment, also, that there stood against the
            western wall, a gigantic clock of ebony. Its pendulum
            swung to and fro with a dull, heavy, monotonous clang;
            and when the minute-hand made the circuit of the face, and
            the hour was to be stricken, there came from the brazen
            lungs of the clock a sound which was clear and loud and deep
            and exceedingly musical, but of so peculiar a note and emphasis that, at each lapse of an hour, the musicians of the
            orchestra were constrained to pause, momentarily, in their
            performance, to harken to the sound; and thus the waltzers perforce ceased their evolutions; and there was a brief disconcert of the whole gay company ; and, while the chimes
            of the clock yet rang, it was observed that the giddiest grew
            pale, and the more aged and sedate passed their hands over
            their brows as if in confused reverie or meditation. But when
            the echoes had fully ceased, a light laughter at once pervaded the assembly; the musicians looked at each other and
            smiled as if at their own nervousness and folly, and made
            whispering vows, each to the other, that the next chiming
            of the clock should produce in them no similar emotion ; and
            then, after the lapse of sixty minutes, (which embrace three
            thousand and six hundred seconds of the Time that flies,)
            there came yet another chiming of the clock, and then were
            the same disconcert and tremulousness and meditation as before.
         </p>
         <p>But, in spite of these things, it was a gay and magnificent
            revel. The tastes of the duke were peculiar. He had a fine
            eye for colors and effects. He disregarded the decora of mere
            fashion. His plans were bold and fiery, and his conceptions
            glowed with barbaric lustre. There are some who would
            have thought him mad. His followers felt that he was not.
            It was necessary to hear and see and touch him to be sure
            that he was not.
         </p>
         <p>He had directed, in great part, the moveable embellishments of the seven chambers, upon occasion of this great
            fete; and it was his own guiding taste which had given
            character to the masqueraders. Be sure they were grotesque.
            There were much glare and glitter and piquancy and phantasm—much of what has been since seen in “ Hernani.’
            There were arabesque figures with unsuited limbs and appointments. There were delirious fancies such as the madman fashions. There was much of the beautiful, much of
            the wanton, much of the bizarre, something of the terrible,
            and not a little of that which might have excited disgust. To
            and fro in the seven chambers there stalked, in fact, a multitude of dreams. And these—the dreams—writhed in and
            about, taking hue from the rooms, and causing the wild music of the orchestra to seem as the echo of their steps. And,
            anon, there strikes the ebony clock which stands in the hall
            of the velvet. And then, for a moment, all is still, and all
            is silent save the voice of the clock. The dreams are stifffrozen as they stand. But the echoes of the chime die away
            —they have endured but an instant—and a light, half-subdued laughter floats after them as they depart. And now
            again the music swells, and the dreams live, and writhe to
            and fro more merrily than ever, taking hue from the many
            tinted windows through which stream the rays from the
            tripods. But to the chamber which lies most westwardly of
            the seven, there are now none of the maskers who venture:
            for the night is waning away; and there flows a ruddier light
            through the blood-colored panes ; and the blackness of the
            sable drapery appals ; and to him whose foot falls upon the
            sable carpet, there comes from the near clock of ebony a
            muffled peal more solemly emphatic than any which reaches
            their ears who indulge in the more remote gaieties of the other apartments.
         </p>
         <p>But these other apartments were densely crowded, and in
            them beat feverishly the heart of life. And the revel went
            whirlingly on, until at length there commenced the sounding
            of midnight upou the clock. And then the music ceased, as
            I have told ; and the evolutions of the waltzers were quieted ;
            and there was an uneasy cessation of all things as before.
            But now there were twelve strokes to be sounded by the bell
            of the clock ; and thus it happened, perhaps, that more of
            thought crept, with more of lime, into the meditations of
            the thoughtful among those who revelled. And thus, too, it 
            happened, perhaps, that before the last echoes of the last
            chime had utterly sunk into silence, there were many indi viduals in the crowd who had found leisure to become aware
             of the presence of a masked figure which had arrested the
            attention of no single individual before. And the rumor of
            this new presence having spread itself whisperingly around,
             there arose at length from the whole company a buzz, or
             murmur, expressive of disapprobation and surprise—then,
            finally, of terror, of horror, and of disgust.
         </p>
         <p>In an assembly of phantasms such as I have painted, it
            may well be supposed that no ordinary appearance could
            have excited such sensation. In truth the masquerade license of the night was nearly unlimited ; but the figure in
            question had out-Heroded Herod, and gone beyond the bounds
            of even the prince's indefinite decorum. There are chords in
            the hearts of the most reckless which cannot be touched without emotion. Even with the utterly lost, to whom life and
            death are equally jests, there are matters of which no jest con
            be made. The whole company, indeed, seemed now deeply
            to feel that in the costume and bearing of the stranger neither
            wit nor propriety existed. The figure was tall and gaunt,
            and shrouded from head to foot in the habiliments of the
            grave. The mask which concealed the visage was made so
            nearly to resemble the countenance of a stiffened corpse that
            the closest scrutiny must have had difficulty in detecting
            the cheat. And yet all this might have been endured, if not
            approved, by the mad revellers around. But the mummer
            had gone so far as to assume the type of the Red Death.
            His vesture was dabbled in blood—and his broad brow, with
            all the features of the face, was besprinkled with the scarlet
            horror.
         </p>
         <p>When the eyes of Prince Prospero fell upon this spectral
            image (which with a slow and solemn movement, as if more
            fully to sustain its role, stalkod to and fro among the waltzers) he was seen to be convulsed, in the first moment with a
            strong shudder either of terror or distaste ; but, in the next,
            his brow reddened with rage.
         </p>
         <p>“ Who dares ?" he demanded hoarsely of the courtiers
            who stood near him—“ who dares insult us with this blasphemous mockery ? Seize him and unmask him—that we
            may know whom we have to hang at sunrise, from the battlements !”
         </p>
         <p>It was in the eastern or blue chamber in which stood the
            Prince Prospero as he uttered these words. They rang
            throughout the seven rooms loudly and clearly—for the
            prince was a bold and robust man, and the music had become hushed at the waving of his hand.
         </p>
         <p>It was in the blue room where stood the prince, with a
            group of pale courtiers by his side. At first, as he spoke,
            there was a slight rushing movement of this group in the direction of the intruder, who at the moment was also near at
            hand, and now, with deliberate and stately step, made clo ser approach to the speaker. But from a certain nameless
            awe with which the mad assumptions of the mummer had
         </p>
         <p>inspired the whole party, there were found none who put
            forth hand to seize him; so that, unimpeded, he passed
            within a yard of the prince’s person ; and, while the vast assembly, as if with one impulse, shrank from the centres of
            the rooms to the walls, he made his way uninterruptedly, but
            with the same solemn and measured step which had distinguished him from the first, through the blue chamber to the
            purple—through the purple to the green—through the green
            to the orange—through this again to the white—and even
            thence to the violet, ere a decided movement had been made
            to arrest him. It was then, however, that the Prince Prospero, maddening with rage and the shame of his own mo mentary cowardice, rushed hurriedly through the six chambers, while none followed him on account of a deadly terror
            that had seized upon all. He bore aloft a drawn dagger, and
            had approached, in rapid impetuosity, to within three or four
            feet of the retreating figure, when the latter, having attained the extremity of the velvet apartment, turned suddenly
            and confronted his pursuer. There was a sharp cry—and
            the dagger dropped gleaming upon the sable carpet, upon which, instantly afterwards, fell prostrate in death the
            Prince Prospero. Then, summoning the wild courage of despair, a throng of the revellers at once threw themselves into
            the black apartment, and, seizing the mummer, whose tall
            figure stood erect and motionless within the shadow of the
            ebony clock, gasped in unutterable horror at finding the
            grave-cerements and corpse-like mask which they handled
            with so violent a rudeness, untenanted by any tangible form.
         </p>
         <p>And now was acknowledged the presence of the Red
            Death. He had come like a thief in the night. And one by
            one dropped the revellers in the blood-bedewed halls of their
            revel, and died each in the despairing posture of his fall.
            And the life of the ebony clock went out with that of the last
            of the gay. And the flames of the tripods expired. And
            Darkness and Decay and the Red Death held illimitable dominion over all.
         </p>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">IMAGINATION.
            
         </div>
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>An arch immeasurably tower’d
            
            <br></br>Where Aiden’s glories spring,
            
            <br></br>And through the opened diamond valves
            
            <br></br>Majestically strode the King.
            
            <br></br>Truth, with a crown of stars
            
            <br></br>On a large brow free from stain,
            
            <br></br>While all her motions music made,
            
            <br></br>Held up his royal train:
            
            <br></br>Flowers of a rare undying hue
            
            <br></br>Sprang round the glowing arch,
            
            <br></br>And tones, that float like a seraph’s note,
            
            <br></br>Rolled out a solemn march.
            
            <br></br>'T was when the Deity appeared
            
            <br></br>Beneath the portal's flame,
            
            <br></br>He felt his might, and in the light
            
            <br></br>Creator then became.
            
            <br></br>His kindled mind conceived a sun,
            
            <br></br>And out the great fire burst
            
            <br></br>From Chaos that fell shuddering back
            
            <br></br>Like a fiend accursed :
            
            <br></br>And still the God-head wrought,
            
            <br></br>Wrought still the poet-power,
            
            <br></br>While Time was spending on the earth
            
            <br></br>His primal hour.
            
            <br></br>The labor yet went on
            
            <br></br>Where Chaos heard the curse,
            
            <br></br>Nor ceased till in a sea of space 
            
            <br></br>Floated a universe.
         </div>	
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">WM. WALLACE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Contrasted Prejudices.
            
         </div>
         <p>The Avon bard has sung in sweet tune, and we, essaying to
            make the belief ours, hum after him, “ What’s in a name?”
            But experience has an opposing conviction ; it rises up with
            the argument, much is in a name, and each of us has many
            clinging associations to maintain the affirmative. How
            eagerly we inquire the name baptismal name especially,) of
            a person whom we have not yet seen, and how hastily, determine his appearance, whether he will be agreeable, or
            repellent to us, from our association with what he is
            called.
         </p>
         <p>So it is; we are creatures of strange prejudices; these,
            though, are not wholly unaccountable. We can sometimes
            trace their origin back even to our cradles. The first lullaby
            we have any recollection of, is linked with a name, loved for
            the one who hushed us into rest with its soothing strain ; or
            recurs to us unpleasantly as we remember some discordant
            chiding for our playful wakefulness. The sweet sound of
            Viola at once creates a phantom of loveliness. And what
            more appropriate name for a sunny faced, budding little
            beauty, than Rosa. And Mary, the pet call with so many,
            in all degrees of life. It graces the lonely cot, and softens
            the splendor of the palace. The downcast, modest eye, and
            fair Madonna brow, steal upon you, with the graceful tie of
            piety and love, attached for so many centuries to the gentle
            sound.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>With what nicety an author selects a title for his romance !
            he well knows what depends on it ; frequently the remark
            has reached us, “ I will read it, if I like the name.” “ The
            Pirate,” charming—we are certain here is a rich treat of love
            and venture; already we are interested in the hero, though he
            may be
         </p>
         <div class="ab">“Link’d with one virtue, and a thousand crimes.”
            
         </div>
         <p>It is needless for me to enumerate more instances of the
            tenacity with which our prejudices hold to us, (for all can
            recall likes and dislikes, associated with names and places,)
            but I will hasten to relate one which followed me for many
            years like a grim spectre.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The first horror that presented itself to me at the threshold
            of discernible life, was the woman who presided over the
            department of edibles in my father’s house. She was the
            cook par excellence, and we the envied of the neighbourhood.
            Whenever a dinner or supper was to be given, (even in the
            most remote house of the block,) she was duly consulted as
            to the propriety of such and such dishes, which in her important opinion should be placed the first before the guests.
            If it chanced we wished any change, the suggestion was politely made, for none ventured to find fault with her arrangements. At once the assurance was given, that it was “ dressed precisely in the manner my lord had it served up to him,
            and surely such quality knew what good eating was.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This was a quietus to the matter; and the dish was tasted
            of by all, to which “ my lord” had set his imperishable seal
            of approbation in the brain of our good cook. Thanks to
            her, for my first impression of the blessings of a Republic,
            as my youthful fancy pictured the frightful rule of lords, and
            a land where people could not eat what best pleased them.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Follow me now into her empire no Sultana ever swayed
            her waiting-woman with more despotic rule, than she the
            other domestics of the house. Every article had its place.
            The saucepans hung in a row and told of the labor bestowed upon them. The kitchen was radiant with the glow of
            the tortured metal. If one passed, and accidentally unhung
            a skewer from its culinary gibbet, the tumult was enough to
            give rise to the supposition that the premises were crumbling
            in, and utter destruction inevitable, unless the spot was
            speedily vacated.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The name of this wonder of my juvenile days, was Hannah
            Johnson; she was a native of England, and had come to this
            country to live with her son, Samuel Johnson. I know not
            if he boasted being of the lineage of his illustrious predecessor
            and LL. D., of the same name, but he was a clever young
            man, and filled his calling with propriety. He was a supernumerary clerk in my father’s counting-house, transacting
            some little of the business, and performing all the menial requirements. Samuel was the surviving child of five. Only  a few months the mother and son realised the comfort of being together; he also died, and the mother was left destitute.
            My father being aware of this, arrangements were made,
            and she was received at home, where her grief was soon
            dispelled by the continued employment she had allotted herself.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In appearance, she will stand for time immemorial, unique.
            She was tall, far above the usual height of women, and
            muscular, as though she had practised gymnastic exercises all
            her life; undeniably belonging to the “locomotive order.”
            Her eyes were large, pale blue, and protruding. Hair of the
            peculiar dapple grey I have always given in my fancy to
            witches, parted smoothly on her yellow seamed forehead,
            and adorned by a snowy white linen cap, with a border about
            four inches wide, standing erect around her face in bold defiance, looking as if the fashion of Queen Bess’ frill was revived again, and rebelliously mounted to encircle a face, instead of cautiously standing up in ready defence for the neck.
            Her gown was composed of that blue domestic spotted with
            white, which was at one time the usual working attire of
            people in her capacity, but now has entirely faded from
            sight, and almost recollection. Upon great occasions, this
            was thrown aside for a calamanco, she had “bought when
            dear George was a baby, and if he had lived, he would have
            been nine the day she left for this country,” and fixed in my
            memory, for seventeen years she was a moveable in our house,
            and still the rustling dress was presentable. The dress so far
            met with my approval, but her neck-gear was a dense mystery, and the cause of many a strange surmise. Winter and
            summer it was wrapt in a strip of red flannel, which was
            never laid aside, unless to be replaced by a similar piece,
            whilst the cast off underwent a washing, and was stretched
            on a little board for the noon-day sun to dry. Whether it
            was intended as a preventive against affections of the
            throat, or a slow cure, or perhaps a talisman, I never could
            ascertain; still, year in, and year out, the rubyish necklace
            obstinately obtruded on the eye. I never since have met with
            any one who was not accessible in some way : all the blandishments of childhood were used, pins, needles, threadcases, and even pinafores were purchased for her out of
            my pocket-money, in hopes of getting a little kindness in return. A portion of each Sunday evening, I left the family
            circle, and spent reading to Hannah, and never concluded
            the favor, without going over her choicest selection, “The
            order for the burial of the dead,” from, “ I am the resurrection
            and the life,” to the close, which always drew forth her most
            hearty “ amen.” Affection she had for none, except for an
            old black cat, that at night slept by her feel, and mewed at
            them through the day. In the animal creation, this was the
            only living thing that elicited her admiration. Black and
            sleek she was, without one white hair to redeem her in my
            estimation from the name of jet; but this was not the naming
            suited to her; she was called Blanche, after one of “my
            lord’s” accomplished danghters. The said cat, and a bundle
            of patches, comprised her earthly treasure; the latter she
            reverently looked over occasionally, and pointed out: “ this
            was dear John’s, this that blessed boy, Sammy’s, &amp;c.,” until
            she had shown a sample of the clothes once worn by each
            of her departed children.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Gratitude was held by her to be the crowning virtue,
            though it was never manifested in words or deeds of love,
            but cold, rigid justice ; “ ingratitude,” she would say, “is the
            blackest of crimes." “Yes, Hannah,” my brother Harry
            would playfully reply, “he that's ungrateful has no guilt
            but one; all other crimes may pass for virtues in him.” “ Oh !
            that poesy, Mister Harry, was made for the drawing-room,and folk what don’t like anything but what’s dressed up, but,
            for my part, I say in plain English, it’s no better than stealing.” Yet, with this unexceptionable sentiment, she was the
            most disagreeable person I ever encountered. Her very
            name, Hannah, was hateful to me.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If any of my schoolmates were so unfortunately called,
            they seldom knew any of my indulgence. I would not prompt
            them in a lesson, or assist with an exercise, and preferred to
            be alone to being escorted by Hannahs. When I studied
            Mythology, I wondered if Proserpine did not wear a red bandage around her neck as a mark of designation for the queen
             of hell. I sometimes thought she might be Lot’s wife come
            back to earth to atone for her disobedience; so rocky, so unwomanly was she.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>When I was about fourteen my mother laid before me
            several works she especially wished me to read. This I
            thought no hardship, (for I was fond of reading), until my
            eye fell upon “Life and Writings of Hannah More.” I was
            electrified, and quietly slipped the volumes back into the book
            case, ejaculating (wittily as I thought) “ pray, no more Hannah !”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In vain I urged her removal from the house, as a nuisance.
            Mother said she was an invaluable creature; my father pitied
            her loneliness, and Harry; the sharer of my joys and sorrows,
            liked to have her to plague and laugh at. Once, and only
            once, was she tenderly moved for one of us. I was ill,—a
            tear glistened in her eye as she hoped “ Miss Kate would not
            die, for who else would read to her.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Thus time sped on. My brother who was in the navy,
            and had been for nearly three years kept at southern stations, wrote to us. He had “at last concluded to light up
            the dreariness of life, and take to himself a wife.” He described the lady as highly intelligent, and quite pretty
            enough ; but did not give her name. However, I was delighted at the prospect of Harry’s future happiness, and pleased with the thought of having so companionable a person
            for my sister. The next letter dealt the blow,—she was called Hannah Fairfax. Fairfax contented me, but Hannah, oh
            horror ! how could I receive her without giving offence ?
            Impossible! I never could like her. Treat her as a sister ?
            No, no, the welcome she met with must come from others
            of the family, for Kate Rodney would be out of the way
            when another Hannah arrived. Thoughts like these ran
            through my silly head. I said little about the wedding, or
            our expected guest, but my nurtured prejudice was suspected, and spoken of by my fond mother, though she did not
            endeavor to dissuade me from it, but left it to the removal of
            time and reason. We were all on the stilts of expectation ;
            even myself, though I differed from the rest, for I lamented
            the pain I inevitably would cause my brother.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Night—a winter night again gathered us around the bright,
            peaceful hearth of home. My father was reading aloud,
            whilst my mother was webbing some fancy article for one
            of the gifts of love and welcome to the unknown comer. I,
            apparently was idle, but in reality busily engaged, far in a
            chaotic reverie of pleasure and disappointment; when it was
            broken in upon by the sound of stopping carriage wheels, and
            a well known voice in the hall told me Harry and the shock
            had arrived. I closed my eyes as he entered the parlor, but
            opened them, (for I had nerved myself) when I heard him
            say, “here dear father and mother is your daughter Hannah."
            My head reeled; a revolution had taken place. I thought he
            said “Heavenly,” and not “Hannah." Unconsciously I uttered,
            "Angelic !’’ for such was the being who was encircled in our
            mother’s arms. She was one of the most lovely I ever looked upon,—her soft hazel, beseeching eyes, asked for love,— 
            her forehead was low, but faultlessly white, and draped by j
            folds of the richest black hair Her form was a Houri’s.
            
         </p>
         <p>Daily this gentle being won upon me. She was the lovely moonlight to our summer home; every one loved her, indeed it was impossible not to. The bliss of her husband
            seemed entire, and I trembled lest it was too much for earth,
            and ere long would be interrupted. Wherever I went I
            wished Hannah with me. A party had not its complement
            of beauty if she was not there. A book read with but half
            the zest, if she did not peruse it with me ; in fact she had
            become an essential in my cup of happiness. Still her name
            was not wholly endurable, for a long time. I called her
            Annie. At last an event occurred which was to be the burial of my prejudice,—the birth of a daughter. It was determined the little stranger should be called Hannah,—the
            name of my sister’s mother, whose memory she cherished,
            with the sacredness of an affectionate daughter and sensitive
            woman. How dearly I loved this liny one ! Scarcely a cap
            could be found pretty enough for the velvety face, or socks
            soft as the dainty wee feet they were to enclose. This little
            love was another jewel to our diadem of happy home,—
            never were one and all more joyous.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Even old Hannah looked well pleased, and hobbled in to
            the christening, for she had two reasons for wishing to be
            there. “ Mr. Rodney had been even as kind as ' my lord,’
            and she had seen all his children christened,” (to witness the
            baptism of a grandchild was I presume a greater pleasure
            and compliment.) “Then Miss Kate, the baby’s name is
            just what I like.” For better than a year she had been unable to work, but imagined her control not yet at an end, and
            actually hastened the decline of years, grieving over the
            waste which must be during her absence; retaining only
            breath to utter her final amen as she beckoned me to her bed
            side, and pointed to the prayer book.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Poor Hannah ! that she had an annoying temper none can
            deny, but she practised virtues many do not even comprehend—justice and gratitude.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A miniature Babel is below stairs ;—the fourth anniversary
            of the birth of aunty’s pet; and she must join the little revellers in a game of “ hot butter blue beans” or “ blind man's
            buff”, twine a wreath for the evening's Queen, and help eat
            bon-bons. Oh the laughing ones ! lovely budding flowers,
            each possessing an imperishable germ. To be in such an
            assemblage of innocence and beauty, makes one feel very
            young again ; if time or care has impressed a furrow, it is
            hushed away for the present.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Reader, I can tarry with you no longer ; but thanks for listening to my story, and if you hold a similar dislike to a name
            because of a disagreeable person, then seek a lovelier association to render it musical, and believe me you can succeed.
            Our great will should not be kept subservient to prejudices.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">SONNET TO ZANTE.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Fair isle, that, from the fairest of all flowers,
            
            <br></br>Thy gentlest of all gentle names dost take !
            
            <br></br>How many memories of what radiant hours
            
            <br></br>At sight of thee and thine at once awake !
            
            <br></br>How many scenes of what departed bliss!
            
            <br></br>How many thoughts of what entombed hopes!
            
            <br></br>How many visions of a maiden that is
            
            <br></br>No more—uo more upon thy verdant slopes!
            
            <br></br>No more ! alus that magical sad sound
            
            <br></br>Transforming all! Thy charms shall please no more—
            
            <br></br>Thy memory no more! Accursed ground
            
            <br></br>Henceforth I bold thy flowcr-enamelled shore,
            
            <br></br>O hyacinthine isle ! O purple Zante !
            
            <br></br>“ Isola d'oro! Fior di Levante !"
            
         </div>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Antigone.
            
         </div>
         
         <p>I had been to see the Antigone of Sophocles not long
            since, and sate through the five acts and four choruses with
            mingled feelings of pleasure at the recollections of my schoolboy love for antiquity, which the scenes and action recalled,
            and of disappointment that the translation so feebly shadowed
            the nervous language and imagery of the most philosophical
            of tragedians. In fact, what Porson had said of Pope's Iliad,“ It is a very pretty
            poem, Mr. Pope, but you must not call it
            Homer,” seemed doubly applicable to the present instance.
            
         </p>
         <p>I had left the theatre in this mood, thinking only of what I
            had seen, not of what I had read, and at the door was addressed by Leslie, the Alcibiades of my acquaintance. He
            thus addressed me : “ Come to my room, most Athenian, for
            if I remember well, of all the band who walked with me
            in the Academic Grove of Cambridge, you were the most
            entirely Hellenic; come with me, and while I uncork some
            wine of Cyprus, (it must be my substitute for Chian), we will
            talk over the new Antigone and the old one, grow classical,
            as we sacrifice to Dionusos, and fancy ourselves beneath the
            shadow of the Hill of Mars, and inhaling the balmy air that
            sweeps over Old OEgea, Plataea and Salamis.” Though
            unused to revel “ late of nights,” the temptation was too
            strong to be resisted.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Leslie was domiciled in a quiet street not far from Hudson
            Park, a key to which he has, and often with him I sate, in
            the shadow of its trees, and discoursed of similar themes.
            On that night, however, we were in his library, in which was
            more than one cast from the great modern and ancient sculptors, and in which was found most that was valuable in the
            reveries of philosophers and delicious in the dreams of poets.
            Upon the table lay open a volume of Sophocles, with which
            he had been evidently occupied, previous to leaving for the theatre, to which I naturally turned while he occupied himself
            in bringing from an adjoining room, not a bottle, but a narrow
            necked vessel with a handle of twined serpents on each side,
            giving it a semblance to an ancient amphora, and two cyathoi, not glasses. In this, however, he was not strictly correct, and the vessel and cyathoi were evidently not Grecian
            but Etruscan or Pelasgican their shape. “I brought these,”
            said he, speaking to me, “ from Herculaneum, where I
            bribed the keepers, as Italians of modern times may always
            be bribed. I did it too with a safe conscience. I know not why
            the King of Naples should monopolize what must have been
            intended as a legacy to Posterity. The wine is a present
            from the Captain of the brig AEgeus, in which I came hither
            from Smyrna, in company with a midshipman, three Jews,
            and a cargo of tigs. But, fill up, and let us drink to the
            memory of the Athenian drama! After that we must determine whether one of the next cups shall not be to its Anaslasts."
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I had thrown myself upon a chaise longue, not unlike
            the couch of the classic ages, and resting my head upon a
            pillow which meetly might have supported Croesus in his
            prosperous days, began to sip from the cyathos the delicious
            wine, which reflected, in its purple depths, the delicate tracery of vine-leaves and grapes, with which it was overlaid.
            I know not how it was, but I remember that while Leslie
            spoke one of those glittering phrases which fall from his
            lips like drops of honey from Hybla, and whose subject was
            Alcibiades, I fell asleep. It may be that, inclined somewhat
            to the philosophy of the porch, the strong Cyprus had overcome my senses, and that I had poured too deep a libation
            to Bacchus.
         </p> 
         
         <p>Straight it seemed to me that Alcibiades entered, clad in
            the rich and spotless dress of his day, with the crimson buskin and Median train. Perfumes dripped from his waving
            hair, and many a jewel sparkled upon his marble fingers.
            Without more ado, he threw himself beside us, and filling
            from the amphora a beaker, with his fingers filliped a few
            drops upon an inkstand, fashioned in the shape of an ancient
            altar, murmured the word “ Dionuso,” and quaffed it down
            bocca aperta.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Your wine,” said he, “ is good ; I like most, however,
            the rich Italian and Ionian wines. That of Chios and Cyprus is too strong and heavy for me ; yet Salustius, a Roman,
            who, 450 Olympiads since, joined us enerthen, tells me that
            the wines of Falernum are thrice as strong as this. Anthony Hamilton tells me that those of Spain, and that grown in
            islands of which we had not very vivid ideas—our Islands
            of the Blest, are yet more potent; verily as the world grows
            older, your taste for excitement increases.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This remark astonished me, because, though, as the great
            master of the porch had taught, I believe in the identity and
            personality of the dead in Hades, I had no idea they lived so
            sociably as Alcibiades seemed to insinuate; at the lime, however, I did not speak of it, thinking, possibly, that it might
            not be polite to recall to a gentleman and a stranger that he
            was a subject of the Plutonian realm. I fancy that my
            distaste to this, was, in character, similar to the feeling a
            well-bred Englishman would entertain at asking an American the news from Pennsylvania. “ We drank,” continued
            he, “some tolerable wine, grown in the neighborhood of
            AEtna, last night, which was not unlike this, and, as we sat
            over our cups, I heard that a tragedy of old Sophocles’ was
            to be represented, and could not resist the temptation to visit
            anothen again. I was fond of Sophocles.”
         </p>
         <p>“ But,” said Leslie, “ I knew not that you gentlemen sha-
            dows often visited us.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“ We do not. It has been some years since I was up.—
            It was when a mad fellow named Bozzaris, near the field of
            old Plataea, fought with and conquered the Scythian horde,
            who now have possession of the soil of Hellas.”
         </p>
         <p>" Oh !” said I, “ you have heard of Bozzaris.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“Yes, a poetaster, a countryman of your own, named
            Drake, some four Olympiads since, joined us, and recited
            some glorious verses, which served as a fitting introduction
            for him to the whole population of Hades. Besides, some of
            us Greeks had previously heard of Bozzaris from countrymen
            of our own, who had died in the strife with the Scythians,
            (Turcomans you call them.)”
         </p>
         <p>“Well, the schoolmaster is abroad,” said Leslie, “he is
            even gone to the Devil.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“ I know not that word, or its precise meaning; some Ionians I have heard, speak of the Heiraoi ; they believe in a
            power antagonist to their God, whom they cal! Diabolos."
         </p>
         <p>“I assure you, Diabolos is here all potent, almost as the
            Hatui, of which your old tragedians spoke so much.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“ You have, then, more than one God. Count Anthony
            said you had but one. I did not, however, understand him,
            as I knew your Allan tides were not Epicureans, and men
            have loo many wants for one God to be able to attend them
            all.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Conversation then waned for a moment, while we more
            than once replenished our cyathoi from the amphora. It astonished me somewhat that Alcibiades did not respond to
            us while we drank his health, but, after a few moments, I
            remembered that was a custom derived from our northern
            progenitors. At length we began to speak of the subject
            matter, the Antigone, and Alcibiades remarked—
         </p>
         
         <p>“ As I sate last night in the Koilon, I was pleased to see
             that women sate in the lowest row, showing that the wives
            and daughters of the principal citizens sate with them to witness the play : verily the cool determination of Eurydice and
            of Antigone seemed to blanch their cheeks. Our fair Athe nians would not accompany us to such places:—true, Aspasia
            did so, but then, you know, she was differently situated. A
            rare woman was Aspasia.”
         </p>
         <p>“ Yes, we have heard of her.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“The music pleases me; in that you have made great
            improvements. You have adopted the brazen instruments
            of the Medes and the delicate Spartan flute. The Medea of
             Euripides would, from the joint accompaniment, have had a
            double effect. Even the Ocean Nymphs, and the Gossamer
            Spirits of the Air, who came to the crags of Caucasus to
            console the Prometheus Desmotes, would have found a music
            soft as their own voices.”
         </p>
         <p>“ What thought you then of the declamation ?”
            
         </p>
         <p>“What could I think? The Creon was not so good as
            Pratinas, or as other actors whom I have known, but he
            knew his part and felt it. The words of Sophocles, if the actor
            but feels them, cannot be marred. The Antigone and Euridice were played so well, they seemed to me women.
            Yet there were discords. I use that term to express things
            to which I am unused. The appurtenances of the tiring
            room seem to me incompatible. No Anax ever dressed as
            Creon did ; where was his sword? and Eurydice wore the
            crescent of a Priestess of Athena, not of a Grecian matron.
            The tragedy, however, may not be marred ; indeed old Thespis, in his wagon knew not, five hundred Olympiads ago, that
            his fame would pass into the Atlantis, of which Plato had
            not yet written. Your Bronteion, too, is strangely placed :
            the lightning is from Jove, but the thunder is of Saturn;
            yours was, I know not where, it seemed to pervade the
            whole house; but reach me yon amphora ! I will quaff a cup
            and make a libation to the Hatai: let us sacrifice to them and
            propitiate them.”
         </p>
         <p>“But our theatre is small.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“Ah, yes, the very Koilon is not so large as the mere
            Episkenion of our theatres, which were two stadia in breadth,
            and made to contain the whole population of Athens, while
            yours can only contain your wealthiest citizens, those of fortune. The slave at the door asked of me for admittance an
            Attic talent of gold at Athens the price was half an obolus.
             The great and useful scenes our drama portrays, should, too,
            be represented in the open air, not within walls. The marble columns and seats, the beauty of the caryatidae, and the
            severe and stern serenity of the works of the older sculptors,
            well befitted the severity of AEschylus, and the philosophy of
            Sophocles; for Euripides, another model of decoration might
            be adopted, but it would not be that of the Atrion where I
            saw the Antigone.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Reach me again yon amphora. The wine I have usually
             drank for the last 450 Olympiads, has grown near AEtna or
            Vesuvius, and has a sulphury twang, not so pleasant as
            this.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ One or two things,” said Leslie, “ I wish to ask you of
            the ancient drama—and the first is, who were the chorus,
            and where were they placed ? Had they part in the play ?"
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ The chorus were musicians, and as the science of harmony was not so far advanced as it is now, our instruments
            were fewer, and the greater part of their music was vocal;
            they had no part in the action of the play, except that they
            wore the costume of the age of the actors, and during the
            changing of the scene, spoke in explanations of allusions,
            with which the mass of the audience were not familiar.”
         </p> 
         
         <p>“Did your tragic actors wear masks?”
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Masks ? what are they ?”</p>
         
         <p>“ Coverings for the face, representing the passion supposed
            to characterize the personage they assumed.’’
         </p>
         
         <p>“ How could that be ? Creon even has his joy, and it must
            be expressed, the mask would destroy all expression.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Whence can we have derived the idea ?”</p>
         
         <p>“ Our actors painted, covering the whole face, often thick-
            ly enough, that possibly may explain the idea.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“ I do not,” said Leslie, “ see how it was possible for the
            human voice to reach over the vast extent of your theatres: 
            even our actors cannot always fill up the circumference of
            the buildings in which they perform ?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Ah,” said Alcibiades, “ we had various contrivances for
            the purpose of increasing the sound ; among other things, we 
            used echeea, or their various vases of brass, like to the Egyp- 
            tian tumpanon, by which the sound was prolonged, and sent 
            in reverberation to the very verge of the Koilon. These
            vases were placed upon pedestals, upon which they rested
            by the contact of but a single point. Over these echeea,
            which were interspersed through the building, seals were
            placed, lest the architectural beauty of the building should
            be marred by their presence. Your vaulted dome must be
            a great improvement, and a voice of ordinary capacity must,
            beneath it, be able to reach with distinctness every ear. At
            Athens, by the gesture alone, was the actor recognised, and
            that alone was necessary, for every Athenian knew the works
            of the great Tragedian, as you, doubtless, of your master
            pieces, and could easily supply any word which he did not
            hear.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ There were other differences which struck me, too ; they 
            are not, however, material. The curtain now falls from the
            roof of the building, on the stage : it was with us drawn up.
            Usually before the curtain rose, the chorus had taken their
            places, and the Coryphceus, the Aggelos, usually the first
            character, spoke the long introductory to the action. It often seemed to me to be regretted that our tragedians did not
            adopt some more artful manner of introducing the plot; the
            custom, however, of all tragedians, has permanently fixed
            the rule."
         </p>
         <p>“Did the chorus dance?”
            
         </p>
         <p>“Not generally; if, however, it was composed of females, it did dance. There was a place called orchestra, in our theatres; the word was handed down to us
            from the very days of Thespis, though its reason, long
            before, disappeared. The chorus usually clustered around
            their coryphoeus, who stood on the thumele, where was the
            altar."
         </p>
         <p>“ The music you have heard to-day, differs from that of
            your nation ?’’
            
         </p>
         <p>“Ah, yes ! ours was monotone, like a Sapphic stanza, finite and beautiful, not running, as yours does, infinitely through
            all the changes of Choric verse. Ah, you have much that
            we were ignorant of: mere music with us, was a womanly
            art, or rather, a slavish one: with you, however, a poet and
            philosopher may, without error, devote themselves to so glorious an accomplishment.”
         </p>
         <p>“ There is one thing more. I did not see you during the
            representation; yet, with your graceful and peculiar dress,
            I cannot well see how you escaped observation.”
            “ Up early enough, the Dianusiakoi Technitoi gave me a
            private box.”
            
         </p>
         <p>When I heard this, I remembered that I had seen the
            sleeve of a white robe, and a jewelled finger occasionally
            on the outside of the left balcony box! we then sate for
            for some time, and conversed together. Alcibiades saidsome prettinesses relative to our number, which was that
            of the Graces, and other similar things, with which I did not
            charge my memory, for, recurring to the days of the perfection of Grecian drama, I naturally used the system of
            mnemonics then in vogue, which I will remark, is not near
            so good as that of Professor Gouraud, whose lectures I have
            attended, and whose octavo I have read.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Alcibiades took hold again of the amphora : it was dry.
            While I thought Leslie moved to substitute for it another,
            I awoke, strangely enough; I was alone, except that my
            host slept soundly; the cyathos overturned, and the Cyprus
            wine streaming over his bosom. I went home, and began
            to write out this imaginary conversation, which I have just
            now finished.
         </p>	
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">FAY. ROBINSON</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Correspondence with a Governess.
            No. II.
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Dear Mrs. S——,</div>
            
            <p>I write to you, without an answer to my last. As I
               cannot return to my children at present, you must relate to
               me every thing about them. Please to send me an account
               of the state of James’ room, when he leaves it in the morning. He is not as yet so neat and considerate as I wish. I
               have no severity of feeling on such subjects : carelessness
               may exist with justice and kindness, and its demonstrations
               not only be inferior to, but in contrariety with the disposition.
               He is rather more short of his own ideal than some of the
               rest. I recommend to him for a motto,
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">  "Heaven loves the ideal which practises too.”</div>
            
            <p>This is a line of Leigh Hunt’s, which I read this morning.
               I have had great pleasure in turning over the new edition of
               his poems, just collected in a little volume, where, amidst
               too much that is vapid and grovelling, there is some of the
               finest of the fine, I find the story of Ben Adhem somewhat
               impaired.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab"> “ Write me as one that loves his fellow men,”</div>
            
            <div class="ab">for</div>
            
            <div class="ab">“ Ecrivez-moi en quality d’amie de ceux qui aiment Dieu,”</div>
            
            <div class="ab">is a less easy and natural transition.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">“ Captain Sword and Captain Pen” is very much to the
               
               <br></br>purpose.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“ Captain Sword,
               
               <br></br>...... forget the close thought, and the burning heart,
               
               <br></br>And prayers, and the mild moon hanging apart,
               
               <br></br>Which lifteth the seas with her gentle looks,
               
               <br></br>And growth, and death, and immortal books,
               
               <br></br>And the Infinite Wildness, the soul of souls,
               
               <br></br>Which layeth earth soft with her silver poles;
               
               <br></br>Which ruleth the stars and saith not a word;
               
               <br></br>Whose speed in the hair of no comet is heard ;
               
               <br></br>Which sendeth the soft sun, day by day,
               
               <br></br>Mighty, and genial, and just alway ;
               
               <br></br>Owning no difference, doing no wrong,
               
               <br></br>Loving the orbs and the least bird’s song ;
               
               <br></br>The great, sweet, warm angel with golden rod,
               
               <br></br>Bright with the smile of the distance of God.”
               
               <br></br>“ Indestructible souls among men
               
               <br></br>Were the souls of the line of Captain Pen ;
               
               <br></br>Sages, patriots, martyrs mild
               
               <br></br>Going to the stake, as child
               
               <br></br>Goeth with his prayer to bed:
               
               <br></br>Dungeon-beams from quenchless head ;
               
               <br></br>Poets making earth aware
               
               <br></br>Of its wealth in good and fair.”
            </div> 
            
            <p> Are not these capital passages? You will enter with all
               your heart into what he says about fishing, and “Izaak.”
               “ Bodryddan” is dearly beautiful: it makes the reader feel truly,
            </p>
            <div class="ab">	" That earth also is a star”</div>
            
            <div class="ab">worthy of her
               
            </div>  
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>" That sat retired in reverend chair,
               
               <br></br>Fading heavenward beauteously
               
               <br></br>In a long-drawn life of love.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">There have been many good words about clocks and bells,
               but these are memorable:—
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>" Lost on the roof, a clock’s old grace
               
               <br></br>Looked forth like some enchanted face
               
               <br></br>That never slept, but in the night
               
               <br></br>Dinted the air with thoughtful might
               
               <br></br>Of sudden tongue, which seemed to say,
               
               <br></br>‘ The stars are firm and hold their way ’ ”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">“An Angel in the House,” “Songs of the Flowers,” are
               
               <br></br>most choice. I thought I would have done with quoting, but
               
               <br></br>here are two lines describing martyrdom, which I must co-
               
               <br></br>py;—
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>" Now, now he gives the skies
               
               <br></br>The heart they gave (sweet thought 'gainst bitter wonders! )”
            </div>
            
            <p>There are some lines my fingers can scarcely resist, in
               “ To Kosciusko,” “ To the Author of Ion,” “Our Cottage,”
               “ Reflections of a Dead Body,” noble pieces. You will pick 
               them out.
            </p>
            
            <p>Part of the revelling in a book of value is its evocation of
               wonders that lie in the past. Hunt’s beautiful illustrations
               of the “ Divine Mildness,” recalled Milton’s description of our
               unconscious diurnal revolution:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br> “ Or she from west her silent course advance
               
               <br></br>With inoffensive pace, that spinning sleeps
               
               <br></br>On her soft axle, while she paces even,
               
               <br></br>And bears thee soft with the smooth air along.”
            </div>
            
            <p>The “ One that sat Retired” in “ Bodryddan,” brought to
               mind a beautiful passage in a lecture of Hudson’s—that on
               “All’s Well that Ends Well.” The Countess Rousillon is
               to him, as he said, one of Shakspeare’s choicest fancies. It
               has a hold on his affections, reminding him of an ancient
               gentlewoman, “who was his friend in childhood, whose
               head had blossomed for the grave, and her heart for heaven;
               one to whom, if he had anything good he owed it. She told
               me,” he said, “ the story of the Babes in the Wood, the Captivity of the Jews. I can never read of this Divine Countess
               without thinking of that heavenly old child.” At the closing
               words of this tender and beautiful sketch, a feeling burst of
               sympathy, delicately subdued, came from the audience.
               Gresset’s words were never more fit:—
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">  
               <br></br>Voir avec clairte,
               
               <br></br>Que l’homme n’est point fait pour la mechantete,
               
               <br></br>Consultez, ecoutez pour juges, pour oracles,
               
               <br></br>Les hommes rassembles ! voyez a nos spectacles,
               
               <br></br>Quand on peint quelque trait de candeur, de bonte,
               
               <br></br>Ou brille en tout son jour la tendre humanite,
               
               <br></br>Tous les coeurs son remplis d’une volupte pure,
               
               <br></br>Et c’est la qu’ on entend le cri de la nature.
            </div>
            
            <p>What a lovely phrase, “heavenly old child”! Hunt avoids
               both “ old lady” and “ old woman.”
            </p>
            
            <p>I am very glad you think with me as to walking in the
               fields with the children. I have heard you say, what is very
               just, “ how much more can be seen in a walk than a drive !”
               This excellent modem invention of gum-shoes enables the
               lady’s foot to reach the lovely marsh flowers. I have found
               lately improvement to all parts of my own nature from rambles in the woods and fields, and my attention has been
               turned more than ever to the beauty of flowers. I have been
               Steeped in poetry lately, turning over the American poets to
               enjoy the descriptions you allude to in one of your late letters. I am now sorry that my intended embellishments of
               wild flowers must leave behind the charm of their native
               haunts. These, may my children search annually all their
               lives! May every spring be to them, what it has been to
               me always a new spring ! May they see, time after time,
               what Bryant saw,
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“ When violets lean
               
               <br></br>O’er wandering brooks and things unseen,
               
               <br></br>Or columbines in purple drest.
               
               <br></br>Nod o’er the ground-bird’s hidden nest.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">with Emerson—</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br> “ Beneath dim aisles in odorous beds,
               
               <br></br>The slight Linnaea hangs its twin-born heads,
               
               <br></br>And bless the monument of the man of flowers,
               
               <br></br>Which breathes his sweet fame through the northern bowers.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">with Street,</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“ Where its long rings uncurls the fern,
               
               <br></br>The violet, nestling low,
               
               <br></br>Casts back the white lid of its urn,
               
               <br></br>Its purple streaks to show.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">May they share his feelings, when he exclaims,
               
            </div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“ Beautiful blossom ! first to rise
               
               <br></br>And smile beneath Spring’s wakening skies,
               
               <br></br>The courier of the band
               
               <br></br>Of coming flowers, what feelings sweet
               
               <br></br>Gush, as the silvery gem we meet
               
               <br></br>Upon its slender wand !
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Nor leave wandering for heat or cold, but see with Dana's
               eyes delicate shadows embellish the expanse of snow.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“ A lovely tracery
               
               <br></br>Of branch aud twig, that naked tree
               
               <br></br>Of shadows soft and dim has wove,
               
               <br></br>And spread so gently, that above
               
               <br></br>The pure white snow it seems to float
               
               <br></br>As if its darkening touch, through fear,
               
               <br></br>It held from thing so saintly dear”
            </div>
            
            <p>I was thanking you all the time for leading me this pleasant road. It puzzles me, by the way, how Bryant can compare the gentian for color to the blue sky, since the blue is a
               great deal darker; but I explain it by supposing he meant
               that which grows in New York and south, which is, according to Pursh, of a paler tint. Our gentiana crinita does not
               I think express serenity, which it would, if it was of the
               shade of the blue sky. Are you an observer of the expression of flowers ? Burns, I suppose, considered the fox-glove
               as expressive of dignity when he said,
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“ The stately fox-glove fair to see,”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">and in that line,</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“ Wee, modest, crimson tipped flower.”
            </div>
            
            <p>doubtless he thought the low stature and rosy hue of the
               daisy denoted blushing humility. To go back in imagination to June, the swamp honeysuckle seems to me the emblem of a beautiful country woman. I do not mean one unrefined or illiterate, but full of naivete and careless graces,
               like that one-sided flower, delighting the eye with its heaped
               up cups and innocent whiteness.
            </p>
            
            <p>The kalmialatifolia seems like a beautiful duchess elegantly dressed for a birthnight, yet with great precision, and with
               decorations very elaborate and angular.
            </p>
            
            <p>Those plants which have a peculiar regularity of form, as
               the galeum, and lysimachia quadrifolia, for instance, awaken
               devotional feelings, as the hand of the divine architect seems
               so obvious in their structure. A pinnate leaf has a voice.
            </p>
            
            <p>My brother has a patient now, (Mrs L.) whose recovery
               is retarded by excessively sombre religious views. I think
               it would have a tendency to cure her morbid fear of God, if
               in the proper season, she could wander in the fields as I do,
               and see the marmot eating grass, and then retreating to his
               subterraneous castle, and the caterpillar devouring in perfect
               peace the leaves of the milk-weed. If my brother’s unfortunate patient had seen the benevolence of God exercised to
               the animal creation, she would be very backward to conclude He could be otherwise than loving to human beings.
               You would say perhaps, why not turn her attention to the
               past blessings of her own lot ? But that might not have so
               great a tendency to cure her dejection, because she has alwas been too sickly to enjoy much.
            </p> 
            
            <p>Henry says he observed two of my brother’s spruces recently, and from having just read Harris’s book, he was induced to search them for the false caterpillar, which he
               found, and relieved the trees of seventy. Henry says
               that Harris, for extending his protection over the trees, deserves from the Dryads their fairest wreath. Pray suggest
               to James to examine our firs and pines.
            </p>
            
            <p>And now my dear friend, guardian of my children, I bring
               my long letter to an end with love to all.
            </p>
            <div class="ab">	E. M.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">August, 184-.
               Dear Mrs. M :—
            </div>
            <p>The letter of mine, which failed to reach
               you, chiefly concerned Mary’s accident, but as you had another of the same date equally particular, it is an unimportant loss. James, who you know is always overrunning with
               kindness to Mary, taxes his invention continually to amuse
               her in her tedious confinement. This month of the caterpillars, for the sake of the month of the butterflies, he has
               been looking up an old box and applying to me to furnish a
               gauze cover with a string. Then he set off to the china
               shop, where he procured a very little mug. This he filled
               with the leaves of the carrot, on which the caterpillars of the
               Asterias were feeding. The box was placed on Mary’s little
               table, where it forms one of her amusements. Besides these,
               he has introduced others, scanning every twig, and turning
               up all the leaves in the garden to add to the stock. As they
               are not very pretty creatures, in this stage of development,
               he brings Mary only the full grown, just in season to secure
               the fair sylph. Mary has a little book, in which she inserts
               the description of the larva, leaving the page opposite blank
               to receive the account of the creature in its perfect state. I
               like this process, independent of the recreation necessary in
               her present irksome condition. The habit of observation is
               formed, and what can be more salutary to the mind, more in
               harmony with itself, than to follow these divine processes?
               The remarkable developement of this tribe must, consciously or unconsciously, keep alive the idea of personal improvement. I think it one of the most luminous pages of
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">“ The book of God before (us) set.”</div>
            
            <p>Mary is asking me to give up the pen to her. She thinks
               she can fill up what remains of my sheet though unable to
               complete a whole one, which she is discontented not to do,
               when she writes to her mother, if she begins one. I give it
               to her, meaning to continue my letter.
            </p>
            
            <p>Dear Mother :—I long to see you, but that you know
               without my saying so, yet I love to write it. You do not
               know how kind James is to me. Yes, that you must guess
               at too. I hope I am improving, as I walk across the room
               with less difficulty every day. You recollect that bunch of
               the prettiest everlastings, that came up in the border last
               spring. James, you remember, wished to have it spared,
               as he says he likes even weeds, ever since he studied botany,
               but that ought not to be called a weed, should it ? James
               has been reading about all the gnaphaliums in North America, in Gray, and all over the world in Rees. He says he
               likes to know how many nations see the same flower. He
               complains very much of that Dr. Gray for making us wait so
               long for the rest of his book. But the everlasting, which I
               was going to tell you about; lately some caterpillars were
               found in webs on the top of the flowers. They ate the florets, and the white scales coming loose hid the webs. When
               they grew large James brought them to me for my box that
               Mrs. — says she has been telling you about. They are black
               with stripes round, of yellow lines, spiny, with white dots in
               pairs. Mrs. M. tells me the butterfly comes out, after hanging itself up, in about a fortnight, and is chiefly orange. I
               mean, dear mother, to send you a chrysalis. James says he
               has tried without success to rear the species you mentioned
               in your letter to him, but they are described in Harris, creeping and flying.
            </p>
            
            <p>James has brought me a little flower-pot, full of earth for
               those that go into the ground. When they seem to be roaming round and have left off eating, I put them on the top of
               the earth and cover the pot with a gauze ; they go in, and in
               ten days, I pour out the earth carefully, pick up the chrysalis,
               and lay it on some cotton wool in a box, to stay till next
               spring ; then the pot is ready for another.
            </p>
            <div class="ab">Yours, dearest mother,
               Mary M.
            </div>
            
            <p>I begin anew, dear Mrs. M., as Mary has not filled the
               sheet. James' room I visited, and will give you an exact
               account. First, the top bed clothes were not turned over the
               foot board as you direct—the window was open but a crack,
               clothes changed lay on the floor instead of being put in the
               clothes-bag. James had been walking on the beach to gather shells for Mary, and as he came home with his shoes
               full of sand, it was poured out on the carpet. The clothes
               that belonged in the wardrobe, were hanging, some over the
               foot-board of the bed, some were on chairs, shoes every-where, 
               the dressing-table——! I am glad you never wish me to find
               
            </p>
            <p>fault with your children, especially this most generous, kindhearted little fellow. I do not know but my affection is deep
               enough to pull down, as it certainly is to build up with true
               satisfaction ; but you are right in thinking the best and mostbeloved friend, is the most successful reformer. They will
               listen to you as Dante did to Beatrice.
            </p>
            
            <p>You will like to hear of Alfred's punctuality. I received the
               quarterly money at breakfast time, the first day of the month.
               Indeed I was so sure of his faithfulness, I had promised to pay
               a debt of Joseph’s that morning; so Joseph and I were much
               relieved. Joseph hoped I should make him a short visit, as
               soon as the children’s vocation was finished,but I tell him he
               must wait till you return.
            </p>
            
            <p>We went to see your friend Mrs. T. lately. She took us
                to the cemetery, which, in the newer parts, holds much I
               thought beautiful. One of the late enclosures within its
               hedge of thuga with its braided foliage, contained the trientalis, the uva ursi, various Solomon’s seals, the epigoea, the Mitchelle, pyrolas of different species, most of the beautiful pyrola maculata, enough of andromudas and elethias to make a
               a necessary shade for the forest flowers. One, still later
               planted, was enclosed with privet : how beautiful for such
               a purpose, with its pure, white pyramidal tops of flowers
               brightening its night of green ! Within, were many neottias,
               whose sculpture-like, marbled leaves and spikes of white,
               look so monumental. Here were all the lycopodiums, the
               Linnoea, the gnaphalium margaritaceum, and a great variety
               of ferns. In both, brilliant colors were avoided, and foreign
               flowers—one of the last I wished for, the white rose. Why
               have not we a while rose, but why should we have every
               thing ? One colored flower was there: the witch hazel, the
               autumn flower of whose leafless branches is almost as
               beautiful an illustration of the immortal creature as the butterfly. The monument in each of these enclosures was embellished by a beautiful design from Retsch’s Hamlet, one
               by the angel keeping watch at the gate of the omb, and the
               other by the Psyche striving heavenwards. With some want
               of good taste, a butterfly, extricating itself from the sheath,
               was carved on Capt. ——stone. James, who has been
               drawing a good deal lately, and become very dexterous,
               drew with his pencil upon the marble, a beetle emerging
                
               from the earth ; however, when his back was turned, I succeeded in effacing the lines. You once enlightened me on
               the falsity of contempt. I was always repelled by its ill-nature. In the morning, James had been, as you might expect
               from his sweet disposition, quite annoyed with B—— for
               eyeing affectedly, in an indolent way, through the ring of a
               whip he had in his hand, a negro girl who was passing, and
               after we got home, I tried to make out his case to be the
               same thing, thoughnot so obvious .Now, said I, that clumsy
               form was the temple of a soul, and glorified by it, as the
               meanest hovel is ennobled by having a bible in it. The captain did not look more unpromising, than the blunt, clumsy
               black chrysalis of the lonely luna-moth. Ah! my friend, you
               are no intellectual Swammerdamm!
            </p>
            <div class="ab">Dear lady, yours,
               N. S.
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Alfred Tennyson</div>
         
         <p>We do not know when we have seen in any American or
            British Journal an article we have so much admired, or one
            with whose opinions we have so thoroughly accorded, as
            with a late review, by Mr. Whipple, of Mr. Griswold’s
            “ Poets and Poetry of the Nineteenth Century.” The paper
            appeared in the last number of the whig Magazine. We
            extract some passages relating to Tennyson. They seem to
            us the very echo of thoughts which hitherto we have had an
            opportunity of expressing only in conversation. The injustice done in America to the magnificent genius of Tennyson
            is one of the worst sins for which the country has to answer.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of all the successors of Shelley, he possesses the most sureness of
            insight. He has a subtle mind, a keen, passionless vision. His
            poetry is characterized by intellectual intensity, as distinguished
            from the intensity of feeling. He watches his consciousness with
            a cautious and minute attention, to fix, and condense, and shape into form, the vague and mystical shadows of thought and feeling,
            which glide and flit across it. He listens to catch the lowest whisperings of the soul. His imagination broods over the spiritual and
            mystical elements of his being, with the most concentrated power.
            His eye rests firmly oif an object, until it changes from film into
            form. Some of his poems are forced into artistical shape, by the
            most patient and painful intellectual processes. His utmost
            strength is employed on those mysterious facts of consciousness,
            which form the staple of the dreams and reveries of others. His
            mind winds through the mystical labyrinths of thought and feeling,
            with every power awake, in action, and wrought up to the highest
            pitch of intensity. The most acute analysis is followed, step by
            step, by a suggestive imagination, which converts refined abstractions into pictures, or makes them audible to the soul through the
            most cunning combinations of sound. Everything that is done is
            the result of labor. There is hardly a stanza in his writings, but
            was introduced to serve some particular purpose, and could not be
            omitted without injury to the general effect. Every thing has meaning. Every idea was won in a fair conflict with darkness, or dissonance, or gloom. The simplicity, the barrenness of ornament, in
            some of his lines, are as much the result of contrivance as his most
            splendid images. With what labor, for instance, with what attentive watching of consciousness, must the following stanza have been
            wrought into shape:
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>“ All those sharp fancies, by down-lapsing thought
            
            <br></br>Stream’d onward, lost their edges, and did creep,
            
            <br></br>Roll’d on each other, rounded, smooth’d and brought
            
            <br></br>Into the gulfs of sleep.”
         </div>
         
         <p>This intense intellectual action is displayed in his delineations of
            nature and individual character, as well as in his subjective grossings into the refinements of his own consciousness. In describing
            scenery, his microscopic eye and marvellously delicate ear, are exercised to the utmost in detecting the minutest relations and most
            evanescent melodies of the objects before him, in order that his representation of it shall include everything which is important to its
            full perception. His pictures of English rural scenery, among the
            finest in the language, give the inner spirit as well as the outward
            form of the objects, and represent them, also, in their relation to
            the mind which is gazing on them ; but nothing is spontaneous; the
            whole is wrought out elaborately by patient skill. The picture in
            his mind is spread out before his detecting and dissecting intellect,
            to be transferred to words, only when it can be done with the most
            refined exactness, both as regards color, and form and melody. He
            takes into calculation the nature of his subject, and decides whether it shall be definitely expressed in images, or indefinitely
            through tone, or whether both modes shall be combined. His object is expression, in its true sense; to reproduce in other minds
            the imagination or feeling which lies in his own ; and he adopts the
            method which seems best calculated to effect it. He never will
            trust himself to the impulses of passion, even in describing passion.
            All emotion, whether turbulent or evanescent, is passed through
            his intellect, and curiously scanned. To write furiously, would to
            him appear as ridiculous, and as certainly productive of confusion,
            as to paint furiously, or carve furiously. We only appreciate his
            art, when we consider that many of his finest conceptions and most
            sculptural images, originally appeared in his consciousness as formless and mysterious emotions, having seemingly no symbols in nature or thought.
         </p>
         
         <p>If our position is correct, then most certainly nothing can be
            more incorrect than to call any poem of Tennyson’s unmeaning.
            Such a charge simply implies a lack in the critic’s mind, not in the
            poet’s. The latter always means something, in everything he
            writes; and the form which it is embodied is chosen with the most
            careful deliberation. It seems to us that the purely intellectual element in Tennyson’s poetry, has been overlooked, owing perhaps to
            the fragility of some of his figures and the dreariness of outline apparent in others. Many think him to be a mere rhapsodist, fertile
            in nothing but a kind of melodious empiricism. No opinion is
            more contradicted by the fact. Examine his poetry minutely, and
            the wonderful artistical finish becomes evident. There are few
            authors who will bear the probe of analysis better.
         </p>
         
         <p>The poetry of Tennyson is, moreover, replete with magnificent
            pictures, flushed with the finest hues of language, and speaking to
            the eye and the mind with the vividness of reality. We not only
            see the object, but feel the associations connected with it. His
            language is penetrated with imagination ; and the felicity of his
            epithets leaves nothing to desire. “ Godiva” is perfect as regards
            taste and the skill evinced in compelling the mind of the reader to
            sympathize with all the emotions of the piece. Like the generality
            of Tennyson’s poems, though short, it contains elements of interest
            capable of being expanded into a much larger space. But the poem
            which probably displays to the best advantage his variety of power,
            is “ The Gardener's Daughter.” It is flushed throughout with the
            most ethereal imagination, though the incidents and emotions come
            home to the common heart, and there is little appearance of elaboration in the style. It is bathed in beauty—perfect as a whole, and
            finished in the nicest details with consummate art. There is s seeming copiousness of expression with a real condensation; and the
            most minute threads of thought and feeling,—so refined as to be
            overlooked in a careless reading, yet all having relation to the general effect,—are woven into the texture of the style, with the most
            admirable felicity. “ Locksley Hall,” Aenone,” “ The May
            Queen,” “Ulysses,” “ The Lot s Eaters,” “ The Lady of Shalott.’’
            “ Marianna,” “ Dora,” " The Two Voices,” “ The Dream of Fair
            Women,” “ The Palace of Art,” all different, all representing a peculiar phase of nature or character, are still all characterized by the
            cunning workmanship of a master of expression, giving the most
            complete form to the objects which his keen vision perceives. The
            melody of verse, which distinguishes all, ranging from the deepest
            organ tones to that
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"> 
            <br></br>" Music which gentlier on the spirit lies,
            
            <br></br>Than tired eyelids upon tired eyes,”
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">is also of remarkable beauty, and wins and winds its way to the
            
            <br></br>very fountains of thought and feeling.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Young America.</div>
         
         <p>Regretting the necessity of employing a phrase which is
            not only borrowed, but redolent of affectation, we still have
            the most earnest sympathy in all the hopes, and the firmest
            faith in the capabilities of “ Young America.” We look upon
            its interests as our own, and shall uniformally uphold them in
            this Journal. What these interests are—what should be the
            aspirations of the new men of the country, and of the country
            through them in especial, it has been our intention to express
            fully in our own words, at the first convenient opportunity—but
            we have now lying before us an address which embodies all
            that there is any necessity for saying.
         </p>
         
         <p>We allude to a paper read by Mr. Cornelius Mathews
            at the late annual meeting of the Eucleian Society of the
            University of New York. We shall be pardoned for making
            some extracts:
         </p>
         
         <p>I do take it for granted, Gentlemen, that there are some new influences to be represented in Literature by the authors of this country. I am foolish enough to believe and insist that we are a province to no other country on the face of the world. I therefore, in 
            behalf of this young America of ours, insist on nationality and true
            Americanism in the books this country furnishes to itself and to the
            world : nationality in its purest, highest, broadest sense. Not such
            as is proclaimed in taverns, ranted of in Congress, or made the occasion of boasting and self-laudation on public anniversaries. It need
            not (though it may ) speak of the Revolution—nor Washington—nor
            the declaration of independence—nor Plymouth Rock—nor Bunker
            Hill, Nor Bunker Mill Monument. And yet it may be instinct with
            the life of the country, full of a hearty, spontaneous, genuine home
            feeling; relishing of the soil and of the spirit of the people. It will
            not be petty, I can assure you: in poetry, the echo of effete and
            by-gone English schools, nor in history, the re-production of French
            rhetoric, nor in humor, the popular authors of the time in another
            country. It will not, in a word, grow cross-eyed with straining its
            vision on models, three thousand miles away, while it makes a show
            of busying itself with a subject spread on the desk before it. If I
            read aright, the journals and periodicals of this country begin to
            indicate a weariness of the petty standards, by which they have
            been accustomed to measure and adjudge books of home production :
            to be dissatisfied with the mere elegance in writing which has been
            the prevailing demand and fashion of our literature. They feel that
            here is a giant speaking in a piping treble, and dancing a child’s
            hornpipe, to the universal contempt and mockery of the world.
            The writings of a great country should sound of the great voices
            of nature of which she is full. The march of a great people in
            literature should be majestic and assured as the action of their institution is calm and secure. The discovery begins to be made that
            the life of a young Continent is not to be represented, nor its heart
            moved, by tinkling rhymers and sketches with sparrow's quills. It
            is not necessary to enter, now, upon causes which have kept us in
            servitude so long to men not worthy of us; nor to show why it is
            that you may wander through whole bodies and collections of (so
            called) American literature, and find no word or verse worthy of the
            nation. The cause (allowing duly for the absence of great individual genius) must at least be general, which produces so constant
            and melancholy a uniformity of result. In the drama the people
            begin to exhibit a like weariness and aversion to the constant iteration and re-iteration of plays written for another people, another
            state of society, and to speak not unfairly, in many of the true elements of manhood and progress, far behind ourselves. That spirit
            which disdains defeat in war, in commerce or in science, cannot
            much longer rest content with an iguominious vassalage in literature. The mere growth of the country will burst the bonds, and
            leave it free to re-assume the vigorous step of a country yet in its
            prime. Here in New York, is the seat and strong hold of this
            young power : but, all over the land, day by day, new men are
            emerging into activity: who partake of these desires, who scorn
            and despise the past pettiness of the country, and who are ready to
            sustain any movement towards a better and nobler condition.
         </p>
         
         <p>They contend for home-writers, home-writings, and home criticism: and it is their belief that the world is yet to receive at the
            hands of the authors of America works which it will be willing to
            add to its catalogue of illustrious influences; to Homer and Dante,
            Shakapeare and Milton, and whoever else has laboured in the broad
            bold of human nature building on a base of sure good sense, and
            embracing in a catholic spirit all that is good and of good influence
            in all the world; drawing it home to their native land in a true nationality, and returning it again to the world that gave it to bless,
            and cheer, and purify all mankind. It is not a vain desire, I hope,
            that we may yet live to see the world waiting the steps of authors,
            of our own, watching the motions of their spirit, and hanging on the
            birth of their labors : as of men who make a part of their daily
            pleasure and happiness, as they do now of ours.
         </p>
         
         <p>And in art, shall we not have schools of our own ? Partaking of
            the climate, the rocks, the woodlands, the rivers and the human
            faces of our own country ? Chosen from what ever region of the
            world the subjects may he, will there not be something in the
            form and spirit, in the skill and kind of execution, to inform us that
            their origin is in the American heart and the American genius ? I
            Would not here, any more than in the writing of books, restrict the
            artist to parallels of latitude and longitude ; nor insist that his subjects be American, even in name. But what am I to think of a
            country whose very caricatures—the little pieces illustrative of the
            great national incident of the election of a President—are made up
            from the odds and ends of English designers : as though we were
            made thankful for the crumbs and ends of dry crust that drop from
            the table of a master and superior. A stranger visiting us might
            argue against our character, with almost irresistible success, from
            that single circumstance. A people whose mirth—in a question
            where all are ready to think for themselves, and laugh for themselves, one would suppose,—is the charity gift of foreigners. There
            is room and occasion—no more room, no better occasion, any
            where in the world—for a school of comic design, here in New
            York, which shall be truly national, characteristic, and eminently successful. I have not yet had the good fortune to encounter a single person capable of a respectable performance in this
            way although I am told there are such.
         </p>
         
         <p>In sculpture, and some departments of painting, we have already
            accomplished something in the true spirit of Young America, and
            the world is ready to acknowledge it. But in another province of
            art, that of engraving,, we have played the copyist and servant with a
            vengeance. For fifty years, at least, I take it, the whole force of
            engravers of the United States has been employed in the dilligent
            imitation and copying and re-production of worn-out and cast-off
            plates of France and England. There are a few examples of creditable effort annually ; but the eye for the long intervals between,
            is pained and wounded by the saddest parodies and extravaganzas,
            in steel, and copper, and wood. And in music are we never to have
            melodies that shall fix us with links, invisible, yet stronger than
            steel, to our native land; whose sounds swelling over the sea as
            we draw near, or chaunted in far lands, away from home, or sounding here at our own firesides, shall awaken in us every tender, and
            pleasing, remembrance of this dear country that is ours? You see
            the spirit of what I am attempting to enforce? The business of
            Young America in this regard, is then, as I understand it, to nourish,
            and encourage, and sustain, by a harmonious combination of all the
            true young influences, the manly young writers of the country:
         </p>
         
         <p>A Home Literature, national, vigorous, of the soil and the spirit
            of the people : and a popular press, ready to sustain it and itself, by
            showing that it is worthy to form the guide and the friend of the
            country, through which, and to which, it speaks ;
         </p>
         
         <p>National Drama, free of the conventionalities, abuses, and false
            usages of the stages of the old world ; a drama, which all Americans
            of all classes, without distinction of sect or party, may attend not
            only without wound or dishonor, but to be moved, and made proud
            and glad by pictures and appeals true to their own experience, and
            to that which they, as Americans, desire and long for;
         </p>
         
         <p>Schools of Art in Portraiture, Humor, History-Painting, Sculpture, Music, which shall grow like these out of the national spirit,
            elevating and enlivening our daily life : making mirth,and similitude,
            and enduring forms of that which we know to be true, and worthy,
            and our own.
         </p>
         
         <p>And to further these objects : to bring on their accomplishment
            speedily and happily, let me counsel perfect union and harmony
            among this young brotherhood ; let every writer and every man
            having an influence in art and literature, look upon his fellow-laborer as his brother. Let him insist that he shall be respected, and
            that his labor be worthily rewarded. Let such as are the auxiliaries of literature and art, be given to understand that the writer and
            the artist is something in the nature of a Principal in transactions
            relating to his craft, and that he will and must he dealt with as
            such. Let him demand his station among men, and let men know
            that, one of the ruling powers of the world, will not have his weapon of authority made, when out of actual service, a scourge for
            his degradation and overthrow.
         </p>
         
         <p>United, the authors and artists of America, the unelected, but selfsustained governors of a free people, will be the noblest body, the
            manliest phalanx that walks the earth ; at the head of a movement,
            to whose march the whole world will, ere long, be beating joyful
            time.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Wiley and Putnam s Library of Choice Reading. No. XIII.
               The Age of Elizabeth. By William Hazlitt.
            </div>
            
            <p>We cannot help regarding the thorough success of Wiley
               and Putnam’s Library of Choice Reading, as the harbinger
               of a better day for the interest of American Letters. It has
               at length been fairly shown, that not only our educated
               classes, but our public at large, will purchase, and have capacity to enjoy, a kind of books immeasurably superior, in all
               that renders a book valuable, to the species of literature
               with which we have been latterly deluged.
            </p>
            
            <p>The experiment of fine paper, well-sized type, and a tasteful form of getting up generally, has been attempted, and
               not in vain. The day of “cheap literature” is, we thank
               Heaven, happily over; and for this much-desired result it is
               difficult to say how much we are indebted, or rather how
               much we are not indebted, to the liberality and good judgment of Messrs. Wiley &amp; Putnam. To have failed in this
               enterprise would have been to throw us back for several years
               into the quagmire of the yellow-backed pamphleteering. Of
               course a great deal depended upon the tact with which books
               for the series were selected. There was a juste milieu to be
               attained—a happy medium between the stilted and jejune
               —between the ponderous and the ephemeral. Works were
               required of a piquancy to render them at once popular, (for
                
               the immediate and extensive sale of the Library was indispensible) and at the same time, of a gravity which would enable them to make their way as volumes not only sufficient
               ly well gotten up, but of a sufficiently standard character to
               warrant their preservation in our book-cases. This difficult
               task fell into the best hands; and the result has been one
               whose importance to the present interest of literature in
               America, can scarcely be overrated. Booksellers in this
               country have a trick of as implicitly following a good lead,
               as did les moutons de Panurge, and we fancy that we already perceive, in all quarters, a disposition to prosecute the
               good work of readable books, so auspiciously commenced.
            </p>
            
            <p>Perhaps the very best, although not the last volume, of the
               European series, is No. XIII—“ Lectures on the Dramatic
               Literature of the Age of Elizabeth, by William Hazlitt."
            </p>
            
            <p>It is indeed a rich work. We cannot, to be sure, agree
               with some of its author’s admirers, in calling him “ The best
               critic which England has produced in the nineteenth century,” for in almost every point, except the vivida vis of glowing fancy, we look upon him as the inferior of Macaulay—a
               man who, if he has not written the best criticisms ever penned, has at least shown the capacity to write them ;—but
               we would rank him next to Macaulay, and very far before
               Leigh Hunt, who was a dexterous but unanalytical, and somewhat confused prosodist—or Charles Lamb, who thought
               brilliantly, and never troubled himself with thinking if he
               thought to any purpose—or Wilson who always considered
               himself most honest when he was the fullest of prejudice,
               and who had cultivated rhodomontade into a passion. Of
               Jeffrey and Gifford we say nothing—for between these men
               and Hazlitt there are no points of approximation and they
               cannot be compared.
            </p>
            
            <p>The criticisms of the latter are, we think, his best compositions :—his best book is “The Age of Elizabeth.” Upon
               the whole he is singularly vivid, forceful, acute, discriminative, and suggestive. His honesty is wonderful in an age of
               dishonesty. His courage is very well as things go. His
               judgment is never for one moment to be depended upon in
               any connected or consecutive series of opinions. He is often
               profound—but his profundity is invariably detailed or particular.
            </p>
            
            <p>We quote a few highly characteristic passages from his
               disquisition on the Get man Drama :
            </p>
            
            <p>“ I have half trifled with this subject: and I believe I have done so
               because I despaired of finding language for some old rooted feelings
               I have about it, which a theory could never give nor can it take
               away. ‘ The Robbers’ was the first play I ever read : and the effect produced upon me was the greatest. It stunned me like a
               blow, and I have not recovered enough from it to describe how it
               was. There are impressions which neither time nor circumstances
               can efface. Were I to live much longer thau I have any chance of
               doing, the books which I rend when I wus young I can never forget. Twenty years have elapsed since I first read a translation of
               ‘ The Robbers,' but they have not blotted the impression from my
               mind : it is here still, an old dweller in the chambers of the brain.
               The scene in particular in which Moor looks through his tears at
               the evening sun from the mountain’s brow, and says in his despair,
               “ It was my wish like him to live, like him to die: it was au idle
               thought, a boy's conceit,' took last hold of my imagination, and that
               sun has to me never set! The last interview in ‘ Don Carlos' between the two lovers, in which the injured bride struggles to burst
               the prison-house of her destiny, in which her hopes and youth lie
               confined, and buried, as it were, alive, under the opposition of unspeakable anguish, I remember gave me a deep sense of suffering
               and a strong desire after good, which has haunted me ever since.
               I do not like Schiller’s late style so well. His ' Wallenstein,’
               which is admirably and almost literally translated by Mr. Coleridge, is stately, thoughtful, and imaginative: bnt where is the enthusiasm, the throbbing of hope and fear, the mortal struggle between the passions: as if all happiness or misery of a life were
               crowded into a moment, and the die was to be cast at that instant ?
               Gotzebue’s best work I read first in Cumberland's imitation of it in
               The Wheel of Fortune,’ and I confess that that style of sentiment
               which seems to make of life itself a long-drawn endless sigh, has
               something in it that pleases me, in spite of rules and criticism.
               Goethe's tragedies are (those that I have seen of them, his ' Count
               Edmont,' ‘ Stella, ’&amp;c.) constructed upon the second or diverted manner of the German stage, with a deliberate design to avoid all possible effect and interest, and this object is completely accomplished.
               He is however spoken of with enthusiasm almost amounting to
               idolatry by his countrymen, and those among ourselves who import
               heavy German criticism into this country in shallow, flat-bottomed
               unwieldy intellects. Madame de Stael speaks of one passage in
               his ‘ Iphigenia,’ where he introduces a fragment of an old song,
               which the Furies are supposed to sing to Tantalus in Hell, reproaching him with the times when he sat with the Gods at their golden
               tables, and with his after-crimes that hurled him from heaven, at
               which he turns his eyes from his children and hangs his head in
               mournful silence. This is the true sublime. Of all his works I
               I like his ' Werter' best, nor would I part with it at a venture, even
               for the ‘ Memoirs of Anastasius the Greek,’ whoever is the author;
               nor ever cease to think of the times, “ when in the fine summer
               evenings they saw the frank, noble-minded enthusiast coming up
               from the valley,” nor of “ the high grass that by the light of the
               departing sun waved in the breeze over his grave.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Orthophony: or Vocal Culture in Elocution ; a Manual of
               Elementary Exercises, adapted to Dr. Rush's “ Philosophy
               of the Human Voice," and designed as an Introduction to
               “ Russell's American Elocutionist."By James E. Murdoch. Instructor in Orthophony and Vocal Gymnastics;
               and William Russell, author of “ Lessons in Enunciation,"
               etc. With an Appendix containing directions for the cultivation of pure tone, by G. I. Webb, Professor in the Boston Academy of Music. Boston: William D. Ticknor &amp;
               Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ The design of the exercises presented in this manual,” say
               the authors in a well-written Preface, “ is to furnish the
               groundwork of practical elocution, and whatever explanations are needed for the training of the organs, and the cultivation of the voice.” We have looked through the work
               with great interest, and believe it to be the best American
               treatise on the subject discussed. There are some passages,
               (relating chiefly to metre), with which we totally disagree,
               and of which we may take an opportunity of speaking more
               fully hereafter—but in general the book appears to us remarkably accurate and valuable. The elocutionary abilities
               of Mr. Murdoch arc of a high order. We rejoice to learn
               that be is about returning to the stage.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A Dictionary of the English Language, containing the Pronunciation, Etymology, and Explanation of all words authorized by Eminent writers: to which are added a Vocabulary of the Roots of English words, and an Accented
               List of Greek, Latin and Scripture Proper Names. By
               Alexander Reid, A. M., rector of the Circus-Place School,
               Edinburgh ; author of" Rudiments of English Composition," etc. With an introduction by Henry Reed, Professor of English Literature in the University of Pennsylvania. New York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>This is a neat and valuable volume of about 500 pages duodecimo—fine type, but distinct. It comprises 40,000 words.
               Its Preface speaks of four material improvements. First,
               the primitive word is given, and then follow the immediate
               derivatives in alphabetical order, with the part of speech appended. Secondly, after the primitive words, is inserted the
               original term whence it is formed, with the name of the language from which it is derived. Thirdly, there is a vocabulary of the roots of English words, by which the accurate
               purport of them is discoverable—a very important improvement. Fourthly, there is an accented list of 15,000 Greek,
               Latin, and Scripture proper names. As a text book for
               schools the volume cannot fail of being useful. It is well
               recommended.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A History of the Protestant Episcopal Churches in the Cit
               of New York. By Henry M. Onderdonk. Embellished
               with a highly finished engraving of each Church, on steel 
               executed by different artists. New York. Henry M. On-
               derdonk &amp; Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>This beautiful work is published in the serial form. No V.
               is received, containing Trinity Church and St John’s. The
               engravings, and type, and paper are excellent, and the literary matter of value.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>Mrs. Mowatt, at Niblo’s, has been the great theatrical
            attraction of the week. She has been very successful, drew
            large and fashionable as well as intellectual audiences, and
            elicited boisterous applause, with much of a kind less equivocal.
         </p>
         
         <p>She has erred, we think, in making this arrangement—
            that is to say, she has somewhat injured the prestige of her
            name, first in appearing at a summer theatre, and secondly
            in appearing again at all after so brief an interval. Mrs.
            Mowatt owes it to herself to maintain a certain dignity ; and,
            although this certain dignity be preposterous, in fact in the
            fiction of the world's view it is all important. A lady so
            well-connected, and so well established in the public eye by
            her literary reputation, could have had no difficulty in coming
            upon the stage in her own fashion, and almost on her own
            terms. The Park, as the place of her debut, was, of course,
            unobjectionable, although in a negative sense. She lost no
            caste by coming out here, but the fact cannot be disputed
            that she would have gained much by first appearing in London, and presenting herself to her countrymen and countrywomen with the eclat of a foreign reputation. We say this,
            with a bitter sense of our national degradation, and subserviency to British opinion:—we say it, moreover, with a consciousness that Mrs. Mowatt should not have done this thing
            however much it would have furthered her interests.
         </p>
         
         <p>On another point she has beyond doubt acted unwisely.
            Mr. Crisp is in many respects an excellent actor, but he is by
            no means of that degree of eminence which we should have
            desired in the supporter of Mrs. Mowatt. With Mr. Forrest
            she would have had advantages which can never be afforded
            her by Mr. Crisp.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have no sympathies with the prejudices which would
            entirely have dissuaded Mrs. Mowatt from the stage. There
            is no cant more contemptible than that which habitually decries the theatrical profession—a profession which, in itself,
            embraces all that can elevate and ennoble, and absolutely
            nothing to degrade. If some—if many—or if even nearly all
            of its members are dissolute, this is an evil arising not from
            the profession itself, but from the unhappy circumstances
            which surround it. With these circumstances Mrs. Mowatt
            has, at present, no concern. With talents, enthusiasm, and
            energy, she will both honor the stage and derive from it honor. In the mere name of actress she can surely find nothing
            to dread—nothing, or she would be unworthy of the profession—not the profession unworthy her. The theatre is ennobled by its high facilities for the development of genius—
            facilities not afforded elsewhere in equal degree. By the
            spirit of genius, we say, it is ennobled—it is sanctified—beyond the sneer of the foul or the cant of the hypocrite. The
            actor of talent is poor at heart indeed, if he do not look with
            contempt upon the mediocrity even of a king. The writer
            of this article is himself the son of an actress—has invariably
            made it his boast—and no earl was ever prouder of his earldom than he of his descent from a woman who, although
            well-born, hesitated not to consecrate to the drama her brief
            career of genius and of beauty.
         </p>
         
         <p>At Niblo’s, as at the Park, Mrs. Mowatt made her first appearance as Pauline, in “The Lady of Lyons;” and this is the
            only character she has yet sustained. On the play itself we
            have lately seen some strictures which seem to us unjust.
            We regard it as one of the most successful dramatic efforts of
            modern times. It is popular, and justly so. It could not
             fail to be popular so long as the people have a heart. It
            abounds with sentiments which stir the soul as the sound of
            a trumpet. It proceeds rapidly, and consequentially : the
            interest not for one moment being permitted to flag. Its incidents are admirably conceived, and wrought into execution
            with great skill. Its dramatis personae throughout, have the
            high merit of being natural, although, except in the case of
            Pauline, there is no marked individuality. She is a creation
            which would have done no dishonor to Shakspeare—and she
            excites in us the most profound emotion. It has been sillily
            objected to her that she is weak, mercenary, and at points
            ignoble. She is—and what then? We are not dealing with
            Clarissa Harlowe. Bulwer wished to paint a woman, and
            has done so. The principal defect of the play lies in the heroine’s consenting to wed Beauseant, while aware of the existence and even of the continued love of Claude. As the plot
            runs, there is a question in Pauline’s soul between a comparatively trivial, because mere worldly, injury to her father,
            and utter ruin and despair inflicted upon her husband. Here
            there should have been not an instant’s hesitation. The audience have no sympathy with any. Nothing on earth should
            have induced the wife to give up the living Melnotte. Only
            the assurance of his death could have justified her in sacrificing herself to Beauseant. As it is we hate her for the
            sacrifice. The effect is repulsive—at war with the whole
            genius of the play.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of Mrs. Mowatt, and of her acting, we have to speak only in terms of enthusiastic admiration. We have never had
            the pleasure of seeing her before—and we presume that there
            are many of our readers who have never seen her. Her
            figure is slight—even fragile—but eminently graceful. Her
            face is a remarkably fine one, and of that precise character
            best adapted to the stage. The forehead is the least prepossessing feature, although it is by no means an unintellectual
            one. The eyes are grey, brilliant, and expressive, without
            being full. The nose is well formed, with the Roman
            curve, and strongly indicative of energy ; this quality is also
            shown in the prominence of the chin. The mouth is somewhat large, with brilliant and even teeth, and flexible lips,
            capable of the most effective variations of expression. A
            more radiantly beautiful smile we never remember having
            seen. Mrs. Mowatt has also the personal advantage of a
            profusion of rich auburn hair.
         </p>
         
         <p>Her manner on the stage is distinguished by an ease and
            self-possession which would do credit to a veteran. Her
            step is very graceful and assured—indeed all her movements
            evince the practised elocutionist. We watched her with the
            closest scrutiny throughout the whole play, and not for one
            instant did we observe her in an attitude of the least awkwardness, or even constraint, while many of her seemingly
            impulsive gestures spoke in loud terms of the woman of genius—of the poet deeply imbued with the truest sentiment of
            the beauty of motion.
         </p>
         
         <p>Her voice is rich and voluminous, and although by no
            means powerful, is so well managed as to seem so. Her utterance is singularly distinct—its sole blemish being an occasional Anglicism of accent, adopted probably from her instructor. Her reading could scarcely be improved. In this
            respect no actress in America is her equal—for she reads not
            theatrically, but with the emphasis of Nature. Indeed the
            great charm of the whole acting of Mrs. Mowatt is its natu 
            ralness. She moves, looks, and speaks with a well-controlled impulsiveness as can be conceived from the customary
            rant and cant—the hack conventionality of the stage. If she
            does not suffer herself to be badgered out of this good path
            it will lead her inevitably to the highest distinction—a very
            proud triumph will assuredly be hers.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Crisp makes a respectable Melnotte, but little more.
            His action and general manner in this part, are not we think,
            sufficiently calm. Claude is not so much impetuous and impulsive, as the man of profound passions and deliberate purposes. Where he takes the character of the Prince Mr.
            Crisp very improperly makes him assume the coxcombical
            airs of the Count in “ Fashion.” He should be made to
            sneer—but no more. His true dignity should never be left
            out of sight. In light comedy Mr. Crisp is, indeed, a very
            admirable actor.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the Park, the French troupe have been very successful,
            and have unquestionably deserved success.
         </p>
         
         <p>At Castle Garden, the chief attraction has been the admir- j
            able dancing of Mademoiselle Desjardins. Since Elisler we
            have had no one more graceful.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Chatam Street and the New Bowery are both, we believe doing well. At the latter, Mrs. Flynn (an excellent
            actress) has been winning new laurels in such pieces as
            “ Perfection” and “ The Four Sisters.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Flynn’s new theatre at Richmond Hill will be opened
            in a few weeks. It will be large and airy, accommodating a
            more numerous audience, perhaps, than did the Old Bowery.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div>          
         
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">An Apology for Church Music and Musical Festivals, by
               Edward Hodges, Mus. Doct. of Sidney Sussex College.
               Cambridge.
            </div>
            
            <p>The subject of the remarks which we propose to present
               to our readers, is one of paramount importance to the professors, and to the cause of music. There is ever a host of enemies ready to fall open-mouthed upon music and upon all relating to it, and more particularly is church music open to
               bitter and bigoted persecution, from men of all sects, more
               especially among the clergymen. Some of them probably
               are wroth at being compelled to shorten their sermons, in
               consequence of music lengthening the service; others, perfectly conscious of the eloquence and beauty of their discourses, feel afraid that the music should draw off some of
               the admiration due to them. There are also, doubtless, some
               who conscientiously believe music an ungodly science, because sinners and other profane people sing and play, and
               others who think that the money paid to singers and organists could be used to much better advantage if placed at their,
               disposal. But we will leave to Dr. Hodges the defence of;
               church Music, being perfectly satisfied that there is no other
               man in this country so fully capable of handling the subject.
            </p>
            
            <p>The remarks, of which we give a portion this week, were
               furnished us by the kindness of the author, and were written
               by him some years since, in answer to certain papers in
               which the propriety of refusing to allow the performance of
               the London Grand Musical Festival, to take place in Westminster Abbey, was powerfully argued.
            </p>
            
            <p>How ably and triumphantly Dr. Hodges advocated the
               cause of church music will be seen in our future numbers.
               
            </p>
            <p>We shall give the remarks nearly entire, for we are sure
               that the elegance and force of the writer's style, the unanswerable truth of the arguments he advances, and the great
               authorities he quotes in his support, will prove all sufficient,
               to recommend the papers to the earnest attention of cur rea-
               ders.
               
            </p>
            <p>There is no science, human or divine, of such universal aceptation among mankind, as that no man can be found to impugn its
               pretensions. In this age of subversion, therefore, wherein all religion is denounced as priestcraft, and civil government as tyranny, we
                are not to wonder that music also should have its adversaries. And
                yet, if in the whole range of human contemplation, there be any
                one thing which would seem less likely than all others to stir up
               strife and contention, that subject is the science of sweet sounds.
               Man, in all ages, from the infancy of the world to the present day,
               has recognized its power, and bowed to its influence. In every
               clime from the frigid regions about the poles, to the burning plains
               of the torrid zone, music has been appealed to as the laborum dulce
               lenimen, the joy of buoyant youth, the solace of declining age.
               Practised by saints and angels, lauded by sage philosophers, encour aged by grave legislators, and sanctioned not only by the usage of
               time but by almost an identification with the most solemn offices
                of our most holy religien, it has come down to us to be aspersed and
               vilified in this our day as a pursuit utterly unworthy of an intellectual being, and in its noblest exhibitions to be stigmatized as a profanation of our ecclesiastical edifices.
            </p>
            
            <p>Now although nothing has been recently alleged against church
               music, which has not been adduced and triumphantly refuted, again
               and again, in past times ; yet forasmuch as it is possible that some
                persons may be carried away by the specious plausibility with
               which old sophistries have been tricked out, I have thought it not
               amiss, in the absence of a better champion, to attempt a brief reply
                to what modern gainsayers continue so pertinaciously to advance.
               This is the more necessary inasmuch as the opposition at present is
               principally conducted by two most respectable public prints, viz.
               the Standard, which may be considered as the organ of the highchurch section of Toryism, and the Record, which may with equal
               truth be deemed the representative of the opinions of the so-called
               Evangelical party in the establishment. Had the “ railing accusation’’ been confined to that portion of the public press which trades
               in sedition and revels in the imaginary perspective of the progressive destruction of all our venerable institutions, civil as well as sacred, the reproach might have been borne with honor, and suffered
               to pass unheeded as the idle snail which leaves its slimy track upon
               the village steeple. Every Christian musician [and I trust there
               are many such] feels on the occasion with David, the man after
                God’s own heart, and yet the most musical king the world ever
               saw, when he bemoans himself in Psalm LV., “ For it was not an
               enemy that reproached me, then I could have borne it; neither
                was it he that hated me, that did magnify himself against me, then
               I would have hid myself from him:" a psalm appropriately address ed “ To the chief musician on Neginoth.” Still I should not have
                had recourse to this method of defending the science which I have
                the honor to profess, had not the editor of the Standard refused to
                insert a short communication which I addressed him in reply to some
               of his animadversions; contenting himself in his notice to correspondents with calling me “an enthusiast,” and informing the public that “ he could not accommodate his conscience to he the means
               of disseminating opinions which he believed to be erroneous,”
               although the latter referred to consisted principally of a statement
               of facts. Although this conduct of the editor would seem to be a
               departure from that straightforward rule of rectitude which I would
               fain believe has been and is generally his actuating principle, I can
               not be very angry with him on the occasion, as it has afforded me
               an opportunity of throwing into a more permanent shape the few
               arguments which I hope shortly to bring forward.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Standard from time to time, for many months last past, has
               dropped hints of its antipathy to music. At length it began to speak
               more distinctly, and under date of the 26th March has a passage of
               this sort:
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Sensuality of every kind, feasts and festivals, whether culinary or musical, for both are alike sensual, ought to be forever excluded from the seats of
               learning and religion.”
            </p>
            
            <p>"If the Bishop thinks with us, that the propriety of employing a Church
               as a place of sensual recreation, or as a place lor the collection of money, received in consideration of enjoyment of any kind ; if the Bishop thinks with
               us that the propriety of such an employment of a Church is at best doubtful,
               it is surely not merely his right, but his duty to avoid taking part in the approaching festival.”
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Our views are altogether practical. Leaving out of view, for the present,
               the higher question, whether the application to seculur uses of things usually
               devoted to the uses of religion be directly sinful or otherwise, we are quite
               sure that it is, consequentially, injurious to the interests of the Church that
               permits it.”
            </p>
            
            <p>“ It is almost an instinct, or if it he not an instinct, it must be amongst the
               earliest truths that open to the mind, which teaches that the things of this
               world cannot he permitted to intrude upon the considerations of the next, and
               the services which these last enjoin, without detriment to the purity of religious feeling. Nor must we lose sight of the fact, that at the present the
               Church of England is, in the strictest sense of the word a Church militant;
               that she is beset with enemies, by no means scrupulous in their warfure—with
               enemies who could easily enough convert a muster of singers and fiddlers in
               one of her principal temples, with an apparatus of check-takers and doorkeepers to collect money for hearing these singers and fiddlers, into a very opprobitious similitude of a theatrical representation; and, unquestionably, they
               who would so represent a musical festival in a cathedral, would find ready
               hearers amongst the nonmusical part of the world, that is, among nineteentwentieths of the populalion, including ourselves in the unhappy majority. 
               It is very true, there are those who think that music may be made subservient
               to the cultivation of religion; but it is a doleful truth that there are also
               those, we are persuaded the great majority, if they dare confess it, who feel
               eaen the very small infusion of music usually permitted in our liturgical service,
               an obstruction, rather than an aid to their religious contemplations.	The truth
            </p>
            <p></p>
            <p>of the matter is, the musical faculty not indigenous to our soil. We must
               not fall into the common mistake, that a love of songs is a taste for music,
               even were we a singing people, which we are not. It is merely the gratification which arises from the combination of variety with regularity, as expressed in sounds, the same which we see exhibited in dancing, which adds to
               whatever pleasure is afforded by the words of a song,—but we must not get
               into a metaphysical treatise. Suffice it to say, that as the uninitiated in music do not go to musical festivals for the sake of devotion, so it may reasonably be doubted. that many who do go to such festivals may be classed with
               those who go to church
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">‘ To hear the music there ;'</div>
            
            <p> and that many more deceive themselves into the notion that their feelings
               are religious, when they are little better than animal sensuality.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The National Academy of Design</div> 
            <p>has presented to the
               treasurer, Thomas S. Cummings, Esq., service of plate, in
               token of approbation of his services. Mr. Cummings is now
               treasurer of the Academy, and has been so for some twenty 
               years, having been that number of limes unanimously elected to the office.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">To Correspondents.</div>
            <p>—Many thanks to the author of the Corre-
               spondence with a Governess—also to F. M.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
            Published monthly, at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            THE MESSENGER has been established since
            1835, has a large subscription list, and is the principal organ of
            Southern opinion.
            Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the “Broad-
            way Journal,” 135 Nassau streeet.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">JUST PUBLISHED,
            WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'S
            LIBRARY OF AMERICAN BOOKS.
            I.
            JOURNAL OF AN AFRICAN CRUISER.
            Journal of an African Cruiser ; comprising Sketches of the Ca-
            
            <br></br>naries, the Cape de Verdes, Liberia, Maderia, Sierra Leone, and
            
            <br></br>other places of interest on the West Coast of Africa. By an Officer
            
            <br></br>of the U. S. Navy. Edited by Nathaniel Hawthorne. 50 cents.II.
            POE’S TALES.
            Tales. By Edgar A. Poe. 50 Cents.
            This excellent collection will include the most characteristic of the
            
            <br></br>peculiar series of Tales written by Mr. Poe. Among others will be
            
            <br></br>found " The Murders of the Rue Morgue,” " The Purloined Letter,”
            
            <br></br>" Marie Roget,” " The House of Usher,” " William Wilson,” " The
            
            <br></br>Gold Bug,” “ The Descent into the Maelstrom,” “ The Premature
            
            <br></br>Burial,” Mesmeric Revelations,” &amp;c.&amp;c.III.
            LETTERS FROM ITALY.
            By J.T. Headley. 50 cts.
            Contents.—Voyage to Italy—Man Lost Overboard; Gibraltar—Ap-
            
            <br></br>proach to Geneva ; First impressions—Lunatics; Description of Ge-
            
            <br></br>noa; House Hunting—Romantic Marriage; Funeral in the Morning-
            
            <br></br>Murder of an American Officer; Carnival—Clara Novella—Persecu-
            
            <br></br>tion of a Painter ; Columbus’s Manuscripts—Horseback Ride—Death
            
            <br></br>in the Theatre ; a Day’s Ramble through Genoa ; Italian Soirees and
            
            <br></br>Beauty—Marquis of Palavicini, &amp;c., &amp;c. Published and for sale by WILEY &amp; PUTNAM,
            161 Broadway.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
            
            <br></br>(formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway,
            
            <br></br>will keep a complete assortment of the largest approved Grand Action
            
            <br></br>Piano Fortes, of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
            
            <br></br>guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish.
            
            <br></br>and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard
            
            <br></br>prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on
            
            <br></br>hire.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">JOHN DOUGLAS,
            
            <br></br>BOOK AND JOB PRINTER.
            
            <br></br>106 FULTON STREET.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">INTERESTING WORKS
            
            <br></br>JUST PUBLISHED BY
            
            <br></br>HARPER &amp; BROTHERS, NEW-YORK.
            
            <br></br>THE NEW REFORMATION.
            
            <br></br>Now ready, with curious Illustrative Plate, price 25 cents, or Muslin,
            
            <br></br>37 1-2 cents.
            
            <br></br>JOHN RONGE,
            
            <br></br>THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES,
            
            <br></br>AND THE NEW GER. CATHOLIC CHURCH.
            
            <br></br>Including authentic details of the events connected with the recent
            
            <br></br>exhibition of the pretended " Coat of our Lord ” in the Cathedral of
            
            <br></br>Treves, during the months of August and September, 1844 : compris-
            
            <br></br>ing the letters and protestations of the author against the imposition
            
            <br></br>and superstitions of the Roman Catholic priests, &amp;c.
            
            <br></br>This publication is exceedingly opportune; it will be perused with
            
            <br></br>deep interest by the Protestant community at large.—Commercial Ad-
            
            <br></br>vertiser.
            
            <br></br>The noble protest of Ronge has been circulated in Germany, not by
            
            <br></br>thousands, but by millions of copies ; and it has been hailed with loud
            
            <br></br>applause by all classes, because it expeesses a public sentiment, and
            
            <br></br>finds a response in all hearts.—New York Observer.
            
            <br></br>PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES.
            
            <br></br>In one volume, 12mo., beautifully printed, price 75 cts.
            
            <br></br>A PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES,
            
            <br></br>THROUGH THE VALLEY OF THE MEUSE, AND THE FOREST OF
            
            <br></br>ARDENNES.
            
            <br></br>BY CHARLES EDWARD ANTHON, Esq.
            
            <br></br>This is the production of a young American, who had the rare for-
            
            <br></br>tune to be present at the most marvellous occurrence of the 19th cen-
            
            <br></br>tury—the exhibition of the Holy Robe. In addition to a very graphic
            
            <br></br>description of this extraordinary event, which, from the excitement it
            
            <br></br>has created, seems destined to be an era in the Christian Church, this
            
            <br></br>unpretending volume is replete with antiquarian lore, relating to the
            
            <br></br>city of Charlemagne, from which the " Pilgrimage ” commences—
            
            <br></br>the intermediate historic and poetic ground ; and of the once renowned
            
            <br></br>city of Treves, with which it closes. It is the work of a scholar, and
            
            <br></br>cannot fail to enlist a profound interest.—Oswego Advertiser.
            
            <br></br>MR. PRESCOTT’S HISTORICAL WORKS.
            
            <br></br>In 3 volumes 8vo, beautifully printed and accompanied with fine En-
            
            <br></br>gravings.
            
            <br></br>HISTORY OF
            
            <br></br>THE CONQUEST OF MEXICO
            
            <br></br>WITH A LIFE OF THE CONQUERER, HERNANDO CORTES,
            
            <br></br>AND A VIEW OF ANCIENT MEXICAN CIVILIZATION.
            
            <br></br>BY WILLIAM H. PRESCOTT, Esq.
            
            <br></br>Mr. Prescott appears to possess almost every qualification for his
            
            <br></br>task; he has a pure, simple, and eloquent style—a keen relish for the
            
            <br></br>picturesque—a quick and discerning judgment of character, and a calm,
            
            <br></br>generous and enlightened spirit of philanthropy, There is no exag-
            
            <br></br>geration in stating that his Conquest of Mexico” contains most of the
            
            <br></br>valuable qualities which distingush the most popular historical writers
            
            <br></br>in our language of the present day. It unites the chivalrous but truth-
            
            <br></br>ful enthusiasm of Col. Napier, and the vivacity of the accomplished
            
            <br></br>author of the " Siege of Granada,” with the patient and ample research
            
            <br></br>of Mr. Tytler.—Edinburgh Review, May, 1845.
            
            <br></br>In 3 volumes 8vo, uniform with the above, with Portraits and Maps.
            
            <br></br>HISTORY OF THE
            
            <br></br>REIGN OF FERDINAND AND ISBAELLA,
            
            <br></br>THE CATHOLIC.
            
            <br></br>BY WILLIAM H. PRESCOTT, Esq.
            
            <br></br>The Tenth Edition.
            
            <br></br>It would be altogether supererogatory to make this celebrated work
            
            <br></br>the subject of critical analysis, since it has so long been distinguished
            
            <br></br>by the concurrent and enthusiastic applause of the whole reading com-
            
            <br></br>munity. We know of scarcely any other work so amusing, instruc-
            
            <br></br>tive, and powerfully attractive as the “ History of Ferdinand and Isa-
            
            <br></br>bella ;” it possesses every charm which elegance of diction, graceful-
            
            <br></br>ness of style, and interest of subject can impart. In a word, it is such
            
            <br></br>a production as could only have emanated from a mind richly stored
            
            <br></br>with the wealth of sound learning, genius, and the felicitous art of its
            
            <br></br>application.—-N. Y. Review.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. —A. H. GALE &amp; CO.s Ware-
            
            <br></br>Rooms, No. 289 Broadway — Manufactory Third Avenue, corner
            
            <br></br>of 13th Street.
            
            <br></br>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assort-
            
            <br></br>ment of Rosewood and Mahogany Piano Fortes, with from six to
            
            <br></br>seven octaves, embracing every variety of patterns, made in their well-
            
            <br></br>known substantial manner, under their immediate and personal super-
            
            <br></br>intendence, by skillful and experienced mechanics, from the best sea-
            
            <br></br>soned materials.
            
            <br></br>These instruments embrance many important improvements, which
            
            <br></br>will recommend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of
            
            <br></br>perfection, with the best French grand action, warranted in every re
            
            <br></br>spect by the manufacturer.
         </div>
      </div>
       
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">A CARD.
            
            <br></br>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANO-
            
            <br></br>forte, ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street,
            
            <br></br>where his terms lor giving instruction can be ascertained. myl7
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER.—JAMES
            
            <br></br>PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near Elm. A
            
            <br></br>Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms mode-
            
            <br></br>rate. FOR SALE—A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a
            
            <br></br>great bargain for cash.
         </div>	
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
            
            <br></br>Street, N. Y.		
            
            <br></br>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
            
            <br></br>Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made
            
            <br></br>from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful
            
            <br></br>workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the busines.
            
            <br></br>N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ.
            
            <br></br>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
            
            <br></br>Mundy &amp; Pethick.) invites the attention of the musical public to
            
            <br></br>the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establish-
            
            <br></br>ment, corner of Cottage Place and Bleecker street, which he will sell
            
            <br></br>at prices unusually low.
            
            <br></br>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twen-
            
            <br></br>ty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two
            
            <br></br>of the largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that
            
            <br></br>his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the
            
            <br></br>best makers in this country or Europe, and that they contain all the
            
            <br></br>real improvements of the day.
            
            <br></br>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
            
            <br></br>Repaired.
            
            <br></br>New York, April 23d, 1845.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. The Subscribers, while return-
            
            <br></br>ing thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at
            
            <br></br>the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and
            
            <br></br>seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood and mahogany cases.
            
            <br></br>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
            
            <br></br>the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
            
            <br></br>to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
            
            <br></br>upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            
            <br></br>STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway.
            
            <br></br>Manufactory, 13th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">THE BOEHM FLUTE.
            
            <br></br>NEW INVENTION.
            
            <br></br>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the Conservato-
            
            <br></br>rie at Paris, and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
            
            <br></br>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the ‘Boehm Flute,’
            
            <br></br>110 Fulton St. N. Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of
            
            <br></br>this city the above Imported Invention, which has been so enthusi-
            
            <br></br>astically received and generally used by the most distinguished Eu-
            
            <br></br>ropean artists, feels happy in being able to place before them the
            
            <br></br>following testimonial to its merits, signed by two of the most distin-
            
            <br></br>guished of our resident Artists.
            
            <br></br>We hereby testify to the excellence of the Boehm Flute, as manufac- j
            
            <br></br>tured by Mr. J. D. Larrabee ; to the beauty of its tone, the perfec-
            
            <br></br>tion of its tune, and the simplicity of its FIngering, which renders
            
            <br></br>a brilliant execution comparatively easy.
            
            <br></br>Philip Ernst, (who has already introduced it
            
            <br></br>successfully among his pupils.)
            
            <br></br>John A. Kyle, Principal Flute of the Philhar-
            
            <br></br>monic Society, and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm
            
            <br></br>Flute, 41 Forsyth st. New York.
            
            <br></br>Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory
            
            <br></br>110 Fulton st. and judge for themselves.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">VAN DENHOFF’S ELOCUTION.
            
            <br></br>SECOND EDITION.—This valuable work is being
            
            <br></br>introduced into a large number of the best Schools in the City and
            
            <br></br>Country.
            
            <br></br>It only needs to be generally known to become universally estab-
            
            <br></br>lished.
            
            <br></br>Testimonials are received from every quarter.
            
            <br></br>From Rev. R. F. Burnham, Rector of St. Paul's Church, Hoboken.
            
            <br></br>“ Having seen with much pleasure, a second edition, by your house,
            
            <br></br>of " A Plain System of Elocution," I beg leave to express to you my
            
            <br></br>opinion of the high merit of that work.
            
            <br></br>Its title is in keeping with the plan pursued in the book ; a rare fact
            
            <br></br>in this age of making many books. In the work may be found what
            
            <br></br>this age needs—a System of Elocution, that presents to the learner
            
            <br></br>something tangible; and that combines meaning with beauty, and
            
            <br></br>beauty with force.
            
            <br></br>I hereby express the opinion that the Principals of Seminaries of
            
            <br></br>Learning would benefit the department of Elocution, by the introduc-
            
            <br></br>tion of Mr. Vandenhoff’s System."
            
            <br></br>C. SHEPARD, Publisher,
            
            <br></br>191 Broadway, opposite John-street.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
            
            <br></br>THE FIRST PREMIUM A WARDED FIVE YEA RS BY THE AMERICAN INSTI-
            
            <br></br>TUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF HAND PENMANSHIP.
            
            <br></br>GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
            
            <br></br>No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            
            <br></br>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
            
            <br></br>tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
            
            <br></br>in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            
            <br></br>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course
            
            <br></br>of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Sta-
            
            <br></br>tionery. Payable at the commencement.
            
            <br></br>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M., daily, for gentlemen,
            
            <br></br>and from 11 to 1 o’clock, for ladies. Private instruction given.
            
            <br></br>For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
            
            <br></br>Price Five Dollars.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PAINE AND BURGESS,
            
            <br></br>62 JOHN STREET, N. Y.,
            
            <br></br>ARE just sending to press a New Series of Choice
            
            <br></br>Works, selected from the Prose Literature of Italy. Translated
            
            <br></br>and Edited by Edwards Lester, U. S. Consul at Genoa, auther of the
            
            <br></br>“ Glory and Shame of England,” &amp;c., &amp;c. This series will be made
            
            <br></br> up of original translations of the best works of the best Italian writers,
            
            <br></br>with original notes and sketches in illustration of the Genius, the Lives
            
            <br></br>and Times of the Authors. Five vols. are ready for the Press.
            
            <br></br>1. Ettore Fieramosca, or the Challenge of Barletta, an Historical
            
            <br></br> Romance of the Times of the Medici, by Agegbio.
            
            <br></br>2 and 3, The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli.
            
            <br></br> 4. The Autobiography of Alfieri.
            
            <br></br>These numbers will be issued in quick succession, in beautiful style,
            
            <br></br>and sold for fifty cents per volume. The object of this series is to
            
            <br></br> make known to the American people the Literature of Italy.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            
            <br></br>SIR —WE WILL THANK YOU TO CAUTION
            
            <br></br> the public against a set of imposters who are calling upon our cus-
            
            <br></br> tomers, asserting that they are engaged by us in the capacity of agents.
            
            <br></br> In several instances they have succeeded in obtaining orders. But
            
            <br></br> when the goods are delivered great dissatisfaction has been given by
            
            <br></br>the infamous and utterly base imitations. But still persisting that the
            
            <br></br> cards are our manufacture, they too often succeed in foisting them
            
            <br></br> upon the unsuspecting. We ourselves would strenuously caution the
            
            <br></br>said parties that, should they persist after this notice, we will try what
            
            <br></br>effect a State Prison will have upon them.
            
            <br></br>We are, Sir, Yours most obt’y,
            
            <br></br>J. B. CAREY &amp; CO ,
            
            <br></br>Ornamental Show Card Manufacturers,
            
            <br></br>34 Beekman street, (late 323 Broadway.)
            
            <br></br>An agent wanted for New York City. Also one for New York State
            
            <br></br>—whose name will be published as our authorized agent.
            
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            
            <br></br>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work
            
            <br></br>yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this me-
            
            <br></br>thod, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
            
            <br></br>The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exerci-
            
            <br></br>ses, scales and studies are given in such progressive order, that they
            
            <br></br>enlist the interest of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly
            
            <br></br>through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, arc too often
            
            <br></br>made irksome in other instruction books. The time has arrived when
            
            <br></br>a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is
            
            <br></br>only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will be ena-
            
            <br></br>bled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good
            
            <br></br>musicians.
            
            <br></br>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ; the
            
            <br></br>rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and
            
            <br></br>each lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            
            <br></br>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations
            
            <br></br>from professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of
            
            <br></br>Bertini’s Method over all others yet published in this country, most
            
            <br></br>of them having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be
            
            <br></br>necessary to give a lew of the names in the principal cities.
            
            <br></br>Boston.	New-York.
            
            <br></br>Messr. G. J. Webb,	Messrs. H. C.Timm,
            
            <br></br>J. G. Maeder,	W. Alpers,
            
            <br></br>H. T. Hach,	U. C. Hill,
            
            <br></br>E. L. White,	F. H. Brown,
            
            <br></br>David Paine,	Philadelphia.
            
            <br></br>A.Kurek,	B. C. Cross,
            
            <br></br>T. B. Moses.	Joseph Duggan.
            
            <br></br>Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            
            <br></br>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the
            
            <br></br>work. American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H.
            
            <br></br>OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            
            <br></br>Redding &amp; Co......................Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance...................Philadelphia, Pa.
            
            <br></br>R.G. H. HUNTINGTON,...............Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>George Jones,......................Albany, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Thomas H. Pease...................New-Haven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>L. Willard, ................ Troy.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">JOHN DOUGLAS, Printer, 106 Fulton-street, New-York.</div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
   </div>
</div>