<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab"> VOL. 2.
            NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JULY 12, 1845.	NO. l.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Three Dollars per Annum.	Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.</div> 
         <div class="ab">Edited by EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.</div>	
         <div class="ab">Published at 136 Nassau St.
            		By JOHN BISCO.
         </div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">OUR NEW VOLUME.</div>
         
         <p>To the Public.—The suspension of “ The Broadway
            Journal" for one week, has been occasioned by the necessity
            for some arrangements in which the public have no interest,
            but which, beyond doubt, will give increased value and
            efficiency to the paper.
         </p>
         
         <p>In commencing the Second Volume, the undersigned begs
            leave to return his sincere thanks to the numerous friends
            who have lent him their aid in the very difficult task of
            establishing a literary and critical weekly. The success of
            the work, in the brief period of its existence, has been, he
            truly believes, beyond precedent—and from a brilliant Past,
            he looks confidently to a triumphant Future.
         </p>
         
         <p>The editorial conduct of “ The Broadway Journal” is under the sole charge of Edgar A. Poe—Mr. H. C. Watson,
            as heretofore, controlling the Musical Department.
         </p>
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">John Bisco</span>,
            Publisher.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">HOW TO WRITE A BLACKWOOD
            ARTICLE.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">“ In the namc of the Prophet—figs!!”
            <br>Cry of the Turkish fig-pedler.
         </div>
         
         <p>I presume every body has heard of me. My name is the
            Signora Psyche Zenobia. This I know to be a fact. No
            body but my enemies ever calls me Suky Snobbs. I have been
            assured that Suky is but a vulgar corruption of Psyche, which
            is good Greek, and means “the soul" (that’s me, I'm all
            soul) and sometimes “ a butterfly,” which latter meaning
            undoubtedly alludes to my appearance in my new crimson
            satin dress, with the sky-blue Arabian mantelet, and the
            trimmings of green agraffas, and the seven flounces of
            orange-colored auriculas. As for Snobbs—any person who
            should look at me would be instantly aware that my name
            was n’t Snobbs. Miss Tabitha Turnip propagated that report through sheer envy. Tabitha Turnip indeed! Oh
            the little wretch ! But what can we expect from a turnip ? Wonder if she remembers ihe old adage about "blood
            out of a turnip, &amp;c.” [Mem : put her in mind of it the first
            opportunity.] [Mem again—pull her nose.] Where was I ?
            Ah ! I have been assured that Snobbs is a mere corruption
            of Zenobia, and that Zenobia was a queen—(So am I. Dr.
            Moneypenny, always calls me the Queen of Hearts)-and that
            Zenobia, as well as Psyche, is good Greek, and that my father was “a Greek,” and that consequently I have a right
            to our patronymic, which is Zenobia, and not by any means
            Snobbs. Nobody but Tabitha Turnip calls me Suky SnobbsI am the Signora Psyche Zenobia.
         </p>
         
         <p>As I said before, every body has heard of me. I am that
            very Signora Psyche Zenobia, so justly celebrated as corresponding secretary to the “ Philadelphia. Regular, Exchange,
            Tea, Total, Young, Belles, Lettns. Universal, Experimental, Bibliographical, Association, To, Civilize, Humanity.”
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>Dr. Moneypenny made the title for us, and says he chose it
            because it sounded big like an empty rum-puncheon. (A
            vulgar man that sometimes—but he’s deep.) We all sign
            the initials of the society after our names, in the fashion of
            the R.S.A., Royal Society of Arts—the S.D.U.K., Society for
            the Diffusion of Useful Knowledge, &amp;c. &amp;c. Dr. Moneypenny says that S stands for stale, and that D.U.K. spells duck,
            (but it don’t,) and that S.D.U.K. stands for Stale Duck, and
            not tor Lord Brougham’s society—but then Dr. Moneypenny
            is such a queer man that I am never sure when he is telling
            me the truth. At any rate we always add to our names the
            initials P.R.E.T.T.Y.B.L.U.E.B.A.T.C.H.—that is to say,
            Philadelphia, Regular, Exchange, Tea, Total, Young, Belles,
            Lettres, Universal, Experimental, Bibliographical, Association, To, Civilize, Humanity—one letter for each word,
            which is a decided improvement upon Lord Brougham. Dr.
            Moneypenny will have it that our initials give our true character—but for my life I can’t see what he means.
         </p>
         
         <p>Notwithstanding the good offices of the Doctor, and the
            strenuous exertions of the association to get itself into notice,
            it met with no very great success until I joined it. The
            truth is, members indulged in too flippant a tone of discussion. The papers read every Saturday evening were characterized less by depth than buffoonery. They were all
            whipped syllabub. There was no investigation of first causes, first principles. There was no investigation of anything
            at all. There was no attention paid to that great point the
            “ fitness of things.” In short there was no fine writing like
            this. It was all low—very ! No profundity, no reading, no
            metaphysics—nothing which the learned call spirituality,
            and which the unlearned choose to stigmatise as cant. [Dr.
            M. says I ought to spell “cant” with a capital K—but I
            know better.]
         </p>
         
         <p>When I joined the society it was my endeavour to introduce a better style of thinking and writing, and all the world
            knows how well I have succeeded. We get up as good papers now in the P.R.E.T.T.Y.B.L.U.E.B.A.T.C.H. as any
            to he found even in Blackwood. I say, Blackwood, because
            I have been assured that the finest writing, upon every subject, is to be discovered in the pages of that justly celebrated
            Magazine. We now take it for our model upon all themes,
            and are getting into rapid notice accordingly. And, after
            all, it’s not so very difficult a matter to compose an article
            of the genuine Blackwood stamp, if one only goes properly
            about it. Of course I do n’t speak of the political articles.
            Every body knows how they are managed, since Dr. Money
            penny explained it. Mr. Blackwood has a pair of tailor’sshears, and three apprentices who stand by him for orders.
            One hands him the “ Times,” another the “ Examiner,” and
            a third a “Gulley’s New Compendium of Slang-Whang.’
            Mr. B. merely cuts out and intersperses. It is soon done—
            nothing but Examiner, Slang-Whang, and Times — then
            Times, Slang-Whang, and Examiner—and then Times, Examiner, and Slang-Whang.
         </p>
         
         <p>But the chief merit of the Magazine lies in its miscella
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page2"></div> 
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            neous articles ; and the best of these come under the head of
            what Dr. Moneypenny calls the bizarreries (whatever that
            may mean) and what every body else calls the intensities.
            This is a species of writing which I have long known how
            to appreciate, although it is only since my late visit to Mr.
            Blackwood (deputed by the society) that I have been made
            aware of the exact method of composition. This method is
            very simple, but not so much so as the politics. Upon my calling at Mr. B.’s, and making known to him the wishes of the
            society, he received me with great civility, took me into his
            study, and gave me a clear explanation of the whole process.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ My dear madam,” said he, evidently struck with my
            majestic appearance, for I had on the crimson satin, with the
            green agraffas, and orange-coloured auriculas, “ My dear
            madam,” said he, “ sit down. The matter stands thus. In
            the first place, your writer of intensities must have very black
            ink, and a very big pen, with a very blunt nib. And, mark
            me, Miss Psyche Zenobia!” he continued, after a pause,
            with the most impressive energy and solemnity of manner,
            “mark me!—that pen—must—never be mended! Herein,
            madam, lies the secret, the soul, of intensity. I assume it
            upon myself to say, that no individual, of however great
            genius, ever wrote with a good pen,—understand me,—a
            good article. You may take it for granted, that when manuscript can be read it is never worth reading. This is a leading principle in our faith, to which if you cannot readily assent, our conference is at an end.”
         </p>
         
         <p>He paused. But, of course, as I had no wish to put an
            end to the conference, I assented to a proposition so very obvious, and one, too, of whose truth I had all along been sufficiently aware. He seemed pleased, and went on with his
            instructions.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ It may appear invidious in me, Miss Psyche Zenobia, to
            refer you to any article, or set of articles, in the way of
            model or study ; yet perhaps I may as well call your attention to a few cases. Let me see. There was ‘ The Dead
            Alive,' a capital thing!—the record of a gentleman's sensawhen entombed before the breath was out of his body—ful]
            tions, of taste, terror, sentiment, metaphysics, and erudition.
            You would have sworn that the writer had been born and
            brought up in a coffin. Then we had the ‘ Confessions of
            an Opium-eater’—fine, very fine !—glorious imagination—
            deep philosophy—acute speculation—plenty of fire and fury,
            and a good spicing of the decidedly unintelligible. That was
            a nice bit of flummery, and went down the throats of the
            people delightfully. They would have it that Coleridge
            wrote the paper—but not so. It was composed by my pet
            baboon. Juniper, over a rummer of Hollands and water, ' hot.
            without sugar.’” [This I could scarcely have believed had
            it been any body but Mr. Blackwood, who assured me of it.]
            “ Then there was ' The Involuntary Experimentalist,' all
            about a gentleman who got baked in an oven, and came out
            alive and well, although certainly done to a turn. And
            then there was ' The Diary of a Late Physician,' where
            the merit lay in good rant, and indifferent Greek—both of
            them taking things, with the public. And then there was
            ' The Man in the Del!,' a paper by-the bye, Miss Zenobia,
            which I cannot sufficiently recommend to your attention. It
            is the history of a young person who goes to sleep under the
            clapper of a church bell, and is awakened by its tolling for a
            funeral. The sound drives him mad, and, accordingly, pulling out his tablets, he gives a record of his sensations. Sensations are the great things after all. Should you ever be
            drowned or hung, be sure and make a note of your sensations—they will be worth to you ten guineas a sheet. If you
            wish to write forcibly, Miss Zenobia, pay minute attention to 
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            the sensations.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“ That I certainly will, Mr. Blackwood,” said I.
            
         </p>
         <p>“Good!” he replied. “I see you are a pupil after my
            own heart. But I must put you au fait to the details necessary in composing what may be denominated a genuine
            Blackwood article of the sensation stamp—the kind which
            you will understand me to say I consider the best for all purposes.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ The first thing requisite is to get yourself into such a
            jscrape as no one ever got into before. The oven, for instance,
            —that was a good hit. But if you have no oven, or bigbell,
            iat hand, and if you cannot conveniently tumble out of a balloon, or be swallowed up in an earthquake, or get stuck fast
            in a chimney, you will have to be contented with simply imagining some similar misadventure. I should prefer, however, that you have the actual fact to bear you out. Nothing
             so well assists the fancy, as an experimental knowledge of the
             matter in hand. ‘Truth is strange,’ you know, ‘ stranger
            than fiction’—besides being more to the purpose.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Here I assured him I had an excellent pair of garters, and
            would go and hang myself forthwith.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Good !” he replied, “do so;—although hanging is somewhat hacknied. Perhaps you might do better. Take a dose
            of Brandreth’s pills, and then give us your sensations. However, my instructions will apply equally well to any variety
            of misadventure, and in your way home you may easily gel
            knocked in the head, or run over by an omnibus, or bitten by
            a mad dog, or drowned in a gutter. But, to proceed.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Having determined upon your subject, you must next
            consider the tone, or manner, of your narration. There is
            the lone didactic, the tone enthusiastic, the tone natural—all
            common-place enough. But then there is the lone laconic,
            or curt, which has lately come much into use. It consists in
            short sentences. Somehow thus. Can’t be too brief. Can’t
            be too snappish. Always a full stop. And never a para graph.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Then there is the tone elevated, diffusive, and interjectional. Some of our best novelists patronize this tone. The
            jwords must be all in a whirl, like a humming-top, and make
            a noise very similar, which answers remarkably well instead
             of meaning. This is the best of all possible styles where
            the writer is in too great a hurry to think.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ The tone metaphysical is also a good one. If you know
            any big words this is your chance for them. Talk of the
            Ionic and Eleatic schools—of Archytas, Gorgias and Alemoeon. Say something about objectivity and subjectivity. Be
            sure and abuse a man called Locke. Turn up your nose at
             things in general, and when you let slip anything a little too
            absurd, you need not be at the trouble of scratching it out,
            but just add a foot-note, and say that you are indebted for the
            above profound observation to the ' Kritik der reinem Vernunft,' or to the ‘ Metaphysische Anfangsgrunde der Naturwissenschaft.' This will look erudite and—and—and frank.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ There are various other tones of equal celebrity, but I
            shall mention only two more—the tone transcendental and the
            tone heterogeneous. In the former the merit consists in
            seeing into (he nature of affairs a very great deal farther than
            any body else. This second sight is very efficient when properly managed. A little reading of the ‘ Dial’ will carry you
            a great way. Eschew, in this case, big words; get them as
            small as possible, and write them upside down. Look over
            Channing’s poems and quote what he says about a ‘ fat little
            man with a delusive show of Can.’ Put in something about
            the Supernal Oneness. Don’t say a syllable about the Infernal Twoness. Above all, study inuendo. Hint every
            thing—assert nothing. If you feel inclined to say ‘ bread 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page3"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            and butter’ do not by any means say it outright. You may
            say anything and every thing approaching to ‘bread and
            butter.' You may hint at buck-wheat cake, or you may
            even go so far as to insinuate oat-meal porridge, but if bread
            and butter be your real meaning, be cautious, my dear Miss
            Psyche, net on any account to say ' bread and butter!’ ”
         </p>
         
         <p>I assured him that I should never say it again as long as I
            lived. He kissed me and continued:
         </p>
         
         <p>“As for the tone heterogeneous, it is merely a judicious
            mixture, in equal proportions, of all the other tones in the
            World, and is consequently made up of everything deep,
            great, odd, piquant, pertinent, and pretty.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Let us suppose now you have determined upon your incidents and tone. The most important portion, — in fact
            the soul of the whole business, is yet to be attended to—I
            allude to the filling up. It is not to be supposed that a lady
            or gentleman either has been leading the life of a bookworm.
            And yet above all things it is necessary that your article have
            an air of erudition, or at least afford evidence of extensive
            general reading. Now I’ll put you in the way of accomplishing this point. See here!’’ (pulling down some three
            or four ordinary looking volumes, and opening them at random.) “ By casting your eye down almost any page of any
            book in the world, you will be able to perceive at once a host
            of little scraps of either learning or bel-esprit-ism, which are
            the very thing for the spicing of a Blackwood article. You
            might as well note down a few while I read them to you. I
            shall make two divisions: first, Piquant Facts for the Manufacture of Similes; and second, Piquant Expressions to be
            introduced as occasion may require. Write now!—" and I
            wrote as he dictated.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Piquant Facts for Similes. ‘ There were originally
            but three Muses—Melete, Mneme, and Aoede—meditation,
            memory, and singing.’ You may make a great deal of that
            little fact if properly worked. You see it is not generally
            known, and looks recherche. You must be careful and give
            the thing with a downright improvise air.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Again. ‘ The river Alpheus passed beneath the sea, and
            emerged without injury to the purity of its waters.’ Rather
            stale that, to be sure, but, if properly dressed and dished up,
            will look quite as fresh as ever.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Here is something better. ' The Persian Iris appears to
            some persons to possess a sweet and very powerful perfume,
            while to others it is perfectly scentless.’ Fine that, and very
            delicate! Turn it about a little, and it will do wonders.
            We’ll have something else in the botanical line. There’s
            nothing goes down so well, especially with the help of a little
            Latin. Write!
         </p>
         
         <p>"'The Epidendrum Flos Aeris, of Java, bears a very
            beautiful flower, and will live when pulled up by the roots.
            The natives suspend it by a cord from the ceiling, and enjoy
            its fragrance for years.’ That’s capital! That will do for
            the similes. Now for the Piquant Expressions.
         </p>
         
         <p>Piquant Expressions. ‘ The venerable Chinese novel JuKiao-Li.’ Good ! By introducing these few words with
            dexterity you will evince your intimate acquaintance with
            the language and literature of the Chinese. With the aid
            of this you may possibly get along without either Arabic, or
            Sanscrit, or Chickasaw. There is no passing muster, however, without Spanish, Italian, German, Latin, and Greek.
            I must look you out a little specimen of each. Any scrap
            will answer, because you must depend upon your own ingenuity to make it fit into your article. Now write!
         </p>
         
         <p>“ ' Aussi tendre que Zaire'—as tender as Zaire—French.
            Alludes to the frequent repetition of the phrase, la tendre
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>Zaire, in the French tragedy of that name. Properly introduced, will show not only your knowledge of the language,
            but your general reading and wit. You can say, for instance,
            that the chicken you were eating (write an article about being choked to death by a chicken-bone) was not altogether
            aussi tendre que Zaire. Write!
         </p>
         <div class="lg">
            <br>‘ Van muerle tan escondida,
            <br>Que no te sienta renir,
            <br>Porque el plazer del morir
            <br>No me torne a dar la vida.'
            
         </div>
         <p>That’s Spanish—from Miguel de Cervantes. ‘ Come quickly
            O death! but be sure and don’t let me see you coming, lest
            the pleasure I shall feel at your appearance should unfortunately bring me back again to life.’ This you may slip in
            quite a propos when you are struggling in the last agonies
            with the chicken-bone. Write!
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>‘ Il pover ’huomo che non se’n era accorto,
            <br>Andava combattendo, e era morto.’
         </div>
         
         <p>That’s Italian, you perceive,—from Ariosto. It means that
            a great hero, in the heat of combat, not perceivin that he
            had been fairly killed, continued to fight valiantly, dead as
            he was. The application of this to your own case is obvious
            —for I trust, Miss Psyche, that you will not neglect to kick
            for at least an hour and a half after you have been choked to
            death by that chicken-bone. Please to write!
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>‘ Und sterb’ich doch, no sterb’ich denn
            <br>Durch sie—durch sie."
         </div>
         
         <p>That’s German—from Schiller. ‘And if I die, at least I die
            —for thee—for thee!’ Here it is clear that you are apostrophising the cause of your disaster, the chicken. Indeed what
            gentleman (or lady either) of sense, would'nt die, I should
            like to know, for a well fattened capon of the right Molucca
            breed, stuffed with capers and mushrooms, and served up in
            a salad-bowl, with orange-jellies en mosuiques. Write!
            (You can get them that way at Tortoni’s,)—Write, if you
            please'.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Here is a nice little Latin phrase, and rare too, (one can’t
            be too reckerche or brief in one’s Latin, it’s getting so common,)—ignoratio elenchi. He has committed an ignoratio
            elenchi—that is to say, he has understood the words of your
            proposition, but not the ideas. The man was a fool, you
            see. Some poor fellow whom you addressed while choking
            with that chicken-bone, and who therefore did’nt precisely
            understand what you were talking about. Throw the ignoratio elenchi in his teeth, and, at once, you have him annihilated. If he dare to reply, you can tell him from Lucan
            (here it is) that speeches are mere anemonae verborum, anemone words. The anemone, with great brilliancy, has no
            smell. Or, if he begin to bluster, you may be down upon
            him with insomnia Jovis, reveries of Jupiter—a phrase which
            Silius Italicus (see here!) applies to thoughts pompous and
            inflated. This will be sure and cut him to the heart. He
            can do nothing but roll over and die. Will you be kind
            enough to write?
         </p>
         
         <p>“In Greek we must have something pretty—from Demosthenes, for example. Ανερ ο φεογων χαι παλιν μαχεσεται.
            [Aner o pheogon kai palin makesetai.] There is a tolerably
            good translation of it in Hudibras—
         </p>
         <div class="lg"><br>For he that flies may fight again,
            <br>Which he can never do that’s slain.
         </div>
         
         <p>In a Blackwood article nothing makes so fine a show as your
            Greek. The very letters have an air of profundity about
            them. Only observe, madam, the astute look of that Epsiion! That Phi ought certainly to be a bishop! Was ever
            there a smarter fellow than that Omicron ? Just twig that
            Tau! In short, there is nothing like Greek for a genuine
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page4"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            sensation-paper. In the present case your application is the
            most obvious thing in the world. Rap out the sentence,
            with a huge oath, and by way of ultimatum, at the good-fornothing dunder-headed villain who couldn’t understand your
            plain English in relation to the chicken-bone. He’ll take
            the hint and be off, you may depend upon it.”
         </p>
         
         <p>These were all the instructions Mr. B. could afford me upon the topic in question, but I felt they would be entirely
            sufficient. I was, at length, able to write a genuine Blackwood article, and determined to do it forthwith. In taking
            leave of me, Mr. B. made a proposition for the purchase of
            the paper when written; but as he could offer me only fifty
            guineas a sheet, I thought it better to let our society have
            it, than sacrifice it for so paltry a sum. Notwithstanding
            this niggardly spirit, however, the gentleman showed his
            consideration for me in all other respects, and indeed treated
            me with the greatest civility. His parting words made a
            deep impression upon my heart, and I hope I shall always
            remember them with gratitude.
         </p>
         
         <p>" My dear Miss Zenobia,” he said, while the tears stood
            in his eyes, “ is there anything else I can do to promote the
            success of your laudable undertaking? Let me reflect! It
            is just possible that you may not be able, so soon as convenient, to — to — get yourself drowned, or — choked with
            a chicken-bone, or — or hung, — or —bitten by a — but
            stay ! Now I think me of it, there are a couple of very excellent bull dogs in the yard — fine fellows, I assure you —
            savage, and all that — indeed just the thing for your
            money — they’ll have you eaten up, auriculas and all, in
            less than five minutes (here’s my watch !) — and then only
            think of the sensations! Here! I say — Tom! — Peter!
            — Dick, you villain ! — let out those” — but as I was really
            in a great hurry, and had not another moment to spare, I
            was reluctantly forced to expedite my departure, and accordingly took leave at once— somewhat more abruptly, I admit, than strict courtesy would have, otherwise, allowed.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was my primary object, upon quitting Mr. Blackwood,
            to get into some immediate difficulty, pursuant to his advice,
            and with this view I spent the greater part of the day in wandering about Edinburgh, seeking lor desperate adventures—
            adventures adequate to the intensity of my feelings, and
            adapted to the vast character of the article I intended to
            write. In this excursion I was attended by my negro-servant
            Pompey, and my little lap-dog Diana, whom I had brought
            with me from Philadelphia. It was not, however, until late
            in the afternoon that l fully succeeded in my arduous undertaking. An important event then happened, of which the
            following Blackwood article, in the tone heterogeneous, is
            the substance and result.
         </p>
         A predicament.
         
         <div class="ab">What chance, good lady, hath bereft you thus?—COMUS.</div>
         
         <p>It was a quiet and still afternoon when I strolled forth in
            the goodly city of Edina. The confusion and bustle in the
            streets were terrible. Men were talking. Women were
            screaming. Children were choking. Pigs were whistling.
            Carts they rattled. Bulls they bellowed. Cows they lowed. Horses they neighed. Cals they caterwauled. Dogs
            they danced. Danced! Could it then be possible ? Danced ! Alas, thought I, my dancing days are over! Thus it
            is ever. What a host of gloomy recollections will ever and
            anon be awakened in the mind of genius and imaginative
            contemplation, especially of a genius doomed to the everlasting, and eternal, and continual, and, as one might say, the—
            continued—yes, the continued and continuous, bitter, har
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            assing, disturbing, and, if I may be allowed the expression,
            the very disturbing influence of the serene, and godlike, and
            heavenly, and exalting, and ele ated, and purifying effect of
            what may be rightly termed he most enviable, the most
            truly enviable—nay! the most benignly beautiful, the most
            deliciously ethereal, and, as it were, the most pretty (if I
            may use so bold an expression) thing (pardon me, gentle
            reader!) in the word—but I am led away by my feelings. In
            such a mind, I repeat, what a host of recollections are stirred
            up by a trifle ! The dogs danced ! I—I could not! They
            frisked—I wept. They capered—I sobbed aloud. Touching circumstances! which cannot fail to bring to the recollection of the classical reader that exquisite passage in relation to the fitness of things, which is to be found in the commencement of the third volume of that admirable and venerable Chinese novel, the Jo-Go-Slow.
         </p>
         
         <p>In my solitary walk through the city I had two humble
            but faithful companions. Diana, my poodle! sweetest of
            creatures ! She had a quantity of hair over her one eye, and
            a blue ribband tied fashionably around her neck. Diana was
            not more than five inches in height, but her head was somewhat bigger than her body, and her tail, being cut off exceedingly close, gave an air of injured innocence to the interesting animal which rendered her a favorite with all.
         </p>
         
         <p>And Pompey, my negro!—sweet Pompey ! how shall I
            ever forget thee? I had taken Pompey’s arm. He was three
            feet in height (I like to be particular) and about seventy, or
            perhaps eighty, years of age. He had bow-legs and was
            corpulent. His mouth should not be called small, nor his
            ears short. His teeth, however, were like pearl, and his
            large full eyes were deliciously white. Nature had endowed
            him with no neck, and had placed his ankles (as usual with
            that race) in the middle of the upper portion of the feet.
            He was clad with a striking simplicity. His sole garments
             were a stock of nine inches in height, and a nearly-new drab
            overcoat which had formerly been in the service of the tall,
            stately, and illustrious Dr. Moneypenny. It was a good
            overcoat. It was well cut. It was well made. The coat
            was nearly new. Pompey held it up out of the dirt with
            both hands.
         </p>
         
         <p>There were three persons in our party, and two of them
            have already been the subject of remark. There was a
            third—that third person was myself. I am the Signora
            Psyche Zenobia. I am not Suky Snobbs. My appearance
            is commanding. On the memorable occasion of which I
            speak I was habited in a crimson satin dress, with a skyblue Arabian mantelet. And the dress had trimmings of
            green agraffas, and seven graceful flounces of the orange colored auricula. I thus formed the third of the party. There
            was the poodle. There was Pompey. There was myself.
            We were three. Thus it is said there were originally but
            three Furies—Melty, Nimmy and Hetty—Meditation, Memory, and Fiddling.
         </p>
         
         <p>Leaning upon the arm of the gallant Pompey, and attended
            at a respectful distance by Diana, I proceeded down one of
            the populous and very pleasant streets of the now deserted
            Edina. On a sudden, there presented itself to view a church
            —a Gothic cathedral—vast, venerable, and with a tall
            steeple, which towered into the sky. What madness now
            possessed me ? Why did I rush upon my fate ? I was seized with an uncontrollable desire to ascend the giddy pinnacle, and thence survey the immense extent of the city. The
            door of the cathedral stood invitingly open. My destiny prevailed. I entered the ominous archway. Where then was
            my guardian angel ?— if indeed such angels there be. If!
            Distressing monosyllable! what a world of mystery, and
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page5"></div> 
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            meaning, and doubt, and uncertainty is there involved in thy
            two letters! I entered the ominous archway! I entered;
            and, without injury to my orange-colored auriculas, I passed
            beneath the portal, and emerged within the vestibule!
            Thus it is said the immense river Alfred passed, unscathed,
            and unwetted, beneath the sea.
         </p>
         
         <p>I thought the staircases would never have an end.
            Round! Yes, they went round and up, and round and up
            and round and up, until I could not help surmising, with the
            sagacious Pompey, upon whose supporting arm I leaned in
            all the confidence of early affection—I could not help surmising that the upper end of the continuous spiral ladder had
            been accidentally, or perhaps designedly, removed. I paused
            for breath; and, in the meantime, an incident occurred of
            too momentous a nature in a moral, and also in a metaphysical point of view, to be passed over without notice. It appeared to me—indeed I was quite confident of the fact—I
            could not be mistaken—no! I had, for some moments, carefully and anxiously observed the motions of my Diana—I say
            that I could not be mistaken—Diana smell a rat! At once
            I called Pompey’s attention to the subject, and he—he
            agreed with me. There was then no longer any reasonable
            room for doubt. The rat had been smelled—and by Diana.
            Heavens! shall I ever forget the intense excitement of that
            moment? Alas! what is the boasted intellect of man?
            The rat!—it was there—that is to say, it was somewhere.
            Diana smelled the rat. I—I could not! Thus it is said the
            Prussian Isis has, for some persons, a sweet and very powerful perfume, while to others it is perfectly scentless.
         </p>
         
         <p>The staircase had been surmounted, and there were now
            only three or four more upward steps intervening between us
            and the summit. We still ascended, and now only one step
            remained. One step! One little, little step! Upon one
            such little step in the great staircase of human life how vast
            a sum of human happiness or misery often depends! I
            thought of myself, then of Pompey, and then of the mysterious
            and inexplicable destiny which surrounded us. I thought of
            Pompey !—alas, I thought of love ! I thought of the many
            false steps which have been taken, and may be taken again.
            I resolved to be more cautious, more reserved. I abandoned
            the arm of Pompey, and, without his assistance, surmounted
            the one remaining step, and gained the chamber of the belfry. I was followed immediately afterwards by my poodle.
            Pompey alone remained behind. I stood at the head of the
            staircase, and encouraged him to ascend. He stretched
            forth to me his hand, and unfortunately in so doing was forc
            ed to abandon his firm hold upon the overcoat. Will the
            gods never cease their persecution ? The overcoat it dropped,
            and, with one of his feet, Pompey stepped upon the long and
            trailing skirt of the overcoat. He stumbled and fell—this
            consequence was inevitable. He fell forwards, and, with
            his accursed head, striking me full in the—in the breast,
            precipitated me headlong, together with himself, upon the
            hard, filthy and detestable floor of the belfry. But my revenge was sure, sudden and complete. Seizing him furiously by the wool with both hands, I lore out a vast quantity of
            the black, and crisp, and curling material, and tossed it from
            me with every manifestation of disdain. It fell among the
            ropes of the belfry and remained. Pompey arose, and said
            no word. But he regarded me piteously with his large eyes
            and—sighed. Ye gods—that sigh ! It sunk into my heart.
            And the hair—the wool! Could I have reached that wool
            I would have bathed it with my tears, in testimony of regret.
            But alas! it was now far beyond my grasp. As it dangled
            among the cordage of the bell, I fancied it still alive. I fancied that it stood on end with indignation._Thus the happ
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>dandy Flos Aeris of Java, bears, it is said, a beautiful flower, which will live when pulled up by the roots. The natives suspend it by a cord from the ceiling and enjoy its fragrance for years.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our quarrel was now made up, and we looked about the
            room for an aperture through which to survey the city of
            Edina. Windows there were none. The sole light admit,
            ted into the gloom chamber proceeded from a square opening, about a foot in diameter, at a height of about seven feet
            from the floor. Yet what will the energy of true genius
            not effect? I resolved to clamber up to this hole. A vast
            quantity of wheels, pinions, and other cabalistic-looking machinery stood opposite the hole, close to it; and through the
            hole there passed an iron rod from the machinery. Between
            the wheels and the wall where the hole lay, there was barely room for my body—yet I was desperate, and determined
            to persevere. I called Pompey to my side.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ You perceive that aperture, Pompey. I wish to look
            through it. You will stand here just beneath the hole—so.
            Now, hold out one of your hands, Pompey, and let me step
            upon it—thus. Now, the other hand, Pompey, and with its
            aid I will get upon your shoulders.”
         </p>
         
         <p>He did everything I wished, and I found, upon getting up,
            that I could easily pass my head and neck through the aperture. The prospect was sublime. Nothing could be more
            magnificent. I merely paused a moment to bid Diana behave herself, and assure Pompey that I would be considerate and bear as lightly as possible upon his shoulders. I
            told him I would be tender of his feelings—ossi tender que
            beefsteak. Having done this justice to my faithful friend, I
            gave myself up with great zest and enthusiasm to the enjoyment of the scene which so obligingly spread itself out before my eyes.
         </p>
         
         <p>Upon this subject, however, I shall forbear to dilate. I
            will not describe the city of Edinburgh. Every one has
            been to Edinburgh—the classic Edina. I will confine myself to the momentous details of my own lamentable adventure. Having, in some measure, satisfied my curiosity in regard to the extent, situation, and general appearance of the
            city, I had leisure to survey the church in which I was, and
            the delicate architecture of the steeple. I observed that the
            aperture through which I had thrust my head was an opening in the dial-plate of a gigantic clock, and must have appeared, from the street, as a large keyhole, such as we see
            iu the face of french watches. No doubt the true object was
            to admit the arm of an attendant, to adjust, when necessary,
            the hands of the clock from within. I observed also, with
            surprise, the immense size of these hands, the longest of
            which could not have been less than ten feet in length, and,
            where broadest, eight or nine inches in breadth. They were
            of solid steel apparently, and their edges appeared to be
            sharp. Having noticed these particulars, and some others,
            I again turned my eyes upon the glorious prospect below,
            and soon became absorbed in contemplation.
         </p>
         
         <p>From this, after some minutes, I was aroused by the voice
            of Pompey, who declared he could stand it no longer, and requested that I would be so kind as to come down. This was
            unreasonable, and I told him so in a speech of some length.
            He replied, but with an evident misunderstanding of my
             ideas upon the subject. I accordingly grew angry, and told
            him in plain words that he was a fool, that he had committed an ignoramus e-clench-eye, that his notions were mere
            insommary Bovis, and his words little belter than an enemy
            werrybor'em. With this he appeared satisfied, and I resumed my contemplations.
         </p>
         <p>It might have been half an hour after this altercation
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page6"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>when, as I was deeply absorbed in the heavenly scenery beneath me, I was startled by something very cold which
            pressed with a gentle pressure upon the back of my neck.
            It is needless to say that I felt inexpressibly alarmed. I
            knew that Pompey was beneath my feet, and that Diana
            was sitting, according to my explicit directions, upon her
            hind legs in the farthest corner of the room. What could it
            be? Alas! I but too soon discovered. Turning my head
            gently to one side, I perceived, to my extreme horror, that
            the huge, glittering, scimetar-like minute-hand of the clock,
            had, in the course of its hourly revolution, descended, upon
            my neck. There was, I knew, not a second to be lost. I
            pulled back at once—but it was too late. There was no
            chance of forcing my head through the mouth of that terrible trap in which it was so fairly caught, and which grew
            narrower and narrower with a rapidity too horrible to be
            conceived. The agony of that moment is not to be imagined. I threw up my hands and endeavoured, with all my
            strength, to force upwards the ponderous iron bar. I might
            as well have tried to lift the cathedral itself. Down, down,
            down it came, closer, and yet closer. I screamed to Pompey
            for aid: but he said that I had hurt his feelings by calling him
            “an ignorant old squint eye.” I yelled to Diana ; but she
            only said “ bow-wow-wow,” and that “ I had told her on no
            account to stir from the corner.” Thus I had no relief to expect from my associates.
         </p>
         
         <p>Meantime the ponderous and terrific Scythe of Time (for I
            now discovered the literal import of that classical phrase)
            had not stopped, nor was it likely to stop, in its career, 
            Down and still down, it came. It had already buried its
            sharp edge a full inch in my flesh, and my sensations grew ;
            indistinct and confused. At one time I fancied myself in
            Philadelphia with the stately Dr. Moneypenny, at another in
            the back parlor of Mr. Blackwood receiving his invaluable!
            instructions. And then again the sweet recollection of better 
            and earlier times came over me, and I thought of that happy 
            period when the world was not all a desert, and Pompey not
            altogether cruel.
         </p>
         
         <p>The ticking of the machinery amused me. Amused me, I
            say, for my sensations now bordered upon perfect happiness,
            and the most trifling circumstances afforded me pleasure.
            The eternal click-clack, click-clack, click-clack, of the clock
            was the most melodious of music in my ears, and occasionally even put me in mind of the grateful sermonic harangues
            of Dr. Olapod. Then there were the great figures upon
            the dial-plate—how intelligent, how intellectual, they all
            looked ! And presently they took to dancing the Mauzurka,
            and I think it was the figure V who performed the most to
            my satisfaction. She was evidently a lady of breeding.
            None of your swaggerers, and nothing at all indelicate in
            her motions. She did the pirouette to admiration—whirling round upon her apex. I made an endeavor to hand her
            a chair, for I saw that she appeared fatigued with her exertions—and it was not until then that I fully perceived my
            lamentable situation. Lamentable indeed ! The bar had
            buried itself two inches in my neck. I was aroused to a
            sense of exquisite pain. I prayed for death, and, in the agony
            of the moment, could not help repeating those exquisite verses of the poet Miguel De Cervantes:	
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Vanny Buren, tan escondida
            <br>Query no te senty venny	
            <br>Pork and pleasure, delly morry	
            <br>Nommy, torny, darry, widdy !
         </div>
         
         <p>But now a new horror presented itself, and one indeed sufficient to startle the strongest nerves. My eyes, from the 
            cruel pressure of the machine, were absolutely starting from 
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            their sockets. While I was thinking how I should possibly
             manage without them, one actually tumbled out of my head,
             and, rolling down the steep side of the steeple, lodged in the
             rain gutter which ran along the eaves of the main building.
             The loss of the eye was not so much as the insolent air of
             independence and contempt with which it regarded me after
             it was out. There it lay in the gutter just under my nose,
             and the airs it gave itself would have been ridiculous had
             they not been disgusting. Such a winking and blinking
             were never before seen. This behaviour on the part of my
             eye in the gutter was not only irritating on account of its
            manifest insolence and shameful ingratitude, but was also exceedingly inconvenient on account of the sympathy which always exists between two eyes of the same head, however far
            apart. I was forced, in a manner, to wink and to blink, whether I would or not, in exact concert with the scoundrelly
            thing that lay just under my nose. I was presently relieved,
            however, by the dropping out of the other eye. In falling it
            took the same direction (possibly a concerted plot) as its fellow. Both rolled out of the gutter together, and in truth I 
            was very glad to get rid of them.
         </p>
         
         <p>The bar was now four inches and a half deep in my neck,
            and there was only a little bit of skin to cut through. My
            sensations were those of entire happiness, for I felt that in a
            few minutes, at farthest, I should be relieved from my disa greeable situation. And in this expectation I was not at all
             deceived. At twenty-five minutes past five in the afternoon
            precisely, the huge minute-hand had proceeded sufficiently
            far on its terrible revolution to sever the small remainder of
            my neck. I was not sorry to see the head which had occasioned me so much embarrassment at length make a final separation from my body. It first rolled down the side of the
            steeple, then lodged, for a few seconds, in the gutter, and
            then made its way, with a plunge, into the middle of the
             street.
         </p>
         
         <p>I will candidly confess that my feelings were now of the
            most singular—nay of the most mysterious, the most perplex ing and incomprehensible character. My senses were here
            and there at one and the same moment. With my head I
            imagined, at one time, that I the head, was the real Signora
             Psyche Zenobia—at another I felt convinced that myself, the
            body, was the proper identity. To clear my ideas upon this
            topic I felt in my pocket for my snuff-box, but, upon getting
            it, and endeavoring to apply a pinch of its grateful contents
            in the ordinary manner, I became immediately aware of my
            peculiar deficiency, and threw the box at once down to my
            head. It took a pinch with great satisfaction, and smiled
            me an acknowledgement in return. Shortly afterwards it
            made me a speech, which I could hear but indistinctly without ears. I gathered enough, however, to know that it was
            astonished at my wishing to remain alive under such circumstances. In the concluding sentences it quoted the noble
            words of Ariosto—
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Il pover hommy che non sera corty
            <br>And have a combat tenty erry morty.
         </div>
         
         <p>thus comparing me to the hero who, in the heat of the combat, not perceiving that he was dead, continued to contest
            the battle with inextinguishable valor. There was nothing
            now to prevent my getting down from my elevation, and I
            did so. What it was that Pompey saw so very peculiar
            in my appearance I have never yet been able to find out.
            The fellow opened his mouth from ear to ear, and shut his two
            eyes as if he were endeavoring to crack nuts between the lids.
            Finally, throwing off his overcoat, he made one spring for
            the staircase and disappeared. I hurled after the scoundrel those vehement words of Demosthenes—
         </p>
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page7"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div class="ab">Andrew O' Phlegethon, you really make haste to fly,</div>
         
         <p>and then turned to the darling of my heart, to the one-eyed!
            the shaggy-haired Diana. Alas ! what horrible vision affronted my eyes ? Was that a rat I saw skulking into his
            hole ? Are these the picked bones of the little angel who
            has been cruelly devoured by the monster ? Ye Gods! and
            what do I behold—is that the departed spirit, the shade, the
            ghost of my beloved puppy, which I perceive sitting with
            a grace so melancholy, in the corner ? Harken ! for she
            speaks, and, heavens! it is in the German of Schiller—
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>"Unt stubby duk, so stubby dun
            <br>Duk she ! duk she !”
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Alas !—and are not her words too true ?</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>And if I died at least I died
            <br>For thee—for thee.
         </div>
         
         <p>Sweet creature ! she too has sacrificed herself in my behalf
            Dogless, niggerless, headless, what now remains for the unhappy Signora Psyche Zenobia ?	Alas—nothing!	I have
            done.
         </p>
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">THE DEPARTED.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Where the river ever floweth,
            <br>Where the green grass ever groweth.
            <br>Where each star most faintly gloweth,
            <br>Do I wander on;
            <br>My thick pulses hastily beating.
            <br>My quick glances now retreating,
            <br>And, with bold advance, now meeting.
            <br>Shadows of the gone !
            <br>Lonely, by that lovely river,
            <br>Where the moon-lit blossoms quiver,
            <br>Do I wander on forever,
            <br>Musing on the past;
            <br>When the weary moon descendeth.
            <br>When each pals star earthward bendeth.
            <br>Then my soul strong memories sendeth,—
            
            <br>Joys too bright to last!
            <br>She, earth’s bright and loveliest flower,
            <br>Spirit, cooped in mortal bower,
            <br>She, whose voice alone bad power
            <br>O’er my soul, is gone!
            <br>Vain, oh! vain, are tears and wailing.
            <br>Fierce deep grief is unavailing,
            <br>Yet are they my heart assailing,—
            <br>Proud heart, never won !
            <br>By that river, ever flowing.
            <br>With heaven’s light upon her glowing.
            <br>Sometimes comes she to me, showing
            <br>Things past and to come.
            <br>And we wander on. caressing,
            <br>While the mute earth sheds her blessing
            <br>Happy in that dim possessing,
            <br>Spirits in the gloom !
            <br>Were it not for that dim meeting.
            <br>Were it not for that dark greeting.
            <br>Its own core my wild heart eating,
            <br>Soon would turn to clay.
            <br>Now along that lonely river.
            <br>Lonely do I wander ever,
            <br>Where the nightly blossoms shiver,—
            <br>Dark and sad as they !
         </div>
      </div>
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">CRITICAL NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Coming of the Mammoth—the Funeral of Time, and
               other Poems, by Henry B. Hirst, Boston: Philips &amp;
               Sampson.
            </div>
            
            <p>Mr. Hirst is a young lawyer of Philadelphia—admitted to
               practice, we believe, about two years ago, and already deriving a very respectable income from his profession. Some
               years since, his name was frequency seen in the contenttables of our Magazines, but latterly the duties of his profession seem to have withdrawn him from literary pursuits.
               He has, nevertheless, done quite right in collecting his fugitive poems, and giving them to the public in a convenient
               and durable form. The day has happily gone by when a
               practitioner at the bar has anything to fear from its being understood that he is capable of inditing a good sonnet.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have no hesitation in saying that Mr. Hirst has not
               only given indication of poetical genius, but that he has
               composed some very commendable poems. His imagination
               is vigorous, bold, and at the same time delicate. His sense
               of the true provinces of poetical art is remarkably keen and
               discriminating, and his versification is superior to that of
               any American poet. We perhaps should qualify this latter
               remark by observing that his knowledge of the principles of
               the metrical art is more profound and more accurate than
               that of any American poet—but that his knowledge too frequently leads him into the pedantry of hyperism. He is apt
               to overdo a good thing. He insists upon rhythmical and metrical effects until they cease to have any effect at all—or
               until they give to his compositions an air of mere oddity.—
               His other defects are, chiefly, a want of constructive ability,
               occasional extravagance of expression, and a far more than
               occasional imitativeness. This last sin, is, in poetry, never to
               be forgiven, and we are sorry to say that Mr. Hirst is inordinately given to it. There is not a single poem in the beautifully printed volume before us which does not remind us,
               instantly, of some other composition. If we except some
               rhythmical effects (for which the author deserves great
               praise) there is nothing in the book which is fairly entitled
               to be called original, either in its conception, execution, or
               manner, as a whole. Of detached thoughts, nevertheless,
               there are many very striking ones which are quite new, for
               any evidence that we have to the contrary.
            </p>
            
            <p>As very usually happens in a case of this kind, the leading and longest poem of the collection is the least worthy of
               notice. It is called “The Coming of the Mammoth,” and,
               to say nothing of its being a mere paraphrase, in all its most
               striking points, of Mr. Mathews’ “ Behemoth,” is feebly and
               incoherently narrated—narrated, indeed, very much as a
               schoolboy would narrate it. In fact, we understand that it
               is one of the earliest compositions of the author, who began
               to write at a very immature age.
            </p>
            
            <p>The story runs simply thus. The aborigines are suddenly
               startled from the quiet of ages, by the apparition of “ myriad forms” of the mammoths. These creatures carry death
               and desolation every where—destroying vegetation, and animal life wherever they pass. The extravagance with which
               their nature is delineated, may be instanced by one stanza:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"> <br> We saw them hunt the buffalo,
               <br>And crush them with their tusks of steel;
               <br>The mountains rocking to and fro
               <br>Like trees that in the tempest reel,
               <br>When passed their herds; and lake and river
               <br>A draught of theirs made dry forever.
            </div>
            
            <p>The aborigines themselves fall a prey and are reduced to
               a small band, when they bethink them of supplicating the
               aid of Moneddo (Manitou) who forthwith attacks the rava-
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page8"></div>
               gers with lightning, and destroys them all but one.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Bolt rushed on bolt till, one by one,
               <br>Howling in agony, they died,
               <br>Save him, the fiercest! And alone
               <br>He stood—almost a God in pride—
               <br>Then with a loud defying yell
               <br>Leapt, like a shaft, o’er hill and dell.
            </div>
            
            <p>He flies at great speed ; the lightnings and the Indians
               still pursuing. He reaches the Mississippi—leaps it at one
               bound (possibly at a point not very far from the source)
               and is at last brought up by the Rocky Mountains—but only
               for a few moments—he ascends the highest peak—throws
               rocks and trees “ in the face of God ” and fairly defies him,
               until at length the “ mightiest spirits ” are summoned to
               put an end to the contest:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">  <br>They heard : with one tremendous crash
               <br>Down on the Mammoth’s forehead came
               <br>A surging sea of withering flame.
               <br>Earth trembled to its core ; and weak
               <br>But unsubdued the Mammoth leapt
               <br>Furiously from that lofty peak
               <br>To where the dark blue ocean swept.
               <br>Down ! down ! The startled waters sever ;
               <br>Then roll above him—and forever!
            </div>
            
            <p>Our readers will agree with us that from the summit of
               the Rocky Mountains to the Pacific, is a tolerably long leap 
               even for a Mammoth—although he had had some previous 
               practice in jumping the Mississippi.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are not extravagant in saying (are we?) that the 
                "Coming of the Mammoth” which might as well have 
               been called the “ Coming and the Going of the Mammoth” 
               is the most preposterous of all the preposterous poems ever 
               deliberately printed by a gentleman arrived at the years of
               discretion. Nor has it one individual point of redeeming
               merit. Had Mr. Hirst written only this we should have
               thrown his book to the pigs without comment.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ The Funeral of Time" is a forcible allegory, very indistinctly made out, but well versified in some respects, and
               filled with majestic images—although disfigured, too often,
               by something even more mad than Nat Leeism.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Isabelle ” is the finest ballad ever written in this country, and but for its obvious and no doubt intentional imitations, might be called one of the best ever written anywhere.
               It is indeed exceedingly difficult to understand how the
               author of such trash as “ The Mammoth ” could be at the
               same time author of anything so widely different as “Isabelle.” Its simplicity is exquisite—its conduct could not be
               improved—and its versification (within the narrow limits
               designed) is full of original force. We quote (unconnected-
               ly) a few of the best quatrains:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>A lustrous maid was Isabelle,
               <br>And quiet as a brooding bird ;
               <br>She never thought of passion’s spell—
               <br>Of love she never heard ;
               <br>But in her lonely chamber sat,
               <br>Sighing the weary hours away
               <br>From morn till flitting of the bat
               <br>Around the turrets gray.
               <br>And trembling with a strange unrest—
               <br>A yearning for—she knew not what ;
               <br>She only knew her heaving breast
               <br>Was heavy with its lot.
               <br>At last she passed to womanhood,
               <br>And sat her down on Beauty’s throne,
               <br>A statue with a beating heart
               <br>Beneath a breast of stone.
               <br>Her lustrous eyes grew large with love ;
               <br>Her cheeks with passion flushed and bright;
               <br>Her lips, whereon no bee might rove
               <br>Undrunken with delight,
               <br>Were, &amp;c.
               <br>She felt she bad not lived in vain ;
               <br>She saw the Eden of her dreams
               <br>Close round her, and she stood again
               <br>Beside its silver streams.
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               <br>The servants followed her with their eyes,
               <br>And prayed the virgin that her hours
               <br>Might ever pass under azure skies
               <br>And over parterres of flowers.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ Geraldine ” is a far better poem than “ Isabelle ” and is
               unquestionably the best in the volume. It is, however, in
               manner a palpable imitation of Tennyson. In justice to Mr.
               Hirst we quote it in full:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>The martins twitter round the eaves,
               <br>The swift adown the chimney glides,
               <br>The bees are humming ’mid the leaves
               <br>Along the garden side ;
               <br>The robin whistles in the wood,
               <br>The linnet on the vane,
               <br>And down the alder-margined lane
               <br>The throstle sings, and by the flood
               <br>The plover pipes again.
               <br>But ah—alas alas ! no more
               <br>Their merry melodies delight ;
               <br>No more along the river’s shore
               <br>I watch the swallow’s flight:
               <br>And bees may hum and birds may sing,
               <br>And silver streamlets shine,
               <br>But on the rocks I sit and pine
               <br>Unheeding all; for thought will cling
               <br>To naught but Geraldine.
               <br>Oh, Geraldine ! my life, my love !
               
               <br>  I only wander where we met
               <br>In emerald days, when blue above
               <br>The skies were o’er us set—
               <br>  Along the glen and o’er the vale
               <br>And by the willow tree
               <br>I wander where at even with thee
               <br>I sang the song and told the tale
               <br>Of olden chivalry.
               <br>  I stand beneath the sombre pines
               <br>That darken all thy father’s hall,
               <br>Begirt with noisome ivy vines
               <br>That shroud me like a pall.
               <br>Aye there !—where ruin frowns around !
               <br>Until the cock doth crow
               <br>I watch thy window-panes below,
               <br>Upon the sodden blackened ground
               <br>Where nothing good will grow.
               <br>I’ve watched thy lattice as before
               <br>To see the glimmer dimly pass,
               <br>(When thou wouldst open thy chamber door)
               <br>Of lamp-light on the glass ;
               <br>But none from out thy lattice peeps,
               <br>And all within is gloom,
               <br>And silent as a vacant tomb,
               <br>Save when a bat affrighted cheeps
               <br>In some deserted room.
               <br>Why comest thou not? Night after night,
               <br>For many a long and weary year,
               <br>’Neath many and many a May-moon’s light,
               <br>I’ve waited for thee here.
               <br>Aye blackest night and wildest storm
               <br>When frowning in the sky
               <br>Have looked on me with lightning eye,
               <br>And charnel figures round my form
               <br>Have gleamed and hurried by.
               <br>Why comest thou not ? or wilt thou soon ?
               <br>The crimson sun doth wax and wane
               <br>Day after day; the yellow moon
               <br>Gildeth thy casement pane
               <br>Night after night; the stars are pale
               <br>Expecting thee ; the breeze
               <br>Rustling among the dreary trees
               <br>Sighs for thee with a woful wail
               <br>Who art beyond the seas.
               <br>They tell me thou wilt never come—
               <br>Alas ! that thou art cold and dead,
               <br>And slumbering in the green sea-foam
               <br>Upon some coral bed :—
               <br>That shriekingly thy ship went down
               <br>Beneath the wailing wave,
               <br>And none were near to hear or save—
               <br>And then they weep to see me frown—
               <br>To hear me groan and rave.
               <br>Thou dead ?—no, no !—it cannot be !
               <br>For if thou wast, thy ghost had kept
               <br>The solemn trist thou madest with me
               <br>When all save passion slept—
               <br>  Thy ghost had come and greeted me
               <br>And bade me be at rest;
               <br>And long ere this upon my breast
               <br>The clod had fain : and I with thee
               <br>W'ere roaming ’mid the blest.
            </div>
            
            <p>  “ The Unseen River" is musical, but has the defect of
               being imperfectly made out. Few persons will understand 
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page7"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>that by the river always heard but never seen, until the traveller is overtaken by death, it is the poet’s intention to
               typify Happiness. We quote a fine stanza of which the
               whole is very poetic (in the best sense) and of which the
               concluding line is a specimen of exquisite versification.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>From the valley—from a river
               <br>Which, like many a silver quiver.
               <br>Through the landscape stole in light:—
               <br>From the bushes, shrubs and blossoms—
               <br>Flowers unfolding fragrant bosoms—
               <br>Curled the shadows out of sight,
               <br>Fading like a ghost in air; and ever the river rippled bright.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ The Burial of Eros" is a very effective allegorical poem
               —but all allegories are contemptible:—at least the only two
               which are not contemptible (The Pilgrim’s Progress and
               The Fairy Queen) are admired in despite of themselves (as
               allegories) and in the direct ratio of the possibility of keeping the allegorical meaning out of sight.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ The Sea of the Mind ” is another allegory, or (what is
               less objectionable) an allegorical enigma. It is miserably
               indefinite. Its only merit lies in detached thoughts, and in
               its admirable management of the trochaic rhythm. The
               metre is heptameter catalectic—consisting of seven (trochaic) feet and a final coesura, equivalent. The trochees
               are finely varied, now and then, with dactyls; only the
               most forcible consonants are employed; the richest vowel
               sounds abound; and all the effects of alliteration, with other
               rhythmical effects less common, are skilfully introduced.—
               For example;
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Silvery the ocean singeth over sands of pearly glow ;
               <br>Under its surface shapes are gliding—gliding last or sailing slow—
               <br>Shapes of strange supernal beauty, floating through a fairy wave—
               <br>Fairer, purer, lovelier, brighter than the streams that Iram lave.
            </div>
            
            <p>“The Birth of a Poet” is somewhat like an imitation
               from John Neal's poem of the same title; the commencement, especially, is stolen.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Hirst’s conception throughout is fantastical—not to
               say absurd. The poem, however, is redeemed by one remarkably well-managed quatrain:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Music like what the poet hears
               <br>When, wrapt in harmony, he wings
               <br>His soul away through argent spheres,
               <br>And back their melody brings.
            </div>
            
            <p>The concluding anapoest here beautifully and most appropriately varies the iambic rhythm—making the sound “echo
               the sense.”
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Everard Grey ” is a superb specimen of dactylic trimeter, catalectic on one syllable—three dactyls and one equivalent coesura. E. g.—</p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Time it has passed; and the lady is pale—
               <br>Pale as the lily that lolls on the gale:
               <br>Weary and worn she hath waited for years
               <br>Keeping her grief evergreen with her tears :—
               <br>Years will she tarry—for cold is the clay
               <br>Fettering the form of her Everard Grey.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>“ The Fringilla Melodia ” is truly beautiful throughout,
               possessing a natural force and grace (without effort) which
               would do honor to the most noted poet in the land. We
               quote the first quatrain :
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Happy song-sparrow that on woodland side
               <br>Or by the meadow sits, and ceaseless sings
               <br>His mellow roundelay in russet pride,
               <br>Owning no care between his wings.
            </div>
            
            <p>The “sits” here is not ungrammatical; the sparrow is
               not invoked, The construction is nevertheless a little equivocal.
            </p>
            <p>“The Coming of Autumn" is spirited—but is a little too
                much in the Old King Cole way.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ The Autumn Wind ” has a noble beginning, and as no-
               ble an end—but as a whole is unimpressive.
            </p>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            
            <p>“Eleanore” has no merit at all except the effect of the
               constantly recurring refrain, “ Eleanore !” and this is taken
               'from Tennyson’s “ Oriana.”
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Mary ” has some fine passages—e. g.</p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>He watched each motion of her rustling dress,
               <br>Each lustrous movement of her liquid eyes—
               <br>Envied the air its undisturbed caress
               <br>Of her whose presence was his Paradise.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>“To an Old Oak;” “To E—with a Withered Rose;”
               and “The Death-Song of the Nightingale” have nothing
               in them remarkable—“ Eulalie Vere ” nothing beyond the 
               barroques lines,
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Cheeks where the loveliest of lustres reposes
               <br>On valleys of lilies and mountains of roses.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ To the American Sky-Lark ” is professedly an imitation
               of Bryant's “Waterfowl:” we need, therefore, say nothing
               about it.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ Ellena ” has some glowing thoughts. For example,</p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>at her word
               <br>The hushed air shook, with human passion stirred.
            </div>
            
            <p>And again:</p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>a maniac tune
               <br>Rang in mine ears, like songs sung in a swoon.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ The Coming of Night ” is excellent throughout—if we
               except the grammatical error in the ante-penultimate line.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Oh Blessed Night that comes to rich and poor.
            </div>
            
            <p>Here are two admirable quatrains:</p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Forest and field are still
               <br>Nature seems wrapt in slumber; wholly dumb,
               <br>Save when the frog’s deep bass or beetle's bum,
               <br>Or wailing whippoorwill,
               <br>Disturb her weary ear,
               <br>Or the far falling of the rippling rill
               <br>That sings, while leaping down the silent hill,
               <br>Her dreamless sleep to cheer.
               
            </div>
            <p>“ Violet” is merely an absurd imitation of Barry Cornwall’s
               most absurd Tom-Foolery.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ A Gift” is well versified, but common-place.</p>
            
            <p>“ The Owl" opens with too finely imaginative
               stanzas:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>When twilight fades and evening falls
               <br>Alike on tree and tower,
               <br>And silence, like a pensive maid,
               <br>Walks round each slumbering bower;
               <br>When fragrant flowerets fold their leaves,
               <br>And all is still in sleep,
               <br>The horned owl on moonlit wing
               <br>Flies from the donjon keep.
               <br>And he calls aloud “ too-whit! too-whoo !”
               <br>And the nightingale is still,
               <br>And the pattering step of the hurrying hare
               <br>Is hushed upon the bill;
               <br>And he crouches low in the dewy grass
               <br>As the lord of the night goes by,
               <br>Not with a loudly whirring wing
               <br>But like a lady's sigh.
            </div>
            
            <p>Every critic—at least every poetical critic—will admit
               that the images in these two stanzas are such as only a true
               poet could conceive. At the same time they are embodied
               with much art.
            </p>
            
            <p>“A Song’’ and “Mutius Sccevola” have no particular
               merit. “ The Forsaken” ends with nerve:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Well, go thy way! and never wake
               <br>The feeblest memory of me,
               <br>To wring thy worthless heart! I break
               <br>Thy chains and set thee free.
               <br>Thou to thy mirth ! I to my gloom !
               <br>Health to the coldest of the twain !
               <br>And mine—not thine—the iron doom
               <br>Of having loved in vain.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ The Lament of Adam” is chiefly remarkable for the effect of its versification—not altogether original, to be sure,
               but rare, and very forcible when well-managed. The
               rhythm is dactylic, the lines terminating with equivalent
               caesuras. The metre is generally tetrameter, catalectic on
               one syllable (the exsura forming the catalexis)—but the
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page10"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               lines increase towards the closing of the stanzas, and in one
               instance are hexameter catalectic. We give the last stanza:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Life hath its pleasures—but perishing they as the flowers :
               <br>Sin hath its sorrows; and, sighing we turned from those bowers:
               <br>Bright were the angels behind with their falchions of heavenly 
               <br>flame :
               <br>Dark was the desolate desert before us, but darker the depth of our
               <br>shame.
            </div>
            
            <p>Here the alliteration is too obvious—quite overdone, and
               is an instance of the hyperism to which we alluded in the
               beginning of our notice.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ The Statue-Love” is not very good.</p>
            
            <p>“ May” is a remarkably line poem, with an exquisite close:</p>
            
            <div class="lg"> <br>---the passionate bard
               <br>Wanders away through sylvan lonelinesses,
               <br>Alive with love—his heart a silver river
               <br>On which the swan of song floats gracefully for ever.
            </div>
            
            <p>“Dramatic Fragments” are worth nothing. “ The Song 
               of the Scald Biorne” is, to our astonishment, badly versified. 
               How comes Mr. Hirst in an anapaestic rhythm, or in any
               rhythm, with such a verse as—
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>My iron hand on her arm when before her I knelt ?
               
            </div>
            
            <p>“Summer” is quite feeble.</p>
            
            <p>Twenty well-constructed sonnets conclude the volume.
               Among these, Bethlehem” and “ Dead Man’s Island” may
               be cited as particularly good : but by way of finale to our review we quote “ Astarte” as the best.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>Thy lustre, heavenly star ! shines ever on me.
               <br>I, trembling like Endymion over-bent
               <br>By dazzling Dian, when with wonderment
               <br>He saw her crescent light the Latmian lea :
               <br>  And like a Naiad’s sailing on the sea,
               <br>Floats thy fair form before me: the azure air
               <br>Is all ambrosial with thy hyacinth hair:
               <br>While round thy lips the moth in airy glee
               <br>Hovers, and hums in dim and dizzy dreams,
               <br>Drunken with odorous breath: thy argent eyes
               <br>(Twin planets swimming through love’s lustrous skies)
               <br>Are mirrored in my heart’s serenest streams—
               <br>Such eyes saw Shakespeare, flashing, bold and bright,
               <br>When Queenly Egypt rode the Nile at night.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Wiley and Putnam's Library of American Books. No. 11.
               Tales by Edgar A. Poe. New York and London : Wiley
               if Putnam.
            </div>
            
            <p>This collection embraces the Gold Bug; the Black Cat;
               Mesmeric Revelation ; Lionizing ; the Fall of the House of
               Usher; the Descent into the Maelstrom; the Colloquy of
               Monosand Una; the conversation of Eiros and Charmion; the
               Murders in the Rue Morgue; the Mystery of Marie Roget;
               the Purloined Letter and the Man of the Crowd. This is a
               selection from about seventy tales, of similar length, written
               by Mr. Poe. No particular arrangement has been made in
               the selection. The stories published in the volume before
               us, are neither better nor worse, in general, than the remainder of the seventy. In the composition of the whole series,
               variety of subject and manner, especially diversity of invention, were the objects held in view. Of course these objects
               are lost sight of, and must necessarily be sacrificed, in any
               mere selection of twelve tales from seventy.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">A System of Latin Versification, in a series of progressive
               exercises, including specimens of translation from English
               and German poetry into Latin verse. For the use of schools
               and colleges. By Charles Anthon, L.L.D., professor of the
               Greek and Latin languages in Columbia College, N. Y.
               New York : Harper and Brothers.
            </div>
            
            <p>This excellent work is intended as a sequel to the Treatise on Latin Prosody, published a few years ago. It is a
               very full and useful manual—useful, that is to say, if we
               can regard the making of Latin verses as in any respect, or
               under any circumstances, as a useful occupation. The materials have been collected from a great variety of sources.
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>As a text book the volume cannot be too highly commended.
               The exercises form a regular and progressive course. A key
               has been prepared, and can be obtained from the publishers
               on personal application. The work is got up in the usual
               admirable manner of Professor Anthon’s Classical Series.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">The Trials of Margaret Lindsay. By John Wilson, author
               of “Lights and Shadows of Scottish Life." Boston:
               Saxton if Kelt. New York: Saxton if Miles.
            </div>
            
            <p>In England and Scotland there is scarcely any book more
               universally popular than this, and we have often wondered
               why it has not been reprinted in this country. The story
               is one of the most intense yet natural interest. The American edition is prefaced with a very judicious commentary
               from the pen of Mr. Hamilton.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">The Foresters. A tale of Domestic Life. By Professor
               Wilson, author, fr. Boston : Saxion &amp; Kelt. New
               York: Saxton &amp; Miles.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ The Foresters” has been nearly, if not quite, as popular
               as The Trials,” and is equally pathetic. The American
               edition of this work, also, has an excellent preface by Mr.
               Hamilton. The two volumes are handsomely printed.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">The Modern British Essayists. Philadelphia: Carey &amp;
               Hart.
            </div>
            
            <p>Messrs. Carey k Hart have issued in three large volumes,
               the Critical and Miscellaneous Essays of Macaulay, Sidney
               Smith, and Allison. Each volume is accompanied with an
               admirable portrait. This collection is invaluable. For sale
               in New York by Messrs. Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Republication of the London, Edinburgh, Foreign and
               Westminster Quarterly Reviews, No. 176. The Westminster Review, No. 85, for June, 1845. American Edition—
               Vol. 20, No. 2. New York : Leonard Scott and Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>We can hardly say too much in praise of the admirable
               neatness and accuracy of Messrs. Scott &amp; Co’s reprints.
               They furnish for the small sum of eight dollars all the four
               invaluable reviews mentioned above—any one of them for
               three dollars—any two for five—any three for seven. The
               June number of the Westminster (just issued) contains many
               deeply interesting papers—among others, “ Old and New
               London,” and an examination of Mrs. Norton’s “ Child of
               the Islands.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The London Lancet for July. New York: Burgess,
               Stringer and Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>The July number commences the second volume of the
               New Series of this excellent work. Messrs. B. &amp; S. have still
               for sale a few copies of the first volume.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">THE MAGAZINES.</div>
         
         <p>The American Review for July has some very admirable
            papers, among which we notice especially “ Marshal Macdonald by the clever author of “ Letters from Italy,” and a
            discriminative review of Mr. Griswold’s “ Poets and Poetry
            of England,” by Mr. Whipple, undoubtedly one of our finest
            critics. We are truly delighted to find him so keenly appreciating the magnificent genius of Tennyson. This number
            contains, also, a poem, “ The Gods of Old" which does high
            credit to its author, Mr. Wm. Wallace. Speaking of it the
            editor of the Review says:—
         </p>
         
         <p>The following highly imaginative poem adds a third to the list on
            a beautilul and suggestive subject. It is a little remarkable that nei.
            ther of them bears any resemblance in the conception or execution.
            Miss Barrett’s idea is the absolute death of the ancient Divinities—
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page11"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            Schiller laments the decay of their influence—the following Ode is
            based on their continued existence as poetical creations which delight
            the human mind.—
         </p>
         
         <p>It cannot be doubted that Mr. Wallace's conception is the
            best of the three, and he has handled it in a masterly manner. We quote the concluding stanza.
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">V.
            <br>Like far off stars that glimmer in a cloud,
            <br>Deathless, O Gods ! shall ye illume the past:
            <br>To ye the Poet-Voice will cry aloud,
            <br>Faithful among the faithless to the last:—
            <br>Ye must not die !
            <br>Long as the dim robes of the Ages trail
            <br>O’er Delphi’s steep or Tempe’s flowery vale—
            <br>An awful Throng—
            <br>Borne upward on the sounding wings of Song
            <br>That cast the Beautiful o’er Land, o’er Sea,
            <br>Ye shall not die :
            <br>Though Time and storm your calm, old temples rend,
            <br>And, rightly, men to the “ One Only” bend—
            <br>Your Realm is Memory !
         </div>
         
         <p>The Knickerbocker for July has also some meritorious contributions—but neither man nor devil can dissuade its editor
            from a monthly farrago of type so small as to be nearly invisible, and so stupid as to make us wish it were quite so.
            In three lines devoted to the “Broadway Journal” intended
            to be complimentary, we believe, although we sincerely hope
            not, he makes use of what he supposes to be a French proverb, and writes it Chacun a son gout, taking great pains to
            place a grave accent on the verb, mistaking it for the preposition, and complimenting the hard c with a cedilla. Within
            the compass of the same three lines, he talks about a nil admirari critic ; some person, we presume, having quizzed
            him with the information that the meaning of nil admirari
            is " to admire nothing.” We certainly do not admire Mr.
            Clarke—nor his wig—but the true English of the Latin
            phrase is “to wonder at nothing,” and we plead guilty to
            having wondered at nothing since we have found the Knickerbocker sinking day by day in the public opinion in despite
            of the brilliant abilities and thoroughly liberal education of
            Mr. Lewis Gaylord Clarke.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">MUSICAL DEPARTMENT.</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">French Opera at the Park.</div>
            
            <p>—Since our last notice of
               this establishment, Donizetti’s opera La Favorite, Auber’s
               Le Domino Noir, and Mayerbeer’s Robert Le Diable, have
               been produced, each of them with considerable success.
               Regardnig the audience, one peculiarity must be observed
               and commented upon by everybody. Although the cress
               circle is frequently crowded at a dollar, and the upper tier
               filled to overflowing at fifty cents admission, yet the doomed
               parquette rarely contains more than forty persons, thus proving beyond dispute the wholesomeness of the advice proffered 
               in our last number. If the price of admission to the parquette were reduced to fifty cents, the receipts of the house
               would be increased from fifty to a hundred dollars per night.
               We should advise Mr. Davis to drop the dignity and look
               to the profit. La Favorite is the first on our list. It is a
               grand opera seria, and contains many striking beauties peculiar to Donizetti. The Andantes are generally of a chaste,
               sweet, and tender character; and if they do not possess any
               originality particularly striking, they are yet earnest, and
               full of passion. There is a quartette in the second act, we 
               believe, which is a most charming subject, but its close is
               strained, inharmonious, and by no means appropriate. The
               chorus of Signori in the third act is characteristic, spirited, 
               and full of point. It was well sung—indeed we might say,
               admirably well: short, stern, and precise, the manner was
               worthy of the matter. Indeed, we can not praise its per
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>formance too highly, and the public were of our opinion,
               for they encored it upon each occasion. The finales do not
               call for much remark. They ate chiefly noticeable for great
               noise and want of clearness. The instrumentation is, generally, very poor and thin, but some passages of exceeding
               beauty relieved what else would have been monotonous
               insipidity.
            </p>
            
            <p>The plot of the opera is full of dramatic interest and striking situations. The scene is laid in Spain during the reign
               of Charles XI. and the story turns upon a (supposed) circumstance in the life of his famous favorite, Leonora de Guseman.
            </p>
            
            <p>Fernand, a youth of patrician birth, is a neophite in the
               monastesy. He sees Leonora as she comes to pray in the
               chapel, and becomes enamored of her. She is also struck
               by his noble appearance, and determines that he shall not
               become a monk. She procures for hint a captain’s commission, and he leaves the monastery. Fernand is introduced
               to Lenora at court the next day, but is not aware of her position with the king. They become deeply attached, and
               are only aroused from their dream of love by an order for
               Fernand to join the army. He leaves her with regret, but
               returns covered with the glory which his daring courage and
               good fortune in the wars have won for him. The king distinguishes him with extraordinary favor; and Fernand emboldened by his kindness, asks for the hand of Leonora. This,
               too, the king grants; and they are wedded. On their rereturn from the alter, he seeks for congratulation from his
               friends; but they turn from him with sullen looks and gestures. He asks an explanation. They tell him he has married the king’s mistress. He is overwhelmed with astonishment, sorrow, and anger. At this moment the king and Leonora enter. Fernand casts the king’s gifts on the ground,
               repudiates his wife, and rushes out with the friendly monk.
               We next see he him as a shaven monk, he having assumed
               the cowl on the discovery of Leonora’s falsehood. Leonora,
               humbled and repentant, leaves the court, and, arriving at
               the monastery, distinguishes Fernald’s voice among the singers. Shrieking out his name, she falls upon the steps of
               cross, overcome by surprise and fatigue. He rushes from
               the church ; discovers Leonora ; a reconciliation takes place,
               and she dies in his arms, happy in being loved and forgiven.
            </p>
            
            <p>Although we sincerely acknowledge Calve to be an especial favourite with us, yet are we compelled to say that
               in Leonora de Guzman she disappointed us. We did not expect
               much, but even our moderate expectations were unfulfilled.
               She sang with her usual lightness, delicacy, and finish ;
               she dressed to admiration, and she looked very charming,
               but she was by no means the character she assumed. She
               lacked dignity of carriage, force and earnestness—in expression and feeling. In the lighter operas of Auber and Donizetti, she has but one rival this side the ocean, but she
               should not attempt opera seria.
            </p>
            
            <p>Arnaud, as we predicted, is gaining rapidly in public favour. His pure school of singing could not fail to make
               ample amends for the unpleasant quality of his voice. He
               sung throughout in a most artistical style. His acting lacks
               passion, but it is scarcely observable, so deep and earnest
               is the feeling he imparts to his singing.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Garry, also, fully justifies our favorable opinion. He occasionally indulges in a coarse and forced method of delivery,
               but as a general thing, his style is good, emphatic, and
               earnest.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Douvy, as the priest, acquitted himself in a very creditable manner, with the exception that occasionally he was
               most painfully out of tune.
            </p>
            
            <p>The band, as usual, formed the most delightful feature in
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page12"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               the evening’s entertainment. Its performance was admira- 
               ble throughout the evening. Prevost did all that a fine leader
               should do, and the band seconded his efforts to the very
               letter.
            </p>
            
            <p>The opera was, in every respect, beautifully put upon the 
               stage. It forms a splendid contrast to the usual style of 
               producing operas in this city. Let those who bring out
               English opera bear this in mind.
            </p>
            
            <p>Le Domino Noir met with distinguished success when 
               the French company were here, two years ago. The music
               indeed is of that light and fascinating character which hits 
               the popular taste at once. It abounds with delicious melodies, and clever concerted pieces, whose quaintness and 
               originality possess a charm, which increases in power the
               more familiar the hearer becomes with the music. Auber
               is a great and true artist, he is not appreciated, out of Paris,
               as he should be, but the time is fast approaching when he
               will be as dear to the lovers of music in this country as a
               familiar household god. The instrumentation of Le Domino
               Noir is light, sparkling, novel and ingenious, and was executed by the orchestra in a manner worthy of its excellence. 
            </p>
            
            <p>Mad'lle Calve was in this opera most entirely at home, 
               whether as the lady or the simple country maiden ; in the
               one she was all grace, elegance and refinement—in the other,
               simple, arch, and natural. Her singing was equally to be
               praised throughout, but more especially in the second act,
               when repeated bursts of applause testified the delight and
               approbation of the audience.
            </p>
            
            <p>Madame Cceuriot is also entitled to our warm commendation. She sang well, acted well, dressed well, and in an
               unobtrusive manner, pleasing to behold, she wins her way 
               swiftly and surely into popular favour.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Coeuriot is the very perfection of a French lover. He
               is the breathing semblance of many of Eugene Sue’s
               metaphisical monstrosities. His impetuosity, though it may
               come within probability, is so truly extravagant, that it becomes ridiculous ; we laugh where we should look sad, and
               sympathize with him only as his folly places him in ludicrous positions. But we would not wish to seem to blame
               M. Coeuriot for acting so naturally ; his is the praise—the
               fault lies with the class which he so faithfully represents.
               M. Coeuriot’s singing is also to be highly praised, for he uses
               a voice not too good, like an accomplished artist, and renders with great fidelity all that the composer has apportioned
               him. The choruses were well sung, and the ensemble was
               highly gratifying. We hope to see this opera again.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of Meyerbeer’s great work, Robert le Dioble, we cannot
               speak this week, for our notice of the French Company has
               already extended beyond our usual limits. We will endavour
               to notice it in our next. This much we can say, that it is
               produced upon a magnificent scale, and has met with distinguished success, not more flattering than deserved.
            </p>
            
            <p>We earnestly advise all those of our musical friends who
               have not heard this opera to make sure of the next performance, as it will be withdrawn after a short time.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div> 
            <div class="head">Mr. Fry’s Opera.</div>
            <p>—We regret not having time to attend to
               the Philadelphia papers this week, but we will oblige those we
               have received by noticing them in our next number. Their
               attempts to puff up Mr Fry’s opera would be laughable were
               they not so contemptible.
            </p>
            
            <p>We seem to be the special object of their sublime indignation, and they fume and rave at us with a ferocity truly
               entertaining. The only argument they use, however, to
               prove that our criticism of poor Leonora was no criticism,
               and to prove how impossible it is that we should be able to
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>write a criticism, is the following. We beg our readers to
               forbear laughing while we state it, for the charge is a grave
               charge. The reason why we have not, and why we cannot,
               write a criticism is—that we eat beef! Serious as this
               charge is, and likely as it is to affect our moral and intellectual character, yet, in the beautiful simplicity of our nature, we acknowledge its truth. We do eat beef; and, by
               a singular coincidence, we were dining on beef when the
               papers containing this exterminating charge reached our
               residence. What appetite we had left, after reading them,
               may be better imagined than described.
            </p>
            
            <p>If our modesty were not too painfully oppressive, we
               would suggest that the nerve, bone, and sinew of the criticisms which some folks find so difficult to digest, owe something to our partiality to that estimable beast from which
               that nourishing article of food, called beef, is derived ; and
               were we not singularly fearful of disturbing the naturally
               amiable tempers of our Philadelphia brethren, we would, in
               all kindness, suggest that, judging from the internal eviidences afforded by their writings, the sustenance of our
               contemporaries consisted of water melons and weak gruel.
            </p>
            
            <p>We acknowledge ourselves overcome ; for, out of all the
               absurdities which they have indited, they have, at last, hit
               upon one startling and important truth. But if we are honest and candid enough to admit that we da live on roasts,
               surely our adversaries, who labour so hard and so vainly to
               write up a reputation, with like ingenuousnous, will acknowledge having frequently feasted on Fries !
            </p>
            
            <p>The foregoing remarks were in type last week, but were
               unfortunately crowded out. It was our intention to refer, at
               length, to two of the Philadelphia papers, so enviably prominent in abusing us; but, on looking them through, we
               find that they contain little else but vulgar personalities and
               low abuse; and, as we cannot reply in the same strain, we
               shall, after a few remarks, dismiss the subject for the present.
            </p>
            
            <p>The person who signs himself Colley Cibber, and accuses
               us of being English and eating beef, commenced his defence
               of Leonora in the most grandiloqnent style, talking of Memory’s Lake, &amp;c., &amp;c., and promised, in his next communication, to analize, dissect, dismember—nay, to reduce our
               criticism to very dust. Although Colley Cibber gave but
               little evidence of common sense or moderate understanding
               of his subject, we were in hopes that, what with friendly
               promptings and laborious researches in Burrowes’ primer or
               Hunter's instruction book, we say we hoped that the person
               with the English alias wonld hit upon something which
               would jastify a reply. But his second article is a ridiculous
               rambling rhodomontade, without point, order, or argument.
               It is evident that Mr. Cibber has read our critique udon Leonora, and has fallen upon no point on which he could found
               a reasonable objection, or support a contrary argument. In
               this dilemma, he has, fortunately as he supposes, run his
               head against what he calls a contradiction in our critique.
               We will quote his quotation, in order that he may have the
               full benefit of his discovery, and for the purpose of allowing
               our readers to judge themselves of (he vast analytical powers
               of this critic upon critics:
            </p>
            
            <p>“ It is generally conceded that the great emotions which
               agitate the human heart—love, jealousy, hatred, and revenge
               —demand no conventional mode of expression ; they owe to
               no rule their intensity of feeling ; they speak in a language
               which is universal; and, whether it be the Spaniard or the
               Englishman, the Italian or the German, these amotions
               spring right up from the heart, and are dependent for the
               truthfulness of expression upon the genius or inspiration of
               the composer." Mr. Colley Cibber says: “Well, let that
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page13"></div>
               pass; but see how this learned critic contradicts himself.”
               Now for the contradiction. “There is a rule, however,
               which is never departed from by composers of any talent—
               a rule so natural that it must suggest itself to every reflecting
               mind. It is, that all ballads, dances, and simple chorusses,
               should be purely and entirely national. The national music
               of every country is faithfully portrayed in its ballads and
               dances; and if these do not partake of the national character,
               the scene might as well be laid in Russia as in France, or
               in China as in Spain.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Our readers, we believe, will be as much puzzled as we
               have been to discover in what particular one quotation contradicts the other. The truth is plain enough that Mr.
               Somebody, alias Mr. Colley Cibber, undertook a task which
               he had not the capacity to accomplish.
            </p>
            
            <p>Some papers have thrown out a doubt as to our having
               been present at the performance of Leonora; others insinuate that we were actuated, in our remarks, by ill feeling towards the composer. To the first, we reply that we visited
               Philadelphia for the express purpose of hearing the opera :
               and to the last, that, having spoken to Mr. Fry but once,
               and then only for five minutes, we could not possibly entertain any ill will towards the gentleman. It is well known
               to all with whom we spoke, previous to our visit to Philadelphia, how earnest we were in the hope of being able to
               praise this work: nothing less would have induced us to incur the expense and loss of time attendant upon the journey.
               But, having heard it, we were bound to express ourself according to its merits. We did so without fear and without
               prejudice, and hence the fuss made by injudicious friends
               and partizans.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head"> Pianofortes.</div>
            <p>—Last week we were requested by Mr. T.
               H. Chambers to call at his store, 385 Broadway, and examine a pianoforte which he was about to send into Virginia.
               We found the instrument everyway worthy our attention.
               Its compass was seven octaves, and its quality of tone was
               very fine, rich and powerful, clear and brilliant, and equal
               throughout the scale. The touch was light, but so well
               balanced, that almost any amount of power could be procured. The case was elegant and carefully finished—in
               short, it was in every way a fine instrument, and the gentleman who has purchased it will find that he has invested
               his money to advantage.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">TOWN AMUSEMENT IN SUMMER.
            THE ETHIOPIAN MUSIC.
         </div>
         
         <p>Though the fashionable American world would fain persuade us, that ‘ all the world is out of town,’ at this season,
            in palpable imitation of the English world of fashion,<span class="anchor" id="a001"><a href="#n001"> Link </a></span> yet,
            as the streets appear tolerably full, and as the public places
            are not altogether empty : as we happen to know a few
            ladies and as many gentlemen, who happen to be still remaining in town; we take it for granted our readers may
            know a few also, and hence, by a simple act of addition and
            multiplication, a pretty fair body of intelligent, clever, social
            persons may be collected, who require some rational public
            amusements. To these we address this general and rambling paper.
         </p>
         
         <p>The theatres proper, ought to be closed all the summer,
            they are open until quite too late in the season. The extreme
            heat, together with the blaze of light and a crowded audience, destroy any gratification to be derive from any perfor
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>mances on the stage. The French company at the Park,
            draw now select houses: chiefly of their countrymen and
            countrywomen. But they will do better at Niblo’s by-and
            by, in a light, airy, open place, and with reduced price. The
            Bowery and Chatham, ought to give way also, for the same
            reason as the Park, to which might be added the reasons that tragedy in hot weather is altogether too tropical, unless, it be the farce of that name. It is too exciting,
            makes too much and too heavy demands on the attention and
            feelings. So too of farces that makes one laugh too loud and
            long. It is almost as bad as high tragedy, yet not so simulating. Circus performances are a nuisance ; the least public sympathy on the part of the audience converting the
            contortions of the performers into absolute martyrdom. The
            other actors deal too much in horse play.
         </p>
         
         <p>The museums would do well enough: they give you (at
            the least) far more than the value of your entrance money,
            but they are crowded to suffocation, and by the extreme radical party, the great unwashed and unterrified Democracy.
         </p>
         
         <p>If the legitimate drama be too heavy for summer, so is almost everything in the shape of intellectual amusement. Good
            elocutionists, like Simmons and Mrs. Mowatt, draw select
            audiences. Full lectures do not go down at all now. If they
            do badly in January, they are dead failures in July.
         </p>
         
         <p>Vaudeville, the lightest farce, Fairy Spectacles, &amp;c., such
            as Niblo gives one, are the only dramatic performances suited
            to summer. Concerts, at Castle Garden, are best of all, out
            of doors, and are, perhaps, at once, the healthiest and most
            agreeable of all public amusements. And this brings us to
            the principal topic we meant to touch upon.
         </p>
         
         <p>Ethiopian Melodies have been for the past year or two
            unanimously popular. Last summer, in particular, the
            Plantation Niggers threatened to overthrow Rossini himself,
            and Wark in Steben, fairly competed, in popular esteem,
            with una voce poco fa.
         </p>
         
         <p>Dandy Jim and Tom Rice, became the avowed rivals of
            Auber and Mendelssohn. Nor could we tell, last summer,
            where this enthusiasm would stop. But, now, the taste for
            these native airs is on the decline, since we have been fed
            on the foreign graces of the Italian opera during the winter.
            Or rather, we ought perhaps to say that the liking for
            this class of music, is settling down into a national fondness
            for a certain species of homebred rustic melody. In truth,
            the Ethiopian is our only national music, strictly; and the
            sunny South, in both hemispheres, is the true region of mirth
            and song and the dance—equally, in America and Europe, the
            land of gallantry and generous qualities of all kinds ; the
            home of hospitality ; the fountain of courtesy; the meridian
            of luxury and voluptuousness.
         </p>
         
         <p>This school of music, for such it is fast becoming, is truly
            national and truly democratic. It has its home among the
            slaves, and fairly represents their amusements, character,
            and social condition. It combines drollery with feeling; a
            peculiar broad (almost burlesque) humor, with a natural vein
            of pathos: of this mixed character are most of the songs,
            while the dancing airs are as near perfection in their way
            [we may call it a low way, if we please, and tell the truth,]
            as any music in the world. The negro has an instinctive
            love of music, a capital ear, and the most accurate idea of
            lime. Without any scientific knowledge of the art, he will
            whistle or fiddle an air, with the utmost precision, after having heard it played a few times. He is thought to be all
            the better musician, by many, from his (general) want of
            individuality and proneness to imitation. To a certain point,
            he is only clever, but never gets beyond it. The airs, commonly supposed to be indigenous, bear a model somewhere 
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page41"></div>among old English or Scotch songs, or hymn tunes, marches, etc. Yet some of the negro airs, are as old, as the first
            settlement of Georgia by Oglethorpe: some may be older still.
            The air of Gen’l Morris’ song, “On the Lake where droops
            the Willow,” is called a Southern refrain ; yet it is only the
            delightful Scotch original of “ Comin’ thro’ the Rye,” with
            the character of the music altered by playing it, in slower
            time, and thus giving a pathetic caste to an originally
            sprightly air.
         </p>
         
         <p>In speaking of these negro songs, we must be understood
            to refer to the airs, and not to the words commonly adapted
            to them. In general, the libretto of the Ethiopean Opera,
            is as fiat and tasteless, as that of the Stabat. The South is
            still without its Metastasio.
         </p>
         
         <p>Get the airs ;—nothing of a hot summer’s evening can be
            more delightfully soothing in the way of music, than Old Jar
            River and Lucy Neal well played, and for serenades, Long
            Time Ago. Played with expression, the music of these three
            pieces is delicious.
         </p>
         
         <p>For liveliness and sweetness together, what can surpass,
            Dandy Jim, Jim Along Josey, Lucy Long, or the Old Grey
            Goose, Uncle Gabriel, Walk Along John, It Will Never Do
            To Give It Up So, &amp;c. A few of the songs have a stirring
            chorus, that wakes a man up who inclines to doze over an
            Italian Cadenza. Lastly, are Old Dan Tucker, the Boatmen
            Row, and Coming over the Mountain, (a good thing.)
         </p>
         
         <p>We do n’t pretend to enumerate a quarter of the fine airs.
            The only genuine negro songs we have heard, in this city,
            are “Good News, Tena” “Lynchburg Town” and “Walk in
            Heben,” songs to be heard only from the really original band
            of Dan Emmit, who performed at the Chatham Circus last
            season. The other bands, (there are at least ten) contain
            some good, but more indifferent performers who distort broad
            humour into the most extravagant burlesque. The Serenaders at Palmo's sing well and act cleverly, but they sing
            mostly parodies, and not always the genuine music. Every
            museum and public garden has its band. We heard some
            very clever fellows last summer, on board of a steamboa
            that made trips to the fishing banks; and at Hoboken, also.
            In this company was one of the most original violin players
            we ever saw, who held his bow every way, and fiddled in
            a matchless style. Broken down gentlemen, sporting characters, and all sorts of people, find their way into these
            associations.
         </p>
         
         <p>Many vulgar-minded persons speak of this music as low.
            Such persons (if entitled to judge at all) should disconnect
            the ideas of place and performers, front the music itself. No
            music can be, essentially, degraded, that has in it the elements of truth and simplicity. These essential features
            cannot be mistaken, by however humble minstrels sung, or
            to whatever song they may be unhappily married.
         </p>
         
         <p>Go then, we advise, ye fanatics per la musica, a few times,
            to hear these minstrels! the places they fill, are worth visiting occasionally, for the study of character, and the rich incidents, that sometimes occur in them. Get your wives and
            daughters, or sisters and cousins, to play the airs, repeatedly.
            They will not destroy the taste for pure and fine music;
            though their melody may beget a distaste for the more complete harmonies of the German Muse.
         </p>
         
         <p>Summer is the proper season for hearing this music. It
            accords with the season. You can easily change the scene,
            of a hot evening from the green at Hoboken, or Palmo’s, to a
            southern plantation. You see many from Georgia, the Carolinas, and Alabama among the audience. Out of doors <span class="anchor" id="a002"><a href="#n002"> Link </a></span>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>through the open windows you hear negro voices calling
            ‘ hot corn’ or ‘I—scream.’ In winter, these adjuncts are
            wanting, and the music sounds spiritless, in consequence.
         </p>
         
         <p>The turn for music and dancing in the negro, is wonderful.
            What dancers, what scrapers on the violin, can be made out
            of a fellow who has not three ideas to boast of! The sweeps
            along the streets are vocalists of no mean rank. They sing
            a chaunt, duetts on either side of the way, admirably, and
            whistle to perfection. As to mere time and agility, and
            awkward steps of all kinds gracefully conquered; the negro
            rivals Fanny Ellsler, on the present idol, Cerito.
         </p>	
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">J.</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">THE COLISEUM.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"> <br>Type of the antique Rome ! Rich reliquary
            <br>Of lofty contemplation left to Time
            <br>By buried centuries of pomp and power!
            <br>At length—at length—after so many days
            <br>Of weary pilgrimage and burning thirst,
            <br>(Thirst for the springs of lore that in thee lie,)
            <br>I kneel, an alter’d and an humble man,
            <br>Amid thy shadows, and so drink within
            <br>My very soul thy grandeur gloom and glory !
            <br>Vastness ! and Age ! and Memories of Eld !
            <br>Silence! and Desolation! and dim Night!
            <br>I feel ye now—I feel ye in your strength—
            <br>O spells more sure than e’er Judaenn king
            <br>Taught in the gardens of Gethsemane!
            <br>O charms more potent than the rapt Chaldee
            <br>Ever drew down from out the quiet stars !
            <br>Here, where a hero fell, a column fulls!
            <br>Here, where the mimic eagle glared in gold,
            <br>A midnight vigil holds the swarthy bat!
            <br>Here, where the dames of Rome their gilded hair
            <br>Waved to the wind, now wave the reed and thistle!
            <br>Here, where on golden throne the monarch loll’d,
            <br>Glides, spectre-like unto his marble home,
            <br>Lit by the wan-light of the horned moon.
            <br>The swift and silent lizard of the stones!
            <br>But stay ! these walls—these ivy-clad arcades—
            <br>These mould’ring plinths—these sad and blacken’d shafts—
            <br>These vague entablatures—this crumbling frieze—
            <br>These shatter’d cornices—this wreck—this ruin—
            <br>These stones—alas ! these gray stones—are they all—
            <br>All of the fam’d, and the colossal left
            <br>By the corrosive Hours, to Fate and me?
            <br>“ Not all"—the Echoes answer me—“ not all!
            <br>“ Prophetic sounds and loud, arise forever
            <br>"From us, and from all Ruin, unto the wise,
            <br>“ As melody from Memnou to the Sun.
            <br>“ We rule the hearts of mightiest men—we rule
            <br>“ With a despotic sway all giant minds.
            <br>“ We are net impotent—we pallid stones.
            <br>" Not all our power is gone—not all our fame—
            <br>“ Not all the magic of our high renown—
            <br>“ Not all the wonder that encircles us—
            <br>“ Not all the mysteries that in us lie—
            <br>“ Not all the memories that hung upon
            <br>“ And cling around about us as a garment,
            <br>“ Clothing us in a robe of more than glory."
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">ALEXANDER VON HUMBOLDT’S “COSMOS.”</div>
         
         <p>The publication or Alexander von Humboldt’s “ Cosmos,”
            has engaged the attention of the most distinguished public
            writers in Germany. The late number of the “Deutsche
            Schnellpost ’ contains a critick of the work from Berlin, addressed to the editor of a newspaper in Cologne.
         </p>
         <p>The following is a true translation of it.</p>
         <div class="ab">—Ebs. B. J.</div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page15"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>The first volume of Alexander von Humboldt’s “ Cosmos
            Sketches of a Physical Oosmoarapy,” has just been published, and it is no more than natural that this work should become the topic of the conversation of the day, not only among
            the literary classes, but also the educated generally; and, indeed, for this double reason, that the publication of the
            “ Cosmos,” such as Alexander von Humboldt has treated it,
            is in itself a matter of universal interest, and that this work,
            besides, has a special relation to the more scientific portion
            of society. When in the years 1827 and 1828, the learned 
            author who has traversed the whole world, delivered public
            lectures on Physical Cosmography alternately in the great
            hall of the singing-academy, and in a lecture-room of the
            university of this city, he was listened to with enthusiastic
            applause. The information which those lectures afforded, is
            yet in fresh memory in Berlin. All that time the lectures 
            were written down by many, and—it may justly be said—
            with passion ; it was also rumoured that they should appear
            in print, which, however, did not ensue. And now these lectures are presented to us at once from Alexander von Humboldt’s master-pen, and, even, more of them, and, indeed, 
            something more valuable; for, although the “Cosmos”
            treats on the same subject as those lectures did, and is subdivided just as they were ; yet with the exception of the introductory words of those lectures (observations on the
            variety of the enjoyment of nature, and a scientific explanation of the laws of the world), which occupy some 40 and
            odd pages, the whole is written newly, and the work, therefore, contains the latest results of sciences and the last conclusions drawn from them upon the mind and understanding.
            The work is one of the finest and most finished blossoms
            which the cultivation of natural sciences has ever produced.
         </p>
         
         <p>To state what and how much it contains would be beyond
            the limits of a newspaper article ; suffice it to say, that the
            work when once finished, as may amply be inferred from the
            first volume, will contain the whole of natural sciences taken
            up from their latest results. The single results of the investigation of nature arranged encyclopedically, by no means
            constitute the contents of the work, but only afford a most
            general view. The work exhibits the worth and close connexion of all the laws of nature. Astronomy, natural philosophy, chemistry, natural history and geology, appear by it 
            a living whole. The “ Cosmos” may be likened to a burning-glass by which all investigations in natural philosophy
            are reflected on the mind of the reader in a cleared state and
            united in an organic whole.
         </p>
         
         <p>The almost infinite combination of experience and facts
            which were to be illustrated for such a great aim and exhausted in generality, renders the work, written as it is, in 
            the usual style of Alexander von Humboldt, a cheering and
            popular one, and which especially astonishes him who knows
            fully to appreciate the abundance of its contents. Every
            other reader, to whom the information is imparted so easily,
            is far from anticipating its extent, because every thing dev2elops
            itself in such a natural and easy manner. And this would
            prove a test of the value of the work if it were not yet established. The most excellent manner of illustration is, the
            reason why the work is read with such a lively interest, as
            though it were the most interesting volume of polite literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>It would be most fortunate for our times if such a phenomenon would contribute to advance the taste for the sublime
            in natural sciences. The odious religious controversy which
            now excites and occupies too much society and its external
            organs—the newspapers, would then easily and rapidly arrive at its end. A. von Humboldt has dedicated the
            “ Cosmos” in profound reverence and with hearty thanks, to
            the King of Prussia.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab"> PIANO FORTES.—THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
            <br>(formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway,
            <br>will keep a complete assortment of the largest approved Grand Action
            <br>Piano Fortes, of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
            <br>guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish,
            <br>and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard
            <br>prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on
            <br>hire.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">James pirsson, piano forte manufac-
            <br>TURER, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker street, near Elm A large stock of
            <br>the finest Instruments always on hand. Terms moderate.
            <br>FOR SALE—A splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a great
            <br>bargain tor cash
         </div>
      </div>
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">INTERESTING WORKS
            <br>JUST PUBLISHED BY
            <br>HARPER &amp; BROTHERS, NEW-YORK.
            <br>THE NEW REFORMATION.
            <br>Now ready, with curious Illustrative Plate, price 25 cents, or Muslin,
            <br>37 1-2 cents.
            <br>JOHN RONGE,
            <br>THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES,
            <br>AND THE NEW GER. CATHOLIC CHURCH.
            <br>Including authentic details of the events connected with the recent
            <br>exhibition of the pretended “ Coat of our Lord ” in the Cathedral of
            <br>Treves, during the months of August and September, 1844: compris-
            <br>ing the letters and protestations of the author against the imposition
            <br>and superstitions of the Roman Catholic priests, &amp;c.
            <br>This publication is exceedingly opportune; it will be perused with
            <br>deep interest by the Protestant community at large.—Commercial Ad-
            <br>vertiser.
            <br>The noble protest of Ronge has been circulated in Germany, not by
            <br>thousands, but by millions of copies ; and it has been hailed with loud
            <br>applause by all classes, because it expeesses a public sentiment, and
            <br>finds a response in all hearts.—New York Observer.
            <br>PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES.
            <br>In one volume, 12mo., beautifully printed, price 75 cts.
            <br>A PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES,
            <br>THROUGH THE VALLEY OF THE MEUSE, AND THE FOREST OF
            <br>ARDENNES.
            <br>BY CHARLES EDWARD ANTHON, Esq.
            <br>This is the production of a young American, who had the rare for-
            <br>tune to be present at the most marvellous occurrence of the 19th cen-
            <br>tury—the exhibition of the Holy Robe. In addition to a very graphic
            <br>description of this extraordinary event, which, from the excitement it
            <br>has created, seems destined to be an era in the Christian Church, this
            <br>unpretending volume is replete with antiquarian lore, relating to the
            <br>city of Charlemagne, from which the " Pilgrimage ” commences—
            <br>the intermediate historic and poetic ground ; and of the once renowned
            <br>city of Treves, with which it closes. It is the work of a scholar, and
            <br>cannot fail to enlist a profound interest.—Oswego Advertiser.
            <br>MR. PRESCOTT’S HISTORICAL WORKS.
            <br>In 3 volumes 8vo, beautifully printed and accompanied with fine En-
            <br>gravings.
            <br>HISTORY OF
            <br>THE CONQUEST OF MEXICO.
            <br>WITH A LIFE OF THE CONQUERER, HERNANDO CORTES,
            <br>AND A VIEW OF ANCIENT MEXICAN CIVILIZATION.
            <br>BY WILLIAM H. PRESCOTT, Esq.
            <br>Mr. Prescott appears to possess almost every qualification for his
            <br>task; he has a pure, simple, and eloquent style—a keen relish for the
            <br>picturesque—a quick and discerning judgment of character, and a calm,
            <br>generous and enlightened spirit of philanthropy, There is no exag-
            <br>geration in stating that his “ Conquest of Mexico” contains most of trie
            <br>valuable qualities which distingush the most popular historical writers
            <br>in our language of the present day. It unites the chivalrous but truth-
            <br>ful enthusiasm of Col. Napier, and the vivacity of the accomplished
            <br>author of the " Siege of Granada,” with the patient and ample research
            <br>of Mr. Tytler.—Edinburgh Review, May, 1845.
            <br>In 3 volumes 8vo, uniform with the above, with Portraits and Maps.
            <br>HISTORY OF THE
            <br>REIGN OF FERDINAND AND ISBAELLA,
            <br>THE CATAOLIC.
            <br>BY WILLIAM H. PRESCOTT, Esq.
            <br>The Tenth Edition.
            <br>It would be altogether supererogatory to make this celebrated work
            <br>the subject of critical analysis, since it has so long been distinguished
            <br>by the concurrent and enthusiastic applause of the whole reading com-
            <br>munity. We know of scarcely any other work so amusing, instruc-
            <br>tive, and powerfully attractive as the " History of Ferdinand and Isa-
            <br>bella ;” it possesses every charm which elegance of diction, graceful-
            <br>ness of style, and interest of subject can impart. In a word, it is such
            <br>a production as could only have emanated from a mind richly stored
            <br>with the wealth of sound learning, genius, and the felicitous art of its
            <br>application—N. Y. Review.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. —A. G. GALE &amp; CO.s Ware-
            <br>Rooms, No. 289 Broadway — Manufactory Third Avenue, corner
            <br>of 13th Street.
            <br>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assort-
            <br>ment of Rosewood and Mahogany Piano Fortes, with from six to
            <br>seven octaves, embracing every variety of patterns, made in their well-
            <br>known substantial manner, under their immediate and personal super-
            <br>intendence, by skillful and experienced mechanics, from the best sea-
            <br>soned materials.
            <br>These instruments embrance many important improvements, which
            <br>will recommend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of
            <br>perfection, with the best French grand action, warranted in every re-
            <br>spect by the manufacturer.
         </div>
      </div>
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page16"></div>
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">A CARD.
            <br>WM. A. KINO, PROFESSOR of the PIANO-
            <br>FORTE, ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street,
            <br>where his terms for giving instruction can be ascertained. my17
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO ORTE MANUFACTURER.—JAMES
            <br>PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near Elm. A
            <br>Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms mode-
            <br>rate. FOR SALE—A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a
            <br>great bargain for cash.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
            <br>Street, N. Y.
            <br>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
            <br>Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made
            <br>from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful
            <br>workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the business.
            <br>N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ.
            <br>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—JOHN PE THICK, (formerly
            <br>Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to
            <br>the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establish-
            <br>ment, corner of Cottage Placer and Bleecker street, which he will sell
            <br>at prices unusually low.
            <br>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twen-
            <br>ty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two
            <br>of the largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that
            <br>his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the
            <br>best makers in this country or Europe, and that they contain all the
            <br>real improvements of the day.
            <br>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
            <br>Repaired.
            <br>New York, April 23d, 1845.
            
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. The Subscribers, while return-
            <br>ing thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at
            <br>the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and
            <br>seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood and mahogany cases.
            <br>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
            <br>the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
            <br>to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
            <br>upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            <br>STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway.
            <br>Manufactory, 13th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">THE BOEHM FLUTE
            <br>NEW INVENTION.
            <br>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the Conservato-
            <br>ire at Paris, and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
            <br>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the ‘Boehm Flute,’
            <br>110 Fulton St. N. Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of
            <br>this city the above Imported Invention, which has been so enthusi-
            <br>astically received and generally used by the most distinguished Eu-
            <br>ropean artists, feels happy in being able to place before them the
            <br>following testimonial to its merits, signed by two of the most distin-
            <br>guished of our resident Artists.
            <br>We hereby testify to the excellence of the Boehm Flute, as manufac-
            <br>tured by Mr. J. D. Larrabee; to the beauty of its tone, the perfec-
            <br>tion of its tune, and the simplicity of its fingering, which renders
            <br>a brilliant execution comparatively easy.
            <br>Philip Ernest, (who has already introduced it
            <br>successfully among his pupils.)
            <br>John A. Kyle, Principal Flute of the Philhar-
            <br>monic Society, and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm
            <br>Flute, 41 Forsyth st. New York.
            <br>Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory
            110 Fulton st. and judge for themselves.
         </div>
      </div>	
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">VANDENHOFF’S ELOCUTION.
            <br>SECOND EDITION.—This valuable work is being
            <br>introduced into a large number of the best Schools in the City and
            <br>Country.
            <br>It only needs to be generally known to become universally estab-
            <br>lished.
            <br>Testiomonials are received from every quarter.
            <br>From Rev. R. F. Burnham, Rector of St. Paul’s Church, Hoboken.
            <br>" Having seen with much pleasure, a second edition, by your house,
            <br>of “ A Plain System of Eloculion,” I beg leave to express to you my
            <br>opinion of the high merit of that work.
            <br>Its title is in keeping with the plan pursued in the book ; a rare fact
            <br>in this age of making many books. In the work may he found what
            <br>this age needs a System of Elocution, that presents to the learner
            <br>something tangible; and that combines meaning with beauty, and
            <br>beauty with force.
            <br>I hereby express the opinion that the Principals of Seminaries of
            <br>Learning would benefit the department of Elocution, by the introduc-
            <br>tion of Mr. Vandenhoff’s System.”
            <br>C. SHEPARD, Publisher,
            191 Broadway, opposite John-street.
            
         </div>
      </div>
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab"> GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
            <br>THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE YEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTI-
            <br>TUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
            <br>GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-RUEPING ACADEMY,
            <br>No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            <br>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
            <br>AJ tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
            <br>in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            <br>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course
            <br>of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Sta-
            <br>tionery. Payable at the commencement.
            <br>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M., daily, for gentlemen,
            <br>and from 11 to 1 o’clock, for ladies. Private instruction given.
            <br>For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
            <br>Price Five Dollars.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PAINE AND BURGESS,
            <br>62 JOHN STREET, N. Y.,
            <br>ARE just sending to press a New Series of Choice
            <br>Works, selected from the Prose Literature of Italy. Translated
            <br>and Edited by Edwards Lester, U. S. Consul at Genoa, auther of the
            <br>“ Glory and Shame of England,” &amp;c., &amp;c. This series will be made
            <br>up of original translations of the best works of the best Italian writers,
            <br>with original notes and sketches in illustration of the Genius, the Lives
            <br>and Times of the Authors. Five vols. are ready for the Press.
            <br>1. Ettore Fieramosca, or the Challenge of Barlotta, an Historical
            <br>Romance of the Times of the Medici, by Agegbio.
            <br>2 and 3, The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli.
            <br>4, The Autobiography of Alfieri.
            <br>These numbers will be issued in quick succession, in beautiful style,
            <br>and sold for fifty cents per volume. The object of this series is to
            <br>make known to the American people the Literature of Italy.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">  TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            <br>SIR —WE WILL THANK YOU TO CAUTION
            <br>the public against a set of imposters who are calling upon our cus-
            <br>tomers, asserting that they are engaged by us in the capacity of agents.
            <br>In several instances they have succeeded in obtaining orders. But
            <br>when the goods are delivered great dissatisfaction has been given by
            <br>the infamous and utterly base imitations. But still persisting that the
            <br>cards are our manufacture, they too often succeed in foisting them
            <br>upon the unsuspecting. We ourselves would strenuously caution the
            <br>said parties that, should they persist after this notice, we will try what
            <br>effect a State Prison will have upon them.
            <br>We are, Sir, Yours most obt’y,
            <br>J. B. CAREY‘S &amp; CO ,
            <br>Ornamental Show Card Manufacturers,
            <br>34 Beckman street, (late 323 Broadway.)
            <br>An agent wanted for New York City. Also one for New York State
            <br>—whose name will be published as our authorized agent.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab"> BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            <br>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work
            <br>yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this me-
            <br>thod, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
            <br>The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exerci-
            <br>ses, scales and studies are given in such progressive order, that they
            <br>enlist the interest of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly
            <br>through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often
            <br>made irksome in other instruction books. The time has arrived when
            <br>a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is
            <br>only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will be ena-
            <br>bled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good
            <br>musicians.
            <br>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the
            <br>rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and
            <br>each lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            <br>The publishers arc in possession of the highest recommendations
            <br>from professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of
            <br>Bertini’s Method over all others yet published in this country, most
            <br>of them having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be
            <br>necessary to give a few of the names in the principal cities.
            <br>Boston.	New-York.
            <br>Messr. G. J. Webb,	Messrs. H. C. Timm,
            <br>J. G. Maedar,	W. Alpers,
            <br>H. T. Hach,	U. C. Hill,
            <br>E. L. White,	F. H. Brown,
            <br>David Paine,	Philadelphia.
            <br>A. Kurek,	B. C. Cross,
            <br>T. B. Moses.	Joseph Duggan.
            <br>Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            <br>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the
            <br>work. American edition published by E. H. WADE aud W. H.
            <br>OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            <br>Redding &amp; Co.....................Boston, Mass.
            <br>Colon &amp; Adriance,.................Philadelphia, Pa.
            <br>R. G. H. HUNTINGTON,.............Hartford, Ct.
            <br>George Jones......................Albany, N. Y.
            <br>Thomas H. Pease..................New-Haven, Ct.
            <br>L. Willard........................Troy.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab"><br>JOHN DOUGLAS, Printer, 106 Fulton-street, New-York
         </div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      <a href="#a001"> Link </a><div class="note" id="n001">Horace Smith has written a capital paper on this tonic, in his Odi-
         ties and Varieties.
      </div>
      <a href="#a002"> Link </a><div class="note" id="n002">Southern Minstrels, Kentucky Minstrels, Carolina Minstrels. Far
         River Roarers, &amp;c., &amp;c., &amp;c.
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>