<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, FEBRUARY 15, 1845. N° 7.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div>
         
         
         <div class="cit">
            
            <span class="quote">Truth, whether in or cut of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something
               worse.
            </span>
            
            <div class="bibl">
               <span class="person">Locke</span>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p1">
            
            <div class="ab">Woman in the Nineteenth Century.</div>
            
            <p>This is the title of a book now in press in this city, which
               will be likely to excite a good deal of remark, for and against.
               It is from the pen of Margaret Fuller, a woman of more
               powerful intellect, comprehensive thought, and thorough
               education, than any other American authoress, with whose
               productions I am acquainted. Her style is vigorous and significant, abounding with eloquent passages, and affluent in illustration ; but it is sometimes rough in construction, and its
               meaning is not always sufficiently clear. This does not arise
               from affectation, or pedantic elaboration; it is the defect of a
               mind that has too many thoughts for its words ; an excess by
               no means common, either in men or women. She is a contralto voice in literature: deep, rich, and strong, rather than
               mellifluous and clear.
            </p>
            
            <p>The book in question is written in a free energetic spirit.
               It contains a few passages that will offend the fastidiousness
               of some readers; for they allude to subjects which men do
               not wish to have discussed, and which women dare not approach. But the clean-minded will not sneer; for they will
               see that the motive is pure, and the object is to ennoble human nature.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is a great deal of unuttered thought and suppressed
               feeling, concerning the terrible discords of society, as it now
               exists. The passion of love, divorced from the pure and elevating sentiment, is felt to be unsatisfactory, as well as degrading. More and more earnestly rise the questions, "Is
               love a mockery, and marriage a sham? What is woman’s
               true mission ? What is the harmonious relation of the sexes ?”
            </p>
            
            <p>This extending murmur of the human heart, this increasing conviction that woman should be the friend, the companion, the real partner of man in all his pursuits, rather than
               the mere ornament of his parlor, or the servant of his senses,
               cannot be silenced.
            </p>
            
            <p>The author of “Woman in the Nineteenth Century,” has
               uttered noble aspirations on this subject, rather than definite
               theories. She is wise enough to see, that to purify the atmosphere will gradually affect all forms of life.
            </p>
            
            <p>I quote a few passages at random, to give some idea of the
               import and tendencies of the book.
            </p>
            
            <p>“A better comment could not be made on what is required to perfect man, and place him in that superior position for which he was
               designed, than by the interpretation of Bacon upon the legends of the
               Syren coast. When the wise Ulysses passed, says he, he caused his
               mariners to stop their ears with wax, knowing there was no power to
               resist the lure of that voluptuous song. But he, the much experienced
               man, who wished to be experienced in all, anil use all to the service
               of wisdom, desired to hear the song that he might understand its
               meaning. Yet, distrusting his own owu power to be firm in his better
               purpose, he caused himself to be bound to the mast, that he might be
               kept secure against his own weakness. But Orpheus passed unfettered, so absorbed in singing hymns to the gods, that he could not even
               bear those sounds of degrading enchantment.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Meanwhile not a few believe, and men themselves have expressed the opinion, that the time is come when Eurydice is to call for an
               Orpheus, rather than Orpheus for Eurydice : that the idea of Man,
               
               however imperfectly brought out, has been far more so than that of
               Woman ; that she, the other half of the same thought, the other
               chamber of the heart of life, needs now to take her turn in the full
               pulsation, and that improvement in the daughters will best aid in the
               reformation of the sons of this age.
            </p>
            
            <p>"It should be remarked that, as the principle of liberty is better understood, and more nobly interpreted a broader protest is made in behalf of Woman. As men become aware that few men have had a fair
               chance, they are inclined to say that no women have had a fair
               chance.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Without attaching importance, in themselves, to the changes demanded by the champions of woman, we hail them as signs of the
               times. We would have every arbitrary barrier thrown down. We
               would have every path laid open to woman as freely as to man.
               Were this done and a slight temporary fermentation allowed to subside, we should see crystallizations more pure and of more various
               beauty. We believe the divine energy would pervade nature to a degree unknown in the history of former ages, and that no discordant
               collision, but a ravishing harmony of the spheres would ensue.
            </p>
            
            <p>'Yet, then and only then, will mankind be ripe for this, when inward and outward freedom for woman as much as for man shall be
               acknowledged as a right, not yielded as a concession. As the friend
               of the negro assumes that that one man cannot by right, hold another
               in bondage, so should the friend of woman assume that man cannot,
               by right, lay even well-meant restrictions on woman. If the negro be
               a soul, if the woman be a soul, apparelled in flesh, to one Master only
               are they accountable. There is but one law for souls, and if there is to
               be an interpreter of it, he must come not as man. or son of man, but
               as son of God.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Were thought and feeling once so far elevated, that man should
               esteem himself the brother and friend, but nowise the lord and tutor of
               woman, were he really bound with her in equal worship, arrangements
               as to function and employment would be of no consequence. What
               woman needs is not as a woman to act or rule, but as a nature to grow,
               as an intellect to discern, as a soul to live freely and unimpeded, to
               unfold such powers as were given her when we left our common home.
               If fewer talents are given her, yet if allowed the free and full employment of these, so that she may render back to the giver his own with
               usury, she will not complain ; nay, I dare to say she will bless and
               rejoice in her earthly birth-place, her earthly lot.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Man, in the order of time, was developed first; as energy comes
               before harmony; power before beauty.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Woman was therefore under his care as an elder. He might have
               been her guardian and teacher.
            </p>
            
            <p>“But as human nature goes not straight forward, but by excessive
               action and then reaction in an undulated course, he misunderstood and
               abused his advantages, and became her temporal master instead of
               her spiritual sire.
            </p>
            
            <p>"On himself came the punishment. He educated woman more as a
               servant than a daughter, and found himself a king without a queen.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The children of this unequal union showed unequal natures, and,
               more and more, men seemed sons of the hand-maid, rather than
               princes.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The civilized world is still in a transition state about marriage ;
               not only in practice, but in thought. It is idle to speak with contempt
               of the nations where polygamy is an institution, or seraglios a custom,
               when practices far more debasing haunt, well nigh fill, every city and
               every town. And so far as union of one with one is believed to be the
               only pure form of marriage, a great majority of societies and individuals are still doubtful whether the earthly bond must be a meeting of
               souls, or only supposes a contract of convenience and utility. Were
               woman established in the rights of an immortal being, this could not
               be. She would not, in some countries, be given away by her father,
               with scarcely more respect than is shown by the Indian chief, who
               sells his daughter for a horse, and beats her if she runs away from
               her new home. Nor in societies where her choice is left free, would
               she be perverted, by the current of opinion that seizes her, into the
               belief that she must marry, if it be only to find a protector, and a
               home of her own.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Neither would man, if he thought the connection of permanent
               importance, form it so lightly. He would not deem it a trifle, that he
               was to enter into the closest relations with another soul, which, if not
               eternal in themselves, must eternally affect his growth.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Neither, did he believe woman capable of friendship, would he, by
               rash haste, lose the chance of finding a friend in the person who
               might, probably, live half a century by his side. Did love, in his
               mind, stretch forth into infinity, he'would not miss in his chance of
               its revelations, that he might, the sooner, rest from his weariness by a
               bright fireside, and secure a sweet and graceful attendant "devoted to
               him alone.” Were be a step higher, he would not carelessly enter
               into a relation where he might not be able to do the duty of a friend,
               as well as protector from external ill, to the other party, and have a
               being in his power pining for sympathy, intelligence and aid, that he
               could not give.”
            </p>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">L. M. C.</span>
            </div>
            
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p2">
            
            
            <div class="ab">Rome ; as Seen by a New Yorker in 1843-4. New York and London.
               
               <br></br>Wiley &amp; Putnam, 1846. 12mo. pp. 216.
            </div>
            
            <p>The author of this book is William M. Gillespie, whose
               initials were familiar to readers a year or two ago, appended to a series of traveller’s letters from Europe in the Tribune. Italy attracted most of the writer’s attention. There
               were several descriptive sketches of Venice and Florence;
               while Rome, in consideration of the extent and unity of the
               subject, was reserved for the present volume. It is an excellent book of a traveller's first visit to the imperial city;
               describing such objects and scenes as all have to see, methodising a great deal of miscellaneous knowledge in small
               compass, and valuable alike to the people who journey and
               those who read at home. If one wants to be in the position
               with respect to information and the reception of future ideas
               he would be in after a diligent six weeks at Rome, let him
               read this book. It clears away all the matter-of-fact duty
               of sight seeing, in a pleasant way, and prepares the way for
               new thought or observation. It is not the book of a classical
               antiquarian, or a book of personal adventure; but it tells us
               what a well-informed man sees about him, on first going to
               Rome. The philosophy of the people, and new moral and
               social speculations, come afterwards.
            </p>
            
            <p>General good sense, a pains-taking eye and a careful style,
               are the characteristics of the volume. The subjects are conveniently arranged in groups, beginning with St. Peter’s, and
               ending with a valuable classification of the various sights in
               a chapter entitled "How to see Rome.” The time, it should
               be remarked, to which our traveller’s visit was limited, is
               mid winter, which introduces the ceremonies of Christmas,
               and excludes those of Easter and the Holy Week.
            </p>
            
            <p>Our writer sometimes carries the remark to do in Rome as
               the Romans do, rather too far. Thus in the chapter on Reliques, after an enumeration of various pitiable delusions,
               when we expect the atmosphere to be purged by a good
               hearty laugh from the author, he tells us that though "Democritus -would laugh at all these things, and Heraclitus
               would weep, we travel to very little purpose if we do not
               learn charity to every sincere belief, however it may seem to
               us; remembering that our own may seem equally so to a more
               enlightened order of beings." This is neither sense nor
               benevolence. For that is no charity at all, when a man has
               to sink his understanding to practice the virtue. If man becomes wiser when he is an angel, so much the better. But
               is that any reason why he should throw away any little wisdom he has got on the earth? Let us hold on to what we
               have, and call ignorance ignorance and delusion delusion.
               In patronizing folly after our author’s fashion, we are encouraging the accompanying knavery.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is a hit in much better style at the implicit Romish idolatry, when Mr. Gillespie tells us a story of one of the attendants at the Vatican, who, learning that he was an American,
               showed him some idols from the Western Hemisphere, and
               wondered he did not fall down and worship them !
            </p>
            
            <p>In similar unconsciousness of his good American understanding, in that affair of the apology for the reliques, is the
               somewhat astonishing sentence after an account of the Inquisition, which it seems (page 199) is still alive at Rome :—
               "After all, this is not much worse than our own Inquisition
               of Public Opinion.” There has been too much nonsense uttered on this last subject. There is no country in the world,
               we believe, where there is less of this tyranny of public opinion than in the United States
            </p>
            
            <p>The description of the Duomo of Milan will convey a very
               fair impression of our writer’s style in description.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">THE DUOMO OF MILAN.</div>
            
            <p>"The only Rival or St. Peter’s is the Duomo or Milan ; and
               wonderful as is the former, I am so heretical as to find the latter far
               more beautiful and impressive. Imagine a white marble pyramid,
               miraculously sprouting, and shooting up from every part of its surface, spires, pinnacles and statues, and you will have a better idea
               of
               this most glorious Duomo, than by comparing it with any other
               Church. "None but itself can be its parallel.” "Facile Princeps.”
               The Cathedral of Cologne is indeed inspired by the same feeling, and
               is akin in some of its details, but it is only the bare single rose, while
               here in the more luxuriant soil and more balmy sky of Italy, the flower puts forth so many new leaves, and so doubles and re-duplicates its
               petals, that the luxuriant double rose of Milan can scarcely recognize
               its prototype in the single wild flower of Cologne.
            </p>
            
            <p>"This mountain of marble sends out on each side clustered buttresses connected with the main structure by flying arches, which spring
               through mid air, and form noble bridges, which are half invisible from
               below, and on which angels might not disdain to tread. From the front
               also, six buttresses project and rise above the sloping summit of the
               body of the Church. All these are filled with statues, each In a niche
               of its own, and from each buttress rise pinnacles on pinnacles, and
               spire branching from spire, each crowned with statues, so that the
               whole church is covered with a marble population of Saints and Angels. The whole front is also embossed with sculptures in high relief, wherever the statues have left room ; and these pictures carved
               in stone record the various scenes and events of sacred history with
               more distinctness and expression than could any words. Between
               them are fantastic faces, smiling and frowning on you like mischievous
               sprites; and among other whims of the sculptor is a female head,
               covered with a marble veil, through which you seem to see features,
               which in reality have never been chiselled out, but only artfully suggested to the fancy. Days might be given to the study of all these
               devices, and at every visit much would be found both new and beautiful. The whole building is indeed a poem written in stone.
            </p>
            
            <p>But great as is your admiration while you are below, you find when
               you mount to the roof, that you had not yet seen the tithe of its splendors. A winding staircase conducts you up, and you see that the same
               lavish and tasteful labor is given to the most secluded and seldom seen
               portions, as to the most conspicuous. The artists seem to have been
               deeply impressed with the feeling that nothing was too good for the
               service of the Divinity, to whom their labors were consecrated. The
               slabs which cover the roof, and on which you walk, are of fine marble.
               The backs of the statues, which can be seen only with particular
               pains, are found to be as highly finished as the fronts. The rich ornaments are in the most out-of-the-way corners, and everything shows
               that the workmen felt themselves engaged in a true labor of love.
               Every part of the roof seems perfectly alive with statues. Each of
               the spires and pinnacles, and each of their branches, bears a colossal
               statue. Among the rest is placed one by Canova, and the fact that
               it passes unnoticed among the rest, is a sufficient proof of the great
               merit of all. The inhabitants of this city of marble Saints are now
               nearly seven thousand in number, and when the designs are fully carried out, ten thousand marble statues, each different, and each of itself a model, will people this noblest of Cathedrals. The readers of
               Wordsworth will remember his fine allusion, in his poem on " The
               Eclipse of the Sun on Lake Lugano,” to the darkness shading, as with
               sorrow, the faces of these Saints and Cherubs.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The chapter entitled a Roman Dining House and Cafe, is
               one of the most interesting in the volume, both because it
               contains details which are new, having been plucked from
               the writer’s experience, and because, as he himself remarks,
               though every man may not be an Antiquarian, a Poet, or an
               Historian, yet we all agree in our reverence for a good dinner.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Fountains of Rome will attract the New-York read-
               er’s attention.
            </p>
            
            <p>Every square in Rome—every public edifice—almost every private garden—is made cheerful and picturesque by the gush of water
               from Fountains decorated with sculpture and statuary. None are
               more graceful than the two in front of St. Peter’s (in which the jet
               falls into the vase, from the sides of which it streams in a circular
               sheet into a second vase, and from it again into a marble basin), but
               the others are so ingeniously varied in form and ornaments, that no
               two are alike, although I find forty-four engraved in "a selection of
               the principal fountains of the renowned city of Rome,” published
               there in 1773. In one, a broad sheet of water pours down from a high
               aperture ; in another the nymph empties the stream from her pitcher;
               in a third, dolphins pour it from their mouths ; and in one of those
               which are always running from the walls for common use (the "free
               hydrants” of Rome), the water flows from the bunghole of a marble
               cask which a marble porter is holding in his arms. In one Piazza the
               fountain is shaped like a boat, of which the main jet represents the
               mast; in another, four graceful youths support the basin on their
               heads ; and in a third, a Triton sits on a shell supported by four dolphins, and holds over his head a conch, from which spouts up the water. The Piazza Savona contains three fountains, and in the principal
               one an Egyptian obelisk stands on a mass of rock, pierced with caverns on every side, and having chained it to four river gods, representing the Danube, the Ganges, the Nile, and the Rio de la Plata ; so
               that the four quarters of the globe are thus made tributary to the Imperial city. The Fontano Paulina rises like the front of a church on
               the Janiculum hill, overlooking all Rome, and three torrents rush
               
               
               through its central arches, and fall into a large basin, from which they
               roll down the hill, turning mills and supplying reservoirs. Over the
               Fontana dell’ Acqua Felice rises an Ionic arcade, in the central niche
               of which stands Moses striking the rock at his feet, from which the
               water gushes out, and Aaron and Gideon figure in the basso-relievos on
               the other side. At the Quattro Fontane (known to our countrymen in
               Home as the location of the American Consulate), two broad streets
               cross each other at right angles, and when you stand at their intersection your view is terminated in three directions by Egyptian obelisks,
               one on Monte Cavallo, a second at the Trinita de’ Monti, and a third
               before Santa Maria Maggiore. At each of the four corners of the
               streets the angles of the houses were cut away, and fountains are
               there constructed, with figures recumbent under sculptured trees, and
               other emblematic decorations.
            </p>
            
            <p>"But the Fountain of Trevi is the finest in all Rome, and therefore in
               all the world. In front of a palace adorned with Corinthian columns
               and pilasters, huge masses of rocks are piled up, so natural in shape
               and arrangement, that they seem to have been broken by an earthquake, and then worn by the rush of water into their present forms.
               From every niche and crevice, to the right and to the left, upward
               and downward, gush out torrents of water, in the most copious variety, and finally fall into a capacious white marble basin. In the midst
               of the rocks, and under a niche in the palace, a colossal statue of Neptune stands on a car, to which are harnessed two sea-horses, held by
               Tritons. The god of the Ocean majestically extends his right arm, as
               if about to rebuke the boiling waves with his famous "Quos ego—.”
               On each side of the niche which he occupies are statues of Salubrity
               and Abundance, with appropriate basso-relievos. All the necessaries
               thus combine to heighten the admiration of the visitor to the fountain
               of Trevi.
            </p>
            
            <p>"But should we be satisfied to admire, when we can emulate ? The
               rear of our New York City Hall offers an excellent site for a similar
               work. It is now an eyesore ; but we may make it an ornament to the
               city by arranging artistically before it, rough masses of rock (pleasant
               reminders, in the crowded city, of rural scenes), and pouring over
               them our Croton river, which should gush naturally from irregular
               openings as if it were just bursting up from its source. We may then
               employ our American sculptors to decorate the building in a style
               worthy of our future destinies, and in a grand central niche erect a
               statue, not of the false god, Neptune, but of the true man, Washington ; and thus make this one of his long-desired Monuments.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The rear of the City Hall is, indeed, an eye-sore, but we
               can suggest a better remedy for it than the construction of a
               fountain. The fountain needs a white back-ground for relief, to harmonize with the water—so the brown stone of the
               rear, economically contrived like the lining of a sailor's vest,
               would be only rendered more fatally conspicuous by the
               fountain. Let the City Hall be completed by the extension
               of wings and a new rear on Chambers street, preserving a
               court or quadrangle in the centre. The depth is now out of
               proportion with the width of the front. The order of architecture, too, requires extent of surface to set it forth—a long
               succession of windows, arches, and colonnades. The City
               Hall, with this addition, would offer something to feed the
               eye along the line of Broadway. The only view, the front
               one, is now exclusively enjoyed by the cab-men, an attorney
               hastily crossing the walk to be in time for a motion, and the
               stationary fat cattle who are occasionally exhibited at the
               steps.
            </p>
            
            <p>The typographical execution of the work, we should add,
               is distinguished for its beauty and accuracy—rare merits in
               these days of anti-copyright slovenliness.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p3">
            
            <div class="ab">Letters from a Landscape Painter.—By the author of Essays
               
               <br></br>for Summer Hours. Boston, James Munroe, It Co., 1845.
            </div>
            
            <p>There are many commendable things in this little volume,
               and many that are very far from being either commendable
               or excusable. The author has done himself an injury by
               substituting his profession in the place of his proper name.
               The letters of a Landscape Painter must provoke a critical
               examination of their merits as the production of an artist;
               and we have a right to expect in them fine descriptions of
               landscapes, and fine criticisms on art. But on these points
               Mr. Lanman, the author of the "Letters,” is least capable.
               His remarks on painters are generally very inaccurate, or
               wholly unmeaning, and his descriptions of scenery are cold
               and colorless—they have neither outlines nor fillings up. He
               indulges continually in that style called by an English critic,
               the treble X. Every picture that he sees is the very best that
               he has ever seen, and moreover the best, as he verily be
               lieves, that anybody has ever seen. This is not the way in
               which men who have seen much usually express themselves;
               neither is it the manner of a cautious deliberate observer,
               who knows how ridiculously a critic appears who commits
               himself by giving a decided opinion upon a subject of which
               he is not himselfa master. Forinstance: after quoting some
               very common blank verses by Lewis L. Noble, Mr. Lanman
               asks, "Can anything be more completely exquisite than the
               few lines that I have marked ? Is there anything in Dana
               Bryant, or Longfellow, that can eclipse them ? or in the very
               best of England’s modem poets ? There may be, but I have
               never been able to discern them, although I almost know bv
               heart the poetry of Wordsworth, Coleridge, Wilson, Cowper,
               Goldsmith, Beattie, Shelly, Scott, Rogers, Campbell, and
               Mrs. Hemans.” In speaking of Huntington, the painter, he
               says "the shepherd boy of the Campagna, which we think
               is equal to Murillo’s beggar boy, was painted in the incredible short period of four hours. If this fact and this picture
               do not prove Huntington to be a wonderful genius, we do not
               know what could do so.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Neither do we. But still we do not think that the “shepherd boy” proves Mr. Huntington a genius. It bears no more
               resemblance to Murillo’s beggar boy than it does to the
               Logos of Leonardo da Vinci; and, we do not see what right
               Mr. Lanman has to institute a comparison between these
               pictures, for we believe he has seen but one of them; and being a painter himself he must know that any picture painted
               in four hours must be a daub, as the "shepherd boy” is; and a
               very disagreeable one too. It is, probably, all that the painter meant to make it, a sketch, which he would hardly care
               to see exhibited as a test of his wonderful genius. In a laudation of Durand he describes one of his large landscapes
               and says “the great triumph of this picture is in the water.”
               Nearly all who have seen the painting referred to, feel that its
               great defect is the water, which has a hard basaltic appearance, and is, in fact, inferior in this respect to all of his landscapes. The remarks on Page and Inman are the purest rigmarole; although Mr. Lanman is hardly chargeable with
               their folly, since he does but echo the words of other writers
               more pretending than himself. Inferior artists find themselves unequal to coping with nature, they leave out of their
               representations, therefore, the parts which they cannot imitate, and call their daubs an elevation of nature,—the grand
               style: they paint the most exaggerated and meaningless
               faces, and call them an intellectualisation: they give a caricature of humanity, and it is a representation of the soul.
               The errors afloat on this subject, which we have imbibed from
               the English, have spoilt many a good artist, and kept him in
               rags and poverty, when he might have earned reputation and
               wealth by following his instincts. Every man has a character of his own; his spiritual being impresses itself upon his
               carcass, as it does in a great measure upon his clothes. We
               can distinguish any of our intimate friends by their gait,
               when walking, without seeing their faces; our very intimate
               friends we recognize by the manner of wearing their hats,
               or swinging their arms; or the tread of their feet. If, then,
               a man’s mind impresses itself upon his merely accidental habiliments, how much more does it give its own character to
               his face, which is always the companion of his soul, and
               whose flexibility is such that the slightest emotion of his spirit is moulded upon it. The only thing to be aimed at in
               giving a copy of a man’s face is truth ; any departure from
               the exact lineaments of a man’s countenance must cause a
               false impression of his character; to paint his forehead too
               high is as great a wrong to him as to paint it too low. Some
               artists give all their women red cheeks and scarlet lips,
               
               
               and yet there is not one in a thousand that has either, the
               consequence is that women so misrepresented look as though
               they were rouged. A New York artist, now in Europe,
               once painted the portrait of a young lady for her lover, who
               said when he saw it that it gave him a disagreeable feeling,
               he could not tell why, but it reminded him of a courtesan.
               Somebody remarked to him that it was probably the color in
               the cheeks, and he exclaimed “that’s it!” But this is what
               they call idealizing. Some painters give their portraits a
               smirking expression, which every body feels at the first
               glance is a lie, because no one could sit with a smiling face
               for a picture; and a smile is no more the natural look of any
               person than a frown. Inman’s portrait of Nicholas Biddle has
               this fault, and a very great one it is in such a man’s face.
               The only true expression of any one’s countenance is in perfect repose. People lately deceased always look more familiar than when alive, excepting after a wasting disease, because the features then settle into the habitual, not the accidental mould, which they have received from the mind. It
               is this state of perfect repose which gives the appearance of
               historical dignity to Vandyke’s portraits, and it is the want
               of it that gives to the portraits of Sir Thomas Lawrence, and
               the English school of portraiture, the character of affectation,
               which makes his lords and ladies look more like green-room
               heroes and heroines than real nobilities.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Lanman has carried his theory of ideal perfection to a
               very absurd excess in his present volume, as we will convince him; we are not much acquainted with his works on
               canvass, but we have no doubt that he practices the same
               principles with his brush as with his pen. Perhaps a word
               of timely advice may open his eyes to his false theory, and
               lead him to do better hereafter. One of his letters is called
               a week in a fishing smack, and it professes to give six days’
               experience in a vessel of that description. Part of the time
               was spent in Nantucket, an out-of-the-way place, sufficiently
               quaint, and not requiring the smallest degree of idealizing to
               make any account of it tolerably interesting to a stranger.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Lanman goes “strolling about the town,” as he says,
               "studying the great and solemn drama of life while playfully acting a subordinate part myself." What Mr. Lanman saw in the town he does not tell us, nor how the great
               and solemn drama of life was performed in that remote part
               of the world. Perhaps the inhabitants were not aware who
               it was that was playfully acting a subordinate part among
               them. Playfully, if you please, Messieurs, only playfully,
               not really acting a subordinate part. Oh, no!
            </p>
            
            <p>“This morning, as it happened,” continues Mr. Lanman,
               “I went into the public grave yard, (there are half a dozen
               public grave-yards in Nantucket,) and spent an hour in conning over the rude inscriptions to the memory of the departed,
               (to whose memory should they have been made, but to the
               departed?) In that city of the dead, I saw a number of the
               living walking to and fro, but there was one who attracted
               my particular attention. He was a seaman of noble presence,
               seated upon an unmarked mound, with his feet resting upon
               a smaller one beside it, his head reclined upon one hand,
               while the other was occasionally passed across his face, as
               if wiping away a tear. I hailed him with a few kind questions, (rather, obtrusive, we think,) and my answer was the
               following brief tale. ‘Yes, sir, four years ago I shipped
               aboard that whaler yonder, (all the grave-yards in Nantucket
               are so situated that no whaler can be seen from either of
               them,) leaving behind me in a sweet little cottage of my own,
               a dear, first-rate mother, a good wife, and an only boy. They
               were all in the enjoyment of good health, and happy ; and
               when we were under sail, and I saw from the mast head,
               
               how kindly they waved their handkerchiefs beside my door,
               (there is not a house on the island so situated that such a
               performance could be witnessed from the mast-head of a ship
               under a sail,) I too was happy, even in my hour of grief.
               Since that time, I have circumnavigated the globe, and every
               rare curiosity I could obtain, was intended for my darling
               ones at home. Last Saturday our ship returned. And while
               yet a league from port, I was again at the mast-head, looking with an anxious heart towards my nest on the shore.
               (Two leagues from port there happens to be a sand-bar,
               which prevents a ship from approaching nearer until her cargo is discharged into lighters, which generally occupies eight
               or ten days: and the only "nests” upon the shore are those
               that the gulls build in the cliff.) I saw that the blinds were
               closed, and that all around was very still; but they were
               only gone a visiting, thought I, and rejoiced at heart. (He
               had no need to think about the matter at all, for the pilot must
               have been on board some hours, and he had only to inquire
               after his wife and family, to hear all the particulars.) I landed,
               flew to my dwelling, and found it locked. (The first man he
               met would have told him that his house was shut up, and
               recommended him to go to one of his uncles or cousins, and
               saved him from flying to his cottage.) The flagging in my
               yard attracted my notice, and I thought it strange that the
               rank grass had been suffered to grow over it so thickly. The
               old minister passed by my gate, and running to him with
               extended hand, I inquired for my family. ‘Oh, Mr. B.,’ said
               he, ‘you must bless the Lord, he gave them to you, and he
               hath taken them away.’ And as the thought stole into my
               brain, my suffering, sir, was intense, and I longed to die. And
               there they are, my wife and darling child, and a step or two
               beyond, my dear old mother. Peace to their memories. As
               for me, I am a victim to blight and desolation, and that sacred song, which my mother used to be so fond of singing on
               Sabbath evenings long ago; that song I can understand now:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>'I would not live alway ; I ask not to stay
               
               <br></br>Where storm after storm rises dark o’er the way ;
               
               <br></br>The few lurid mornings that dawn on us here,
               
               <br></br>Are enough for life’s woes, full enough for its cheer.'
               
            </div>
            
            
            <p>(This Song was written by Bishop Onderdonk of Pennsylvania, and we are inclined to think that the seaman with a
               noble presence who was a victim to blight and desolation,
               was mistaken in thinking that he had heard his "first-rate
               mother” sing it long ago. It was probably some other
               song, or some other person. So, too, we think there must be
               some mistake about the old minister, as all the ministers in
               Nantucket for the last ten years have been quite young men.)
               In a few days I mean to deliver up my property to the seaman’s Friend Society, and then launching upon the deep
               once more, become, and forever, a wanderer from my native
               land. Such is the simple story I heard in the Nantucket
               grave-yard, and I have pondered much upon the world of
               woe which must be hidden in the breast of that old mariner.
               May the tale not have been recorded in vain !”
            </p>
            
            <p>We join in this last aspiration very heartily. May it not.
               Of course no such tale was ever told to Mr. Lanman, and of
               course he never "pondered much” about it, or he would not
               have written it. It is not only physically, but morally impossible. But it is exactly in accordance with Mr. Lanman's
               principles in art, and precisely the kind of writing which we
               should expect from a man who could pen such dreadful nonsense as this: "Painting as he does, with great rapidity, we
               find that his (Inman’s) drawing is seldom as correct as it
               should be. He manifests a refined and exalted taste in the arrangement of his portraits, and generally in his miscellaneous
               designs. But, after all, he has painted some poor pictures.
               
               
               and this is an evidence of the fact, that he is a man of uncommon genius, and not talent. There is a wonderful spirit
               in his heads, and, unlike his rival, Page, he portrays the
               mind, which, after all, is a greater triumph of art, and far
               more important in a portrait, than the mere shell of humanity as delineated by Page.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The first letter in the collection is the best, it has the most
               unequivocal marks of being honestly written, and introduces
               us to a scene which needed none of the embellishments of
               fancy. Peter Hummel, the vagabond bark-gatherer, is very
               happily sketched, and evidently from nature ; the draughts
               of fishes appear almost miraculous, but we do not pretend to
               question their truth. The letter from Burlington is also in
               good taste, inasmuch as it treats of facts, and gives us scraps
               of information which we do not find floating in the current of
               daily news. There is almost too great a disposition to glorify the gentlemen whose names are mentioned, but as nothing but good, and what is true is said of them, of course
               nobody will take offence. Mr. Peck may not be ambitious
               of distinction, as a “giver of glorious dinners,” and probably
               he will be as much surprised as any of his friends to see
               himself compared to Roscoe, whom Mr. Lanman evidently
               knows nothing about, except what he gathered from the
               Sketch-Book, or he would not call him a merchant of the
               first-rank. If any gentleman in Burlington can be compared
               with Roscoe, it is Mr. Marsh, who does, in fact, occupy a
               position very similar to that which Roscoe filled in Liverpool, being a lawyer, a legislator, a lecturer, an author, an
               amateur in art, and the possessor of the best collection of
               books in the place.
            </p>
            
            <p>One of the unpleasant things about Mr. Lanman's book
               is its didacticism; he seems to labor under an impression
               that he is especially called upon to extract a solemn reflection out of every incident, and to find a sermon in every
               stone that he stumbles upon. But sermons and solemn reflections are just the things that the world can best afford to
               do without at the present day. It is preeminently an enquiring age; nothing is so much needed as facts; mankind are
               beginning to perceive that nothing finds its way to the heart
               so readily as a truth, and if those who have an opportunity
               to go about, and a desire to make a book, would honestly set
               down a plain account of what they see, rather than what
               they think, the fruit of their labors would be much better
               received by the world.
            </p>
            
            <p>We would recommend Mr. Bryant’s letters from the South
               as a model for all young travellers who have a design of
               publishing a book, or else the Irish Sketch-Book of Mr. Michael Angelo Titmarsh ; but the first will be found a safer
               model, for the style of Mr. Titmarsh is altogether inimitable, and his humor not a thing to be thought of by any one
               besides himself.
            </p>
            
            <p>The most commendable thing in the Letters of a Landscape
               Painter, is the excellence of their aim. The author models
               himself after the best masters to be found, and his presumptions arc evidence that he feels himself capable of doing
               something. He goes a-trouting, like Izaak Walton, and
               ,akes nothing of sleeping in the open air, with a vagabond
               hunter for his companion; he foots it across mountains with
               a rifle on his back with the spirit of Kit North ; he goes out
               in a fishing smack to Nantucket, as Walter Scott went to
               the Hebrides, and wherever he stops, he contrives to fall into
               good rather than flashy company. All these signs are favorable for a young amateur, and did we not dislike affectation
               of all kinds, and affectations of piety the most of all, we
               Would not give it as our opinion that he says his prayers too
               often; or rather that he says he says them. There are some
               
               things which a man might as well keep to himself, and the
               frequency with which he says his prayers is the chief of
               them. It is an act so purely personal, that we see no necessity for trumpeting it, and the command of our Savior is so
               explicit in respect of that act which no Christian is supposed
               to neglect, that we do not see why it should be so often disregarded.
            </p>
            
            <p>We understand that Mr. Lanman is quite a young man,
               and that he has abandoned both painting and writing for
               trade; of course he knows best himself, whether he acts
               wisely in so doing. He will probably not make a worse
               merchant for having painted pictures and published books.
               Men of his age have done much worse things than either,
               and succeeded well in business after all. It is not likely
               that this will be the last time that we shall hear from him,
               but when he comes out again it will be in a better shape than
               he appears in now. Young authors, like other young men,
               have their wild oats to sow, and the sooner they get rid of
               them the better, and the ranker the crop the greater the
               hope of improvement.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         
         <div class="head">PLACES WORTH VISITING.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p4">
            
            <div class="head">MONSIEUR EDOUART’S SILHOUETTE ROOMS.</div>
            
            <div class="byline">BY 
               <span class="person">MRS. L. M. CHILD</span>.
            </div>
            
            <p>Among the places worth visiting, you might have enumerated the room of Monsieur Edouart, No. 285 Broadway. At
               the first glance, his gallery has a singular effect on the eye.
               It reminded me of the democratic procession, by torchlight,
               where horses, men, and temples of liberty, in the intense
               brilliancy of Drummond lights, went stalking by as black
               shadows on the opposite walls.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of these silhouette likenesses, he has some fifty thousand
               Americans, and three times that number of Europeans. On
               examination, one is struck with the wonderful expression
               imparted to these cuttings; the life-like delineation of the
               various passions. The first feeling is that of regret, that such
               an eye for form, such a decided love of art, should not have
               been employed on the more beautiful and enduring material
               of marble. It would have been so, had not the artist’s father
               made the common mistake, of insisting that his son should
               not walk in the path for which nature had designed him.
               Belonging to the genteel classes, he naturally considered
               military distinction more honorable than artistic fame. So
               modelling and drawing were forbidden, and all his seven
               sons became officers in Bonaparte’s army. One only survived
               his numerous campaigns; and he escaped through more
               perils than a truly brave man ever likes to boast of to the
               public.
            </p>
            
            <p>Like most Frenchmen, M. Edouart is an enthusiastic admirer of Napoleon. He shakes his head mournfully, whenever he alludes to his downfall. On such occasions, I never
               intrude my peace principles upon him ; not considering the
               soil very favorable to such a growth. Nor do I jar upon his
               proud recollections of military success and national renown,
               by telling him with what peculiar satisfaction I always listen
               to the words in the Lament for Bonaparte, “He has fought
               his last battle. No sound shall awake him to glory again.”
               The remains of his armies belong to the moral sentiment of
               a warlike past. I trust they were the final efflorescence of
               the “might gives right” principle.
            </p>
            
            <p>But from the turbulent scenes of war, M. Edouart has
               brought some pleasant and refreshing recollections. While
               one of the commissioners of the army, he was distinguished
               for his moderation and forbearance toward those from whom
               be was ordered to raise forced supplies of provisions for the
               
               
               army. Unlike most others in the same office, he never abused his power to fill his own purse. He took only such articles as were absolutely necessary, and for these he was careful to give receipts, the value of which were allowed by the
               government to the people, when the expenses of the war
               were paid by general taxation. The honesty and kindness
               thus manifested, were so highly appreciated by the emperor
               Francis II., that he presented M. Edouart with a magnificent
               gold box, with a hundred diamonds round the edge of the
               cover, four large and brilliant diamonds in the corners, and
               the letter F closely set in diamonds in the centre.
            </p>
            
            <p>The cutting of silhouette likenesses was at first merely taken
               up for amusement, to relieve the loneliness caused by the
               death of his wife, to whom he was strongly attached. His
               early love of Art returned upon him, till this employment
               became an absorbing passion. The common prejudice
               against profile-cutting, as a merely mechanical process, annoyed him considerably. But people soon became aware that
               there was a life and expression about his cuttings, which
               raised them altogether above mere mechanical accuracy, and
               rendered them worthy to be dignified with the name of Art.
               In the gallery, at his room, the two men playing at chess, the
               husband and wife quarrelling, and John’s funny story to the
               cook, are remarkable instances of an almost speaking expression conveyed in mere outline.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Edouart obtained great popularity in England and
               Scotland, and has a very curious profile collection of the distinguished men and women, whose likenesses he took there.
               There is Sir Walter Scott, in his room at Abbotsford; and
               Hannah More in her study at Barley Wood, with a likeness
               of her table, and the favorite silver inkstand, from which she
               wrote all her works. He speaks with much pleasure of his
               visit to the good old lady, who was then eighty-four years
               old. She gave him a small cake that had been sent her,
               saying that she never ate anything with shortening in it, and
               never drank anything but water. A field of grain was waving before the open window; pointing to it with a smile, she
               said, in tones of youthful enthusiasm, "Look, Monsieur Edouart, look on that golden sea.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Charles X. and his court were at Edinburgh, while he was
               there. He took all their likenesses, and the exiled monarch
               was so much pleased with them, that he presented him with
               a valuable diamond ring. The likeness of the king was cut
               on paper folded in two, and one of the duplicates was afterwards carefully corrected. By some accident, this fell upon
               the floor, and M. Edouart, seeing it, exclaimed, “Ah, viola un
               roi tombe; et encore celui gui este corige." (Ah, see a king
               has fallen; and the one that was corrected too.) The dethroned monarch, with a sad smile, replied emphatically,
               "Un roi tombe, et corrige en vente." (A king fallen, and
               corrected indeed). The artist, of course, felt somewhat embarrassed at having made a thoughtless exclamation, which
               brought up such unpleasant reminiscences; particularly as
               be himself was well known to have been one of Bonaparte’s
               officers. But the unfortunate royal family were all polite
               enough to take it very good naturedly.
            </p>
            
            <p>While in Edinburgh, the attention of George Combe, the
               celebrated phrenologist and physiologist, was attracted by
               M. Edouart’s head, which bears a very striking resemblance
               to the busts of Socrates. He was very desirous to have a
               cast of it taken in plaster; but this request was refused, from
               a fear that the wet lime might possibly do some injury to his
               eyes. To evade Mr. Combe’s opportunities, he often playfully replied, “Wait till I am dead—wait till I am dead ; and
               then I promise you that you shall have my skull.”
            </p>
            
            <p>This led to a funny adventure. Not long after, M. Edouart
               was taken ill at Glasgow, and it was supposed that he would
               
               die of an internal tumor. Being a foreigner, his friends
               thought it necessary to inquire whether he had any particular directions to give concerning his burial. "Yes,” said he,
               “I wish you to have a strong box made, pack me in it, and
               write on the outside, ‘To the University of Edinburgh, with
               Monsieur Edouart’s compliments.' " The physician remonstrated in vain. His friends gathered round his bedside, and
               earnestly represented how very unpleasant it would be to his
               sons, should they at any future time visit the University, and
               have their father’s bones pointed out to them. Still he persisted that his body should be sent to Edinburgh, with Monsieur Edouart’s compliments. But notwithstanding this philosophic coolness, the continued expostulations, acting on
               nerves weakened by illness, did make an unpleasant impression. The doctor proposed to apply some leeches, one
               day; but previous to this operation, the patient had taken
               opium freely, to allay violent internal pain. The mental
               hallucination produced thereby, took its coloring partly from
               recent conversations. There was ever in his brain a whirling vision of dissecting knives, skulls and skeletons. In
               the midst of this fantasy, he fell asleep. When he awoke,
               the room was very light, and full of people. Two or three
               doctors stood near him, and kneeling across his body was a
               man with his shirt sleeves rolled up, and his hands covered
               with blood. With a loud shriek, and eyes almost starting
               from their sockets, the dying man sprung up, plunged forward
               with desperate strength, and yelling, "I’m not dead yet!”
               he pitched the man over the foot of the bed, and sent him
               with his bowl of blood and leeches, rolling over the floor.
               This violent exertion, which he could have made only under
               the stimulus of intense terror, saved his life. The inward
               tumor broke, and he once more breathed freely. It is a favorite story of his; and he usually begins with the question,
               "Did I ever tell you how I saved my life by giving my body
               for dissection ?" But to enjoy it fully, one should hear him
               tell it in his own animated and dramatic style, with his lively
               French gestures. He has been in all parts of the world, and
               seen all sorts of people, and it is as good as a well acted
               comedy, to hear him tell his adventures.
            </p>
            
            <p>The introduction of daguerreotype injures his business as it
               does miniatures and pencilled likenesses. But a Frenchman
               is like a cat, who always falls on her feet, throw her as you
               will. Instead of grumbling about modern inventions, he very
               philosophicaily began to take daguerreotypes himself; and
               whatever he undertakes, he never rests till he does it in the
               most perfect manner. At his room people can have their
               choice between daguerreotypes and silhouettes. Among the
               variety of curious workmanship there, are several animals
               covered with their own hair, which are remarkably full of
               life and expression. Altogether, it is a very agreeable place
               to look into.
            </p>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">L. M. C.</span>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            
            <div class="head">THE NEW YORK GALLERY OF THE FINE ARTS</div>
            
            <p>This is not a free exhibition, as it should be to render much
               service to the community ; but it is next door to one. The
               price of life membership is but one dollar, which will entitle
               the subscriber to a free admission forever. Single admissions
               are twenty-five cents, which is too high in proportion. We
               have not the least doubt that if the price of admission were reduced to sixpence, the number of visitors would be increased
               more than four fold. The object in establishing a Gallery of
               Art being the good of the people, every inducement that can
               possibly be held out to them to make it a place of resort,
               should be adopted. The rich and well educated stand in little need of any such aids to refinement, but to the poor and
               ignorant, a public gallery of pictures is a real blessing, and
               it is for their aid that such places are, or should be es
               
               
               tablished. A picture need not be didactic like the picturestories of Hogarth, to do good. Nature affixes no morals to any
               of her productions, yet her perfections and beauty impress
               the heart more sensibly than the wisdom of Solomon. Go to
               the ant, thou sluggard, and behold the lilies of the valley,
               are important directions which the artist should ever bear in
               mind, and aim in his works to imitate nature in representing
               a perfect and beautiful object without giving himself any trouble about the point or moral of it. If every field flower had its medicinal qualities inscribed upon its petals, we
               should take as little pleasure in wandering through the fields
               as in going into an apothecary’s shop. Whatever is beautiful speaks audibly enough to the heart and the understanding;
               all that we want is somebody to make us feel its beauty; the
               moral of it will come out of itself. Perhaps these remarks
               will prepare the way for us to say, that we dislike exceedingly Cole’s allegorical landscapes in the New York Gallery.
               The pictures in themselves are truly beautiful, but the plan
               of them is against nature. Their beauty is marred by being
               seen together. We perceive directly that we are imposed
               upon. Instead of looking upon beautiful landscapes, we discern that they are sermons in green paint; essays in gilt
               frames. The charm of nature is destroyed, the moment that
               the discovery is made; and we turn from them in disgust,
               without knowing the cause of it.
            </p>
            
            <p>But this is not the only defect of these pictures ; they are
               landscapes, and nothing else, while they affect a moral character which landscapes can never have. The men in them
               are not seen at all when they are viewed at a proper distance,
               and if seen they are subordinates, not principals, as they
               should be, in a performance which professes to point a moral. The first of the series represents a wild scene of green
               trees and so forth ; meant to typify the beginning of empire ;
               the sun is just rising from the sea, which symbolises the
               mind rising from the darkness of ignorance; a mass of heavy
               paint which obscures a good part of the canvass represents
               the mists of error fleeing before the rising sun of intelligence.
               This first picture has the least artistic merit of the series, and
               at once lets us into the secret of the allegory, and destroys all
               the pleasure that the others would give if looked upon as
               mere pictures. There can be nothing better than nature.
               Man cannot be wiser than God. It is idle, then, to think of
               improving on his manner of teaching. No landscape can
               ever teach a profitable lesson, when nature is caricatured or
               exaggerated. Her simplicity is the divinest wisdom. Let
               any one test the truth of our principle by looking at this
               "savage state" painting, and then turning to the little piece
               by the same artist at the opposite end of the gallery, numbered 65, and interpreting honestly the effect which each has upon his feelings. This last picture is one of Mr. Cole’s earlier works, painted when he seemed to love nature more than
               newspaper applause, or bank notes; it has more real merit
               than all of his allegorical pictures together; the pure morning
               sky, the still lake, the cool shadows of the dark woods, the
               feeling of nature over all, are unsurpassed by any landscape
               that has been painted in this country. A sensation of country air lingers in our memory for a whole day after seeing
               it; and we cannot but think that many of the subjects in Mr.
               Willis’ Japonica-dom, would be tempted into habits of early
               rising by seeing in this little picture how lovely the morning
               sky looks a half hour before sunrise.
            </p>
            
            <p>The last picture of the five, by Mr. Cole, representing the
               Course of Empire, is worth all the others of the series. It
               should, indeed, be exhibited by itself, without any hint being
               given of its allegorical character, that it might be enjoyed
               without any uncomfortable feeling of its didacticism.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>There is another bit of Nature in the gallery, of a character
               entirely different from the Nature which Mr. Cole loves to
               depict; the "Truant Gamblers,” by Mount. It is one of his
               best pictures; probably the very best. The color is better
               than in many of his paintings, but the expression is unapproachable. The surly farmer with the switch in his hand,
               and a world of ill-nature, which mankind have agreed to dignify with the name of prudent industry, concentrated in his
               features, will bear a comparison with the finest things in
               Hogarth. The contrast between the happy abandonment of
               the boys, whose whole souls are given up to their game, and
               the small ferocity of the farmer, who will have nobody at
               play, because he is at work, is a happy stroke of genius. If
               the gallery contained no other picture than this, it would still
               be one of the places best worth visiting in New York.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         
         <div class="head">SOME SECRETS OF THE MAGAZINE PRISON-HOUSE.</div>
         
         <p>The want of an International Copy-Right Law, by rendering
            it nearly impossible to obtain anything from the booksellers
            in the way of remuneration for literary labor, has had the effect of forcing many of our very best writers into the service
            of the Magazines and Reviews, which with a pertinacity
            that does them credit, keep up in a certain or uncertain degree the good old saying, that even in the thankless field of
            Letters the laborer is worthy of his hire. How—by dint of
            what dogged instinct of the honest and proper, these journals
            have contrived to persist in their paying practices, in the
            very teeth of the opposition got up by the Fosters and Leonard Scotts, who furnish for eight dollars any four of the British periodicals for a year, is a point we have bad much difficulty in settling to our satisfaction, and we have been forced to
            settle it, at last, upon no more reasonable ground than that
            of a still lingering esprit de patrie. That Magazines can
            live, and not only live but thrive, and not only thrive but
            afford to disburse money for original contributions, are facts
            which can only be solved, under the circumstances, by the
            really fanciful but still agreeable supposition, that there is
            somewhere still existing an ember not altogether quenched
            among the fires of good feeling for letters and literary men,
            that once animated the American bosom.
         </p>
         
         <p>It would not do (perhaps this is the idea) to let our poor devil authors absolutely starve, while we grow fat, in a literary sense, on the good things of which we unblushingly pick
            the pocket of all Europe: it would not be exactly the thing
            comme il faut, to permit a positive atrocity of this kind: and
            hence we have Magazines, and hence we have a portion of
            the public who subscribe to these Magazines (through sheer
            pity), and hence we have Magazine publishers (who sometimes take upon themselves the duplicate title of “editor and
            proprietor,”)—publishers, we say, who, under certain conditions of good conduct, occasional puffs, and decent subserviency at all times, make it a point of conscience to encourage
            the poor devil author with a dollar or two, more or less as he
            behaves himself properly and abstains from the indecent habit of turning up his nose.
         </p>
         
         <p>We hope, however, that we are not so prejudiced or so vindictive as to insinuate that what certainly does look like illiberality on the part of them (the Magazine publishers) is
            really an illiberality chargeable to them. In fact, it will be
            seen at once, that what we have said has a tendency directly
            the reverse of any such accusation. These publishers pay
            something—other publishers nothing at all. Here certainly is
            a difference—although a mathematician might contend that
            the difference might be infinitesimally small. Still, these
            Magazine editors and proprietors pay (that is the word), and
            
            
            with your true poor-devil author the smallest favors are sure
            to be thankfully received. No: the illiberality lies at the
            door of the demagogue-ridden public, who suffer their anointed delegates (or perhaps arointed—which is it ?) to insult the
            common sense of them (the public) by making orations in our
            national halls on the beauty and conveniency of robbing the
            Literary Europe on the highway, and on the gross absurdity
            in especial of admitting so unprincipled a principle, that a
            man has any right and title either to his own brains or the
            flimsy material that he chooses to spin out of them, like a confounded caterpillar as he is. If anything of this gossamer
            character stands in need of protection, why we have our hands
            full at once with the silk-worms and the morus multicaulis.
         </p>
         
         <p>But if we cannot, under the circumstances, complain of the
            absolute illiberality of the Magazine publishers (since pay
            they do), there is at least one particular in which we have
            against them good grounds of accusation. Why (since pay
            they must) do they not pay with a good grace, and promptly.
            Were we in an ill humor at this moment, we could a tale unfold which would erect the hair on the head of Shylock. A
            young author, struggling with Despair itself in the shape of a
            ghastly poverty, which has no alleviation—no sympathy from
            an every-day world, that cannot understand his necessities,
            and that would pretend not to understand them if it comprehended them ever so well—this young author is politely
            requested to compose an article, for which he will "be handsomely paid.” Enraptured, he neglects perhaps for a month
            the sole employment which affords him the chance of a livelihood, and having starved through the month (he and his
            family) completes at length the month of starvation and the
            article, and despatches the latter (with a broad hint about
            the former) to the pursy "editor” and bottle-nosed “proprietor” who has condescended to honor him (the poor devil) with
            his patronage. A month (starving still), and no reply. Another month—still none. Two months more—still none. A
            second letter, modestly hinting that the article may not have
            reached its destination—still no reply. At the expiration of
            six additional months, personal application is made at the
            "editor and proprietor” ’s office. Call again. The poor devil
            goes out, and does not fail to call again. Still call again;—and
            call again is the word for three or four months more. His
            patience exhausted, the article is demanded. No—he can’t
            have it—(the truth is, it was too good to be given up so easily)—“it is in print,” and “contributions of this character
            are never paid for (it is a rule we have) under six months after publication. Call in six months after the issue of your
            affair, and your money is ready for you—for we are business
            men, ourselves—prompt.” With this the poor devil is satisfied, and makes up his mind that the "editor and proprietor"
            is a gentleman, and that of course he (the poor devil) will
            wait as requested. And it is supposable that he would have
            waited if he could—but Death in the meantime would not.
            He dies, and by the good luck of his decease (which came by
            starvation) the fat "editor and proprietor” is fatter henceforward and for ever to the amount of five and twenty dollars,
            very cleverly saved, to be spent generously in canvas-backs
            and champagne.
         </p>
         
         <p>There are two things which we hope the reader will not
            do, as he runs over this article: first, we hope that he will
            not believe that we write from any personal experience of
            our own, for we have only the reports of actual sufferers to
            depend upon, and second, that he will not make any personal
            application of our remarks to any Magazine publisher now
            living, it being well known that they are all as remarkable
            for their generosity and urbanity, as for their intelligence, and
            appreciation of Genius.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         
         <div class="head">Original Poetry.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            
            <div class="head">REMEMBERED MUSIC.
               A FRAGMENT.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Thick rushing, like an ocean vast
               
               <br></br>Of bisons the fair prairies shaking,
               
               <br></br>The notes crowd heavily and fast
               
               <br></br>As surfs, one plunging while the last
               
               <br></br>Draws seaward from its foamy breaking.
               
               <br></br>Or in low murmurs they began,
               
               <br></br>Rising and rising momently,
               
               <br></br>As, o’er a harp Ӕolian
               
               <br></br>A fitful breeze, until they ran
               
               <br></br>Up to a sudden ecstacy.
               
               <br></br>And then, like minute-drops of rain
               
               <br></br>Ringing in water silverly,
               
               <br></br>They lingering dropt and dropt again,
               
               <br></br>Till it was almost like a pain
               
               <br></br>To listen when the next would be.
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">JAMES R. LOWELL</span>.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            
            <div class="head">THE REVELATION.</div>
            
            <div class="byline">BY 
               <span class="person">B. H.</span>
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Twilight over earth was stealing,
               
               <br></br>And my spirit’s wing was furl’d,
               
               <br></br>Musing on a dim revealing,
               
               <br></br>Of a purer, brighter world.
               
               
               <br></br>The old book I had been reading,
               
               <br></br>Brimfull was of holy thought,
               
               <br></br>Far away through darkness leading,
               
               <br></br>With a mystic meaning fraught.
               
               
               <br></br>Truth it seemed yet changing ever,
               
               <br></br>Seeking what that truth might be;
               
               <br></br>Long I strove with vain endeavor,
               
               <br></br>To unveil its mystery.
               
               
               <br></br>Sitting by the open casement,
               
               <br></br>With the old book in my hand,
               
               <br></br>Outward looking—with amazement,
               
               <br></br>There I saw a figure stand,
               
               
               <br></br>Shadowy it was and glimmered,
               
               <br></br>Like a billow’s snowy crest,
               
               <br></br>And the moonlight through it shimmered.
               
               <br></br>With a beautiful un-rest.
               
               
               <br></br>Like a shining one descending,
               
               <br></br>Struggling in the wind’s embrace,
               
               <br></br>Seemed she now—now dimly blending;
               
               <br></br>With the shadows in their race.
               
               
               <br></br>Bending with a waving motion,
               
               <br></br>She upon the yellow sand
               
               <br></br>Drew a rainbow based on ocean ;
               
               <br></br>Ocean without sea or land.
               
               
               <br></br>But the sand I saw not—only,
               
               <br></br>On the sand the bended bow,
               
               <br></br>And within it—dim and lonely,
               
               <br></br>Swung a meteor—to and fro.
               
               
               <br></br>Swinging—swinging—like a plummet,
               
               <br></br>’Till the maiden rose and saith,
               
               <br></br>"Lo !” and on the glowing summit,
               
               <br></br>Wrote in golden letters FAITH.
               
               
               <br></br>Then the meteor ceased its motion.
               
               <br></br>Upward rose with deathless ray,
               
               <br></br>And the rainbow and the ocean,
               
               <br></br>Faded from my sight away.
               
               
               <br></br>Then the silver maiden speaketh,
               
               <br></br>But with voice so soft and low,
               
               <br></br>That no word the silence breaketh,
               
               <br></br>Though their import well I know.
               
               
               <br></br>Thus the darkness shall be shivered—
               
               <br></br>And the crooked be made straight.
               
               <br></br>And thy soul shall be delivered
               
               <br></br>If thou faithful watch and wait.
               
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p9">
         
         <div class="head">HORACE GREELEY.</div>
         
         <p>We have been importuned to follow up our portraits of “Mi Boy” and the “Brigadier,”
            with the portraits of the
            other prominent editors of the New York press; and we shall endeavor to do so lest
            we be accused of partiality towards
            our friends of the Mirror. We present our readers this week with a full length
            portrait of the Editor of the Tribune, which
            will be recognized directly by all who know him.
         </p>
         
         <p>Horace Greeley is so widely known by his Tribune, that we could hardly hope to add
            any
            thing to the knowledge of the
            people by giving either an analysis of his genius or a history of his life. It is
            well known that a few years since he was
            a journeyman printer in New York, and that he is now the editor and proprietor of
            a
            leading daily paper. He first made
            himself known as the editor of the New Yorker, a very respectable semi-literary
            weekly newspaper but he has become
            famous as the editor of the Tribune. Perhaps no paper in the country has exercised
            a more extended or a healthier influence upon the public morals. No ordinary man could by the mere force of
            industry and integrity gain the position of a
            leading editor, in a political party, at a time like the present, when intelligence
            is so universally diffused, and men are so
            exacting of those who labor for them. We may, therefore, safely designate Mr.
            Greeley as a remarkable man ; if not a
            genius. The gravest charges that have ever been made against him are, that he eats
            bran bread and is in favor of Fourierism. The Fourierism we believe he has never denied, but the bran bread
            is a more questionable matter. We can testify
            to his eating boiled chicken not long since, and he has confessed that he was
            partial to good things provided they were
            not too good. It is a singular fact that the world will forgive anything in a man
            sooner than self-denial, and we have no
            doubt that the suspicion of eating bran-bread has gained Mr. Greeley more enemies
            than his eating up the substance of a
            dozen widows and orphans in luxurious dinners, could have done.
         </p>
         
         
         <div class="figure">
            
            <div class="byline">Rodman</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <p>Mr. Greeley owes his eminence mainly to his pen ; people listen to his speeches because
            they have read his writings.
            His style is admirably adapted for his uses, but would hardly wear well in a book.
            He is a disciple of Cobbett, and of
            course prides himself on grammatical correctness ; but he is ah admirer of
            Macaulay, and is of course givento flashiness of
            expression. His coloring is so hot, that his style can never be elevated, because
            he starts from the top of a subject at the outset.
            He has yet to learn the advantage of a low tone in his composition. We have rarely
            seen a piece of writing from his.
            pen which did not contain the adjectives thrilling, burning or splendid : sometimes
            these are varied by the use of glorious
            or brilliant. We take up this morning’s paper, and the first sentence which our eye
            rests upon is the following paragraph:
         </p>
         
         <p>“The address of Cassius M. Clay to the people of Kentucky, which was given in our
            last, must electrify every generous and manly heart.
            In compactness and force of argument, in fertility and cogency of illustration, in
            the burning Eloquence of Truth and Conviction, this Address
            has rarely if ever been exceeded.”
         </p>
         
         <p>We have been very careful not to caricature Mr. Greeley in our drawing, but it was
            quite impossioie to give the elevated expression of bis countenance in this style of engraving.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p10">
         
         <div class="head">THE GREAT TOWER OF TARUDANT.</div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY 
            <span class="person">ROBERT OLIVER</span>.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Two meanings have our lightest fantasies—
            
            <br></br>One of the flesh, and of the Spirit one.—Lowell.
         </div>
         
         <p>There was sorrow and lamentation in the city of Tarudant.
            Wailing voices in her pleasant palaces, and gloomy faces in
            her crowded streets. The king of Tarudant was dead. The
            good old king who had reigned so long, that greybearded
            men remembered not his accession : the good old king who
            had reigned so well, that no heart in his dominions felt lighter for his death. Seventy days they mourned him, seventy
            days and nights, in the city and throughout the kingdom.
            Very sincere was their mourning, but it could not last forever. Even the best-beloved monarch can be forgotten when
            the hand of another opens to grasp the descending sceptre.
            So, on the seventy-first day, grief gave place to joy, tears to
            smiles, and groans of woe to shouts of gladness and congratulation.
         </p>
         
         <p>The son of the king, his youngest and only remaining son,
            had ascended the vacant throne, and thereupon was the sorrow of the people turned to merriment. And well might
            they rejoice! For ages the kingdom had not been blessed
            with a more promising sovereign. While yet his father lived, Prince Abdallah had won all hearts by his kindness, his
            generosity, the grace and beauty of his person, and the valor
            he displayed in repelling the inroads of the neighboring infidel tribes—of the Berbers from the mountains and the Tauricks from the desert. Nor was he lacking in graver merits.
            The age and infirmities of the late king had during the last
            years of his reign thrown much of the burden of government
            upon the shoulders of his son, and wisely and strongly was
            that burden borne. Right well therefore might the people
            rejoice!
         </p>
         
         <p>Their sanguine hopes were for a time fulfilled. Under
            the wise and benignant rules of the young king, Tarudant
            eminently prospered, notwithstanding its limited extent and
            the comparative barrenness of the regions adjoining the great
            Sahara. Commerce and population flowed in upon the capital, while peace and plenty spread their blessings over the
            provinces. The rich without fear enjoyed their wealth, the
            poor labored without oppression. Virtue was rewarded and
            encouraged, crime punished and repressed. Learning and
            the arts were cultivated and their professors liberally patronized. The wild infidel tribes were scourged back to their
            remotest haunts, and the bounds of the kingdom enlarged on
            all sides. Secure and flourishing at home and honored
            abroad, the subjects of Abdallah were enthusiastic in his
            praise, and with one voice declared that as vicious monarchs
            were known to transmit their evil propensities to their children who succeeded them, so had the late good king yielded
            his virtues, tenfold augmented, to his son and successor.
         </p>
         
         <p>Unfortunately, this happiness was not of long duration.
            Among the multitude of poets and artists, of astrologers, magicians and other sages who thronged the splendid court of
            Tarudant, there was an Egyptian of whom no one knew
            more, than that in the second year of the king’s reign he had
            entered the city from the west, riding on a miserab|e camel,
            unattended even by a boy, and had taken up his residence in
            one of the vast colleges which the magnificent Abdallah had
            erected for the entertainment of men of learning. He gave
            out that he was a magician of great skill and power, and
            every morning repaired to the royal palace, where until
            high noon he might be seen squatted at the base of a pillar,
            with numerous small parchment rolls lying about him, and
            in his hand a staff formed of three brazen serpents wreathed
            together. He spoke to no one, but he looked in the face of
            each passer by, with an expression that besought employ
            ment, as plainly as words themselves could have done. In
            the afternoon he walked about the city, silent as ever, but
            wistfully glancing at each door and window as if momentarily expecting a call for his magical services.
         </p>
         
         <p>Still, for a long lime he found nothing to do. And in truth
            he was not a very prepossessing magician. In person he
            was short, even to dwarfishness, with a hump, though not a
            large one, on his back ; his features were coarse and ill-arranged, and there was something repulsive, almost disgusting, in his manners and whole appearance. Neither were
            these bodily defects concealed or softened by ingenious or
            splendid habiliments. He wore only a single green garment,
            tattered and dirty, which reached from his head to his heels,
            and was bound about his waist by a rope of camel’s hair.
            
            Who, therefore, could believe that a man so wretchedly
            formed, so shabbily attired, was in possession of supernatural
            knowledge and power ? That he could unveil the future
            and control the world of spirits ? Why, if he could perceive
            the destined course of events, point out hidden treasures, or
            subject the genius to his will, surely he might clothe himself in fine raiment, and surround himself with all earthly enjoyments. Yet he was evidently poor, depending for his
            very bread on the bounty of the king, and seemed depressed
            in spirit almost to unhappiness. No, no, he was certainly
            no magician. Besides he was too young to know much, not
            having a grey hair in his beard. Thus reasoned the people
            of Tarudant with an ebullition of common sense, such as they
            seldom displayed when magic or magicians were concerned.
         </p>
         
         <p>Altogether there was little prospect that Arphaxad, lor by
            this Chaldean name was the Egyptian known, would ever
            become distinguished or popular. But with all his defects he
            was at least gifted with two virtues, patience and perseverance. He persisted in his morning attendance at the palace
            and his afternoon perambulations of the streets, regardless
            alike of the silent sneers of the courtiers or the audible scoffs
            of the populace. A year passed on, and then another. In the
            third year a change occurred in his condition and appearance.
            He found employment, at first among the lowest of the people
            and in the most unimportant branches of his art. He did
            what was required of him with skill and success. He was
            again employed, again and again. His reputation spread, and
            at length began to rise. From casting nativities for tailors’
            children and pointing out hidden springs for well-diggers, he
            was called to read the stars for emirs and make love-potions
            for prince’s daughters. His fame finally reached the royal
            ears, and he was summoned to the presence of the king.
         </p>
         
         <p>He obeyed the summons with the confidence that ever attends the prosperous and popular. He was no longer the desponding and shabby looking personage of a year ago. He
            had changed with his fortunes. His vestment, though still
            green in color, was of fine texture and fashionable make; his
            demeanor was haughty, and wonderful to tell! his stature
            was enlarged and his countenance endued with a striking,
            though somewhat disdainful beauty. Attended by pages and
            running footmen fancifully clad, he rode to the palace” gates
            on a large he-ass of the famous Damascus breed, black as
            night, except where here and there a white spot, shaped like
            a star, broke the dusk of its velvet hide.
         </p>
         
         <p>The glittering courtiers stared with amazement as Arphaxad strode through the great hall of the palace, preceded by an
            emir of rank who was marshalling him to the royal presence.
            They could recognize the former object of their scorn only by
            the staff of twisted serpents which he yet retained, and which
            had been so well polished that it looked like solid gold.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Can this be the hump-backed Egyptian that used to sit
            at the base of yonder pillar ?" eagerly enquired one, with his
            eyes and mouth opened to their fullest extent.
         </p>
         
         <p>“So it seems,” replied another, more philosophical, or less
            inquisitive, who carelessly glanced, with a yawn, at the passing magician, and then resumed the contemplation of his
            own pearl-embroidered slippers.
         </p>
         
         <p>“By the beard of the prophet!” exclaimed a third, whose
            elaborate apparel but indifferently concealed his ungainly
            proportions, and insignificant stature, "the dog is a true magician after all! See, he has got rid of his hump, and if my
            eyes be not enchanted, he is half a cubit taller than he was
            a year ago. I must make his acquaintance.”
         </p>
         
         <p>"His acquaintance would profit thee but little, Cidi Hamet,”
            said a gigantic officer of the royal guard, looking down with
            good humored contempt upon the last speaker, "thou art entirely beneath the reach of magic. Solomon himself, could
            not straighten thy limbs, or stretch thy body to the proper
            height of men.’’
         </p>
         
         <p>Cidi Hamet winced at the rude sarcasm of the soldier, but
            ventured no other reply, than a forced laugh of indifference.
         </p>
         
         <p>"I do not see what the king can want of this shallow
            Egyptian, when so many better men are waiting his commands,” muttered an astrologer from Fez, who had been idly
            kicking his heels in the royal ante-chambers, every day, for
            the last seven years.
         </p>
         
         <p>"His tree of life is blossoming like the rose bushes of
            Hadramut—his fortune is rising like a young palm-tree, we
            had better make haste and sit in its shade,” chanted a poet
            from Granada, whose intolerable couplets were held in such
            general dread, that even in the great hall of the palace, he
            could always be sure of an undisturbed solitude, so dear to
            
            
            the pensive poetic soul, and who, in the absence of other listeners, inflicted his verses upon himself with a persevering
            endurance that would have done honor to an Indian fakir.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Allah il Allah! Fate transcends the finite, and destiny pervades with comprehensive perception the unessential ether,
            but the inextinguishable flame that heretofore envelopes the
            substantial, cannot be quenched by the volition of that which
            is palpable,” solemnly enunciated a philosopher from Samarcand, who for six months past had daily entertained the people
            of Tarudant, with discourses of such profundity, that no one
            had yet been able to understand a syllable of them, and who
            consequently, was held in high esteem, and surrounded by a
            very numerous school of disciples.
         </p>
         
         <p>"God is great! There is no god but God !” shouted a dervise from Persia, whose flaming beard and wise looking face
            always commanded respect, but who had never been known
            to utter any thing more oracular than the above indisputable
            truth—perhaps from a deep consciousness of the vanity of
            all earthly wisdom.
         </p>
         
         <p>While these and similar remarks circulated through the
            ante-chamber, the Egyptian magician entered the royal presence and was soon engaged in close conference with the
            king—a conference that continued till night, and through the
            night, and far into the succeeding day. It was at length
            finished and Arphaxad departed, bearing with him a rich robe
            of honor, such as was granted only to the highest favorites.
            The wondering courtiers remarked, as they obsequiously
            made way for him, that even since he entered the palace, a
            touch of more imperious beauty had been added to his face,
            and his commanding form rose more loftily than ever.
         </p>
         
         <p>From this time forth, rapid was the elevation, and eminent the prosperity of the magician. He was made first an
            emir, then a vizier, and finally, grand-vizier. In all these
            posts, he distinguished himself by his sagacity, energy, and
            activity. He so wisely counselled the king, and so ably
            executed the royal commands, that the kingdom of Tarudant
            flourished as no kingdom ever did, save when Solomon
            reigned in Israel. The magical power of the Egyptian grew
            more potent as he himself increased in dignity and its consequent wealth ; for the success of his principal incantations,
            depended mainly on the employment of certain rare and costly
            ingredients, which none could procure but the rich and
            powerful; and with these at his command, he was enabled
            to enslave numerous mighty genies, by whose aid the
            most stupendous labors were performed. The provinces
            were covered with vast works—aqueducts, canals, reservoirs,
            and water-wheels, intended to correct the sterility of the soil
            and facilitate cultivation—roads, bridges, and caravanserais,
            for the acommodation of commerce and travel. The cities
            were filled with superb edifices, erected alike for ornament
            and use—with palaces, mosques, colleges, libraries, khans,
            bazaars, and baths. Nor was the defence of the kingdom
            less cared for than its splendor and convenience. Strong
            towers rose on every hill-top, and impregnable castles guarded every mountain-pass. Each city was surrounded by a
            treble wall of prodigious height and thickness, and the capital,
            Tarudant itself, was encompassed with a mound of stone, so
            high that its shadow covered a third part of the city, and so
            broad, that its summit sustained trees sufficient to form a
            considerable forest.
         </p>
         
         <p>Great armies were also raised, in whose ranks genies mingled with men, and conquests were made upon all sides, except towards the east, where the mighty chain of Mount Atlas reared its white tops to heaven, presenting so formidable
            an aspect, that even the charm-guarded warriors of the
            Egyptian shrank from attempting to pass the desert which
            lay between the mountains and the eastern border of the
            kingdom.
         </p>
         
         <p>Protected by the mighty fortifications, guarded by the invincible armies, and aided by the vast and cunningly contrived works of the magician, the people of Tarudant waxed
            rich and numerous, for so great and wide-spread became the
            renown of king Abdallah, and his sage vizier, that multitudes
            from other nations, bringing with them their gold, and silver,
            and precious stones, and costliest goods, flocked into the
            kingdom, eager to sit in the shade of its protection, and to
            bask in the sunshine of its prosperity. They came, not only
            from the neighboring Fez, Tafilet, and Morocco, but from
            Granada, and Egypt, and even from remote Persia and India.
            So the kingdom overflowed with wealth and population.
            Caravans bearing rich burdens animated its plains with
            endless processions. Buyers and sellers crowded the capa
            cious bazaars. From morn till eve, the air resounded with
            the din and clangor of innumerable work-shops—from eve till
            morn, the darkness was cheered by the blaze of festivity, and
            the shouts of sport and merriment. Unceasing were the
            praises bestowed by the happy and grateful people on the
            good king and his wise vizier, whose administration had produced such wonderfully beneficial results.
         </p>
         
         <p>But magicians, and especially Egyptian magicians, though
            excellent servants, are very bad masters. And whether it be
            from an aspiring nature, or from habits of imperious command
            acquired in the exercise of their dominion over spirits, they
            ever seek to obtain unlimited control of all with whom they
            are brought into contact. He who had worked such marvels
            in the kingdom of Tarudant, began to be mightily elated by
            the success that attended his efforts, and the praises that
            were lavished upon his achievements. His stature, already
            great, increased and increased, until it was fairly gigantic;
            and the haughty beauty of his face became so imposing, that
            at length it was almost fearful to look upon. His green garment grew more and more vivid in its hue, and the Damascus ass on which he invariably rode, augmented to a size
            proportioned to that of its master.
         </p>
         
         <p>Long ago the magician had taken up his abode in the royal
            palace, so as to be ever at the king’s right hand. He constructed for himself apartments more spacious and splendid
            than even those of the monarch, from which they were separated only by a long narrow court, planted with fig trees.
            Here he dwelt in great pomp, surrounded by a guard of black
            genies, armed with highly polished brazen swords, who held
            themselves always in readiness to execute his least command.
         </p>
         
         <p>Day by day, something was added to this state and to
            the number of these guards. And day by day, the magician
            became more haughty and domineering. Favored by the
            king, and popular with the people, there was nothing to
            check his ambition, except the feeble opposition of a few superannuated viziers, who gravely shook their gray heads, and
            muttered their doubt "whether any good would come of all
            this.” But as such had been, for years, their invariable reception of every thing new, no one paid any attention to
            their sage warnings, and they were merely laughed at as
            men behind the age.
         </p>
         
         <p>(To be continued.)</p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p11">
         
         <div class="head">THE CONCERT ROOM.</div>
         
         <p>Gratuitous Services at Charitable Concerts.--Our
            attention has often been called to this subject, and we have
            frequently determined to discuss it in all its bearings. We
            have been hitherto prevented from fulfilling our intentions,
            but we will do so no now, for it is high time to understand
            in what relation the professor, the beneficiary and the public, stand towards each other, under such circumstances.
         </p>
         
         <p>Every high-minded man must be an advocate of the cause
            of charity. It is a sacred, a holy cause, and one to which
            every one should willingly contribute his mite. But we
            were always of opinion that professional people have ever
            been too highly taxed. They are applied to upon every trivial occasion; benefits, charities, hospitals, churches, compliments, in short, every week brings forth some necessity
            for their valuable services. They are supposed to possess
            souls overflowing with the milk of human kindness, and
            stuffed to repletion with the most extended philanthropy ; for
            every sect, of every denomination, from the Catholic to the
            Jew, appeals to their sympathy and their benevolence. This
            may seem all very natural to those who do not reflect upon
            the subject, who think it is only giving up one evening to
            the service of charity, which certainly cannot hurt them, it
            costs them nothing. This is a false and fatal conclusion. It
            costs them in fact ten times more than it does those who are
            known to the wealthy, and who are by the world deemed
            liberal. Supposing a charitable subscription were opened,
            and application made to a professor of music, surely, five
            dollars would be considered a liberal donation. Contrast
            this small amount with the sum, in a measure demanded, in
            the services of a professor. We will mention two instances,
            
            
            one of them Madame Otto. Within the last six months,
            this lady, whose kindness and disinterested nature is well
            known, has given away in gratuitous services, no less a sum
            than five hundred dollars. Mrs. Edward Loder has in the
            like manner, during the short time she has been in this country, given away in charity not less than fifteen hundred dollars, and on some occasions has been compelled to relinquish
            lucrative engagements which offered, after having allowed
            her name to be announced in a Benefit bill. These are facts
            to which every professor in the city will bear witness. Nor
            does the loss end here; dresses must be bought, gloves,
            shoes, and coach hire provided for, and lessons must be
            missed in order that rehearsals may be attended. And yet,
            for all these sacrifices of time and money, what consideration do they meet with in the community when they apply
            for assistance at a concert for their benefit ? If we look
            through the lists of concerts for the two past years, we shall
            not find more than six concerts given by resident professors,
            and most of these were positive failures. One of these,
            given by a gentleman universally esteemed for his readiness
            to do any act of kindness when called upon, and which held
            out every attraction of novelty and excellence, did not yield
            him sufficient to pay one half of the lessons he was compelled
            to miss in order to get it up.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is a fact which we grieve to state, that every effort of
            this kind made by a resident professor, is utterly discounte
            nanced by the citizens; the encouragement so lavishly bestowed upon Ethiopian serenaders and wandering families,
            is determinedly withheld from the laborious and worthy resident. What encouragement have they then to be liberal,
            when their liberality meets with no return ?
         </p>
         
         <p>We believe that the position of Professors of Music, with
            regard to charitable societies, is this: that at such concerts
            where their abilities and attractions are necessary to raise
            funds for said societies, that some proportion of the gains
            should go to those who earned them at a sacrifice of time and
            money.
         </p>
         
         <p>For several months in the year, professors of music are
            almost without employment—a portion of the year dead to
            them, as regards income. The winter season is their harvest time alone. Time is short, and time is to them money,
            or in other words provision for the coming summer, and every
            non-remunerating engagement is a positive and irreparable
            loss.
         </p>
         
         <p>Under such circumstances, too much should not be asked,
            when in return nothing is given.
         </p>
         
         <p>In our next we shall treat of the duties of professors towards the public, after having gratuitously allowed them to
            appear as performers upon particular occasions. Under this
            head we shall particularly notice the benefit of the Transfiguration Church on Sunday evening last.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         
         <div class="head">VARIETIES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            
            <div class="head">CHEAP POSTAGE.</div>
            
            <p>It is truly astonishing to see with what pertinacity our
               legislators cling to old abuses, and with what eagerness they
               adopt new ones. The people have year after year petitioned
               and begged for a reform in our Post Office system without
               the least success ; some of the keenest intellects in the
               country have demonstrated time after time that a reduction
               in the rates of postage would cause an increase in the revenue of that department of the Government, without being
               able to convince the functionary at the head of the bureau, or a
               majority of the members of Congress. But the President
               recommends the annexation of a foreign territory by joint resolution of Congress, and his hint is acted upon with indecent
               
               haste, notwithstanding that the people declare themselves
               opposed to the measure. But we discern a glimpse of morning breaking out from this darkness. The joint resolution
               will not pass both houses, and the cheap postage has already
               passed one and may pass the other. We hope so. There is
               no need of argument upon the subject at this day, for no project has ever had more lavished upon it, while nothing has
               appeared against it.
            </p>
            
            <p>We believe that one of the most important actors in this
               business has been Mr. James W. Hale, of this city, whose enterprise and courage in establishing a private express between
               New York, Boston and Philadelphia, first opened the eyes of
               the gentlemen who are called the government to the danger
               they incurred of having a rival Post Office department, unless
               they submitted to a reform of the present scandalous system
               of taxing the nation, which results in good to nobody. The
               rates of postage fixed by the bill which has just passed the
               Senate, we believe to be too high; and the consequence will
               be that the private expresses will continue to carry letters at
               a less rate than the government. But, we trust that the bill
               will become a law, notwithstanding. It is of great importance in many points of view, but most so as encouraging the
               people to persevere in petitioning Congress, and in writing to
               members individually, in behalf of any measure which they
               would have carried. We hope to see an international copyright bill passed at the next session by these means.
            </p>
            
            <p>But while we congratulate the people on the achievement
               of their wishes in the passage of the postage reform bill, we
               must not forget those spirited individuals who have labored
               so strenuously the last two or three years to bring it about.
               The New World has contained some admirable papers on
               the subject, which we have understood were from the pen of
               Barnabis Bates. The Tribune has also been untiring and
               indefatigable in the cause, and from its great circulation, and
               influence among politicians, must have done much towards
               bringing our representatives to their senses. The entire
               press, we believe, has favored the measure, but our Congressional Pharoahs hardened their hearts against all argument,
               until Mr. Hale began to demonstrate to them that, if let alone
               a little longer, the people would adopt him for their Post
               Master General, and not trouble them any more upon the subject.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Hale has, at this time, no less than ninety-six branch
               offices, and nearly three hundred assistants; during the past
               year he has paid twenty thousand dollars for conductors and
               office expresses, and twenty-five hundred dollars in defending
               himself in suits brought against him by Government. Judges
               Betts and Conkling of New York, and Sprague of Massachusetts, District Judges of the U. S., and Mr. Justice Story
               of the Supreme Court, are in favor of private mails, or at least
               believe them to be legal, while Judges Randall of Pennsylvania, and Heath, of Maryland, decide otherwise.
            </p>
            
            <p>If the bill that has passed the Senate should become a
               law, the private mails will probably be abolished; but the
               carrying of letters between the principal cities on the Atlantic coast would be a very profitable business at a penny
               each, and if the Supreme Court should decide that the Constitution does not prohibit private mails, the establishment
               of Mr. Hale's will continue to do as large a business as it
               does now. That the Post Office system is on the whole
               injurious to the welfare of the country we have no doubt;
               and we look upon the bill just passed by the Senate as an
               indication of its entire abolition at no very distant day.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Apropos des Bottes.—Speaking of letters, reminds us to remind
               
               <br></br>our readers that the indefatigable manager of the U. S. City Despatch
               
               <br></br>Post Office, has engaged two or three hundred extra carriers to distri-
               
               <br></br>bute Valentines ; so that all will be delivered in time that may be
               sent.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            
            <div class="head">THEFTS OF AMERICAN AUTHORS.</div>
            
            <p>"Somebody is a thief,” said the critic of the Mirror a few
               days since, when commenting on Longfellow's “Waif.”
               The occasion of the remark was a comparison of the following lines by Hood—
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>We watched her breathing through the night,
               
               <br></br>Her breathing soft and low.
               
               <br></br>As in her breast the wave of life
               
               <br></br>Kept heaving to and fro.
               
               <br></br>So silently we seemed to speak,
               
               <br></br>So slowly moved about,
               
               <br></br>At we had lent her half our powers
               
               <br></br>To eke her being out.
               
               <br></br>Our very hope belied our fears;
               
               <br></br>Our fears our hopes belied ;
               
               <br></br>We thought her dying when she slept,
               
               <br></br>And sleeping when she died.
               
               <br></br>For when the mom came dim and sad,
               
               <br></br>And chill with early showers,
               
               <br></br>Her quiet eye lids closed :—the had
               
               <br></br>Another morn than ours.
               
            </div>
            
            
            <p>with these stanzas by Mr. Aldrich—</p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Her sufferings ended with the day,
               
               <br></br>Yet lived she at its close,
               
               <br></br>And breathed the long, long night away
               
               <br></br>In statue-like repose;
               
               <br></br>But when the sun in all its state
               
               <br></br>Illumed the eastern skies,
               
               <br></br>She passed through Glory’s morning gate,
               
               <br></br>And walked in paradise.
               
            </div>
            
            
            <p>We can discover no resemblance between these verses,
               sufficient to warrant the charge of plagiarism, excepting the
               measure and the subject, which are certainly not peculiar to
               Hood; the thoughts are by no means identical. We are
               very sure that the Mirror would not be guilty of accusing any
               one of a literary theft without good reason, but we do not
               perceive the warrant for the accusation in this case. Mr.
               Aldrich is the last man in the world to be guilty of so disreputable an artifice, and certainly would never have committed a theft of this kind, which would have been certain to
               meet with instant detection. The truth is, that his lines appeared in the New World in 1840: and two years afterward,
               when Hood’s lines first appeared, he copied them himself into
               the same paper, of which he had become an assistant editor.
               There is certainly a curious coincidence of feeling between
               the verses of Mr. Aldrich, and those of Hood; but such things
               are very common in all the poets, from Homer downwards.
               There is no such thing as originality of sentiment; expression is all that any poet can claim as his own. There is
               hardly a name in Mr. Griswold’s catalogue of American poets, less obnoxious to the charge of plagiarism than that of
               James Aldrich.
            </p>
            
            <p>Charges of plagiarism are very frequently made, and often
               with good reason, against our popular authors, but we doubt
               whether any man, with a reputation worth having, would
               knowingly commit himself in this manner. The greatest
               writers have always been the greatest plagiarists, or at least
               they have been most frequently accused of this sin. But we
               believe that no author who can claim anything as his own
               ever suffered in his reputation from having used the thoughts
               of other writers. The "Rover” of last week contains a very
               grave charge against Longfellow of passing off in Graham’s
               Magazine a ballad of Motherwell’s as a translation from the
               Herman, which, if true, would lead us to distrust everything
               that came from his pen. But the best way in such cases, is
               to hunt up the proof, before so serious a charge is made
               against an author whose reputation belongs not to himself
               alone, bat to his country.
            </p>
            
            <p>The charge of plagiarism against Mrs. Ellet—which we
               think should have been called “an unblushing charge of
               Plagiarism” rather than "a charge of unblushing plagiarism”
               
               —is thus noticed in the Southern Chronicle, published at
               Columbia, S. C., where Mrs. Ellet resides. The numerous
               friends of Mrs. Ellet needed no explanation, and it seems
               marvellous, that any person connected with the press should
               honestly have mistaken the matter.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Still another, and a more injurious wrong, is sometimes done of
               which authors have to suffer the inconvenience. A newspaper copies
               a tale, which is part, or wholly a translation from some foreign language, and leaves out the acknowledgment, publishing it as original.
               For example, a story that appeared a few months since in the Democratic Review, entitled 'Blind Jaques’—a translation from the French
               —we saw republished in one of the city papers, without the acknowledgment that it had been in the Review, and with the translator’s
               name paraded in staring capitals as the author of the tale Thus, for
               the sake of saving the printer a couple of minute’s work, a positive
               wrong is done, and an innocent person subjected to the charge of
               plagiarism, which is, perhaps, re-echoed by the very paper whose
               culpable neglect occasioned it! We sincerely hope, for the sake of
               honor, and truth, and justice, if not of courtesy, that such doings may
               not be repeated. A word to the wise, we trust, will be sufficient.”
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p14">
         
         <div class="head">THE MAGAZINES.</div>
         
         <p>We have received No. l. of the Aristidean, a Magazine of Reviews,
            Politics, and light Literature, for March, 1845, edited by Thomas Dunn
            English, and published by Lane &amp;. Co., 304 Broadway. Price five dollars per annum.
         </p>
         
         <p>The plan of this new Magazine is altogether admirable ; we can
            conceive of nothing better in the form of a magazine, than a monthly
            miscellany that "combines the solidity of the Review and the lightness of the Magazine, with the political cast of the newspaper.” And
            then "the politics of the Aristidean is democratic,” "it sustains the
            abolition of the death punishment,” "it advocates equal rights,” "it
            labors to be just.” All these good things we pick out of the publisher’s
            advertisement. They are true, of course. Nothing can be finer, nothing better suited to the wants of the public, but, we fear, nothing
            less
            likely to be accomplished. However, it is an important point to have
            a good aim, and Mr. English is certainly entitled to the consideration
            of the public for his good intentions, even though he should fall somewhat short of the mark he aims at. The first article in the Aristidean
            advocates the annexation of Texas to the United States; a measure, to
            our perception, as little savoring of the spirit of Aristides as any that
            could be proposed. The next article is a drinking song as little Aristidean as the paper on Texas.
         </p>
         
         <p>The last stanza runs thus—</p>
         
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>"Old Sampson and Cӕsar—
            
            <br></br>Each man was a sneezer—
            
            <br></br>Tossed off, with a will, rosy wine;
            
            <br></br>While Ovid, the scamp, he
            
            <br></br>With Cato and Pompey,
            
            <br></br>Drank three bottles each when they’d dine.
            
            <br></br>So we tread in the steps of the famous in rhyme—
            
            <br></br>The jolly old Cocks of the gone-sway time.”
            
         </div>
         
         
         <p>What puzzles us most in this article is the difficulty of classing it;
            whether with "the solidity of the review,” or, "the lightness of the
            magazine.” We don’t know which. Article III. is a notice of
            George Jones’s Ancient America, the fairest specimen of an elegant
            book that we have seen in many a day. The notice is funny enough,
            and it has a little vignette by Darley, worthy of Punch. This article
            might have been written by Aristides himself without casting a shadow upon his reputation. The "Mouse Trap,” "Hell and the Maelstrom,” and the article on Bishop Onderdonk, are not exactly in the
            ordinary magazine strain. Nobody will accuse the Aristidean of sham.
            by-pambyism, let them accuse it of what other sins they may. Mr.
            English has had the courage to project a magazine different from the
            prevailing fashion in such publications, and we trust that he will receive the support that he deserves; probably he would ask for nothing
            more himself.
         </p>
         
         <p>Magazine literature is the only literature that can flourish among us
            until we have an international copyright law ; we therefore look with
            an eye of favor upon every new candidate that appears among us ; and
            instead of taking them as they come out, and weighing them in the
            balance with Blackwood’s Magazine, as our reading public are in the
            habit of doing, they should be received kindly, at least, and where we
            have no patronage to bestow, we should withhold our disparagements.
            A book, by itself, is getting every day rarer and rarer in our literature,
            and there being no other channel than the Magazine for our thoughts
            to flow in, the Magazine should be cherished until a better day dawn
            upon us.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         
         <div class="head">LITERARY NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            
            <div class="ab">A Plea for Woman, being a Vindication of the importance and extent of her
               
               <br></br>natural sphere of action. By Mrs. Hugo Reid; with an introduction by
               
               <br></br>Mrs. C. M. Kirkland. New York: Farmer &amp; Daggers, 30 Ann street.
            </div>
            
            <p>The introduction to this book, by the accomplished author of
               Forest Life, is one of the most felicitous essays that we have seen
               from her pen, although it is not in her peculiar vein. Her recommendation of the work, is a guarantee of its claims to notice. "Woman’s
               Rights” is a subject that we have never seen the propriety of handling
               with the kind of inconsiderate flippancy in which it is generally done.
               The motto of this little work is suggestive of all the wisdom belonging
               to the subject:
            </p>
            
            <p>“Can man be free if woman be a slave ?”</p>
            
            <p>Assuredly not. In all ages, the relative rights of men and women have
               been the same ; when we think of the Hindoo widow throwing herself
               upon the funeral pyre of her husband, we must not forget the condition
               of the husband himself when alive, nor the men who suffer by the
               wrongs of the wife. It appears to us that the surest way for women
               to gain their rights—always supposing that they do not enjoy them—
               is to train up their children properly, and they will see that their mothers suffer no wrong. When women dissipate their days and nights
               in idle amusements, and squander their incomes in dress, while their
               sons are entrusted to the keeping of hired servants, or sent away from
               home to distant schools, they must not blame men that they have no
               clearer perception of what is due to women. It is true that men make
               the laws by which women are governed, but the women make the men
               who govern them.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            
            <div class="ab">Hunt’s Merchants' Magazine for February.</div>
            
            <p>We omitted, by accident, to mention this excellent periodical in our
               last week’s Review. The present number contains some admirable
               articles, and a good many valuable tables. One of the most amusing
               papers that we have read in a long while, is an article on the last Census. It is written in all seriousness, but it reveals a series of
               blunders,
               and perverted facts, in the census returns, more laughable than any
               thing which Punch has uttered during the past year; it proves very
               plainly that the census is not worth a copper, and that its returns are
               more likely to be wrong than right. Yet, after all, it is no doubt as
               correct as any census ever was, or ever will be.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            
            <div class="ab">The Monthly Rose. Vol. I. No. 2. A periodical sustained by the present
               
               <br></br>members of the Albany Female Academy. Albany. E. H. Pease and W. C.
               
               <br></br>Little.
            </div>
            
            <p>A neat little pamphlet of sixteen pages, containing some prettily
               written essays and verses, of such a character as might be looked for
               from the pens of well educated young ladies. Among the contributors
               we notice the initials of M. G., which we have seen appended to some
               poetry of an elevated character in the Knickerbocker and in the New
               World.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            
            <div class="ab">Guano; its Origin, Properties, and Uses—showing its importance to the Far-
               
               <br></br>mers of the United State, as a cheap and valuable Manure, with
               directions
               
               <br></br>for using it. New York: Wiley and Putnam. 1844.
            </div>
            
            <p>This pamphlet contains a condensed and well arranged summary
               of all the facts in regard to the subject on which it treats. To every
               cultivator of the soil, from the proprietor of a pot of mignionette to the
               planter of a sugar estate, it is a subject of vast interest. We could
               enter upon the topic con amore, but that its nature renders it unfit for
               extended notice in our columns. The publishers of this pamphlet have
               done a great service to the American public in importing from England
               every work on the cultivation of the soil, which has been published in
               that country. Among their collection of agricultural and horticultural
               books, are some of the most costly and elegantly illustrated works
               which have issued from the British press. They have done much towards rendering agriculture a favorite pursuit among liberal minds, by
               showing that it is not only the most useful of the Arts, for an Art it is,
               or nothing, but one of the most elegant.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            
            <div class="ab">The Edinburgh Review. No. clxiii, for January, 1845. American Edition.
               
               <br></br>Leonard Scott &amp; Co., 112 Fulton street.
            </div>
            
            <p>Since English Reviews must be republished in this country, our own
               writers and publishers being precluded from undertaking the publication of American works of this class, by the absence of a copyright
               law, we are glad that the enterprise has fallen in such good hands as
               the publishers of the London, Edinburgh, Foreign, and Westminster.
               A greater amount of good reading, for so small a sum as these works
               cost, was never before afforded to the public.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The January number of the Edinburgh contains seven articles, the
               the most important being on the progress of Scientific Agriculture.
               The article on Charles Churchill, will be found, perhaps, the best
               reading for a literary gossip.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s6">
         
         <div class="head">BITS OF NEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            
            <p>Schnol for the Arts of Design.—The Mechanic’s Institute of
               this city have established an Evening School for the Arts of Design, as
               applied to the mechanic Arts, and their success is fully equal to the
               most sanguine expectations of the friends of the project. In addition
               to a well selected assortment of casts from the Antique, they have imported from France, copies of the best specimens of scroll work and
               arabesque ornament. T. Cummings, Paul R. Duggan, and the President
               of the Institute, act as teachers, and the pupils have produced some
               drawings which would not disgrace the exhibition of the National
               Academy of Design. The benefits to result from this course are already well understood, and we may fairly hope, that at no distant period of time, our mechanical products will equal the classical beauty
               of those of France, where the Arts of Design form part of a common
               school education. Classes have also been formed in mechanical drawing, mathematics as applied to the mechanic Arts, Chemistry, &amp;c.,
               &amp;c.
               The Conversational meetings of the Institute are also very useful to
               its members, and under its present spirited organization, it is certainly
               worthy the support of our citizens generally.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            
            <p>The Common Council have unanimously resolved to allow the use of
               the building in the Park, known as the Rotunda, to the New York
               Gallery of the Fine Arts, at an annual rent of one dollar We are
               heartily rejoiced at this manifestation of right feeling in the representatives of the people, which we trust will be followed by other
               evidence
               of an appreciation of the importance of Art. We think that the interests of the people would have been better served by a removal of the
               building, but if it is to stand, it could not be put to a better use than
               that to which it is happily appropriated.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p22">
         
         <div class="head">MUSICAL INTELLIGENCE.</div>
         
         <p>Madame Pico has been very successful in Boston. Sanquirico has
            also there created a favorable impression.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Henry Phillips is in Mobile. He has been very generally successful through the country. He returns here in the fall, but we doubt
            if he will have anything to do with concert-giving in this, to him, unsympathising city. We have heard rumors relative to his ulterior
            views, but the time is not ripe enough to gossip thereupon.
         </p>
         
         <p>Frazer and the Seguins' open this week at Savannah.</p>
         
         <p>The Campanologians or Swiss Bell Ringers are in Columbus. Their
            performance has attracted universal admiration.
         </p>
         
         <p>We understand that the nabobs of the "Up-Town Hotel” have determined to build an Opera House on the corner of Second Street. Having thus determined, the only thing which remains to be done is to
            take up the shares. They are fixed at the low price of $500, and are
            expected to yield a great per centage in time.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have heard, however, of another project, which, according to
            the account of our informant, is to be positively carried into operation ; purchase of the property having been made, with agreements
            signed and sealed. The property here alluded to is that generally
            known as Niblo’s Garden, on the site of which it is proposed that a
            splendid Opera House, Concert Room and Hotel shall be built. The
            situation is undoubtedly superior to that chosen by the Up-Town Hotel people.
         </p>
         
         <p>In addition to the great attractions mentioned in our last, Mr. Loder’s Grand Classical Concert will contain yet another. A French genlleinan now in this city, a friend of Henri Vieuxtemps, and therefore
            friendly to every thing classical, observing Mr. Loder’s announcement,
            presented to him a MS. composition of M. Vieuxtemps. It is an offertorium consisting of a duett for soprano voice and violin, with chorus
            and fall orchestral accompaniments. The solo parts will be, we believe, performed by Mrs. Edward Loder and Signor Rapetti.
         </p>
         
         <p>This composition has only been performed once in Europe, at the
            opening of the church of St. Bemacle in Verviers, Belgium, on which
            occasion its extraordinary beauty drew forth, at its close, and in spite
            of the solemnity of the occasion, a tumultuous burst of applause.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Slomans have been very successful in Philadelphia. These
            talented young ladies are beginning lo be justly appreciated.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s7">
         
         <div class="head">CORRESPONDENCE.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            
            <p>For the Broadway Journal.</p>
            
            <p>"With all our boasting of American genius, we have not yet been
               able to design a pattern for a cap ribbon.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The author of the above extract from the article on the Illuminated
               Bible, in the Journal of the 8th inst., does not appear to be well posted
               up on that subject.
            </p>
            
            <p>A friend of the writer, seven years ago, imported cap and bonnet ribbons made after his own designs in this country, and at the present
               time samples of the most beautiful styles recently imported and sold
               here, also from original designs of Americans, not artists, but merchants, can be showed to the editor if desired.
            </p>
            
            <p>The writer sends this correction, because he supposed the author of
               the above article would have no objection to be corrected in a matter
               which, although of little moment in itself, reflects upon the taste and
               ingenuity of a class of men who are supposed by the literary portion of
               the community, to have no ideas beyond those engendered and fostered by the almighty dollar.
            </p>
            <span class="person">S. A. W.</span>
            
            <div class="note">[We give place to the above communication with great pleasure, for
               we are happy to learn that our dealers in fancy goods are not so dependent upon the inventive genius of Frenchmen as we had supposed. If
               our merchants, without an artistical education, are able to make pleasing combinations of colors in a style of goods, whose sole value
               depends
               upon their power to gratify the eye, it is sufficient proof that with a
               proper education, our ornamental artists might furnish all the designs
               requisite to place our manufactures on a basis which the most stringent
               tariff could never do.—Ed.]
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            
            <p>To the Editor of the Broadway Journal.</p>
            
            <p>Mr. Editor—While reading the fifth nnmber of your paper, I was
               much struck by an article entitled, Barbarities of the Theatre. Since
               then it has been forcibly recalled to my memory, by an accident which
               I myself witnessed at the Chatham theatre, only last week. A young
               lady, Miss Orville, came forward to sing a song. She was clad in a full
               dress of some light material. The symphony was scarcely finished,
               when a draught of air blew her dress towards the footlights; it was immediately in flames, but the leader of the orchestra, with a promptitude which reflects great credit upon his humanity, leaned over and
               struck the dress with his bow; this attracted the young lady’s attention, who with admirable presence of mind, though with difficulty, extinguished the flames. The pit greeted the accident with a shout of
               laughter, which was immediately drowned by a hearty burst of applause from other parts of the house.
            </p>
            
            <p>But for her coolness and self-possession in so fearful a situation, Miss
               Orville might have met with a fate similar to that of the unfortunate
               Miss Clara Webster. I do trust, Mr. Editor, that you will, for the sake
               of humanity, wield your powerful pen in the endeavor to correct this
               wanton negligence on the part of managers.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">I remain; your obedient servant,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, Feb. 5, 1845. </div>A Reader.
            
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p25">
            
            <p>To the Editor of the Broadway Journal.</p>
            
            <p>Dear Mr Editor,</p>
            
            <p>Im a surprised that you print our letters; we only wrote to you
               for advice. I am sure I shall never get over seeing my name in a newspaper. It is dreadful. Who knows but somebody will think that I am
               a writer ? I should be mortified to death if they did. I never heard of
               such a thing as printing a lady’s letter; if you do it again I shall not
               like it at all, and my brother will stop the paper. But there is one
               thing that I would like to know. The boys are forever talking about
               Japonica-dom,—and I can’t for the life of me find out what it means.
               What is it ? I think it must be the people who wear japanned leather;
               is it not ? It seems to me that the young men now-a-days do a goop
               many ridiculous things; among the other strange words which the
               boys use, is tricity this and tricity that. It is positively dreadful. The
               other night when I took William to do for speaking so freely about
               brandy and water, he replied to me, "Don’t bother xne with your
               aunt-tricity." I am sure I was never more shocked in my life. It is
               dreadful. Please answer my queries without printing my letter, but to
               prevent exposure, I sign myself only
            </p>
            
            Your Friend.
            
            <div class="note">P. S. The punning gentleman has lately begun upon conundrums, and
               be called upon us in the midst of the snow storm to tell us that a bonnet is not a bonnet when it becomes a lady. Such dreadful trash ! Of
               course nobody laughed but the gentleman himself. Do you think that
               conundrums are as immoral as puns? I mean to ask Dr. Slospoken.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s8">
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">MENDELSSOHN’S LOBGESANG.</div>
            
            <p>MR. GEORGE LODER respectfully announces to
               the public of New York that his CLASSICAL CONCERT will take place
               at the Apollo Rooms, on February 22d, 1844. (Washington’s Birthday,) when
               will be produced, for the first time in America, the
               LOBGESANG, OR HYMN OF PRAISE,
               Symphonic Cantate, for Grand Orchestra and Choir. The solo parts by
               MRS. E. LODER, MISS WATSON and SIGNOR ANTOGNINI.
            </p>
            
            <p>To be followed by a Miscellaneous Concert, in which the first vocal and
               instrumental talent of the city will appear.
            </p>
            
            <p>The subscription list still remains open at the store of Messrs. Scharfenberg and Luis. 361 Broadway, near Franklin street, or at the residence
               of Mr.
               Loder, 97 Crosby street.
            </p>
            
            <p>TICKETS ONE DOLLAR—Family Tickets, to admit five persons, Three
               Dollars.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">KEIGHTLEY’S HISTORICAL WORKS.</div>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF GREECE.—By Thomas Keight-
               ley, with notes and additions by G. Toulman Smith, in one volume.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF ROME— By the same author, with notes and additions in the same manner, in one volume.</p>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF THE ROMAN EMPIRE—Being a continuation of
               the History of Rome. By the same author. In one volume.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF ENGLAND—From the Invasion of Julius Cӕsar to
               the close of the reign of George IV. By the same author, with notes
               and additions as above. In two volumes. Published by
               TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John St.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
               The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
               professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">
               
               <br></br>Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo. Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
               
               <br></br>Joshua Herrick, Me. John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               
               <br></br>James Irvin, Pa. J. Thompson, Miss.
               
               <br></br>Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY</div>
            
            <p>AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
               Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
               the Medal, four first Premiums, and two "Highest Honors,” at the
               Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
               the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
            </p>
            
            <p> Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
               at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
               the score of economy.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American Instruments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polishing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received
               promptly attended to.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE AMERICAN REVIEW.</div>
            
            <p>A WHIG JOURNAL OF POLITICS, LITERATURE, ART AND SCIENCE. Edited by Geo. S. Colton, and published monthly at 118 Nassau St. New York, and by Wiley &amp; Putnam
               161
               Broadway, and 6 Waterloo Place, Regent Street, London,—at Five Dollars
               per anum IN advance—Single Nos. fifty cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is the aim of this Review—discarding all national and sectarian influence
               —to harmonize in a kindlier acquaintanceship the different sections of the
               country ; to set forth more clearly the inexhaustible resources of our territory ; to elevate the morals of the people : to withstand pusillanimity
               at home,
               and indignities abroad; to promote American science, and diffuse throughout
               the land a higher order of taste in letters and the Arts. Though established
               ostentsibly on partisan grounds, the Review proposes to itself no mere party
               triumph—but the moral, social and literary welfare of the commonwealth.
            </p>
            
            <p>The following is from the origional Prospectus issued at Washington by
               the Whig Members of the Twenty-Seventh Congress:
            </p>
            
            <p> "Earnestly approving of the plan of such a national organ, long needed
               and of manifest importance, the undersigned agree to contribute for its pages, from time to time, such communications as may be requisite to set
               forth,
               and defend the doctrines held by the united Whig Party of the Union.—Geo
               P. Marsh, D. D. Barnard, J. R. Ingersoll, E. Joy Morris, T.D. Clingman, J.
               McPherson Berrien, Daniel Webster, Robert C. Winthropk Thomas Butler
               King, Hamilton Fish, J. P. Kennedy, J. Collamer, John J. Hardin, Wm. S.
               Archer, Rulus Choate, Alexander H. Stephens.”
            </p>
            
            <p>In addition to these, a number of writers have been enlisted for its various
               other departments, so that every number, besides strong political articles,
               will contain about 80 pages of Literary Miscellany in History, Biography,
               Criticism, Fiction, Poetry, Statistics, Science and the Arts, three or four Engravings of the most finished—the likenesses of men eminent in the
               present
               or past age, will be given in the course of the year. No pains will be spared,
               or means left unemployed, to make it the first of American periodicals.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">JOHN DOUGLAS,
               BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            </div>
            
            <p>NO. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every description of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
               with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, ou terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
               January 16, 1845.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">MARTIN’S SPLENDIDLY ILLUSTRATED FAMILY BIBLE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE DEVOTIONAL FAMILY BIBLE,
               
               <br></br>EACH PART EMBELLISHED WITH A SPLENDID ENGRAVING, SUCH AS USUALLY SELLS AT
               
               <br></br>A DOLLAR EACH.
               
               <br></br>Price only 25 Cents a Part.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE DEVOTIONAL FAMILY BIBLE, by the REV. ALEXANDER FLETCHER, A.M., Author of the
               GUIDE TO FAMILY DEVOTION, SCRIPTURE HISTORY, &amp;c., containing the OLD AND NEW
               TESTAMENTS, with
               different Readings, Marginal References, and Reflections, each Part embellished
               with a HIGHLY FINISHED ENGRAVING, on Steel,
               from subjects by the Great Masters, together with a Series of VIEWS of the
               principal places mentioned in Scripture,
               From Drawings made on the spot by F. Catherwood &amp; W. H. Bartlett, Esqs.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">R. MARTIN &amp; CO. 26 John St.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DR. ARNOLD’S LIFE AND CORRESPONDENCE.</div>
            
            <p>D. APPLETON &amp; CO. have just published, THE LIFE
               AND CORRESPONDENCE OF THOMAS ARNOLD, D.D.
               By Rev. E. P. Stanley, M.A. From the Third English Edition, 2 vols.
               8vo. in 1 vol. 12mo. Price $1 50.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Life of Dr. Arnold will be found to be of unusual value and interest to all literary persons. Heads of Colleges and Seminaries ot
               Learning, Students and Teachers in public and private schools.
            </p>
            
            <p> No considerable review in England, representing either the high or
               low parties in Church or State—no weekly or daily publication has
               failed to express the wonderful power and beauty of this volume of
               Biography.
            </p>
            
            <p>NEW HISTORY OF THE FRENCH REVOLUTION. D. Appleton and Co. have recently published—History of the
               French Revolution—its causes and cousequences ; by F. Maclean Rowan ; 2 vols 18mo, cloth 75 cts., or 1 vol. 63 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>"This work has many and valuable recommendations. Its comes
               lation has been effected with care and good judgment; its style is essentially popular, its arrangements clear and methodical, and the
               whole form as condensed, comprehensive, and succinct a history of the
               most important event of this age, (both in itself and its consequences,)
               as we remember to have seen in so brief a space.”—English Critic,
               Sept. 16, 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>In a few days, Part 2, price 25 cents—
               HISTORY OF FRANCE, from the earliest period ;
               translated from the French of M. Michelet, by G. H. Smith.
            </p>
            
            <p> The celebrity of this work on the continent, and the want in English
               literature of a good history of France, has induced the publishers to
               introduce it to the American public at a price within the means of all.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">HUNT'S MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE
               AND COMMERCIAL REVIEW.
            </div>
            
            <p>BY FREEMAN HUNT, Editor and Proprietor. Published Monthly, at 142 Fulton Street, New York—at Five Dollars
               per annum, in Advance.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE and COMMERCIAL REVIEW, embraces every subject connected with Commerce, Manufactures and Political Economy, as follows;—Commercial Legislation;
               Commercial History and Geography; Mercantile Biography; Descriptive, Statistical and Historical Accounts, of the various commodities which form the subject of Mercantile transactions; Port Charges;
               Tariffs : Customs and Excise Regulations ; Commercial Statistics of
               the United States and the different countries of the world, with which
               we have intercourse, including their Physical Character, Population,
               Productions, Exports, Imports, Seaports, Monies, Weights, Measures
               Finance and Banking Associations, and Enterprises connected with
               Commerce, embracing Fisheries, Incorporated Companies, Railroads,
               Canals, Steamboats, Docks, Post Offices, &amp;c.; Principles of Com
               merce, Finance and Banking, with Practical and Historical Details
               and Illustrations; Commercial Law, and Mercantile Law Reports, and
               Decisions of Courts in the United States and Europe, including Insurance. Partnership, Principal and Agent, Bills of Exchange, Sale,
               Guaranty, Bankruptcy, Shipping and Navigation, &amp;c., and whatever
               else shall tend to develope the resources of the country and the
               world, and illustrate the various topics bearing upon Commerce and
               Commercial Literature.
            </p>
            
            <p>It has been, and will continue to be, the aim of the Editor and Proprietor of the Merchants' Magazine, to avoid every thing of a party, political, or sectional bias or bearing, in the conduct or the
               work
               —opening its pages to the free and fair discussion of antagonistic doctrines connected with the great interests of Commerce, Agriculture,
               Manufactures and the Currency.
            </p>
            
            <p> ☞ Complete sets of the Merchants’ Magazine, embracing eleven
               semi-annual volumes, of about 600 large octavo pages each, bringing
               it down to December, 1844, inclusive, may be obtained at the Publisher’s Office, 142 Fulton-street, New-York, at the subscription
               price.
            </p>
            
            <p>☞ Publishers of newspapers, in the United States, by giving this
               advertisement two or three insertions, and remitting Two Dollars to
               the Proprietor, will be entitled to the Magazine for one year.
               Office of Merchants’ Magzine, January 1st, 1845.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">The First Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for
               the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons ot one hour each. Terms—Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationary. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen,
               and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale "Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith’s Gems or Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
               much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
               Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
               volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
               of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab"> From the New York Express.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship.—We have seen the original, as
               executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
               wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
               to be "more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">Mrs. Sigourney’s Pictorial Reader.</div>
            
            <p>THE PICTORIAL READER, for the Use of Schools, consisting of Original Articles for the Instruction of Young Children.
               By Mrs. L. H. Sigourney. Being an Introduction to the Boy’s Reading Book and Girl’s Reading Book, by the same author. Illustrated
               by nearly One Hundred aed Fifty Engravings. A very interesting and
               instructive Book for Children, whether in school or out. Published by
               TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John Street,
               And for sale by all the Booksellers.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="p26">
         
         <div class="head">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">To be Published every Saturday.</div>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains
            spared
            to make it worthy of patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers in the country ; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may "let loose their
            thoughts,” will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse tne cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may
            dictate.
            It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octavo form of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum—Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.</p>
         
         <p>A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.</p>
         
         <p>All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor
            of the Broadway Journal, and all letters on business to
             JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.</div>
         
      </div>
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>