<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450419</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1.     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, APRIL 19, 1845.     NO. 16. 
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum. 
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents. 
         
         <br></br>C.F. Briggs, Edgar A. Poe, H.C. Watson, Editors.
         
         <br></br>Published at 153 Broadway, 
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Street-Paving</div>
         <div class="biblPage">241</div>
         <div class="head">STREET-PAVING.</div>
         
         <p>There is, perhaps, no point in the history of the useful arts
            more remarkable than the fact, that during the last two thousand years, the world has been able to make no essential
            improvements in road-making. It may well be questioned
            if the Gothamites of 3345 will distinguish any traces of our
            Third Avenue:—and in the matter of street-pavement, properly so called, although of late, universal attention has been
            directed to the subject, and experiment after experiment has
            been tried, exhausting the ingenuity of all modern engineers,
            it appears that we have at last settled on a result which
            differs in no material degree, and in principle not at all, from
            that which the Romans attained, as if instinctively, in the 
            Via Appia, the Via Flaminia, the Via Valeria, the Via Tusculana, and others. There are streets in Pompeii to-day
            constructed on the very principle which is considered best by
            the moderns: or if there be any especial variation, it certainly is not to the credit of modem ingenuity.
         </p>
         
         <p>The most durable and convenient of the Roman roads
            were thus composed:—The direction and breadth were
            first marked out by two shallow parrallel furrows or trenches (sulci) from 15 to 8 feet apart, according to the importance
            of the via. The loose earth between the trenches was then
            taken away, and the soil farther removed until a sufficiently
            solid foundation was reached upon which to deposit the materials of the bed:—if from any cause, such as swampiness,
            no such natural basis was atttainable, piles (fistucationes)
            were driven. Above the natural or artificial basis (the gremium) four strata were laid, of which the first (statumen)
            consisted of stones about three times the size of those employed by us in Macadamizing; next came the rudus, broken stones, cemented with lime (answering to our rubble-work)
            —this was generally nine inches thick, and densely rammed.
            Then came the nucleus of broken earthen-ware, six inches
            thick, and also cemented with lime. Lastly came the true
            pavement, (pavimentum) which was composed of irregular
            Polygons of silex, commonly basaltic lava. These blocks,
            however, were fitted together with great nicety, and presented just such an appearance as do our best built polygonal stone walls. The centre of the way was slightly elevated,
            as with us, above the curb-stones. Now and then, in cities,
            rectangular slabs of softer stone were substituted for the irregular lava polygons—and here the resemblance to the favorite modern mode was nearly complete. When the road
            or street passed over or through solid rock, the statumen and
            rudus were neglected, but the nucleus was never dispensed
            with. On each side of the way were elevated foot-paths,
            gravelled, and well supported; and at regular intervals
            Were stone blocks, corresponding to our own steps, for the
            convenience of horsemen or carriages. Our mile-stones were
            also employed.
         </p>
         
         <p>We are aware that all this is very school-boyish information— but we venture to place it before our readers by way
            of fairly collating the ancient and modem ideas on the general topic of road-making, and by way, also, of insisting onthe observation with which we commenced—that it is exceedingly remarkable how little we have done to advance
            an art of so vast an importance, notwithstanding the continuous endeavors which have been made, and are still making, to advance it.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Roman road (and our own quadrangular stone-block
            pavement is but a weak imitation of it) is beyond doubt exceedingly durable; and, so far, wherever the experiment
            has been tried, it has fully succeeded. By so far we mean
            so far as concerns durability. The objections are first, its
            cost, which is very great when the proper material is employed; and secondly the street din which is wrought by
            the necessity of having the upper surfaces of the blocks
            roughened, to afford a hold for the hoof. The noise from
            these roughened stones is less, certainly, than the tintamarre proceeding from the round ones—but nevertheless is intolerable still. The first objection (cost) is trivial where
            funds are at command; for in the end this species of pavement is the cheapest which has ever been invented, or probably ever will be invented—for repairs are scarcely needed
            at all. But it is cheap only in a save-at-the-spigot understanding of the term—for our second objection is one of a vital importance. The loss of time (not to mention temper)
            through the insufferable nuisance of street-noise in many of
            our most frequented thoroughfares, would overwhelm all
            reasonable people with astonishment if but once fairly and
            mathematically put; and that time is money—to an American at least—is a proposition not for an instant to be disputed. Nor have we dwelt upon the vast inconvenience, and
            often fatal injury resulting to invalids from the nuisance of
            which we complain—and of which all classes complain,
            without ever mentioning the necessity of getting it abated.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is generally admitted, we believe, that as long as they
            last, the wooden pavements have the advantage over all others. They occasion little noise (we place this item first and
            are serious in so placing it as the most important consideration of all); they are kept clean with little labor; they save
            a great deal in horse power; they are pleasant to the hoof
            and thus save the health of the horse—as well as some twenty or thirty per cent, in the wear and tear of vehicles—and as
            much more, in time, to all travellers through the increased
            rapidity of passage to and fro.
         </p>
         
         <p>The first objection is that of injury to the public health
            from miasmata arising from the wood. Whether such injury
            actually does occur is very questionable—but there is no need
            of mooting the question, since all admit that the source of
            the miasma (decay) can be prevented. It is demonstrated
            that by the process very improperly called Kyanizing (since
            Kyan has not the slightest claim to the invention) even the
            greenest wood may be preserved for centuries, or if need be
            for a hundred, or far more. The experiments by which this
            fact is, as we say, demonstrated, have been tried in every
            variety of way, with nearly identical results. Elocks properly prepared, for example, were subjected for many years,
            in the fungus pit of the dockyard at Woolwich, England, to
            
            all the known decomposing agents which can ever naturally
            be brought to act against a wooden pavement, and yet were
            taken from the pit, at the close of the experiments, in as
            sound a condition as when originally deposited.
         </p>
         
         <p>The preservative agent employed was that of corrosive
            sublimate—the Bi-chloride of Mercury. Let a pound of the
            sublimate be dissolved in fifteen or sixteen gallons of water, and a piece of any wood (not decayed) be immersed for
            seventy-two hours in the solution, and the wood cannot afterwards be rotted. An instantaneous mineralization can be
            effected, if necessary, by injection of the fluid in vacuo into
            the pores of the wood. It is rendered much heavier, and
            more brittle by the process, and has altogether a slightly
            metallic character.
         </p>
         
         <p>The cost of the Bi-chloride of Mercury is we presume, at
            present, something less than one dollar per pound—but the
            cost would be greatly reduced should the mineralizing process occasion an unusual demand. The South American
            quicksilver mines, now unworked, would be put into operation, and we should get the article, perhaps, for forty or even
            thirty cents per pound. But even now the cost of Kyanizing
            is trifling in comparison with that of cutting, squaring, and
            roughening stone—to say nothing of the difference in cost
            between wood itself, and such stone as our present pavements
            demand.
         </p>
         
         <p>Decay being thus prevented, all danger from miasma is of
            course to be left out of question; and although it has been
            frequently assert d that the mercurial effluvium is injurious
            to health—the assertion has been as frequently refuted in the
            most positive and satisfactory manner. The mercury is too
            closely assimilated with the wooden fibre to admit of any
            perceptible effluvium. Even where sailors have lived for
            months in the most confined holds of vessels built of the mineralized wood, no ill consequences have been found to arise.
         </p>
         
         <p>We write this article with no books before us, and are
            by no means positive about the accuracy of our details. The
            general principles and facts, however, are not, we believe,
            matters of dispute. We confess ourselves, therefore, at a
            loss to understand how, or why it is, that a Kyanized wooden pavement to a limited extent, has not been laid (if only
            by way of a forlorn-hope-like experiment) in some of our
            public thoroughfares. Or are we merely ignorant of the
            case—and has the experiment been fairly tried, and found
            wanting?
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Amusements of New York</div>
         <div class="biblPage">242</div>
         <div class="head">AMUSEMENTS OF NEW YORK.</div>
         
         <p>The supposed proneness of Americans (United Statesers)
            to labor too much and play too little, has long been a subject
            of reproach with foreigners, and of complaint among our own
            countrymen. One of our magazines a short time since contained a homily from a city clergyman, in which the evils of
            too great seriousness of demeanor were forcibly set forth, and
            people were urged to give more time to recreation and less to
            business, in a very impressive and serious manner. But these
            reproaches and complaints are made with a total blindness to
            the statistics of fun, and with little argument as to the truth
            of the assumption that Americans are not food of amusements. It is true that we have nothing that resembles the
            impromptu cotillions which seem to belong to the soil of
            France, and that fandangos and polkas are not danced by our
            Broadway ladies in the Park and Bowling-Green; but we
            doubt whether there are more dancers in Paris, if the figurantes of the opera be excepted, than there are in New
            York. In France they dance by daylight in the open air, for
            economy’s sake, but here they dance at night in well lighted
            rooms. The French dance, as though dancing were a matter
            of course, in a trifling light-hearted manner; here we make
            a serious business of it, and amuse ourselves in this manner
            as though it were a duty. Our balls are conducted with as
            much solemnity and consideration as our courts or elections.
            Committees are appointed to make suitable arrangements;
            guests are invited in a precise sedate mannner, and they dress
            themselves with elaborate care, to show that they are fully
            impressed with the importance of the act in which they are
            to engage, namely—to amuse themselves. Instead of that
            light and frivolous behaviour which the French manifest on
            such occasions, showing that they have no sense of the true
            aim of amusement, which is to improve the health and
            spirits, our people prove by their solemnity of carriage and
            gravity of face, that they fully understand what they are
            about, and that they have engaged in their amusements with
            an intelligent appreciation of their importance. You may
            sometimes observe an auctioneer who has rattled away at
            his vocation all day as light-hearted as a parrot, and as full
            of grimace as a monkey, go to his amusements with his wife
            in the evening as sedate and well behaved as a judge. So
            there are lawyers and judges, as thoughtless as crickets
            while engaged in the business of their clients, bandying jokes
            and making awful puns in law Latin, who will go to a ball
            or a soirée as seriously as though they were disappointed
            clients. This resolute determination to be amused certainly
            manifests anything but an indifference to recreations, and it
            is very plain that the foreigners who have complained of our
            too close application to business, took but a very superficial
            view of the national idiosyncrasies. Mr. Dickens looked out
            from the windows of the Carbon House the day after his
            arrival in New York, and not seeing any dancing monkeys
            or organ-grinders in Broadway, directly wrote down in his
            Diary that we had no amusements. But of all other men in
            the world he should have been the last to accuse us of a disinclination to amuse ourselves, for it was made a gala day
            whenever he appeared.
         </p>
         
         <p>The public amusements of New York are very numerous;
            a glance at one of the morning papers, will at any time discover a greater number of public places of amusement than
            any city in Europe of the same extent can show. There are at
            all times six theatres and a circus open nightly, while there
            are two other theatres closed, on account of the season. Besides these theatres, there are two museums where dramatic
            entertainments are presented, and every night in the week
            there are dramatic readings and singing in public lecture
            rooms. The places where free entertainments, in the shape
            of music and singing are given, are very numerous, and private balls and parties are innumerable.
         </p>
         
         <p>The theatres, which are generally looked upon as places
            of amusement only, are generally exceedingly dull and sombre; and people who wish to enjoy a hearty laugh, resort to
            the company of a few choice fellows who have the reputation of saying good things, or seek the companionship of some
            author who can be warranted not to tire.
         </p>
         
         <p>Amusement should be spontaneous, or rather there can be
            no amusement which is not so. The theatre should afford
            amusement, pastime and instruction, but it rarely affords
            either, and still more rarely the three combined. There is
            evidence enough around us that we are an amusement seeking people, and that we do not, as has been falsely charged,
            give too much of our lime to serious business; if we gave
            more we should doubtless be benefitted by it.
         </p>
         
         <p>But we seek our amusements in our own way, and foreign
            visiters, missing the street shows to which they have been
            accustomed, very irrationally set us down in their diaries as
            an overtasked people, who sacrifice every enjoyment to the
            almighty dollar.
         </p>
         
         <p>The city governors have always indulged freely in recreations, setting an example to the people which they have not
            been slow to imitate; but if they should spend part of the
            time which they devote to feasting and merry-making, in
            devising means to keep the streets in a healthy condition, the
            people would hardly complain that they overtasked themselves with hard labor.
         </p>
         
         <p>A walk through Broadway of a sunny morning to a man
            of business as he goes to his office, would be recreation
            enough to sweeten his hours of toil, but in the present condition of our noble thoroughfare, it is a weariness and disgust to make one’s way through it. The past week it has
            been perilous to the lungs and the eyes, and certain ruin to
            one’s clothes. Clouds of dust, soot, ashes, pulverised bricks,
            and all manner of dried substances which have been ground
            beneath the wheels of incessant omnibuses, have been drifting about in dense masses; the raw wind rushing through
            the narrow streets, though apparently impatient to escape
            from such unpleasant places, will stop in Broadway on purpose to play with the dust, and fling it into the eyes and nostrils of pedestrians. Yet people who suffer these inconveniences will yet talk of amusements, and allow their servants,
            the rulers of the city, to amuse themselves, while their
            grievances are unredressed. Nero has been condemned to
            infamous notoriety, for amusing himself with his fiddle while
            Rome was burning; but the spectacle of our mayor and alder,
            men taking a pleasure excursion in a steamboat, or feasting
            themselves at Bellevue, while the highways of the city are
            choked with dirt, and the inhabitants are suffocated with
            dust, is a sight to make the world forget Nero and his fiddle.
         </p>
         
         <p>If a stranger to our country should desire to get a correct
            idea of the earnestness with which we pursue the phantom
            pleasure, let him behold the indomitable perseverance which
            our citizens have shown in the determination to extract enjoyment from the representation of Fashion at the Park theatre, and of Antigone at Mr. Dinneford’s; a disinterested observer would be convinced that people who went so seriously
            to work in seeking their amusements, should not be taxed
            with the sin of devoting too much time to business matters.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reform</div>
         <div class="biblPage">243</div>
         <div class="head">REFORM.</div>
         
         <p>One of those innocent persons who conceive themselves to
            have been sent into the world, like Mr. Moddle, on a mission, has recently taken it into his head to abuse our Journal
            roundly in an eastern paper, on the assumed ground that we
            are opposed to reform. This assumption is mainly based upon
            our remarks upon Miss Fuller’s “Woman in the Nineteenth
            Ceutury.” Our eyes are not shut to the evils of society, nor
            are we by any means indifferent about their existence, for we
            happen to experience personal discomforts every day, which
            are owing to some abuse of law or custom that might better
            be abolished than not; but we have learned to take our daily
            rubs coolly, and we can look upon the sufferings of others
            with quite as much composure as we can endure our own.
            We have but little faith in the plan which our modern reformers adopt, of scolding the world into good behavior; and we
            have less faith still in the efficacy of societies to reform abuses,
            particularly the abuses of foreign governments. Our reformers are too apt to forget that "the earth is the Lord’s," and
            trust to Him too little to provide for the happiness of his
            children, trusting loo much to themselves. Every man has
            it in his own power to reform himself, and when he has done
            that well, he is in a capital condition to help reform the
            world, but not before. There are some excellent hints on this
            subject in the Bible, which would do our eastern friend peculiar
            good, if he were to meditate on them whenever he may feel
            disposed to hurl his arrows at supposed non-reformers, like
            ourselves. We do not believe in the existence of individual or
            isolated vices in a society; it is, therefore, an idle task to attempt to heal it of any one disorder. The whole system must
            be purged of its evil humors. If we concentrate ail our energies in the endeavor to remove a particular evil, all the others
            will grow the more vigorously for being neglected; while we
            are trying to cure the world of gambling, licentiousness and
            avarice and lying and oppression and thievery and drunkenness will grow in strength. The whole body must be physicked, and not one of its members, to restore it to health.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is unfortunate for those unhappy persons who arrogate
            to themselves the divine title of reformers, that they generally forget to reform themselves, and they consequently make
            as ridiculous a figure in the world as the fat man in the mob
            that Dean Swift tells of, who kept complaining of the crowd
            until a by-stander reminded him that it was his own carcass
            that caused all the inconvenience, and that there would be
            room enough if he were only out of the way.
         </p>
         
         <p>The true reformers of the world are those who scatter
            truths; it matters not a straw what they are. Every discovery in what are called the physical sciences, obliterates
            some moral evil. The man with the most knowledge is the
            greatest reformer, but the converse of this proposition is supposed to be the case, and the country is overrun with witlings
            who set about reforming society before they have mastered
            their alphabets. In all countries, but in ours above all, the
            intelligence of the people is the law; therefore it is better to
            aim at enlightening the people, than to get up a crusade
            against the law itself. The statute books of England and the
            United States are full of dead laws, strangled by the intelligence of the people, but not repealed. The law of capital
            punishment is dying daily; the progress of a certain trial the
            past week, proves that it is almost dead. It is well for a bad
            law to be repealed the moment that its wickedness is felt,
            but the philanthropist need give himself no uneasiness about
            it; let him instruct the people, and the law will die of itself.
            Ignorance is the great father of law, and when the law is in
            advance of the people, they will make laws for themselves,
            like the Lynch-laws of the west. If we take a glance at the
            history of the world, we shall find that all the reformers have
            been poets or the discoverers of truths in science, while praters about reform have left the world quite as full of error as
            they found it. Milton’s Comus has doubtless done much
            towards reforming the world, but his Tetrachordon, and other
            tracts, which were intended expressly to reform it, have done
            nothing.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our abusive friend is doubtless very sincere in his belief
            that the world is to be reformed by newspaper paragraphs,
            and we wish him nothing worse than that he may live to
            see his faith verified.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Bon-Bon</div>
         <div class="biblPage">243</div>
         <div class="head">BON-BON.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Quand unbon vin meuble mon estomac,
            
            <br></br>Je suis plus savant que Balzac—
            
            <br></br>Plus sage que Pibrac;
            
            <br></br>Mon bras seul faisant l’attaque
            
            <br></br>De la nation Cossaque,
            
            <br></br>La mettroit au sac;
            
            <br></br>De Charon Je passerois le lac
            
            <br></br>En dormant dans son bac;
            
            <br></br>J’irois au fier Eac,
            
            <br></br>Sans que mon cœur fit tic ni tac,
            
            <br></br>Presenter du tabac.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">French Vaudeville</div>
         
         <p>That Pierre Bon-Bon was a restaurateur of uncommon qualifications, no man who, during
            the reign of---------—, frequented the little Cafe in the cul-de-sac Le Febvre at Rouen,
            will imagine, feel himself at liberty to dispute. That
            Pierre Bon-Bon was, in an equal degree, skilled in the phil
            /&gt;osophy of that period is, I presume, still more especially undeniable. His patés à la fois were beyond doubt immaculate: but what pen can do justice to his essays sur la Nature
            —his thoughts sur I'Ame—his observations sur l'Esprit? If
            his omelettes—if his fricandeaux were inestimable, what littérateur of that day would not have given twice as much (or
            an “Idée de Bon-Bon"  as for all the trash of all the “Idées"
            of all the rest of the savants? Bon-Bon had ransacked libraries which no other man had ransacked—had read more than
            any other would have entertained a notion of reading—had
            understood more than any other would have conceived the
            possibility of understanding; and although, while he flourished, there were not wanting some authors at Rouen to assert “that his dicta evinced neither the purity of the Academy, nor the depth of the Lyceum”—although, mark me, his
            doctrines were by no means very generally comprehended,
            still it did not follow that they were difficult of comprehension. It was, I think, on account of their self-evidency that
            manv persons were led to consider them abstruse. It is to
            Bon-Bon—but let this go no farther—it is to Bon-Bon that
            Kant himself is mainly indebted for his metaphysics. The
            former was indeed not a Platonist, nor strictly speaking an
            Aristotelian—nor did he, like the modern Leibnitz, waste
            those precious hours which might be employed in the invention of a fricasée, or, facili gradú, the analysis of a sensation,
            in frivolous attempts at reconciling the obstinate oils and waters of ethical discussion. Not at all. Bon-Bon was Ionic
            —Bon-Bon was equally Italic. He reasoned à priori—He
            reasoned also à posteriori. His ideas were innate—or
            otherwise. He believed in George of Trebizond—He believed in Bossarion. Bon-Bon was emphatically a—BonBonist.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have spoken of the philosopher in his capacity of restaurateur. I would not, however, have any friend of mine imagine that, in fulfilling his hereditary duties in that line, our
            hero wanted a proper estimation of their dignity and importance. Far from it. It was impossible to say in which
            branch of his profession he took the greater pride. In his
            opinion the powers of the intellect held intimate connection with the capabilities of the stomach. I am not sure,
            indeed, that he greatly disagreed with the Chinese, who
            hold that the soul lies in the abdomen. The Greeks at all events
            were right, he thought, who employed the same word for
            the mind and the diaphragm.
            <span class="anchor" id="a001">
               <a href="n001"> Link </a>
            </span> By this I do not mean to
            insinuate a charge of gluttony, or indeed any other serious
            charge to the prejudice of the metaphysician. If Pierre BonBon had his failings—and what great man has not a thousand?—if Pierre Bon-Bon, I say, had his failings, they were
            failings of very little importance—faults indeed which, in
            other tempers, have often been looked upon rather in the
            light of virtues. As regards one of these foibles, I should not
            even have mentioned it in this history but for the remarkable prominency—the extreme alto relievo—in which it jutted out from the plane of his general disposition.—He could
            never let slip an opportunity of making a bargain.
         </p>
         
         <p>Not that he was avaricious—no.	It was by no means
            necessary to the satisfaction of the philosopher, that the bargain should be to his own proper advantage. Provided a
            trade could be effected—a trade of any kind, upon any terms,
            or under any circumstances—a triumphant smile was seen
            for many days thereafter to enlighten his countenance, and a
            knowing wink of the eye to give evidence of his sagacity.
         </p>
         
         <p>At any epoch it would not be very wonderful it a humor
            so peculiar as the one I have just mentioned, should elicit
            attention and remark. At the epoch of our narrative, had
            this peculiarity not attracted observation, there would have
            been room for wonder indeed. It was soon reported that,
            upon all occasions of the kind, the smile of Bon-Bon was
            wont to differ widely from the downright grin with which
            he would laugh at his own jokes, or welcome an acquaintance. Hints were thrown out of an exciting nature; stories
            were told of perilous bargains made in a hurry and repented
            of at leisure; and instances were adduced of unaccountable
            capacities, vague longings, and unnatural inclinations implanted by the author of all evil for wise purposes of his
            own.
         </p>
         
         <p>The philosopher had other weakneses—but they are scarcely worthy our serious examination. For example, there are
            few men of extraordinary profundity who are found wanting
            in an inclination for the bottle. Whether this inclination be
            an exciting cause, or rather a valid proof, of such profundity, it is a nice thing to say. Bon-Bon, as far as I can learn,
            did not think the subject adapted to minute investigation;—
            nor do I. Yet in the indulgence of a propensity so truly classical, it is not to be supposed that the restaurateur would
            lose sight of that intuitive discrimination which was wont to
            characterise, at one and the same time, his essais and his
            omelettes. In his seclusions the Vin de Bourgogne had its allotted hour, and there were appropriate moments for the
            Côtes du Rhone. With him Sauterne was to Medoc what
            Catullus was to Homer. He would sport with a syllogism
            in sipping St. Peray, but unravel an argument over Clos de
            Vougeot, and upset a theory in a torrent of Chamberlin.
            Well had it been if the same quick sense of propriety had
            attended him in the peddling propensity to which I have
            formerly alluded—but this was by no means the case. Indeed, to say the truth, that trait of mind in the philosophic
            Bon-Bon did begin at length to assume a character of strange
            intensity and mysticism, and appeared deeply tinctured wilh
            the diablerie of his favorite German studies.
         </p>
         
         <p>To enter the little Cafe in the Cul-de-Sac Le Febvre was,
            at the period of our tale, to enter the sanctum of a man of
            genius. Bon-Bon was a man of genius. There was not a
            sous-cuisinier in Rouen, who could not have told you that
            Bon-Bon was a man of genius. His very cat knew it, and
            forebore to whisk her tail in the presence of the man of genius. His large water-dog was acquainted with the fact,
            and upon the approach of his master, betrayed his sense of
            inferiority by a sanctity of deportment, a debasement of the
            ears, and a dropping of the lower jaw not altogether unworthy of a dog. It is, however, true that much of this habitual
            respect might have been attributed to the personal appearance of the metaphysician. A distinguished exterior will, I
            am constrained to say, have its weight even with a beast;
            and I am willing to allow much in the outward man of the
            restaurateur calculated to impress the imagination of the
            quadruped. There is a peculiar majesty about the atmosphere of the little great—if I may be permitted so equivocal
            an expression—which mere physical bulk alone will be found
            at all times inefficient in creating. If, however, Bon-Bon
            was barely three feet in height, and if his head was diminutively small, still it was impossible to behold the rotundity
            of his stomach without a sense of magnificence nearly bordering upon the sublime. In its size both dogs and men must
            have seen a type of his acquirements—in its immensity a fitting habitation for his immortal soul.
         </p>
         
         <p>I might here—if it so pleased me—dilate upon the matter
            of habiliment, and other mere circumstances of the external
            metaphysician. I might hint that the hair of our hero was
            worn short, combed smoothly over his forehead, and surmounted by a conical-shaped white flannel cap and tassels—
            that his pea-green jerkin was not alter the fashion of those
            worn by the common class of restaurateurs at that day—
            that the sleeves were something fuller than the reigning costume permitted—that the cuffs were turned up, not as usual
            in that barbarous period, with cloth of the same quality and
            color as the garment, but faced in a more fanciful manner
            with the particolored velvet of Genoa—that his slippers were
            of a bright purple, curiously filagreed, and might have been
            manufactured in Japan, but for the exquisite pointing of the
            toes, and the brilliant tints of the binding and embroidery—
            that his breeches were of the yellow satin-like material called aimable—that his sky-blue cloak, resembling in form a
            dressing-wrapper, and richly bestudded all over with crimson
            devices, floated cavalierly upon his shoulders like a mist of
            the morning—and that his tout ensemble gave rise to the remarkable words of Benevenuta, the Improvisatrice of Florence, “that it was difficult to say whether Pierre Bon-Bon
            was indeed a bird of Paradise, or the rather a very Paradise
            of perfection."—I might, I say, expatiate upon all these
            points if I pleased;—but I forbear:—merely personal details
            may be left to historical novelists;—they are beneath the
            moral dignity of matter-of-fact.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have said that “to enter the Café in the Cul-de-Sac Le
            Febvre was to enter the sanctum of a man of genius”—but
            then it was only the man of genius who could duly estimate
            the merits of the sanctum. A sign consisting of a vast folio
            swung before the entrance. On one side of the volume was
            painted a bottle; on the reverse a pate. On the back were
            visible in large letters the words Œuvres de Bon-Bon. Thus
            was delicately shadowed forth the two-fold occupation of
            the proprietor.
         </p>
         
         <p>Upon stepping over the threshold the whole interior of the
            building presented itself to view. A long, low pitched room
            of antique construction, was indeed all the accommodation afforded by the Càfe. In a corner of the apartment stood the
            bed of the metaphysician. An array of curtains, together with
            a canopy à la Greque, gave it an air at once classic and comfortable. In the corner diagonally opposite, appeared, in direct family communion, the properties of the kitchen and the
            bibliotheque. A dish of polemics stood peacefully upon the
            dresser. Here lay an oven-full of the latest ethics—there a
            kettle of duodecimo melanges. Volumes of German morality were hand and glove with the gridiron—a toasting fork
            might be discovered by the side of Eusebius—Plato reclined
            at his ease in the frying pan—and contemporary manuscripts
            were filed away upon the spit.
         </p>
         
         <p>In other respects the Càfe de Bon-Bon might be said to
            differ little from the usual restaurants of the period. A large
            fire-place yawned opposite the door. On the right of the
            fire-place an open cupboard displayed a formidable array of
            labelled bottles.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was here, about twelve o’clock one night, during the
            severe winter of-----, that Pierre Bon-Bon, after having listened for some time to the comments of his neighbours
            upon his singular propensity—that Pierre Bon-Bon, I say,
            having turned them all out of his house, locked the door upon them with an oath, and betook himself in no very pacific
            mood to the comforts of a leather-bottomed arm-chair, and a
            fire of blazing faggots.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was one of those terrific nights which are only met with
            once or twice during a century. It snowed fiercely, and the
            house tottered to its centre with the floods of wind that,
            rushing through the crannies in the wall, and pouring impetuously down the chimney, shook awfully the curtains of the
            philosopher’s bed, and disorganised the economy of his patepane and papers. The huge folio sign that swung without,
            exposed to the fury of the tempest, creaked ominously, and
            gave out a moaning sound from it stanchions of solid oak.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was in no placid temper, I say, that the metaphysician
            drew up his chair to its customary station by the hearth.
            Many circumstances of a perplexing nature had occurred during the day, to disturb the serenity of his meditations. In
            attempting des œufs à la Princesse he had unfortunately
            perpetrated an omelete à la Rente; the discovery of a principle in ethics had been frustrated by the overturning of a
            stew; and last, not least, he had been thwarted in one of
            those admirable bargains which he at all times took such
            especial delight in bringing to a successful termination. But
            in the chafing of his mind at these unaccountable vicissitudes, there did not fail to be mingled some degree of that
            nervous anxiety which the fury of a boisterous night is so
            well calculated to produce. Whistling to his more immediate vicinity the large black water-dog we have spoken of
            before, and settling himself uneasily in his chair, he could
            not help casting a wary and unquiet eye towards those distant recesses of the apartment whose inexorable shadows
            not even the red fire-light itself could more than partially
            succeed in overcoming. Having completed a scrutiny whose
            exact purpose was perhaps unintelligible to himself, he drew
            close to his seat a small table covered with books and papers, and soon became absorbed in the task of retouching a
            Voluminous manuscript, intended for publication on the morrow.
         </p>
         
         <p>He had been thus occupied for some minutes when “I am
            in no hurry, Monsieur Bon-Bon,” suddenly whispered a whining voice in the apartment.
         </p>
         
         <p>“The devil!” ejaculated our hero, starting to his feet,
            overturning the table at his side, and staring around him in
            astonishment.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Very true,” calmly replied the voice.</p>
         
         <p>“Very true!—what is very true?—how came you here?"
            vociferated the metaphysician, as his eye fell upon something
            which lay stretched at full length upon the bed.
         </p>
         
         <p>"I was saying,” said the intruder, without attending to
            the interrogatories, “I was saying that I am not at all pushed for lime—that the business upon which I took the liberty of calling is of no pressing importance—in short that I
            can very well wait until you have finished your Exposition.
         </p>
         
         <p>“My Exposition!—there now!—how do you know-how
            came you to understand that I was writing an exposition?
            good God!"
         </p>
         
         <p>“Hush!" replied the figure in a shrill under tone: and,
            arising quickly from the bed, he made a single step towards
            our hero, while an iron lamp that depended overhead swung
            convulsively back from his approach.
         </p>
         
         <p>The philosopher’s amazement did not prevent a narrow
            scrutiny of the stranger’s dress and appearance. The outlines of a figure, exceedingly lean, but much above the common height, were rendered minutely distinct by means of a
            faded suit of black cloth which fitted tight to the skin, but
            was otherwise cut very much in the style of a century ago.
            These garments had evidently been intended for a much
            shorter person than their present owner. His ankles and
            wrists were left naked for several inches. In his shoes,
            however, a pair of very brilliant buckles gave the lie to the
            extreme poverty implied by the other portions of his dress.
            His bead was bare, and entirely bald, with the exception of
            the hinder part, from which depended a queue of considerable
            length. A pair of green spectacles, with side glasses, protected his eyes from the influence of the light, and at the
            same time prevented our hero from ascertaining either their
            color or their conformation. About the entire person there
            was no evidence of a shirt; but a white cravat, of filthy appearance, was tied with extreme precision around the throat,
            and the ends, hanging down formally side by side, gave (although I dare say unintentionally) the idea of an ecclesiastic.
            Indeed, many other points both in his appearance and demeanour might have very well sustained a conception of that
            nature. Over his left ear, he carried, after the fashion of a
            modern clerk, an instrument resembling the stylus of the ancients. In a breast-pocket of his coat appeared conspicuously
            a small black volume fastened with clasps of steel. This
            book, whether accidentally or not, was so turned outwardly
            from the person as to discover the words “Rituel Catholique”
            in white letters upon the back. His entire physiognomy was
            interestingly saturnine—even cadaverously pale. The forehead was lofty, and deeply furrowed with the ridges of contemplation. The corners of the mouth were drawn down
            into an expression of the most submissive humility. There
            was also a clasping of the hands, as he stepped towards our
            hero—a deep sigh—and altogether a look of such utter sanctity as could not have failed to be unequivocally prepossessing. Every shadow of anger faded from the countenance of
            the metaphysician, as, having completed a satisfactory survey of his visiter’s person, he shook him cordially by the
            hand, and conducted him to a seat.
         </p>
         
         <p>There would however be a radical error in attributing this
            instantaneous transition of feeling in the philosopher, to any
            one of those causes which might naturally be supposed to
            have had an influence. Indeed Pierre Bon-Bon, from what I
            have been able to understand of his disposition, was of all
            men the least likely to be imposed upon by any speciousness
            of exterior deportment. It was impossible that so accurate
            an observer of men and things should have failed to discover,
            upon the moment, the real character of the personage who
            had thus intruded upon his hospitality. To say no more, the
            conformation of his visiter’s feet was sufficiently remarkable
            —he maintained lightly upon his head an inordinately tall
            hat—there was a tremulous swelling about the hinder part
            of his breeches—and the vibration of his coat tail was a palpable fact. Judge then with what feelings of satisfaction our
            hero found himself thrown thus at once into the society of a
            person for whom he had at all times entertained the most
            unqualified respect. He was, however, too much of the diplomatist to let escape him any intimation of his suspicions
            in regard to the true state of affairs. It was not his cue to
            appear at all conscious of the high honor he thus unexpectedly enjoyed, but by leading his guest into conversation, to
            elicit some important ethical ideas, which might, in obtaining
            a place in his contemplated publication, enlighten the human
            race and at the same time immortalize himself—ideas which,
            I should have added, his visiter’s great age, and well known
            proficiency in the science of morals, might very well have
            enabled him to afford.
         </p>
         
         <p>Actuated by these enlightened views, our hero bade the
            gentleman sit down, while he himself took occasion to throw
            some faggots upon the fire, and place upon the now re-established table some bottles of Mousseux. Having quickly completed these operations, he drew his chair vis-à-vis to his
            companion’s and waited until the latter should open the conversation. But plans even the most skillfully matured are 
            often thwarted in the outset of they application, and the
            restaurateur found himself nonplussed by the very first words
            of his visiter's speech.
         </p>
         
         <p>"I see you know me, Bon-Bon,” said he: “ha! ha! ha!—
            
            he! he! he!—hi! hi! hi!—ho! ho! ho!—hu! hu! hu!”—and
            the devil, dropping at once the sanctity of his demeanour,
            opened to its fullest extent a mouth from ear to ear, so as to
            display a set of jagged and fang-like teeth, and throwing back
            his head, laughed long, loudly, wickedly, and uproariously,
            while the black dog, crouching down upon his haunches,
            joined lustily in the chorus, and the tabby cat, flying off at a
            tangent, stood up on end and shrieked in the farthest corner
            of the apartment.
         </p>
         
         <p>Not so the philosopher; he was too much a man of the
            world either to laugh like the dog, or by shrieks to betray
            the indecorous trepidation of the cat. It must be confessed,
            he felt a little astonishment to see the white letters which
            formed the words “Rituel Catholique" on the book in his
            guest’s pocket, momently changing both their color and their
            import, and in a few seconds, in place of the original title,
            the words Régitre des Condamnés blaze forth in characters
            of red. This startling circumstance, when Bon-Bon replied
            to his visiter’s remark, imparted to his manner an air of embarrassment which probably might not otherwise have been
            observed.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Why, sir.” said the philosopher, “why, sir, to speak
            sincerely—I believe you are—upon my word—the d----dest
            —that is to say I think—I imagine—I have some faint—
            some very faint idea—of the remarkable honor------”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Oh!—ah!—yes!—very well!” interrupted his Majesty,
            "say no more—I see how it is.” And hereupon, taking off
            his green spectacles, he wiped the glasses carefully with the
            sleeve of his coat, and deposited them in his pocket.
         </p>
         
         <p>If Bon-Bon had been astonished at the incident of the book,
            his amazement was now much increased by the spectacle
            which here presented itself to view. In raising his eves,
            with a strong feeling of curiosity to ascertain the color of his
            guest’s, he found them by no means black, as he bad anticipated—nor gray, as might have been imagined—nor yet hazel nor blue—nor indeed yellow nor red—nor purple—nor
            white—nor green—nor any other color in the heavens above,
            or in the earth beneath, or in the waters under the earth. In
            short Pierre Bon-Bon not only saw plainly that his Majesty
            had no eyes whatsoever, but could discover no indications of
            their having existed at any previous period; for the space
            where eyes should naturally have been, was, I am constrained
            to say, simply a dead level of flesh.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was not in the nature of the metaphysician to forbear
            making some inquiry into the sources of so strange a phenomenon, and the reply of his Majesty was at once prompt, dignified, and satisfactory.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Eyes! my dear Bon-Bon, eyes! did you say?—oh! ah!
            I perceive. The ridiculous prints, eh? which are in circulation, have given you a false idea of my personal appearance.
            Eyes!!—true. Eyes, Pierre Bon-Bon, are very well in their 
            proper place—that, you would say, is the head?—right—the
            ead of a worm. To you likewise these optics are indispensable—yet I will convince you that my vision is more
            penetrating than your own. There is a cat, I see in the
            corner—a pretty cat!—look at her!—observe her well!
            Now, Bon-Bon, do you behold the thoughts—the thoughts, I
            say—the ideas—the reflections—which are being engendered in her pericranium? There it is now!—you do not. She
            is thinking we admire the length of her tail and the profundity of her mind. She has just concluded that I am the most
            distinguished of ecclesiastics, and that you are the most superfluous of metaphysicians. Thus you see I am not altogether blind: but to one of my profession the eyes you speak
            of would be merely an incumbrance, liable at any time to
            be put out by a toasting iron ora pitchfork. To you, I allow,
            these optical affairs are indispensable. Endeavor, Bon-Bon,
            to use them well;—my vision is the soul.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Hereupon the guest helped himself to the wine upon the
            table, and pouring out a bumper for Bon-Bon, requested him
            to drink it without scruple, and make himself perfectly at
            home.
         </p>
         
         <p>“A clever book that of yours, Pierre,” resumed his Majesty, tapping our friend knowingly upon the shoulder, as the
            latter put down his glass after a thorough compliance with
            his visiter’s injunction. "A clever book that of yours, upon
            my honor. It's a work after my own heart. Your arrangement of matter, I think, however, might be improved, and
            many of your notions remind me of Aristotle. That philosopher was one of my most intimate acquaintances. I liked
            him as much for his terrible ill temper, as for his happy
            knack at making a blunder. There is only one solid truth in
            all that he has written, and for that I gave him the hint out
            of pure compassion for his absurdity. I suppose, Pierre BonBon, you very well know to what divine moral truth I am
            alluding.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Cannot say that I-------”</p>
         
         <p>“Indeed!—why it was I who told Aristotle that by sneez-
            ing men expelled superfluous ideas through the proboscis.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Which is—hiccup!—undoubtedly the case,” said the
            metaphysician, while he poured out for himself another
            bumper of Mousseux, and offered his snuff-box to the fingers
            of his visiter.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“There was Plato, too,” continued his Majesty, modestly
            declining the snuff-box and the compliment it implied, “there
            was Plato, too, for whom I, at one time, felt all the affection
            of a friend. You knew, Plato, Bon-Bon?—ah! no, I beg a
            thousand pardons. He met me at Athens, one day, in the
            Parthenon, and told me he was distressed for an idea. I bade
            him write down that ο νους εςτιν αυλος. He said that he
            would do so, and went home, while I stepped over to the
            pyramids. But my conscience smote me for having uttered a
            truth, even to aid a friend, and hastening back to Athens, I
            arrived behind the philosopher’s chair as he was inditing the
            ‘αυλος.’ Giving the lamma a fillip with my finger I turned it
            upside down. So the sentence now reads ‘ο νους εςτιν αυγος,'
            and is, you perceive, the fundamental doctrine in his metaphysics.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Were you ever at Rome?” asked the restaurateur as he
            finished his second bottle of Mousseux, and drew from the
            closet a larger supply of Chambertin.
         </p>
         
         <p>“But once, Monsieur Bon-Bon, but once. There was a
            time”—said the devil, as if reciting some passage from a
            book—“there was a time when occurred an anarchy of five
            years, during which the republic, bereft of all its officers,
            had no magistracy besides the tribunes of the people, and
            these were not legally vested with any degree of executive
            power—at that time, Monsieur Bon-Bon—at that time only
            I was in Rome, and I have no earthly acquaintance, consequently, with any of its philosophy.”
            <span class="anchor" id="a002">
               <a href="#n002"> Link </a>
            </span>
         </p>
         
         <p>“What do you think of—what do you think of—hiccup!
            —Epicurus?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“What do I think of whom?" said the devil in astonishment, “you cannot surely mean to find any fault with Epicurus! What do I think of Epicurus! Do you mean me, sir?
            —I am Epicurus. I am the same philosopher who wrote
            each of the three hundred treatises commemorated by Diogenes Laertes.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“That’s a lie!” said the metaphysician, for the wine had
            gotten a little into his head.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Very well!—very well, sir!—very well indeed, sir,” said
            his Majesty, apparently much flattered.
         </p>
         
         <p>“That’s a lie!” repeated the restaurateur dogmatically,
            “that’s a—hiccup!—a lie!”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Well, well! have it your own way,” said the devil
            pacifically: and Bon-Bon, having beaten his Majesty at an
            argument, thought it his duty to conclude a second bottle of
            Chambertin.
         </p>
         
         <p>“As I was saying,” resumed the visiter, “as I was observing a little while ago, there are some very outre notions in
            that book of yours, Monsieur Bon-Bon. What, for instance,
            do you mean by all that humbug about the soul? Pray, sir,
            what is the soul?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“The—hiccup!—soul,” replied the mataphysician,referring to his MS., “is undoubtedly”—</p>
         
         <p>“No, sir!”</p>
         
         <p>“Indubitably”—</p>
         
         <p>“No, sir!”</p>
         
         <p>“Indisputably”—</p>
         
         <p>“No, sir!"</p>
         
         <p>“Evidently"—</p>
         
         <p>“No, sir!”</p>
         
         <p>“Incontrovertibly”—</p>
         
         <p>“No sir!"</p>
         
         <p>“Hiccup!”—</p>
         
         <p>“No, sir!”</p>
         
         <p>“And beyond all question a”—</p>
         
         <p>“No, sir! the soul is no such thing.” (Here, the philosopher
            looking daggers, took occasion to make an end, upon the
            spot, of his third bottle of Chambertin.)
         </p>
         
         <p>“Then —hic-cup!—pray, sir—what—what is it?"</p>
         
         
         <p>“That is neither here nor there, Monsieur Bon-Bon,” replied his Majesty, musingly. “I have tasted—that is to say,
            I have known some very had souls, and some too—pretty
            good ones.” Here he smacked his lips, and, having unconsciously let fall his hand upon the volume in his pocket, was
            seized with a violent fit of sneezing.
         </p>
         
         <p>He continued:</p>
         
         <p>“There was the soul of Cratinus—passable: Aristophanes—racy: Plato—exquisite—not your Plato, but Plato the
            comic poet; your Plato would have turned the stomach of
            Cerberus—faugh! Then let me see! there were Nœvius,
            and Andronicus, and Plautus, and Terentius. Then there
            were Lucilius, and Catullus, and Naso, and Quintius Flaccus,
            —dear Quinty! as I called him when he sung a seculare for
            my amusement, while I toasted him, in pure good humor, on
            a fork. But they want flavor these Romans. One fat Greek
            is worth a dozen of them, and besides will keep, which cannot
            be said of a Quirite.—Let us taste your Sauterne.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Bon-Bon bad by this time made up his mind to the nil admirari, and endeavored to hand down the bottles in question.
            He was, however, conscious of a strange sound in the room
            like the wagging of a tail. Of this, although extremely indecent in his Majesty, the philosopher took no notice:—simply kicking the dog, and requesting him to be quiet. The
            visiter continued:
         </p>
         
         <p>“I found that Horace tasted very much like Aristotle;—
            you know I am fond of variety. Terentius I could not have
            told from Menander. Naso, to my astonishment, was Nicander in disguise. Virgilius bad a strong twang of Theocritus.
            Martial put me much in mind of Archilochus—and Titus
            Livius was positively Polybius and none other.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Hic-cup!” here replied Bon-Bon, and his Majesty proceeded:</p>
         
         <p>“But if I have a penchant, Monsieur Bon-Bon—if I have a
            penchant, it is for a philosopher. Yet, let me tell you, sir, it
            is not every dev—I mean it is not every gentleman who
            knows how to choose a philosopher. Long ones are not
            good; and the best, if not carefully shelled, are apt to be a
            little rancid on account of the gall."
         </p>
         
         <p>“Shelled!!”</p>
         
         <p>“I mean taken out of the carcass.”</p>
         
         <p>“What do you think of a—hic-cup!—physician?"</p>
         
         <p>“Don't mention them!—ugh! ugh!” (Here his Majesty
            retched violently.) “I never tasted but one—that rascal
            Hippocrates!—smelt of asafœtida—ugh! ugh! ugh!—caught
            a wretched cold washing him in the Styx—and after all he
            gave me the cholera morbus.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“The—hiccup!—wretch!” ejaculated Bon-Bon, “the—
            hic-cup!—abortion of a pill-box!”—and the philosopher dropped a tear.
         </p>
         
         <p>“After all,” continued the visiter, “after all, if a dev—if
            a gentleman wishes to live, he must have more talents than
            one or two; and with us a fat face is an evidence of diplomacy.”
         </p>
         
         <p>"How so?”</p>
         
         <p>“Why we are sometimes exceedingly pushed for provisions. You must know that, in a climate so sultry as mine,
            it is frequently impossible to keep a spirit alive for more than
            two or three hours; and after death, unless pickled immediately, (and a pickled spirit is not good,) they will—smell—
            you understand, eh? Putrefaction is always to be apprehended when the souls are consigned to us in the usual
            way.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Hiccup!—hiccup!—good God! how do you manage?”
            Here the iron lamp commenced swinging with redoubled
            violence, and the devil half started from his seat;—however,
            with a slight sigh, he recovered his composure, merely sayrag to our hero in a low tone, “I tell you what, Pierre BonBon, we must have no more swearing.”
         </p>
         
         <p>The host swallowed another bumper, by way of denoting
            thorough comprehension and acquiescence, and the visiter
            continued:
         </p>
         
         <p>“Why there are several ways of managing. The most of
            us starve: some put up with the pickle: for my part I purchase my spirits vivente corpore, in which case I find they
            keep very well."
         </p>
         
         <p>“But the body!—hiccup!—the body!!!”</p>
         
         <p>“The body, the body—well, what of the body?—oh! ah!
            I perceive. Why, sir, the body is not at all affected by the
            transaction. I have made innumerable purchases of the kind
            in my day, and the parties never experienced any inconvenience. There were Cain and Nimrod, and Nero, and Caligula, and Dionysius, and Pisistratus, and—and a thousand
            others, who never knew what it was to have a soul during
            the latter part of their lives; yet, sir, these men adorned society. Why isn’t there A-----, now, whom you know as
            well as I? Is he not in possession of all his faculties, mental and corporeal? Who writes a keener epigram? Who
            reasons more wittily? Who——but, stay! I have his agreement in my pocket-book.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus saying, he produced a red leather wallet, and took
            from it a number of papers. Upon some of these Bon-Bon
            caught a glimpse of the letters Machi—Maza—Robesp—with
            the words Caligula, George, Elizabeth. His Majesty selected a narrow slip of parchment, and from it read aloud the
            following words:
         </p>
         
         <p>“In consideration of certain mental endowments which it
            is unnecessary to specify, and in farther consideration of one
            thousand louis d’or, I, being aged one year and one month,
            do hereby make over to the bearer of this agreement all my
            right, title, and appurtenance in the shadow called my soul.
            (Signed) A.....
            <span class="anchor" id="a003">
               <a href="#n003"> Link </a>
            </span> (Here his Majesty repeated a name
            which I do not feel myself justified in indicating more unequivocally.)
         </p>
         
         <p>“A clever fellow that," resumed he; "but like you, Monsieur Bon-Bon, he was mistaken about tbe soul. The soul
            a shadow truly! The soul a shadow! Ha! ha! ha!—he!
            he! he!—hu! hu! hu! Only think of a fricasséed shadow!”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Only think—hiccup!—of a fricasséed shadow!" exclaimed our hero, whose faculties were becoming much illuminated by the profundity of his Majesty’s discourse.</p>
         
         <p>“Only think of a—hiccup!—fricasséed shadow!! Now,
            damme!—hiccup!—humph! If I would have been such a
            —hiccup!—nincompoop. My soul, Mr.—humph!”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Your soul, Monsieur Bon-Bon?”</p>
         
         <p>“Yes, sir—hiccup!—my soul is”—</p>
         
         <p>“What, sir?”</p>
         
         <p>“No shadow, damme!”</p>
         
         <p>“Did not mean to say”—</p>
         
         <p>“Yes, sir, my soul is—hiccup!—humph!—yes, sir.”</p>
         
         <p>“Did not intend to assert”—</p>
         
         <p>“My soul is—hiccup!—peculiarly qualified for—hiccup!
            —a”—
         </p>
         
         <p>“What, sir?”</p>
         
         <p>“Stew.”</p>
         
         <p>“Ha!”</p>
         
         <p>“Soufflée.”</p>
         
         <p>“Eh?”</p>
         
         <p>“Fricassée.”</p>
         
         <p>“Indeed!”</p>
         
         <p>“Ragout and fricandeau—and see here, my good fellow!
            I’ll let you have it—hiccup!—a bargain.” Here the philosopher slapped his Majesty upon the back.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Could’nt think of such a thing,” said the latter calmly,
            at the same time rising from his seat. The metaphysician
            stared.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Am supplied at present,” said his Majesty.</p>
         
         <p>“Hiccup!—e-h?” said the philosopher.</p>
         
         <p>"Have no funds on hand.”</p>
         
         <p>“What?”</p>
         
         <p>“Besides, very unhandsome in me"—</p>
         
         <p>“Sir!”</p>
         
         <p>“To take advantage of”—</p>
         
         <p>“Hiccup!”</p>
         
         <p>“Your present disgusting and ungentlemanly situation.”</p>
         
         <p>Here the visiter bowed and withdrew—in what manner
            could not precisely be ascertained—but in a well-concerted
            effort to discharge a bottle at “the villain,” the slender chain
            was severed that depended from the ceiling, and the metaphysician prostrated by the downfall of the lamp.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Lines</div>
         <div class="biblPage">247</div>
         
         <div class="head">LINES</div>
         
         <p>Written on a block of ice brought from America without melting, and
            exhibited in a window in the Strand, London:
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>“Ice placed within a shop or room
            
            <br></br>Will turn to water, we presume;
            
            <br></br>For, 'tis a solvent, all agree;
            
            <br></br>But here IN-solvent ice we see.
            
            <br></br>“Yet, though we cannot solve the ice,
            
            <br></br>We solve the riddle in a trice;
            
            <br></br>It comes from Pennsylvania's State,
            
            <br></br>And therefore will not liquidate."
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Original Poetry</div>
         <div class="head">Original Poetry.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="biblTitle">Osceola Signing the Treaty</div>
            <div class="biblPage">248</div>
            
            <div class="head">OSCEOLA SIGNING THE TREATY.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Stern in the white man’s council hall,
               
               <br></br>’Mid his red brethren of the wood,
               
               <br></br>While fearless flashed his eye on all,
               
               <br></br>The chieftain Osceola stood—
               
               <br></br>And fast the words that keenly stung,
               
               <br></br>Like arrows hurtled from his tongue.
               
               <br></br>“Brothers!” he said, “and ye are come
               
               <br></br>To sign the white man’s treaty here,—
               
               <br></br>To yield to him our forest home,
               
               <br></br>And he will give us lands and deer
               
               <br></br>Beyond the western prairie flowers,
               
               <br></br>For these broad hunting grounds of ours.
               
               <br></br>“The pale-face is a singing bird!
               
               <br></br>Hungry and crafty as the kite—
               
               <br></br>And ye his cunning song have heard
               
               <br></br>Till like his cheek your hearts are white!
               
               <br></br>Till for his fire-drink and his gold
               
               <br></br>Your fathers’ bones their sons have sold!
               
               <br></br>“And ye, the strong and pale of face,
               
               <br></br>Have bought the Indian’s hunting ground—
               
               <br></br>Bought his time-honored burial place,
               
               <br></br>With little gold and many a wound—
               
               <br></br>Yea—bought his right with hand of mail!
               
               <br></br>And with your blood-hounds on the trail,
               
               <br></br>You drive him from the everglades,
               
               <br></br>Beyond the Mississippi’s flow,
               
               <br></br>And with your rifles and your blades
               
               <br></br>You hunt him like the buffalo—
               
               <br></br>Till turns he, goaded, maddened, back,
               
               <br></br>To strike the foe upon the track!
               
               <br></br>"Let the white chieftains pause, and hear
               
               <br></br>The answer of the Seminole:—
               
               <br></br>The red man is a foe to fear—
               
               <br></br>He will not sign yon faithless scroll,
               
               <br></br>Nor yield to you the lands ye prize—
               
               <br></br>The war-belt on your pathway lies!”
               
               <br></br>Leapt from his wampum belt the glaive,
               
               <br></br>As from the bent bow leaps the shaft,
               
               <br></br>And fierce the tempered steel he drave
               
               <br></br>Through board and parchment, to the haft;
               
               <br></br>"And thus,” he said, with eye of flame—
               
               <br></br>"Thus Osceola signs your claim!"
            </div>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">MARY E. HEWITT.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">Stanzas</div>
            <div class="biblPage">248</div>
            <div class="head">STANZAS.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>When the snowy arms of Death
               
               <br></br>Like a shroud encircle thee,
               
               <br></br>And his cold benumbing breath
               
               <br></br>Stills thy pulse’s melody;
               
               <br></br>Then beside thee, lowly bending,
               
               <br></br>Fondest friends shall seek to trace
               
               <br></br>In this blow, our bosoms rending,
               
               <br></br>Tokens of Almighty grace.
               
               <br></br>Daily, us we see thee fade
               
               <br></br>Like a blossom on the bough,
               
               <br></br>Chilling in the wintry shade,
               
               <br></br>Frosted dews upon its brow,
               
               <br></br>How we turn aside in anguish,
               
               <br></br>Chiding tears that flow too free,
               
               <br></br>Lest thy loving heart should languish,
               
               <br></br>Witnessing our grief for thee!
               
               <br></br>Thus to see the vital spark
               
               <br></br>Trembling in its wasted frame,
               
               <br></br>Waiting, longing to embark
               
               <br></br>For the haven whence it came—
               
               <br></br>Who could blame our sad concealings
               
               <br></br>From thy meek and watchful eyes,
               
               <br></br>Of the dark and troubled feelings
               
               <br></br>Which within our bosoms rise?
               
               <br></br>Daily strive our lips to say—
               
               <br></br>Father! let thy will be done!
               
               <br></br>Nightly, kneeling, do we pray—
               
               <br></br>Father, spare our gentle one!
               
               <br></br>Thus from Death we seek to shield thee,
               
               <br></br>Hoping, where no hope avails;
               
               <br></br>Knowing that His hand hath sealed thee—
               
               <br></br>That His arrow never fails!
               
               <br></br>When we fold thee on Earth’s breast,
               
               <br></br>Greenest turf we’ll gather there;
               
               <br></br>Sweetest dews shall lightly rest
               
               <br></br>On that bosom, once so fair.
               
               <br></br>Yes! for thee the tears of Heaven,
               
               <br></br>From the concave's deepest blue,
               
               <br></br>Noiselessly shall flow each even,
               
               <br></br>In the droppings of the dew.
               
               <br></br>There the tender buds of Spring
               
               <br></br>First shall open to the day,
               
               <br></br>Light their little bells shall ring
               
               <br></br>To the robin’s roundelay;
               
               <br></br>And a breezy voice, while straying
               
               <br></br>Through the narrow, vaulted aisles,
               
               <br></br>Sad shall sigh, like mourners praying
               
               <br></br>God’s forgiveness and his smiles.
               
               <br></br>Lo! across thy path of life
               
               <br></br>Death’s white shadow’s stealing now;
               
               <br></br>Let me not behold the strife—
               
               <br></br>Let me still in meekness bow.
               
               <br></br>God be with thee, gentle spirit,
               
               <br></br>When his angel fondly calls—
               
               <br></br>Yielding life, thou wilt inherit
               
               <br></br>Life within our Father’s halls.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Cincinnati, April, 1845.</div> 
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">R. S. NICHOLS.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p8">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Living Artists of Europe, No. 1</div>
         <div class="biblPage">248</div>
         <div class="head">THE LIVING ARTISTS OF EUROPE.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">No. 1.
            
            <br></br>PAUL DE LA ROCHE.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">[We have condensed the following biographical sketch of the great
            
            <br></br>French painter from an article in the London Art-Union. We shall
            
            <br></br>give sketches and portraits of other eminent artists hereafter.]
         </div>
         
         <div class="figure"></div>
         
         <p>Paul Delaroche was born in Paris, in 1797. His father
            was a man of taste, and was appointed to value the works
            of Art which were offered at the Mont-de-Piété. He encouraged in his two sons an inclination for the purest Art; and
            the elder, M. Jules Delaroche, after having made considerable progress as a painter of history, renounced the profession, and succeeded to the appointment which his father
            held, and has risen to the directorship of the Mont-de-Piété.
            The younger persevered in his studies, and has, by his assid-
            uity, attained to the first rank among the painters of the
            French school.
         </p>
         
         <p>Paul Delaroche devoted himself first to landscape painting;
            he then entered the atelier of Gros, under whom he applied
            himself to the human figure, and soon became distinguished
            by the rapid progress he made. Under Gros the young Delaroche also soon declared his dissent from what is termed
            the hitherto prevalent “classicism” of the French school,
            which was then yielding to the Renaissance; but took up a
            position between the classic and the romantic, and labored
            to create a style in harmony with the temper and habits of
            his time. He commenced, notwithstanding, in that mysticobiblical style which flourished a few years under the restoration, and which has even of late shown symptoms of revival; but he soon discovered that this style did not suit him.
            His first picture, 'Naphthali in the Desert,’ which he painted at the age of twenty-two, was exhibited in the year
            1819, but it attracted no attention; another, the subject of
            which was ‘Joas Rescued by Josabeth,’ was more fortunate.
            This was exhibited in 1822,' and sufficiently indicated those
            powers which M. Delaroche subsequently developed and so
            judiciously tempered. In a compte-rendu of the Salon of
            1822, by M. Thiers, this picture is spoken of in terms highly
            complimentary to the young artist. In 1824 he produced
            three pictures, which won for him a gold medal. The first
            represented 'Vincent de Paul Preaching in the Presence of
            the Court of Louis XII.;’ the second, ‘Joan of Arc Examined in Prison by the Cardinal of Winchester;' the third,' Saint Sebastian.’
         </p>
         
         <p>In 1827 ‘ The Capture of the Trocadero’ appeared, a work
            which had been commissioned by the Government, and for
            which he received the cross of the Legion of Honor. About
            the same period he exhibited other works, which have contributed much to his fame. The most celebrated of these
            are, ‘The Death of Agostino Carracci;' 'Flora Macdonald
            Succouring the Pretender after the Battle of Culloden;’ ‘The
            Death of Queen Elizabeth,’ which hangs on the walls of the
            Luxembourg; ‘An Episode of the St. Bartholomew;’ ‘The
            Death of the President Duranti;’ a full-length portrait of the
            Dauphin, as a model, to be worked in Gobelin tapestry;
            and the ceiling of the Museum of Charles X.
         </p>
         
         <p>During some years after this period M. Delaroche painted
            only what the French call moyen-age subjects, although
            the term is scarcely suitable, as comprehending even those
            that come within a century or two of our own time. In
            1831 he produced ‘The Children of Edward,’ which has
            been so often engraved and lithographed, and which induced
            M. Delavigne to compose his tragedy on the same subject.
            Another highly successful picture was ‘Richelieu, on the
            Rhone, with Cinq-Mars and de Thou;' as also that representing Cardinal Mazarin presiding, while even dying, at
            a game of lansquenet. In 1832 M. Delaroche was called to
            the Institute; and in the same year he exhibited, perhaps,
            the most impressive of all his works, ‘Cromwell Contemplating the remains of Charles I.,’ a composition which,
            once seen, either in the original or in engraving, can never
            be forgotten. The extensive popularity of this production
            testifies its perfect success, and affords another extraordinary
            example of the valuable simplicity with which this artist
            can invest subjects, which in other hands would have been
            at least repulsive and, perhaps, atrocious. In 1834 appeared
            ‘The Execution of Lady Jane Gray;’ which during the entire period of its exhibition was, early and late, surrounded
            by a crowd of admiring spectators. On the same occasion
            were exhibited two other works, ‘Galileo Studying in his
            Cabinet;’ and a Saint Amelia, intended as a model for the
            painting of the great window of the chapel at the Chateau
            d’Eu.
         </p>
         
         <p>In 1835 M. Delaroche exhibited his picture of 'The Death
            of the Duke of Guise;’ it is much smaller than his other celebrated works, and was the only one exhibited in 1835. The
            murder of the Duke of Guise, it will be remembered, was
            effected in the Castle of Blois, by order of Henry III. The
            moment chosen is that when the King throws aside the
            arras from before the doorway, and, in his impatience to
            learn the result, asks in an agitated manner “if all is done;"
            he then discovers the body of the Duke, lying near the bed;
            and the murderers are relating to him the manner of his
            death. This picture was purchased by the Duke of Orleans,
            it displays more care and finish than any which preceded it.
            The intention of the painter is shown in the figure of the
            King, who looks from the corner of his eye to ascertain if his
            enemy be really dead: it is also apparent in the courtesy
            with which he is received by the assassins, who separate
            that he may see that his commands have been accomplished. 
            It is in the body of the Duke that the artist recovers his grave
            dignity: he has never produced anything more forcible than
            this. In the meantime he exhibited his well-known pictures,
            ‘Charles I. in the Guard-Room,’ and ‘Lord Strafford.’
            From 1837 to 1841 M. Delaroche was almost entirely occupied by his great work at the Ecole des Beaux Arts, having
            exhibited only two pictures, the one a fine portrait of ‘Napoleon in his Cabinet at the Tuileries.’
         </p>
         
         <p>In 1835 it was proposed to M. Delaroche to enrich the
            walls of the Madeline with suitable compositions; but circumstances subsequently led to his resignation of the task.
            In the same year he proceeded to Italy, where he formed a
            matrimonial alliance with the only daughter of Horace Vernet, who was then director of the French Academy at Rome.
            M. Delaroche was amply compensated for his disappointment, with respect to the Madeline, by having confided to
            him the adornment of the Amphitheatre of the Ecole des
            Beaux Arts—a task to which he devoted three years of assiduous labor.
         </p>
         
         <p>The distinguished artist has recently returned from a second visit to Rome, where he has executed a portrait of the
            Pope; which, in Italy, has received the most unqualified
            praise. M. Delaroche has painted but very few portraits in
            addition to those already mentioned. He has produced a
            portrait of the Countess Rossi (late Madlle. Sontag), and
            some others, in oil, crayon, &amp;c.; all of which exhibit, in a
            high degree, the striking characteristics of the accomplished
            master, who could not devote to portraiture a genius which
            has urged him onward to a series of triumphs in historical
            and didactic art.
         </p>
         
         <p>Few artists of any time, even since the revival of painting, can be pointed out as having passed during any given
            portion of their lives a career so honorable and profitable as
            that hitherto enjoyed by M. Delaroche. At a very early age
            he was already in the arena competing for the suffrages of
            the public; and in the term of twenty years he produced
            thirty pictures, all of which have been signally distinguished
            by the plaudits of the public, and many of which will remain among the remarkable examples of the French School
            of Art. All his works have been popularised by the most
            skilful engravers; from a very early period he received the
            most flattering distinctions, and has in private life enjoyed
            all the felicities attendant on a position so honorable. At
            present, M. Delaroche is again busied in his studio, with a
            prospective yet more brilliant than the past, and which it is
            our sincere and reasonable hope he may live most fully to realize.
         </p>
         
         <p>As a teacher, Delaroche has formed a long train of pupils,
            who speak of him with sincere respect. In stature he
            reaches the middle height, being apparently of a slight but
            active frame; with a head of fine character, an eye of intelligence, and very searching in its gaze.
         </p>
         
         <p>In his private character Delaroche presents much for esteem. Independent of the excellence of his qualities in domestic life, he wears no conscious air of superiority; is free,
            frank, and affable in his manners; liberal in exposing the
            riches of his studio; and communicative in reference to any
            methods of his painting which the stranger may think worthy of enquiry. Offered by the government a large pecuniary present on the completion of the Hemicycle, he waived
            it for himself, on condition that it should be offered to increase the excellence of the engraving which, under sanction
            of the Government, is about to be published.
         </p>
         
         <p>We never encountered one who so completely realized our
            notions of high genius: his eloquent countenance, so full of
            rapid thought and expression—his exceeding, and somewhat
            restless, energy of manner—conveyed to our minds the only
            just idea we ever received of what we understand, or desire
            to understand, by the term soul—as characteristic of a nature far superior to the great mass of humankind. The feeline of respect, not unmingled with affection, with which we
            regard the great painter of France, is enhanced by the knowledge that his high position is sustained not alone by that intellectual power which commands reverence from all, but
            by the continual exercise of the more “private and personal
            virtues"—the perpetual manifestation of a generosity truly
            catholic—and the almost daily proof supplied by his life,
            that true greatness may exist without a particle of selfish,
            ness, vanity, or envy.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p9">
         <div class="biblTitle">The American Authors' Union</div>
         <div class="biblPage">250</div>
         
         <div class="head">THE AMERICAN AUTHORS’ UNION.</div>
         
         <p>“Deccus,” said the reviewer of that gentleman’s works, as
            he opened his manuscript, “as you are well aware, gentlemen,
            is one of our most original, most promising, and most indigenous authors, he is, in fact the American Boz; I have written
            my review of his writings, not from any personal regard, not
            from any wish to display my own learning, but from a sincere desire to promote the interests of American literature.
            I shall begin with an analysis of his greatest work, the
            Cogitations of Christopher Cockroach, citizen. Deccus is a—”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Really, gentlemen,”said Mr. Deccus, rising with a flushed face, “it strikes me that it is taking a liberty with an author’s works which I, in the name of American literature,
            must protest against, to name any one of his writings as the
            greatest. I name no names gentlemen, I designate no presumptuous individual, but the man who takes that liberty
            with my productions can never be classed among the friends
            of American literature. I am an injured man, gentlemen.
            I accuse no one, I name no one, but a certain individual has
            done me an immense injury. If one of my works can be
            classed as the greatest of my productions, perhaps, gentlemen,
            some of my works will be called the smallest. Beware, gentlemen, how you trifle with the interests of American literature, that delicate plant which requires the warm sunlight
            of your favor, but which the cold, the chilly, the withering
            blasts of criticism may uproot and destroy and eradicate forever.”
         </p>
         
         <p>This speech of the injured author so disconcerted the reviewer, that he put his manuscript in his pocket, and sat
            down without opening his lips. But his silence seemed to
            say, that as for satisfying an author by reviewing his book, the
            thing is clearly impossible. I will make the attempt no
            more.
         </p>
         
         <p>Cries were now made for the letter of Areanus, which being produced, was found to contain a tragedy in six acts, by
            Major Laurel, the American Sheridan Knowles. It was
            read by Ostensible Watkins, Esq., the American John Philip Kemble, a remarkable elocutionist, who pronounced the
            title, sufficiently moving in itself, in a manner that sent a
            thrill of horror through all the several authors present.
         </p>   
         
         <div class="ab">The Author's Tragedy
            
            <br></br>OR
            
            <br></br>THE PERFIDIOUS PUBLISHER.
            
            <br></br>A Drama in Six Acts.
         </div>
         ACT I.
         
         <p>Scene—A room with no furniture, except a weeping wife and two
            crying children. Enter
         </p>
         
         <p>Writefort, an American author, with a large roll of paper under
            his arm. He looks with unspeakable anguish on his wife and children,
            strikes his forehead, turns both of his pockets inside out, points to his
            manuscript, and rushes off the stage.
         </p>
         ACT II.
         
         <p>Scene—A counting room, clerke writing at a desk, a publisher with
            spectacles, sitting in an easy chair reading a newspaper. Enter anotheir publisher, sleek, smiling, well fed, and well dressed.
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. Brother, good morning.</p>
         
         <p>2d Pub. Good morning, brother.</p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. Have you read the last manuscript, my brother?</p>
         
         <p>2d Pub. Ha, ha, ha, capital! read it, indeed? What
            innocent fools these authors are, to think we read their
            manuscripts.
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. I am astonished at your trifling talk upon a serious subject; you know I always reed all manuscripts that
            come to hand; I stick a reed in them, so I can always say
            with a clear conscience, (for you know I hate lying,) Sir, I
            have been reeding your manuscript, when an author applies
            to me.
         </p>
         
         <p>2d Pub. You were born a wag, brother; but what will
            you say to Mr. Writefort? He will call this morning for an
            answer.
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. It’s fortunate that you reminded me of him: I’ll
            do it now. Porter, bring in that last nuisance. [The porter
            brings in a roll of manuscripts. The 1st publisher shoves a
            reed through it, and laughs.'] There, I am ready for him;
            and here he comes.
         </p>
         
         <p>Enter Writefort, an American Author. He takes off his hat and bows
            respectfully.
         </p>
         
         <p>Author. Have you examined my work, sir?</p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. [Winks to his brother.] I have this moment
            done reeding it.
         </p>
         
         <p>Auth. Good Heavens! You have read it! Little did I
            expect this. Sir, accept the thanks of a grateful author. I
            cannot doubt, then, that you will buy it. It cost me many
            years of painful study, many privations, many fears, and many
            hopes. I am partial, I know, but still, I know the work has
            merit.
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. [Aside to his brother.] I’ll have a bit of fun. [To
            the author.] Merit? Of course. In the whole course of my
            reading I never encountered greater—greenness. (aside.)
         </p>
         
         <p>Auth. Oh, sir, what would my poor wife say, if she were
            to hear that. Will you, sir, allow me to repeat it to her?
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. Of course. Pray, Mr. Writefort, what value do
            you put upon your work?
         </p>
         
         <p>Author. Indeed, Sir, I am afraid to say. No price would
            seem too large to me who know its value, and none too
            small to meet my wants.
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. Would you refuse ten thousand dollars?</p>
         
         <p>Author. Ten thousand dollars! Surely. Sir, you are jesting or I am dreaming. Did you mean what you said; did you
            say ten thousand dollars?
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. I did.</p>
         
         <p>u thor. Sir, I will take less, I will take nine thousand
            five hundred. Excuse my trembling, Sir, but your offer was
            so unexpected, it has quite unnerved me. I must go home
            and tell my wife. I will return again to-morrow and close
            the bargain. [He shakes both Publishers by the hand, and
            rushes out in a wild delirium of joy.]
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. Ha! ha! ha!</p>
         
         <p>2d Pub. Ho! ho! ho!</p>
         
         <p>All the clerks. He! he! he!</p>
         
         <p>2d Pub. Porter, remove that nuisance, and then pack up
            the case of Bibles.
         </p>
         ACT III.
         
         <p>Scene—the Unfurnished Room.</p>
         
         <p>The author, his wife and two children, with hands joined, dance
            round the table, which has an empty ink bottle and a steel pen in the
            centre. Having danced until their strength is exhausted they fall on
            their knees, forming a tableau in front of the table, and the curtain
            drops.
         </p>
         ACT IV.
         
         <p>Scene—the Publishers as before.</p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. There comes that poor devil author again.
            Now for more fun. Enter Writefort.
         </p>
         
         <p>Write. Sir, I have called again for the last time, ten
            times have I called already. If you do not mean to pay me
            anything for my work, it shall be yours for nothing, if you
            will only print it.
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. I could not think of accepting so valuable a
            work, Sir, for nothing; and as for printing it now it is quite
            impossible—we mean to erect a new steam press ex-pressly
            for it.
         </p>
         
         <p>Author. But while your presses are getting ready, I am
            pressed so sorely by my necessities that I cannot wait. I
            must apply elsewhere, and as you have read my work you
            will, of course, give me a paper setting forth its value.
         </p>
         
         <p>1st Pub. That I cannot do; it’s against my principles to
            recommend any work which I do not publish. Porter, give
            Mr. Writefort his manuscript.
         </p>
         
         <p>Author. Pray, Sir, how is this? You say you read my
            work, but the seal of the wrapper has not been broken.
            Surely you have not been trifling with me?
         </p>
         
         <p>Pub. Porter, show that gentleman to the door; authors
            are getting impudent. Fine times, indeed, when a poor devil writer uses such language to a respectable dealer in books.
            Trifling, indeed!
         </p>
         
         <p>Exit author with his MS. under his arm. and the act closes with a
            grand laughing chorus by the publishers and his workmen.
         </p>
         ACT V.
         
         <p>Scene—in the street, before a cheap publication office.</p>
         
         <p>Writefort—[Solus.] Well, at last my work is out; published upon the cheap and nasty plan. All my hard toil, all
            my high hopes, all my fond dreams at last have come to
            this. My precious work, printed on dingy paper, stitched in
            a cover of dirty hue, and sold at retail for no more than a
            poor quarter dollar. Well, well, I had one glorious hour,
            the while I dreamed I and my wife and little ones were all
            made rich by that magnificent sum! Ten thousand dollars!
            ’T was but a dream, but even in a dream to be so blest, was
            worth the toil, and care, and wasting thought, that my great
            work has cost. Who would not be an author.
         </p>
         ACT VI.
         
         <p>Scene—a garret, a coffin surrounded by the author’s widow and tiro
            children. She holds a copy of the London Times in her hand. She wipes
            her eyes and reads.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Mr. Bentley will publish early next month 'Writefort’s
            History of Pavonia,’ in 3 vols. octavo: price two guineas.”
            Too late, too late! This advertisement would have saved
            my husband’s life. But cannot I and my children reap some
            good from my husband’s labors? Must Mr. Bentley fatten
            upon the toil of my dead husband, and I gain nothing? O,
            strange unequal world, that secures to the meanest laborer,
            the mechanic, the merchant, the farmer, the fruits of their
            toil, the full extent of their possessions, but leaves the author destitute of protection, a prey to every mercenary wretch
            that chooses to appropriate his belongings; O, strange inconsistent, thoughtless, heartless world!
         </p>
         
         <p>The lid of the coffin is suddenly lilted up, the author rising in the
            coffin; the widow and children are on the point of rushing out when
            he calls them back and embraces them.
         </p>
         
         <p>Author. An appeal like that, a wrong so gross, an inconsistency so strange, an evil so monstrous, a statement so
            startling, could not fail to wake the dead. I am alive again.
            Dear wife, and children dear, let those write books who will,
            henceforth I’ll cobble shoes, and then I shall enjoy the fruits
            of my own labor.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">THE END.</div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p10">
         <div class="biblTitle">Achilles' Wrath</div>
         <div class="biblPage">251</div>
         <div class="head">ACHILLES’ WRATH.</div>
         
         <p>At "No. 8 Astor House,” in a style (no doubt) of luxurious elegance and ease, resides a gentleman and a scholar,
            who (without paying his postage) has forwarded us a note,
            (through the Despatch Post,) signing it either Mr. W. Dinnelord, or Mr. P. or Mr. Q. Dinneford—for he writes a shockingly bad hand, and we are unable to make out all his capitals with precision. It is not always the best scribe, however, physically considered, who is capable of inditing the
            most agreeable note—as the note of Mr. Dinneford will
            show. Here it is:
         </p>
         
         <p>SIR!</p>		
         
         <p>In your note of the 2d inst. you request of me the favor of
            being placed on the free list of this theatre, because (as your letter
            says) you were anxious "to do Justice to 'Antigone’ on its representation.” Your name was accordingly placed on the free list. Your
            Critique has appeared, in the Broadway Journal, characterized, much
            more by ill nature and an illiberal spirit, than by fair and candid or
            even just criticism.—
         </p>
         
         <p>In justice therefore to myself, I have withdrawn your name from
            the free list. I am always prepar’d to submit,as a catererer for public
            amusement, to any just remarks, though they may be severe, but I do
            not feel myself called upon to offer facilities to any one, to do me injury by animadversions evidently marked by ill feeling. I am SIR!
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">With very great respect, Your most ob’t serv’t
            
            <br></br>W. DINNEFORD.
            
            <br></br>To Edgar Poe Esq. &amp;c &amp;c &amp;c
            
            <br></br>Author of THE RAVEN.
            
            <br></br>New York APL 15, 1845. No 8 Astor House.
         </div>
         
         <p>We are not wrong (are we?) in conceiving that Mr.
            Dinneford is in a passion. We are not accustomed to compositions of precisely this character—(that is to say, notes written in large capitals with admiration notes for commas—the
            whole varied occasionally with lower case)—but still, we
            think ourselves justified in imagining that Mr. Dinneford
            was in a passion when he sent us this note from his suite of
            boudoirs at the Astor House. In fact, we fancy that we can
            trace the gradations of his wrath in the number and impressiveness of his underscoring. The SIRS!! for example, are
            exceedingly bitter; and in THE RAVEN, which has five
            black lines beneath it, each one blacker than the preceding,
            we can only consider ourselves as devoted to the Infernal
            Gods.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Dinneford is in a passion then—but what about?
            We had been given to understand, that it was usual in New
            York, among editors newly established, to apply (by note)
            for the customary free admission to the theatres. The custom is a wretched one, we grant, but since it was a custom,
            we were weak enough, in this instance, to be guided by it.
            We made our note to this Dinneford as brief and as explicit
            as possible—for we felt that the task was a dirty one. We
            stated distinctly that we wished to be placed on his free list
            for the purpose of “doing justice to Antigone”—just as he
            says himself. To this note the inhabitant of No. 8 Astor
            House condescended to make no reply. Supposing that the
            man “knew no better,” and pitying his ignorance from the
            bottom of our hearts, we proceeded to the theatre on its
            opening night, in the full certainty of at least finding our
            name on the free list. It was not there. And the blatherskite who could behave in so indecent a manner, as to fail
            first in answering our note, and secondly in paying attention
            to the request it contained, has the audacity to find fault with
            us because we dared to express an unbiassed opinion of his
            stupidity—that is to say, of the stupidity of a play gotten up
            by himself, Mr. Dinneford.
         </p>
         
         <p>He failed in his duty—there was no reason that we should
            fail in ours. We told him that we meant to do him justice—
            and we did it.
         </p>
         
         <p>We are not wasting words on this Quinneford—it is the
            public to whom we speak—to the editorial corps in especial.
            We wish to call their attention to the peculiar character of
            the conditions which managers such as this have the impudence to avow, as attached to the privilege of the free list.
            No puff no privilege, is the contract. That is to say, an editor, when admitted to the theatre, is to be understood as
            leaving his conscience in the street. He is admitted not to
            judge—not to criticise—but to adulate. He is to put himself
            to the inconvenience of quitting his business, or his amusement, for the purpose of observing and reporting, for the
            management, whatever is occurring at the theatre. On entering, he is to content himself with standing where he can—
            his usual position being in the lobby, where he peeps, as well
            as he may, through the Venetian shutters of the boxes—for
            usually he cannot go until late, and no accommodations are
            afforded him—no seats are reserved for his use. And for the
            honor of doing all this, he is complimented with what?—the
            privilege of entering the doors of the Temple consecrated to
            the Quinneford—the value of the privilege in actual money,
            ranging from one dollar to twenty-five cents per night; admitting that circumstances are at the very best, and that the
            editor is so fortunate as to secure such a seat as he could
            procure for the twenty-five cents or the dollar, paid at the
            door. Deducting the difficulties and inconveniences to which
            he is necessarily subjected, the privileges may be estimated
            as from 6 1/4 to 12 1/2 cents per evening—a price quite sufficient,
            we presume, in the opinion of the Quinnefords, for the conglomerated consciences of all the editors within the limits of
            Christendom.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have spoken, altogether, of “such managers” as Quinneford—but fortunately such managers are few. There is
            certainly not in New York, at the present moment, any other
            member of the theatrical profession, who either would have
            behaved with the gross discourtesy of this gentleman, or
            who, in inditing the preposterous letter published above,
            could have proved himself, personally, so successful a “catererer for the public amusement.”
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">Night: A Poem</div>
            <div class="biblPage">252</div>
            
            <p>Night: a Poem. In two Parts. New York: Alexander V. Blake, 77
               Fulton street. l845. pp. 60.
            </p>
            
            <p>Alexandre Dumas, in the preface to one of his tragedies,
               says: “Ce sont les hommes, et non pas 1’homme, qui inventent. Chacun arrive à son tour et à son heure, s'empare
               des choses connues de ses pères, les met en œuvre par des
               combinaisons nouvelles, puis meurt après avoir ajouté quelques parcelles à la somme des connaissances humaines.
               Quant à la crèation complète d’une chose, je la crois impossible. Dieu lui même, lorsqu’il crea l'homme, ne put on n’osa
               point 1’inventer: il le fit à son image.
            </p>
            
            <p>We should be unwilling to charge the author of the poem
               before us with the profane sentiment of the audacious plagiarist whom we have quoted, but it is very plain that the
               two authors entertain very similar feelings respecting des
               choses connues de ses pères.
            </p>
            
            <p>The author of Night has chosen an infelicitous title for his
               poem, for the word “Thoughts,” must pop into the minds of
               his readers as soon as they open his volume: yet it would
               have mattered nothing if he had chosen a different one, for
               the same title would have been inevitably suggested by the
               poem itself.
            </p>
            
            <p>We can safely pronounce the author a good man and a
               scholar, which is higher praise than can be bestowed upon
               every good poet. His withholding his name from his combinaisons nouvelles proves him to be a modest man, at least.
               The volume makes a favorable appeal to the eye, if not to
               he heart, by its beautiful externals. It is one of the handsomest books that we have recently handled.
            </p>
            
            <p>There are many lines like the following in the poem,
               which might be vastly improved by the alteration of one
               word:
            </p> 
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“From morn to noon, from noon to dusky eve.”
            </div>
            
            <p>if dewy were substituted for dusky, the line would then be
               quite perfect and original. As an example of the author’s
               art and feeling, we make as long an extract as we can afford
               room for.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>E’en now the gale that stirs this humid air.
               
               <br></br>Is wet with sight and tears that rise to beaten,
               
               <br></br>Despatch’d, how vain, to sue for mercy there.
               
               <br></br>Gay-hearted sufferers! such are not to me
               
               <br></br>The sounds I love the most; for I am of you:
               
               <br></br>Lay but the master his cold hand on me.
               
               <br></br>Press but these cords, and lo! what plaintive airs
               
               <br></br>Running through all my compass, judge me true.
               
               <br></br>A sharer in your lot; partner with all
               
               <br></br>Of human kind, the common nerve of life
               
               <br></br>That knits all nature, country, race, in one,
               
               <br></br>And makes us comrades as in fortune joined;
               
               <br></br>Each bound to each, and one to all, then why
               
               <br></br>Less sad for other’s sorrows than my own?
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">Imagination and Fancy</div>
            <div class="biblPage">252</div>
            
            <p>Imagination and Fancy. By Leigh Hunt. No. IV of the “Library
               of Choice Reading,” published by Mess. Wiley and Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>A better work than this, for the purpose of the “Library”
               could scarcely have been selected.
            </p>
            
            <p>The delicate taste and fine fancy of Leigh Hunt are, at
               the present day, as warmly admitted, as many years ago
               they were clamorously denied. His exquisite sensibility to
               all impressions of the beautiful; his scholarship (by no
               means profound, yet peculiarly available); and his general
               vivacity of intellect—render him an admirable critic on all
               points within the compass of these qualities. No man living
               can put a truly good book of ordinary literature, in a better
               light than he. In poetical criticism, especially, he is at
               home—to the extent we have suggested. His mode is to
               give a running commentary on the poem, citing largely, Italicizing such passages as strike his fancy, and expatiating on
               the effects produced: his sole object, apparently, being to
               extort from the work the greatest amount of beauty which
               it can be made to yield. This, undoubtedly, is a very captivating method, and mankind are by no means the more disposed to quarrel with it on the ground that it is sometimes
               less useful (if the term may be here applied) than delightful.
            </p>
            
            <p>But these are not all the capacities of Hunt. He theorises
               with great ability. An instinct of the fitting—a profound
               sentiment of the true, the graceful, the musical, the beautiful in every shape—enables him to construct critical principles which are thoroughly consistent with Nature, and which
               thus serve admirably as a substructure for Art. But it is in
               the power of passing behind his principles, that he utterly
               and radically fails. Of their composition—of their machinery—he is as ignorant as a child. If any thing goes wrong
               with his critical clock-work, he remains profoundly and curiously embarrassed—not having the commonest idea of the
               steps to be taken to set it in order. He tells us that a passage is beautiful, and very usually (though not always) we
               admit that he is right. He insists on its beauty, and we still
               coincide. He expatiates on it until we grow warm in his
               warmth. He demonstrates to our satisfaction how it is beautiful and at what particular points it is beautiful, and sometimes adventures so far as to assure us (while we agree with
               him) that it would be still better at certain other points if
               written so and so—and then should we be so inconsiderate as
               to ask him why it is beautiful, he would be altogether at a
               loss for an answer.
            </p>
            
            <p>In a word the forte of the author of Rimini is taste—while
               his foible is analysis. Of this latter quality—absolutely indispensable in all criticism that aims at instruction or reformation in letters—he is radically deficient. He himself feels
               his own ability to construct a fine poem, and is content to be
               assured of the validity of the principles upon which he constructs it, without caring to understand the ultimate character
               of the natural laws (of the heart and intellect) upon which
               the validity of the principles depends. Feeling thus, he is
               prone to suppose that in all men the ability may exist without the understanding—and his criticisms therefore take no
               account of the latter. He neglects it first, because he does
               not appreciate its necessity (since it is no necessity for him)
               and secondly through absolute incapacity for its discussion.
               Now the one cause predominates in him and now the other.
               We can at all time trust his comments of love and admira
               tion, and we may put faith to a very great extent in his definitions or general conclusions in art, but we must never ask
               of him too inquisitively, by what process they have been attained, or request him to put us in a condition for the attainment of similar conclusions for ourselves.
            </p>
            
            <p>Now we are quite sure that the author of “Imagination
               and Fancy” would deny in a great measure the utility of
               that analysis for which we contend—but he would deny it
               just as a man born blind might be led to deny the utility of
               light. A far greater than Leigh Hunt has, in fact, denied it
               as far as he could, through implication, in the case of Lord
               Verülam. We allude to Macaulay, who is at much pains to
               detract from the wisest and brightest (we will not say the
               meanest of mankind) on the ground that the inductive processes of reason teach us to reason no better in teaching us
               the modes in which we reason. It is Macaulay who maintains,
               in other words, that a man is enabled to labor to no greater
               advantage by any understanding of the tools with which
               he labors, or of the material upon which his labor is bestowed! The reply to all this is, that Thomas Babington Macaulay is not a man of genius. He is a critic, but no more than a
               critic. We grant that the “Lays of Ancient Rome” would
               have received little or no improvement from any understanding, on the part of their author, of the processes of thought
               which enabled him to put them together. Their merit or
               demerit, in fact, is quite independent of any such understanding—the truth, after all, seeming to resolve itself into this—
               that the value of the comprehension of which we speak, is
               in the direct ratio of the creative ability which employs
               or takes advantage of the comprehension. In this sense,
               there are few who would deny that to Leigh Hunt the faculty
               of analysis would be of greater moment than to Macaulay:—
               and if we have expressed ourselves of the admirable work
               before us less warmly than may seem fitting, it is not that
               we fail to appreciate, or are unwilling to admit its merits,
               but that we feel a sentiment half of grief half of vexation, at
               perceiving how very narrowly it has missed being more meritorious, by a hundred fold at least, than it actually is, as we
               now see it.
            </p>
            
            <p>It would be doing our subject injustice not to give our
               readers at least one extract from the volume. We choose
               the concluding paragraphs of an answer to the query “what
               is poetry?”
            </p>
            
            <p>I cannot draw this essay towards its conclusion better than with
               three memorable words of Milton; who has said, that poetry in comparison with science, is “simple, sensuous, and passionate.” By simple, he means unperplexed and self-evident; by sensuous, genial and
               full of Imagery; by passionate, excited and enthusiastic. I am
               aware that different constructions have been put upon some of these
               words; but the context seems to me to necessitate those before us. I
               quote, however, not from the original, but from an extract in the Remarks on Paradise Lost by Richardson.
            </p>
            
            <p>What the poet has to cultivate above all things is love and truth;—
               what he has to avoid like poison, is the fleeting and the false. He
               will get no good by proposing to be “in earnest at the moment. His
               earnestness must be innate and habitual; born with him, and felt to
               be his most precious inheritance. “I expect neither protit nor general fame by my writings,” says Coleridge in his Preface to his Poems;
               “and I consider myself as having been amply repaid without either.
               Poetry has been to me its ‘own exceeding great reward:' it has soothed my afflictions; it has multiplied and refined my enjoyments; it has
               endeared solitude; it has given me the habit of wishing to discover
               the good and the beautiful in all that meets and surrounds me.’—Pickering’s edition, p. 10.
            </p>	
            
            <p>"Poetry,” says Shelley, “lifts the veil from the hidden beauty of
               the world, and makes familiar objects be at if they were not familiar.
               It reproduces all that it represents; and the impersonations clothed
               in its Elysian light stand thenceforward in the minds of those who
               have once contemplated them, as memorials of that gentle and exalted content which extends itself over all thoughts and actions with
               which it co-exists. The great secret of morals is love, or a going out
               of our own nature, and an identification of ourselves with the beautiful which exists in thought, action, or person, not our own. A man,
               to be greatly good, must imagine intensely and comprehensively; he
               must put himself in the place of another, and of many others: the
               pains and pleasures of hie species most become his own. The great
               instrument of moral good is imagination; and poetry administers to
               the effect by acting upon the cause.”—Essays and Letters,vol. i. p. 16.
            </p>
            
            <p>I would not willingly say anything after perorations like these;
               but as treatises on poetry may chance to have auditors who think
               themselves called upon to vindicate the superiority of what is termed
               useful knowledge, it may be as well to add, that if the poet may be
               allowed to pique himself on any one thing more than another, compared with those who undervalue him, it is on that power of undervaling nobody, and no attainments different from his own, which is given him by the very faculty of imagination they despise. The greater
               includes the less. They do not see that their inability to comprehend
               him argues the smaller capacity.
            </p>
            
            <p>No man recognizes the worth of utility more than the poet: he only
               desires that the meaning of the term may not come short of its greatness, and exclude the noblest necessities of his fellow-creatures. He
               is quite as much pleased, for instance, with the facilities for rapid
               conveyance afforded him by the railroad, as the dullest confiner of its
               advantages to that single idea, or as the greatest two-idead man who
               varies that single idea with hugging himself on his “buttons” or his
               good dinner. But he sees also the beauty of the country through
               which he passes, of the towns, of the heavens, of the steam-engine itself, thundering and fuming along like a magic horse, of the affections
               that are carrying, perhaps, half the passengers on their journey, nay,
               of those of the great two-idead man; and beyond all this, he discerns
               the incalulable amount of good, and knowledge, and refinement, and
               mutual consideration, which this wonderful invention is fitted to circulate over the globe, perhaps to the displacement of war itself, and
               certainly to the diffusion of millions of enjoyments.
            </p>
            
            <p>“And a button-maker, after all, invented it!” cries our friend.</p>
            
            <p>Pardon me—it was a nobleman. A button-maker may be a very
               excellent, and a very poetical man, too, and yet not have been the first
               man visited by a sense of the gigantic powers of the combination of
               water and fire. It was a nobleman who first thought of it,—a captain who first tried it,—and a button-maker who perfected it. And
               he who put the nobleman on such thoughts, was the great philosopher
               Bacon, who said that poetry had “something divine in it,” and was
               necessary to the satisfaction of the human mind.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">Phreno-Mnemotechny; or the Art of Memory</div>
            <div class="biblPage">253</div>
            
            <p>Phreno-Mnemotechny; or the Art of Memory: the series of Lectures explanatory of the Principles of the System, delivered in New York and Philadelphia, in the banning of 1844, by Francis Fauvel Gouraud, D. E. S. of
               the University of France. Now lirst published without alterations or
               omissions, and with considerable additions in the practical application of
               the System. New York and London: Wiley and Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a very large volume of nearly 700 octavo pages, and to pronounce on it hastily would be something worse than folly. We merely
               mentioned, in our last paper, the fact of the publication. Since then
               we have given the whole a careful perusal, and have no hesitation in
               declaring the work one of the most extraordinary ever issued in this
               country or elsewhere. M. Gouraud is of that class of men who, through
               intensity of enthusiasm, accomplish great things, but who again,
               through the very peculiarity, or markedness, of this enthusiasm, excite
               against them a thousand prejudices in the minds of the mass of man.
               kind—who have usually a dislike to be startled by new propositions,
               and cannot comprehend the possibility of a man’s being at once great
               and what they think proper to denominate “eccentric.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The system of Mnemotechny invented by M. Gouraud compares
               with those of Grey and Feinagle as Hyperion to Satyrs—and yet it
               was the immortal Lalande who said he knew of nothing so profoundly
               consequential as the system of Feinagle.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are now merely speaking at random, for we intend to recur to
               this subject again, and perhaps even again. We shall endeavor to
               convey to our readers some idea of what this remarkable volume really is, without reference to any opinions of prejudiced persons respecting it.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Farmer's and Emigrant's Guide-Book</div>
            <div class="biblPage">253</div>
            
            <p>The Farmer's and Emigrant's Guide-Book: being a full and complete
               guide for the Farmer and the Emigrant. Comprising the clearing of forests and prairie land, gardening, farming generally, farriery, cookery, and
               the prevention and cure of diseases. With copious hints, recipes, and tables. By Josiah F. Marshall, author of the “Emigrant’s Guide. Second
               emtion, revised. Appleton &amp; Co., 200 Broadway.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have rarely seen a book that so fully redeemed the promise of
               its title as does the “Farmer’s and Emigrant’s Guide;" it contains directions and recipes for every thing that a farmer or a farmer’s wife
               would care to know, from the construction of a house down to directions for mixing buck-wheat cakes. One of the most novel among the
               recipes is directions for making bread out of pine bark.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Voices of the Night</div>
            <div class="biblPage">253</div>
            
            <p>Voices of the Night. By H. W. Longfellow. Redding &amp; Co., Boston.
               Price 12 1-2 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>A neatly printed edition, in pamphlet form, of a book too univer-
               sally known to require any comment.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Practical Treatise on the Organic Diseases of the Uterus</div>
            <div class="biblPage">253</div>
            
            <p>A Practical Treatise on the Organic Diseases of the Uterus: being the prize essay to which the Medical Society of London awarded the Fothergillian
               gold metal for 1843. By John B.W. Lever, M.D. New York: Burgess,
               Stringer &amp; Co. 1845. pp. 240.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Mysteries of London</div>
            <div class="biblPage">253</div>
            
            <p>The Mysteries of London. Translated from the French. By Henry C. Deming, Esq. New York: Burgess, Stringer &amp; Co.</p>
            
            <p>We have not read this work, but if any thing could induce us to do
               so, it would be the name of the translator on the title-page, who has the
               
               rare art in his translations, of preserving the spirit of the original language, while he invests it with his own graceful and elegant style.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Warwick Woods</div>
            <div class="biblPage">254</div>
            
            <p>The Warwick Woods, or things as they were there ten years ago. By Frank
               Forester. Henry William ilerbert. Philadelphia: Zieber &amp; Co. 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>The essays in this little volume are already well known to the readers of the New York Turf Register, and other sporting magazines;
               and the popularity of the author’s name will doubtless give them a
               wide circulation among readers in general.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Westminster Review</div>
            <div class="biblPage">254</div>
            
            <p>The Westminster Review, for March has just been reprinted. Contents: The French Political Economists; Shakspeare and his Editors;
               Commercial Policy of England and Germany; Chronology of Egyptian
               History; Ship-Owners; Luuatic Asylums; and City Administration.
               L. Scott &amp; Co., 112 Fulton st.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p20">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="biblPage">254</div>
         <div class="head">THE FINE ARTS.</div>
         
         <p>The Indian Guide.—A capital painting, of this name, has recently
            been added to the collection of the Art-Union of this city. It is the work
            of Charles Deas, formerly of New York, but at present residing in St.
            Louis. Those who admired his “Long Jake,” the Santa Fe trader,
            will understand the merit of the "Indian Guide,” when we say that
            it would form an admirable companion to that picture.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Indian Guide is a half-breed; a tall gaunt figure, mounted on a
            pony, moving at a rapid gallop across a prairie: there is no other figure
            in sight, excepting an emigrant standing at his wagon in the extreme
            distance. The pony must be a veritable portrait; he is as characteristic in his hide and trappings as his rider. He has been shorn of every thing not essential to vitality—cars, mane, and tail; and his hide
            has been branded by the marking iron of successive owners. The
            Guide carries a long-barrelled fowling piece in his hand; and slung at
            his back, there is some kind of game that he has just killed. The
            purple sky, though apparently greatly exaggerated in color, is doubtless
            true to nature, and it helps to give an air of mystery and wildness to
            the whole composition.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Deas is not one of the ideal school; he loves to paint Nature as
            he finds her, modestly doubting his ability to improve upon her models. Excepting Mount, he is the most purely American in his feelings
            of any painter that we have produced. There is nothing foreign, nothing copied from other pictures in any of his compositions that we
            have seen; every thing about them has an air of genuineness that
            impresses you with the feeling of truth. Among the wild frontier men
            of the West, Mr. Deas will find many subjects for his pencil, which, we
            trust, will keep him well employed, and we hope to see many companions to “Long Jake” and the “Indian Guide.” Pictures of pure savage life, like those by Mr. Catlin, cannot excite our sympathies as
            strongly as do the representations of beings who belong to our own
            race. The Indian stands at an impassable remove from civilization,
            but the half-breed forms a connecting link between the white and red
            races; we feel a sympathy for the Indian Guide that we never could
            for the painted savage, for we see that he has a tincture of our own
            blood, and his trappings show that he has taken one step towards refinement and civilized life.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is another picture of genuine American feeling just added to
            the exhibition of the Art-Uuion, from an opposite extreme of the country to that from which the Indian Guide has come. A landscape by
            Mr. Harry of Boston, representing an early snow scene at the head of
            the Penobscot river. Though the river is frozen and the ground and
            trees are covered with a frosty rime, there is a warm haze in the air
            which looks like Indian summer. It is a very charming picture, infinitely better than some others which we have seen by the same artist.
         </p>
         
         <p>The National Academy.—The Annual Exhibition of this Institution was opened to the public on the 17th inst. From a hasty glance
            at the pictures, we should say that there were more good ones than any
            exhibition has contained since the first opening of the Academy. We
            shall notice them at length next week.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p21">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Review</div>
         <div class="biblPage">254</div>
         <div class="head">MUSICAL REVIEW.</div>
         
         <p>1.	The real Scotch Polka, as danced at the balls and opera houses of
            Milan, Paris, Vienna, London, and arranged by Ricardo Linter.
         </p>
         
         <p>2.	Variations sur la Valse Favorite de F. Schubert, (nomme
            Schnsuchts, or Clara—Walzer de Beethoven) pour le piano, par Chas.
            Mayer. (De St. Petersburg.)
         </p>
         
         <p>3. Annen, or the Maid of Elbekosteletz; a song written to the popular Polka, composed by Strauss, arranged by James Clarke.</p>
         
         <p>4.	Fantasie Brillante, for the piano-forte, on favorite subjects, from
            Rossini’s Guillaume Tell, composed, arranged, and dedicated to Miss
            Cordelia Kiddie, by James G. Maeder.
         </p>
         
         <p>5.	’Tis Eve on the Ocean. Song composed by Henry Russell.</p>
         
         <p>6.	Street Hawthorn-den. A ballad written and composed by George
            Linley.
         </p>
         
         <p>7.	Cadence, Impromptu en forme d’Etude, pour le piano, executée
            par l’Auteur à son Concert d’Adieu de Londres. Composée par Sigismond Thalberg.
         </p>
         
         <p>The whole of the above pieces are published by W. H. Oakes, and
            for sale by E. H. Wade, 197 Washington street, Boston.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 1, is a set of Scotch Polkas, the airs of which are formed from
            the real old Scotch tunes, put into Polka time. They are exceedingly
            pretty Polkas, and are excellent for dancing. They are got out in the
            most costly style, the title page, representing a couple in tartan, executing one of the figures of the dance, is most gorgeously emblazoned
            with gold and colors. It would be a beautiful embellishment to any
            collection.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 2. The Theme on which these variations are founded, has been
            generally attributed to Beethoven, but the Germans now give it to F.
            Schubert. It is a lovely waltz, and it is but fair that the composer
            should have just credit for the work. The variations by Charles Meyer, are chaste and elegant, and require a light finger and flexible wrist
            to do them justice. The andante is extremely beautiful; the second
            variation and the finale are brilliant and effective. On the whole, this
            piece is worthy the attention of every amateur who possesses good
            musical taste and a moderate degree of skill.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the third bar of the theme the E in the bass should be marked
            sharp.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 3. This is the celebrated Polka, composed by Strauss, to which
            words have been adapted, descriptive of the grief of a young maiden,
            who is forbidden to join in the sports of those of her own age, because
            she has a lover and staid out rather late. A very hard case, to our
            thinking.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the back of the title-page there is an interesting account of the
            supposed early origin and the authenticated modern resuscitation of
            the Polka.
         </p>
         
         <p>The name itself is claimed to be of Latin derivation, and from its
            antiquity, the dance becomes as respectable as it is fascinating. We
            should like to copy the whole of the veritable history, but must be
            content to refer our readers to the song, which will recommend itself
            very generally by its melodious and pleasing character.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 4 is a brilliant Fantasia, introducing two of the most popular
            and pleasing airs from the Guillaume Tell of Rossini. The introduction is appropriate, giving a shadowing forth of one of the themes.
            The airs and the variations are well arranged, very pleasing in their
            character, and lay well under the finger- Mr. Maeder bas produced
            a piece which will be very popular, because it is easy, and every one
            has the themes by heart.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 5. A song by Mr. Henry Russell—one of his favorite waltz
            movements, made up from many things, the principal ingredients being
            three-eighths Strauss, two-eighths Auber, and the remainder selected
            from the familiar common-place material, floating about and always
            on hand. This mixture, alter having been well shaken up, resolves
            itself into something very palatable, and peculiarly adapted to the
            general taste. We shall not pretend to criticise this song, because
            the absence of all thought from the composition renders it quite unnecessary. It is a difficult thing to analyse nothing.
         </p>
         
         <p>We must, however, in fairness state, that by ingeniously dovetailing
            a number of separate phrases, a so-called pretty melody has been produced, which will doubtless sell the song.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 6, is one of a thousand pleasing ballads from the prolific pen of
            George Linley. This gentleman is both poet and musician, and has
            produced some of the sweetest ballads in the language. Sweet Haw.
            thorn-den is simple and expressive, and is to be commended for the
            fact that there is no evidence of any straining after effect. It is well
            suited to a light treble voice, or limited tenor voice, its compass only
            reaching a ninth.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 7, is a charming study, by Thalberg, in A Minor. Unlike the
            generality of this composer’s pieces, the one before us presents but few
            difficulties. It is simply an accompanied air, which, by the bye
            though of a mournful character, is not distinguished either for its
            merit or its originality. This piece will be found a very capital exercise, and especially adapted to strengthen the fingers of the right hand.
            It is most admirably got out, with a very elegant title page. Indeed,
            all the music published by Messrs. Oakes and Wade, of Boston, is distinguished by the excellence and elegance of its mechanical department, both in the interior and the exterior of the works published. The
            liberality and enterprise of these gentlemen fully merit the large patronage bestowed upon them by the public.
         </p>
         
         <p>We shall notice the Social Minstrel, by David Paine of Boston, in
            our next.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p22">
         <div class="biblTitle">Miscellany</div>
         <div class="biblPage">255</div>
         <div class="head">MISCELLANY.</div>
         
         <p>American Engravings in England.—A case has recently
            occurred at the Custom-house, in London, which cannot fail to interest many of our readers. Some lime ago a work was published in
            New York, descriptive of the art of weaving, illustrated by a vast
            number of prints, showing that process in all its stages. It appears
            that the same work has been recently reprinted in London, by Wiley
            and Putnam, and that its publishers have imported several prints, excuted in the United States, intending, as they state, to unite these foreign prints with the British letter press. The officers of the Customs
            charged these prints with the separate duty of 1d. per print, of which
            the parties complained to the Treasury, who referred the matter to
            the Board of Trade. The latter board recommended the Treasury to
            admit these prints at the duty of £2 10s. per cwt.,—that being the
            amount of duty chargeable on books,—on the ground that, if the prints
            had accompanied the letter press, they being subsidiary,—that is,
            merely illustrative of the subject of the work,—they would have been
            admissible as a book at the said duty, viz., at £2 10s.per cwt; considering that the letter-press should not be put upon a worse footing
            for having been printed in England than if it had been printed in the United States. But their lordships required evidence of the fact alleged,
            namely, that the work in question has actually been printed in England. The recommendation has been acted upon.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Benfeit of Mr. Benj. F. Tryon, took place on Friday
            (last) evening at the Olympic Theatre, with a new Farce by T. Picton Milner, under the title of “Behind the Age.” Mr. Tryon belongs
            to Young America: that is to say, the rising generation connected
            with Theatres, Literature, the Arts, &amp;c., &amp;c., and Mr. Milner, we believe, begins to be known as the Juvenile Dramatist, and lays his account mainly with tapping the Reservoir of students at the University,
            of which he is a graduate. Wherever there is a Theatre, Mr. Milner’s
            round hat is sure to be seen.
         </p>
         
         <p>Monumental Loaves.—At a late missionary meeting in
            England, a speaker related the following anecdote, in illustration of
            his remark that “avarice never prospered any people.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“He remembered a baker that was very niggardly, and he was desirous of repairing his oven. Well, how to do this on economical principles was the desideratum. Fire bricks were costly, very costly.—
            What could he get? Oh, he had it! There were some grave stones,
            which, if he could nicely get hold of, would suit very well. Could he
            get them snugly, the job would soon be done. No matter how, but he
            got hold of them, and immediately set to work at his oven. He enlarged it, and flagged it with the fragments of grave-stones; but without thought, he placed the lettered side up. The 'baking day’ took
            took place. His neighbors bought their loaves. Mind, they were not
            in tins, but were oven-bottomed loaves, that is, the dough baked on
            the oven bottom without tins. They were duly baked. The neighbors fetched the loaves, but, astonishment! What magic! On one
            loaf was ‘ departed this life,’ on another, ‘aged seventy-six years,’
            &amp;c. The tale soon got out, and the baker was never troubled to bake
            another, and soon was ruined. His covetousness punished himself,
            and so it would be with all those professing but not acting with that
            liberality that became Christians.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Henry Phillips is in Boston. He sang in Neükomn’s
            Oratorio of David at a Concert of the Handel and Haydn Society on
            Sunday evening last. Signor Rapetti gave a concert there, Friday the
            11th inst., assisted by the Misses Garcia. He is highly spoken of by
            the papers.
         </p>
         
         <p>An entertainment of a novel character has been produced
            at the Melodeon, illustrating the evils resulting from capital punishment. The papers speak very highly of the performance of the company, Miss Orville, Mr. Cunningham, &amp;c., &amp;c., but they could not
            save the piece.
         </p>
         
         <p>Niblo’s Gardens will soon open with a good English company, under the able direction of Mr. Chippendale. The entertainments will, we believe, consist of sterling farces, and light musical
            pieces. Miss Taylor is engaged there, with other efficient and popular talent.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Seguins, with Mr. Frazer, commence an engagement
            at the Park Theatre, early in the ensuing month.
         </p>
         
         <p>The last Concert of the New York Philharmonic Society
            takes place this evening, Saturday the 19th inst.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">255</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">F. RILEY &amp; CO., </div>
            <p>No. 297 Broadway, (between
               Reade and Duane streets,) New York, Publishers of Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition to their
               own catalogue, (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep on hand
               the publications of all the principal Music houses. They are erecting a large
               Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes of a superior quality,
               will be constantly kept on hand.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES,</div>
            
            <p>THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their
               numerous friends, and to the public, would, at the same time, call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, in
               elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of the
               business, have been enabled to add several important improvements to the
               action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNHAM.
               
               <br></br>361 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>Manufactory 13th St., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
            </div>
            
            <p>N. B.—A good second-hand Piano Forte for sale.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
               Street, N. Y.
            </p>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as iron frames,
               &amp;c., with a compass of 6 1/2 and 7 octave-. They are made from choice materials and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of
               23 years experience in the business.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER,
               
               <br></br>88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.
               
               <br></br>A large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
               
               <br></br>TERMS MODERATE.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, late Practical partner of
               the old established firm of 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the larest approved Grand Action P'iano Fortes, of the most superior
               quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone,
               Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano
               Fortes aways on hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
               work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method
               the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies, are
               given in such progressive order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
               carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
               otherwise, are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
               has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,
               and it is only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will be en
               abled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good musi
               cians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the rudments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each lesson
               is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest reccommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of Bertini’s Method
               over ail others yet published in this country, most of them having used the
               foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
               names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">
               <br></br>BOSTON.		 NEW YORK.	
               
               <br></br>Messrs. G. J. Webb	 Messrs. H. C. Timm.	
               
               <br></br>J. G. Maedar		 W. Alpers.	
               
               <br></br>H. T. Hach		 U. C. Hill.	
               
               <br></br>E. L. White		 F. H. Brown.
               
               <br></br>David Paine		 PHILADELPHIA.	
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek			 B. C. Cross.
               
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.		Joseph Duggan.	
               
               <br></br>ALBANY—O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
               American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MITCHELL'S OLYMPIC THEATRE.</div>
            
            <p>PERFORMANCES EVERY EVENING. DOORS  
               open st Seven; Curtain rises at half-past Seven.
            </p>
            
            <p>Dress Circle, 50 Cents. Upper Boxes, 25 cents. Pit, 12 1-2 cents. Private
               Boxes, $3. Box Office open every day.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE
               SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published Monthly at Richmond, Va.; price Five Dollars per Year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835
               A has a large subscription list among the élite of the Southern Aristocracy,
               and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, st the office of the “Broadway Journal," 153 Broadway.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JOHN DOUGLAS,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
               
               <br></br>No. 68 ANN STREET.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">PRICE REDUCED TO $2.50.</div>
            
            <div class="head">THE WAVERLEY NOVELS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Complete, 3340 pages for two dollars and a half.</div>
            
            <p>CAREY &amp; HART will publish this day, volume 1,—
               Price 50 cents, of the Waverley Novels, with all the author’s latest notes
               and additions, complete, without the slightest abridgment.
            </p>
            
            <p>Volume one contains—Waveiley, Rob Roy, Guy Mannering, Black
               Dwarf, Antiquary, Old Mortality, or less than ten cents for each novel.
            </p>
            
            <p>The whole of the Waverley Novels to be completed in five royal 8vo. volumes, upwards of 650 pages in each volume, for Two Dollars and a half.</p>
            
            <p>The publishers wish to be distinctly understood, that while the price is so
               greatly reduced, the work is in no way abridged, but is carefully printed
               from, and contains every word in the last Edinburgh edition, in forty-eight
               volumes.
            </p>
            
            <p>A volume containing at least five novels will be published every month,
               and as the work is stereotyped, no delay can possibly occur.
            </p>
            
            <p>The trade will please forward their orders without delay.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">CAREY &amp; HART, Philadelphia.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">NEW WORKS,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">RECEIVED BY RECENT ARRIVALS FROM LONDON.</div>
            
            <p>MAXIMILIAN’S TRAVELS IN THE UNITED
               STATES in the Years 1832—3—4. In two volumes. One in 4to. containing the English letter-press and numerous fine Cuts; the other, in imperial folio, consisting of Eighty exquisite Engravings, colored in imitation of
               Drawings, and both volumes bound in Morocco. It is the cheapest and most
               beautiful new work ever imported. But few copies remain unsold of the
               English edition. Price much less than the foreign edition, which, although
               not so well colored, sells for 800 francs in parts.
            </p>
            
            <p>2, THE CLANS OF SCOTLAND, Part Eleven, and full sets of
               the same as far as published, each part containing three finely colored plates,
               Portraits of the Clans. 4to. $3 50.
            </p>
            
            <p>3.	THE BEAUTY OF THE HEAVENS, small 4to. cloth. By
               Charles F. Blunt. Containing 104 highly colored illustrations of the Heavens. One copy only received, price $7 50.
            </p>
            
            <p>4. SUMMERLY’S FAIRY TALES, small 4to. with fine illustrations, consisting of the traditional Fairy Tales of Little Red Riding Hood,
               Beauty and the Beast, and Jack and the Bean Stalk.
            </p>
            
            <p>5.	THE NURSERY SUNDAY BOOK, intended to be read to
               young Children. By a Lady. With pretty colored plates, small 4to.
            </p>
            
            <p>HERALDRY—The Arms and Crests of Individuals of all nations,
               furnished from authentic sources, and splendidly emblazoned. Genealogies
               or Pedigrees arranged and illuminated on reasonable terms. Specimens to
               be seen in the store, where orders are received.
            </p> 
            
            <div class="ab">April 18, 1845.	WM. A. COLMAN, 203 Broadway.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">THIS DAY IS PUBLISHED,
               No. IV. of
               WILEY &amp; PUTNAM’S
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING,</div>
            
            <p>CONTAINING “IMAGINATION AND FANCY.”
               By Leigh Hunt. One thick volume, 12mo. beautifully printed, in Urge
               clear type, on fine paper. 50 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>“There is no one who has more thoroughly brought out the sentiment of
               ancient stories; we do not know a translator more thoroughly imbued with
               the old classic spirit; there is no one who has made more happy or continuous advances to the highest aims of poetry, or with whom the study and pursuit have been of a more genuine passion.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The volume is most justly to be called a 'feast of nectared sweets, where
               no crude surfeit reigns.’”—London Examiner.
            </p>
            
            <p>“This is a delicious volume—a very bookfull of honey—it consists of extracts—most exquisite ‘bits’—from the British Poets, linked together in so
               rare a style, that the setting is almost as valuable as the gems."
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">London Art Union.</div>
            
            <p>“Gray’s ideal of earthly happiness was to lie on a sofa and read perpetually new novels by Marivaux. For these substitute an endless series of
               works like the present, and it would not be easy to imagine a more delightful
               course of reading. A more useful book for forming the taste it would be impossible to conceive. We should always think better of the house where we
               saw a well read copy of it lying about. It is a book equally fitted for the fireside and drawing-room table—a book to enjoy one’s self, and to talk of to
               others, and to conjure up trains of pleasant thoughts and recollections with.—
               Tait’s Magazine.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Published and for sale by
               
               <br></br>WILEY &amp; PUTNAM; 161 Broadway.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
               The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A.G. Bigelow’s
               professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo.     Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
               
               <br></br>Joshua Herrick, Me.              John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               
               <br></br>James Irvin, Pa.                 J. Thompson, Miss.
               
               <br></br>Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">VANDENHOFF’S ELOCUTION.</div>
            
            <p>A PLAIN SYSTEM OF ELOCUTION: OR, LOGIcal and Musical Reading and Declamation, with Exercises in Prose and
               Verse, distinctly marked for the guidance of the Ear and Voice of the Pupil:
               o which is added, AN APPENDIX, containing a copious Practice in Oratorical, Poetical, and Dramatic Reading and Recitation: the whole forming a
               Complete Speaker, well adapted to private pupils, classes, and the use of
               schools; by G. Vandenhoff, Professor of Elocution in the City of New
               York. Second Edition.	Published by C. SHEPARD,
               191 Broadway, opposite John st.
            </p>
            
            <p>From the Rev. R. T. Huddart, (Classical Academy, Houston street.)
               It affords me much pleasure to add my testimony to the value, importance,
               and advantage of Mr. George Vandenhoff’s Work on Elocution. He has
               aptly styled it “a plain System such it truly is to those who will pursue
               the instruction given, step by step; and cannot fail of producing a beneficial
               and much wished for result in one of the departments of education so sadly
               neglected—correct reading—devoid of vulgarities, and errors in articulation
               and pronunciation. I hope the book will have a wide circulation, in order
               that the good which it is capable of effecting may be thus more extensively
               diffused, and a better system of instruction be afforded to the rising generation, in that which constitutes a most agreeable accomplishment in every
               gentleman’s education, namely, “Logical and Musical Declamation.”
               (Signed)	R. Townsend Huddart.
               New York, March 14, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>From Mrs. Lawrence, (Academy, Stuyvesant Place.)
               I have great pleasure in stating, that Mr. G. Vandenhofl’s work on Elocution has been used with so much success in my school, that I can safely recommend it to all, who may desire improvement in that elegant branch of
               education; as the most simple, clear and concise treatise on the subject; and
               well adapted to the comprehension of any mind.
               (signed)	Julia Lawrence.
               March 8th, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>From Jacob Le Roy, Esq., (Lafayette Place.)
               Mr. Vandenhoff's Treatise on Elocution has been used by a Class of Ladies at my house, and has been found in every way adapted to produce its
               intended effect.	(Signed)	Jacob Le Roy.
               24th March, 1845.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISBROW’S RIDING SCHOOL,</div>
            
            <p>NO. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette
               Places. New York.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Evening, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS:
               
               <br></br>Lecture Lessons.  Exercise Riding.
               
               <br></br>16 Lessons. . . . . . . . . . $15	00	1	Month. . . . . . . . . .$12 00
               
               <br></br>10	 “ 	   . . . . . . . . . . 10	00  20	Rides. . . . . . . . . . 10 	00
               
               <br></br>4	 “	     . . . . . . . . . . 5	00 10	 “	   . . . . . . . . . . 6	 00
               
               <br></br>Single Lessons . . . . . . . .2 00  Single Rides. . . . . . . . .0 75
               
               <br></br>Road   “	       . . . . . . . 2 50 |
               
               <br></br>N. B.—Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let.
               
               <br></br>Evening Class.
               
               <br></br>12 Lessons................$9 00 | 20 Rides.............$10 00
               
               <br></br>Single “ .................1 00 | Single Ride........... 0 75
            </div>
            RULES:
            
            <p>1.	All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.</p>
            
            <p>2.	One hour allow ed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.</p>
            
            <p>3.	One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.</p>
            
            <p>4.	Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 3 P. M.</p>
            
            <p>5.	Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.</p>
            
            <p>6.	No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladies.</p>
            
            <p>A card of address is requested previous to commencing.</p>
            
            <p>N. B. Gentlemen keeping their horses at this establishment, will have the
               privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            </p>
         </div> 
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The first Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for the
               
               <br></br>best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
               
               <br></br>GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
               
               <br></br>NO. 589 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            </div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms Reduced to TWO DOLLARS
               AND A HALF.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen
               and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale “Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27. 1844.
               Goldsmith’s Gems or Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
               much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
               Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
               volume before us exhibit, more taste and ingenuity, and higher proof,
               of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
            </p>
            
            <p>From the New York Express.
               Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship—We have seen the original, as
               executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
               wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
               to be “more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div> 
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.</div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      <a href="#a001"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n001">* θζενες</div>
      
      <a href="#a002"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n002">* Ils ecrivaient sur la Philosophie, (Cicero, Lucretius, Seneca) mais c’etait la Philosophie
         Grecque. — Condorcet.
      </div>
      
      <a href="#a003"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n003">* Quere—Arouet?</div>
      
   </div>
</div>