<div>
   <div class="front">
         <div>
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         <div class="ab">VOL. 2.NEW YORK,SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 13, 1985.
           NO 10.</div>
         <div class="ab">Three Dollars Per Annum.    Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.</div>
           <div class="ab">Edited by EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.</div>
         <div class="ab">Published at 135 Nassau St. By JOHN BISCO.</div>
      </div>
        </div>
   <div class="body">
      

      <div>
        <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/>
        <div>
            <div class="head">The Village Street.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>In these rapid, restless shadows,
            <br/>Once I walked at eventide,
            <br/>When a gentle, silent maiden,
            <br/>Walked in beauty at my side.
            <br/>She alone there walked beside me
            <br/>All in beauty, like a bride.
            <br/>Pallidly the moon was shining
            <br/>On the dewy meadows nigh ;
            <br/>On the silvery, silent rivers,
            <br/>On the mountains far and high,—
            <br/>On the ocean’s star-lit waters,
            <br/>Where the winds a-weary die.
            <br/>Slowly, silently we wandered
            <br/>From the open cottage door,
            <br/>Underneath the elm’s long branches
            <br/>To the pavement bending o’er;
            <br/>Underneath the mossy willow
            <br/>And the dying sycamore.
            <br/>With the myriad stars in beauty
            <br/>All bedight, the heavens were seen
            <br/>Radiant hopes were bright around me,
            <br/>Like the light of stars serene ;
            <br/>Like the mellow midnight splendor
            <br/>Of the Night’s irradiate queen.
            <br/>Audibly the elm leaves whispered
            <br/>Peaceful, pleasant melodies,
            <br/>Like the distant murmured music
            <br/>Of unquiet, lovely seas ;
            <br/>While the winds were hushed in slumber
            <br/>In the fragrant flowers and trees.
            <br/>Wondrous and unwonted beauty
            <br/>Still adorning all did seem,
            <br/>While I told my love in fables
            <br/>’Neath the willows by the stream;
            <br/>Would the heart had kept unspoken
            <br/>Love that was its rarest dream !
            <br/>Instantly away we wandered
            <br/>In the shadowy twilight tide,
            <br/>She, the silent, scornful maiden,
            <br/>Walking calmly at my side,
            <br/>With a step serene and stately,
            <br/>All in beauty, all in pride.
            <br/>Vacantly I walked beside her,
            <br/>On the earth mine eyes were cast;
            <br/>Swift and keen there came unto me
            <br/>Bitter memories of the past—
            <br/>On me," like the rain in Autumn
            <br/>On the dead leaves, cold and fast.
            <br/>Underneath the elms we parted,]
            <br/>By the lowly^cottage door;
            <br/>One brief word alone was uttere —
            <br/>Never on our lips before;
            <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>And away I walked forlornly,
            <br/>Broken-hearted evermore.
            <br/>Slowly, silently I loitered,
            <br/>Homeward, in the night, alone;
            <br/>Sudden anguish bound my spirit,
            <br/>That my youth had never known ;
            <br/>Wild unrest, like that which cometh
            <br/>When the Night’s first dream hath flown.
            <br/>Now, to me the elm-leaves whisper
            <br/>Mad, discordant melodies,
            <br/>And keen memories like shadows
            <br/>Haunt the moaning willow trees,
            <br/>And the sycamores with laughter
            <br/>Mock me in the nightly breeze.
            <br/>Sad and pale the Autumn moonlight
            <br/>Through the sighing foliage streams;
            <br/>And each morning, midnight shadow,
            <br/>Shadow of my sorrow seems ;
            <br/>Strive, O heart, forget thine idol!
            <br/>And, O soul, forget thy dreams !
          </div>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">A. M. IDE.</span>
            </div>
        </div>



        <div>
            <div class="head">Diddling Considered as one of the Exact Sciences.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Hey, diddle diddle,
            <br/>The cat and the fiddle.
          </div>
            <p>Since the world began there have been two Jeremys. The
            <br/>one wrote a Jeremiad about
            usury, and was called Jeremy <br/>Bentham. He has been much admired by Mr. John Neal,
            <br/>and was a great man in a small way. The other gave name <br/>to the most important
            of the Exact Sciences, and was a great <br/>man in a great way—I may say, indeed, in the
            very greatest <br/>of ways.</p>
            <p>Diddling—or the abstract idea conveyed by the verb to <br/>diddle—is sufficiently well
            understood. Yet the fact, the <br/>deed, the thing diddling, is somewhat difficult to
            define. <br/>We may get, however, at a tolerably distinct conception of <br/>the matter
            in hand, by defining—not the thing, diddling, in <br/>itself—but man, as an animal that
            diddles. Had Plato but <br/>hit upon this, he would have been spared the affront of the
            <br/>picked chicken.</p>
            <p>Very pertinently it was demanded of Plato, why a picked <br/>chicken, which was clearly
            a “biped without feathers,” was <br/>not, according to his own definition, a man? But I
            am not. <br/>to be bothered by any similar query. Man is an animal that <br/>diddles,
            and there is no animal that diddles but man. It will <br/>take an entire hen-coop of
            picked chickens to get over that.</p>
            <p>What constitutes the essence, the nare, the principle of <br/>diddling is, in fact,
            peculiar to the class of creatures that wear <br/>coats and pantaloons. A crow theives;
            a fox cheats; a <br/>weasel outwits; a man diddles. To diddle is his destiny, <br/>“Man
            was made to mourn,” says the poet. But not so :— <br/>he was made to diddle. This is his
            aim—his ob ect—his end<div class="pagebreak" id="#page146"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>And for this reason when a man’s diddled we say he’s <br/>“ done.”</p>
            <p>Diddling, rightly considered, is a compound, of which the <br/>ingredients are
            minuteness, interest, perseverance, ingenuity, <br/>audacity, nonchalance, originality,
            impertinence, and grin.</p>
            <p>Minuteness:—Your diddler is minute. His operations are <br/>upon a small scale. His
            business is retail, for cash, or ap- <br/>proved paper at sight. Should he
            ever be tempted into mag- <br/>nificent speculation, he then, at once, loses
            his distinctive fea- <br/>tures, and becomes what we term “ financier.” This
            latter <br/>word conveys the diddling idea in every respect except that <br/>of
            magnitude. A diddler may thus be regarded as a banker <br/>in petto—a “ financial
            operation,” as a diddle at Brobdignag. <br/>The one is to the other, as Homer to “
            Flaccus”—as a Mas- <br/>todon to a mouse—as the tail of a comet to that of a
            pig.</p>
            <p>Interest:—Your diddler is guided by self-interest. He <br/>scorns to diddle for the
            mere sake of the diddle. He has an <br/>object in view—his pocket—and yours. He regards
            always <br/>the main chance. He looks to Number One. You are <br/>Number Two, and must
            look to yourself.</p>
            <p>Perseverance:—Your diddler perseveres. He is not read- <br/>ily discouraged.
            Should even the banks break, he cares <br/>nothing about it. He steadily pursues his
            end, and <div class="lg">
                  <br/>Ut canis a corio nunquam absterrebitur uncto,
            </div>
               <br/>so he never lets go of his game.</p>
            <p>Ingenuity:—Your diddler is ingenious. He has construct- <br/>iveness large.
            He understands plot. He invents and circum- <br/>vents. Were he not Alexander
            he would be Diogenes. <br/>Were he not a diddler, he would be a maker of patent rat- <br/>traps or an angler for trout.</p>
            <p>Audacity:—Your diddler is audacious.—He is a bold man. <br/>He carries the war into
            Africa. He conquers all by assault. <br/>He would not tear the daggers of the Frey
            Herren. With a <br/>little more prudence Dick Turpin would have made a good
            <br/>diddler; with a trifle less blarney, Daniel O’Connell; with a <br/>pound or two
            more brains, Charles the Twelfth.</p>
            <p>Nonchalance:—Your diddler is nonchalant. He is not at <br/>all nervous. He never had
            any nerves. He is never seduc- <br/>ed into a flurry. He is never put
            out—unless put out of <br/>doors. He is cool—cool as a cucumber. He is calm— <br/>“calm
            as a smile from Lady Bury.” He is easy—easy as <br/>an old glove, or the damsels of
            ancient Baiæ.</p>
            <p>Originality:—Your diddler is original—conscientiously so. <br/>His thoughts are his
            own. He would scorn to employ those <br/>of another. A stale trick is his aversion. He
            would return <br/>a purse, I am sure, upon discovering that he had obtained it <br/>by
            an unoriginal diddle.</p>
            <p>Impertinence:—Your diddler is impertinent. He swag- <br/>gers. He sets his
            arms a-kimbo. He thrusts his hands in <br/>his trowsers' pockets. He sneers in your
            face. He treads on <br/>your corns. He eats your dinner, he drinks your wine, he
            <br/>borrows your money, he pulls your nose, he kicks your <br/>poodle, and he kisses
            your wife.</p>
            <p>Grin :—Your true diddler winds up all with a grin. But <br/>this nobody sees but
            himself. He grins when his daily work <br/>is done—wken his allotted labors are
            accomplished—at night <br/>in his own closet, and altogether for his own private enter-
              <br/>tainment. He goes home. He locks his door. He divests <br/>himself of
            his clothes. He puts out his candle. He gets in- <br/>to bed. He places his
            head upon the pillow. All this done, <br/>and your diddler grins. This is no hypothesis.
            It is a mat- <br/>ter of course. I reason à priori, and a diddle would be no
            <br/>diddle without a grin.</p>
            <p>The origin of the diddle is referrible to the infancy of the <br/>Human Race. Perhaps
            the first diddler was Adam. At<br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>all events, we can trace the science back to a very remote <br/>period of
            antiquity. The moderns, however, have brought it <br/> to a perfection never dreamed of
            by our thick-headed proge- <br/>nitors. Without pausing to speak of the “ old
            saws,” there- <br/>fore, I shall content myself with a compendious account of
            <br/>some of the more “ modern instances.”</p>
            <p>A very good diddle is this. A housekeeper in want of a <br/>sofa, for instance, is seen
            to go in and out of several cabinet <br/> warehouses. At length she arrives at one
            offering an excel- <br/> lent variety. She is accosted, and invited to enter,
            by a po- <br/>lite and voluble individual at the door. She finds a sofa well
            <br/>adapted to her views, and, upon inquiring the price, is sur- <br/>prised
            and delighted to hear a sum named at least twenty <br/>per cent, lower than her
            expectations. She hastens to make <br/>the purchase, gets a bill and receipt, leaves her
            address, <br/>with a request that the article be sent home as speedily as <br/>possible,
            and retires amid a profusion of bows from the shop- <br/>keeper. The night
            arrives and no sofa. The next day pas- <br/>ses, and still none. A servant is
            sent to make inquiry <br/>about the delay. The whole transaction is denied. No so- <br/> fa has been sold—no money received—except by the diddler <br/> who played
            shop-keeper for the nonce.</p>
            <p>Our cabinet warehouses are left entirely unattended, and <br/>thus afford every
            facility for a trick of this kind. Visiters <br/>enter, look at furniture, and depart
            unheeded and unseen. <br/>Should any one wish to purchase, or to inquire the price of
            <br/>an article, a bell is at hand, and this is considered amply suf- <br/>ficient.</p>
            <p>Again, quite a respectable diddle is this. A well-dressed <br/>individual enters a shop
            ; makes a purchase to the value of <br/>a dollar ; finds, much to his vexation, that he
            has left his <br/>pocket-book in another coat pocket: and so says to the
            <br/>shop-keeper—</p>
            <p>“ My dear sir, never mind !—just oblige me, will you, by <br/>sending the bundle home ?
            But stay ! I really believe that <br/>I have nothing less than a five dollar bill, even
            there. How- <br/>ever, you can send four dollars in change with the bundle,
            <br/>you know.”</p>
            <p>“Very good, sir,” replies the shop-keeper, who entertains, <br/>at once, a lofty
            opinion of the high-mindedness of his custo- <br/>mer. “ I know fellows, he
            says to himself, “ who would <br/>just have put the goods under their arm, and walked
            off <br/>with a promise to call and pay the dollar as they came by <br/>in the
            afternoon.”</p>
            <p>A boy is sent with the parcel and change. On the route, <br/>quite accidentally, he is
            met by the purchaser, who exclaims:</p>
            <p>“ Ah ! this is my bundle, I see—I thought you had been <br/>home with it, long ago.
            Well, go on! My wife, Mrs. <br/>Trotter, will give you the five dollars—I left
            instructions <br/>with her to that effect. The change you might as well give <br/>to
            me—I shall want some silver for the Post Office. Very <br/>good! One, two,—is this a
            good quarter?—three, four— <br/>quite right! Say to Mrs. Trotter that you met me, and be
            <br/>sure now and do not loiter on the way.”</p>
            <p>The boy does n’t loiter at all—but he is a very long time <br/>in getting back from his
            errand—for no lady of the precise <br/>name of Mrs. Trotter is to be discovered. He
            consoles him- <br/>self, however, that he has not been such a fool as to
            leave <br/>the goods without the money, and re-entering his shop with <br/>a self
            satisfied air, feels sensibly hurt and indignant when his <br/>master asks him what has
            become of the change.</p>
            <p>A very simple diddle, indeed, is this. The captain of a <br/>ship which is about to
            sail, is presented by an official look- <br/>ing person, with an unusually
            moderate bill of city charges. <br/>Glad to get off so easily, and confused by a hundred
              duties<div class="pagebreak" id="#page174"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
            </p>
            <p>pressing upon him all at once, he discharges the claim forth- <br/>with. In
            about fifteen minutes, another and less reasona- <br/>ble bill is handed him
            by one who soon makes it evident <br/>that the first collector was a diddler, and the
            original collec- <br/>tion a diddle.</p>
            <p>And here, too, is a somewhat similar thing. A steamboat <br/>is casting loose from the
            wharf. A traveller, portmanteau <br/>in hand, is discovered running towards the wharf at
            full <br/>speed. Suddenly, he makes a dead halt, stoops, and picks <br/>up something
            from the ground in a very agitated manner. <br/>It is a pocket book, and—“ Has any
            gentleman lost a pock- <br/>et book ?” he cries. No one can say that he has
            exactly <br/>lost a pocket-book; but a great excitement ensues, when <br/>the treasure
            trove is found to be of value. The boat how- <br/>ever, must not be
            detained.</p>
            <p>“ Time and tide wait for no man,” says the captain.</p>
            <p>“ For God’s sake, stay only a few minutes,” says the fin- <br/>der of the
            book—“ the true claimant will presently appear.”</p>
            <p>“ Can’t wait!” replies the man in authority; “ cast off <br/>there, d’ye hear ?”</p>
            <p>“ What am I to do?” asks the finder, in great tribulation. <br/>“ I am about to leave
            the country for some years, and I can- <br/>not conscientiously retain this
            large amount in my possession. <br/>I beg your pardon, sir,” [here he addresses a
            gentleman on <br/>shore,] “ but you have the air of an honest man. Will you <br/>confer
            upon me the favor of taking charge of this pocket- <br/>book—I know I can
            trust you—and of advertising it? The <br/>notes, you see, amount to a very considerable
            sum. The <br/>owner will, no doubt, insist upon rewarding you for your
            <br/>trouble—”</p>
            <p>“ Me !—no, you !—it was you who found the book.”</p>
            <p>“Well, if you must have it so—I will take a small re- <br/>ward—just to
            satisfy your scruples. Let me see—why these <br/>notes are all hundreds—bless my soul! a
            hundred is too <br/>much to take—fifty would be quite enough, I am sure—”</p>
            <p>“ Cast off there !” says the captain.</p>
            <p>“ But then I have no change for a hundred, and upon the <br/>whole, you had
            better”—</p>
            <p>“ Cast off there !” says the captain.</p>
            <p>“ Never mind !” cries the gentleman on shore, who has <br/>been examining his own
            pocket-book for the last minute or <br/>so—“ never mind ! I can fix it—here is a fifty
            on the Bank <br/>of North America—throw me the book.”</p>
            <p>And the over-conscientious finder takes the fifty with mark- <br/>ed
            reluctance, and throws the gentleman the book, as desired, <br/>while the steamboat
            fumes and fizzes on her way. In about <br/>half an hour after her departure, the “large
            amount" is seen <br/>to be “ a counterfeit presentment,” and the whole thing a
            <br/>capital diddle.</p>
            <p>A bold diddle is this. A camp-meeting, or something <br/>similar, is to be held at a
            certain spot which is accessible <br/>only by means of a free bridge. A diddler stations
            himself <br/>upon this bridge, respectfully informs all passers by of the <br/>new
            county law, which establishes a toll of one cent for foot <br/>passengers, two for
            horses and donkeys, and so forth, and <br/>so forth. Some grumble but all submit, and
            the diddler goes <br/>home a wealthier man by some fifty or sixty dollars well
            <br/>earned. This taking a toll from a great crowd of people is <br/>an excessively
            troublesome thing.</p>
            <p>A neat diddle is this. A friend holds one of the diddler’s <br/>promises to pay, filled
            up and signed in due form, upon the <br/>ordinary blanks printed in red ink. The diddler
            purchases <br/>one or two dozen of these blanks, and every day dips one of <br/>them in
            his soup, makes his dog jump for it, and finally <br/>gives it to him as a bonne bouche.
            The note arriving at ma-<br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>turity, the diddler, with the diddler’s dog, calls upon the <br/>friend, and the
            promise to pay is made the topic of discus- <br/>sion. The friend produces it
            from his escritoire, and is <br/>in the act of reaching it to the diddler, when up jumps
            the <br/>diddler’s dog and devours it forthwith. The diddler is not <br/>only surprised
            but vexed and incensed at the absurd beha- <br/>vior of his dog, and
            expresses his entire readiness to cancel <br/>the obligation at any moment when the
            evidence of the obli- <br/>gation shall be forthcoming.</p>
            <p>A very minute diddle is this. A lady is insulted in the <br/>street by a diddler’s
            accomplice. The diddler himself flies <br/>to her assistance, and, giving his friend a
            comfortable thrash- <br/>ing, insists upon attending the lady to her own
            door. He <br/>bows, with his hand upon his heart, and most respectfully <br/>bids her
            adieu. She entreats him, as her deliverer, to walk <br/>in and be introduced to her big
            brother and her papa. With <br/>a sigh, he declines to do so. “ Is there no way, then,
            sir,” <br/>she murmurs, “ in which I may be permitted to testify my <br/>gratitude
            ?”</p>
            <p>“Why, yes, madam, there is. Will you be kind enough <br/>to lend me a couple of
            shillings ?”</p>
            <p>In the first excitement of the moment the lady decides up- <br/>on fainting
            outright. Upon second thought, however, she <br/>opens her purse-strings and delivers
            the specie. Now this, <br/>I say, is a diddle minute—for one entire moiety of the sum
            <br/>borrowed has to be paid to the gentleman who had the trou- <br/>ble of
            performing the insult, and who had then to stand still <br/>and be thrashed for
            performing it.</p>
            <p>Rather a small, but still a scientific diddle is this. The <br/>diddler approaches the
            bar of a tavern, and demands a cou- <br/>ple of twists of tobacco. These are
            handed to him, when, <br/>having slightly examined them, he says :</p>
            <p>“ I don’t much like this tobacco. Here, take it back, and <br/>give me a glass of
            brandy and water in its place.”</p>
            <p>The brandy and water is furnished and imbibed, and the <br/>diddler makes his way to
            the door. But the voice of the <br/>tavern-keeper arrests him.</p>
            <p>“ I believe, sir, you have forgotten to pay for your brandy <br/>and water.”</p>
            <p>“Pay for my brandy and water !—didn’t I give you the <br/>tobacco for the brandy and
            water ? What more would you <br/>have ?”</p>
            <p>“ But sir, if you please, I do n’t remember that you paid <br/>for the tobacco.”</p>
            <p>“What do you mean by that, you scoundrel?—Didn’t I <br/>give you back your tobacco ? Is
            n’t that your tobacco lying <br/>there? Do you expect me to pay for what I did not
            take?”</p>
            <p>“ But, sir,” says the publican, now rather at a loss what to <br/>say, “but, sir—”</p>
            <p>“ But me no buts, sir,” interrupts the diddler, apparently <br/>in very high dudgeon,
            and slamming the door after him, as <br/>he makes his escape.—“ But me no buts, sir, and
            none of your <br/>tricks upon travellers.”</p>
            <p>Here again is a very clever diddle, of which the simplicity <br/>is not its least
            recommendation. A purse, or pocket-book, <br/>being really lost, the loser inserts in
            one of the daily papers <br/>of a large city a fully descriptive advertisement.</p>
            <p>Whereupon our diddler copies the facts of this advertise- <br/>ment, with a
            change of heading, of general phraseology, and <br/>address. The original, for instance,
            is long, and verbose, is <br/>headed “ A Pocket-Book Lost!” and requires the treasure,
            <br/>when found, to be left at No. 1 Tom street. The copy is <br/>brief, and being
            headed with “ Lost” only, indicates No. 2 <br/>Dick, or No. 3 Harry street, as the
            locality at which the <br/>owner may be seen. Moreover, it is inserted in at least<div class="pagebreak" id="#page148"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>five or six of the daily papers of the day, while in point of <br/>time, it makes
            it appearance only a few hours after the orig- <br/>inal. Should it be read
            by the loser of the purse, he would <br/>hardly suspect it to have any reference to his
            own misfortune. <br/>But, of course, the chances are five or six to one, that the
            <br/>finder will repair to the address given by the diddler, rather <br/>than to that
            pointed out by the rightful proprietor. The for- <br/>mer pays the reward,
            pockets the treasure and decamps.</p>
            <p>Quite an analogous diddle is this. A lady of ton has drop- <br/>ped,
            somewhere in the street, a diamond ring of very unusu- <br/>al value. For its
            recovery, she offers some forty or fifty dol- <br/>lars reward—giving, in her
            advertisement, a very minute des- <br/>cription of the gem, and of its
            settings, and declaring that, <br/>upon its restoration to No. so and so, in such and
            such Ave- <br/>nue, the reward will be paid instanter, without a single
            <br/>question being asked. During the lady’s absence from home, <br/>a day or two
            afterwards, a ring is heard at the door of No. <br/>so and so, in such and such Avenue;
            a servant appears; the <br/>lady of the house is asked for and is declared to be out, at
            <br/>which astounding information, the visitor expresses the most <br/>poignant regret.
            His business is of importance and concerns <br/>the lady herself. In fact, he had the
            good fortune to find her <br/>diamond ring. But, perhaps it would be as well that he
            <br/>should call again. “ By no means!” says the servant; and <br/>“ By no means !’’
            says the lady’s sister and the lady’s sister- <br/>in-law, who are summoned
            forthwith. The ring is clamo- <br/>rously identified, the reward is paid, and
            the finder nearly <br/>thrust out of doors. The lady returns, and expresses some
            <br/>little dissatisfaction with her sister and sister-in-law, because <br/>they happen
            to have paid forty or fifty dollars for a facsimile <br/>of her diamond ring—a facsimile
            made out of real pinchbeck <br/>and unquestionable paste.</p>
            <p>But as there is really no end to diddling, so there would be <br/>none to this essay,
            were I even to hint at half the variations, <br/>or inflections, of which this science
            is susceptible. I must <br/>bring this paper, perforce, to a conclusion, and this I
            cannot <br/>do better than by a summary notice of a very decent, but <br/>rather
            elaborate diddle, of which our own city was made the <br/>theatre, not very long ago,
            and which was subsequently re- <br/>peated with success, in other still more
            verdant localities of <br/>the Union. A middle-aged gentleman arrives in town from
            <br/>parts unknown. He is remarkably precise, cautious, staid, <br/>and deliberate in
            his demeanor. His dress is scrupulously <br/>neat, but plain, unostentatious. He wears a
            white cravat, <br/>an ample waistcoat, made with an eye to comfort alone;
            <br/>thick-soled cosy-looking shoes, and pantaloons without <br/>straps. He has the
            whole air, in fact, of your well-to-do, <br/>sober-sided, exact, and respectable “ man
            of business,” par <br/>excellence—one of the stern and outwardly hard, internally
            <br/>soft, sort of people that we see in the crack high comedies— <br/>fellows whose
            words are so many bonds, and who are noted <br/>for giving away guineas, in charity,
            with the one hand, <br/>while, in the way of mere bargain, they exact the uttermost
            <br/>fraction of a farthing, with the other.</p>
            <p>He makes much ado before he can get suited with a <br/>boarding house. He dislikes
            children. He has been accus- <br/>tomed to quiet. His habits are
            methodical—and then he <br/>would prefer getting into a private and respectable small
            <br/>family, piously inclined. Terms, however, are no object— <br/>only he must insist
            upon settling his bill on the first of every <br/>month, (it is now the second) and begs
            his landlady, when <br/>he finally obtains one to his mind, not on any account, to
            <br/>forget his instructions upon this point—but to send in a bill, <br/>and receipt,
            precisely at ten o’clock, on the first day of every <br/>month, and under no
            circumstances to put it off to the <br/>second.</p>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <p>These arrangements made, our man of business rents an <br/>office in a reputable rather
            than in a fashionable quarter of <br/>the town. There is nothing he more despises than
            pretence. <br/>“ Where there is much show,” he says, “ there is seldom <br/>anything
            very solid behind"—an observation which so pro- <br/>foundly impresses his
            landlady’s fancy, that she makes a <br/>pencil memorandum of it forthwith, in her great
            family Bi- <br/>ble, on the broad margin of the Proverbs of Solomon.</p>
            <p>The next step is to advertise, after some such fashion as <br/>this, in the principal
            business sixpennies of this city—the <br/>pennies are eschewed as not “ respectable”—and
            as demand- <br/>ing payment for all advertisements in advance. Our man of
            <br/>business holds it as a point of his faith that work should <br/>never be paid for
            until done.</p>
            <p>Wanted.—The advertisers, being about to commence ex- <br/>tensive business
            operations in this city, will require the ser- <br/>vices of three or four
            intelligent and competent clerks, to <br/>whom a liberal salary will be paid. The very
            best recom- <br/>mendations, not so much for capacity, as for integrity, will
            <br/>be expected. Indeed, as the duties to he performed, involve <br/>high
            responsibilities, and large amounts of money must <br/>necessarily pass through the
            hands of those engaged, it is <br/>deemed advisable to demand a deposit of fifty dollars
            from <br/>each clerk employed. No person need apply, therefore, who <br/>is not prepared
            to leave this sum in the possession of the <br/>advertisers, and who cannot furnish the
            most satisfactory <br/>testimonials of morality. Young gentlemen piously inclined
            <br/>will be preferred. Application should be made between the <br/>hours of ten and
            eleven, A. M., and four and five, P. M., of <br/>Messrs. Boggs, Hogs, Logs, Frogs, &amp;
            Co.</p>
            <p>No. 110 Dog Street.</p>
            <p>By the thirty-first day of the month, this advertisement <br/>has brought to the office
            of Messrs. Boggs, Hogs, Logs, Frogs <br/>and Company, some fifteen or twenty young
            gentlemen <br/>piously inclined. But our man of business is in no hurry to <br/>conclude
            a contract with any—no man of business is ever <br/>precipitate—and it is not until the
            most rigid catechism in <br/>respect to the piety of each young gentleman’s inclination,
            <br/>that his services are engaged and his fifty dollars receipted <br/>for, just by way
            of proper precaution, on the part of the re- <br/>spectable firm of Boggs,
            Hogs, Logs, Frogs, and Company. <br/>On the morning of the first day of the next month,
            the land- <br/>lady does not present her bill according to promise—a piece
            <br/>of neglect for which the comfortable head of the house end- <br/>ing in
            ogs, would no doubt have chided her severely, could <br/>he have been prevailed upon to
            remain in town a day or two <br/>for that purpose.</p>
            <p>As it is, the constables have had a sad time of it, running <br/>hither and thither,
            and all they can do is to declare the man <br/>of business most emphatically, a " hen
            knee high”—by <br/>which some persons imagine them to imply that, in fact, he <br/>is
            n.e.i.—by which again the very classical phrase non est <br/>inventus, is supposed to be
            understood. In the meantime the <br/>young gentlemen, one and all, are somewhat less
            piously <br/>inclined than before, while the landlady purchases a shilling’s <br/>worth
            of the best Indian rubber, and very carefully obliterates <br/>the pencil memorandum
            that some fool has made in her <br/>great family Bible, on the broad margin of the
            Proverbs of <br/>Solomon.</p>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE.</span>
            </div>
        </div>



        <div>
            <div class="head">TO F-------.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Thou wouldst be loved ?—then let thy heart
            <br/>From its present pathway part not!
            <br/>Being everything which now thou art.
            <br/>Re nothing which thou art not!
          </div>
        </div>

        <div class="pagebreak" id="#page149"/>
        <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/>

        <div>
            <div class="head">Blanche.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Fairest where all is beautiful and bright !
            <br/>M. D. Gallagher.
          </div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Thou of the sunny brow !
            <br/>Thou of the raven hair!
            <br/>Of cheeks where brighter roses grow
            <br/>Than any gardens bear—
            <br/>Thou of the deep jet eye!
            <br/>Of the clear ruby lip,
            <br/>Where untold depths of feeling lie—
            <br/>Sweets choicest are to sip—
            <br/>Thou of the queenly form!
            <br/>The stately step and air,
            <br/>As born to face Life’s coldest storm,
            <br/>With soul to do and dare—
            <br/>Thou of the tender heart!
            <br/>The pure and lofty soul
            <br/>Which grace to thine each grace impart,
            <br/>And crown the beauteous whole—
            <br/>How shall I sing thy praise ?
            <br/>Fairest and best of Earth ?
            <br/>Oh! far the Poet’s loftiest lays
            <br/>Must fail to reach thy worth !
            <br/>As to the Holy One
            <br/>With proffered heart-felt vows,
            <br/>Is he who bendeth blest alone—
            <br/>Not He to whom he bows—
            <br/>So our pure love must be
            <br/>Kindled by thine own rays;
            <br/>It can reflect no worth on thee,
            <br/>But only us who praise.
            <br/>And as, to that great source
            <br/>Which good to all imparts,
            <br/>Our faltering accents most lack force
            <br/>When fullest are our hearts,
            <br/>So we, who best approve
            <br/>Thy loveliness and worth,
            <br/>Still want for words to speak the love
            <br/>That in our hearts hath birth.
            <br/>Not for that thou art fair
            <br/>And beautiful alone,
            <br/>Though every bright endowment rare
            <br/>Of Beauty is thine own—
            <br/>Not for thy lofty brow—
            <br/>Thine eye of sparkling jet—
            <br/>Thy ruby lips—tby cheek’s bright glow—
            <br/>Thy raven hair—nor yet
            <br/>For thy commanding form—
            <br/>Thy queenly step and air—
            <br/>Nor for thy face, though beauties swarm
            <br/>In rich profusion there—
            <br/>Oh ! not for one, or each
            <br/>Of these bright gifts—thine all—
            <br/>Thou livest ever in our speech—
            <br/>Our blessings on thee fall,—
            <br/>But for thine timer self—
            <br/>The graces deeper set
            <br/>The wealth more worth than glittering pelf’
            <br/>Gem, crown, or coronet.
            <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>For the ennobled mind
            <br/>With generous feelings fraught,
            <br/>Rich gifts of intellect, combined
            <br/>With pure and tender thought—
            <br/>The gentle heart, imbued
            <br/>With charity for all—
            <br/>The lofty soul—high, yet subdued
            <br/>To pity’s softest call.
            <br/>The love for all are near—
            <br/>The self-forgetfulness—
            <br/>These are the trraits that make thee dear
            <br/>For these, thyself we bless.
            <br/>For these, till life departs,
            <br/>Through weal and woe the same.
            <br/>Of Earth’s the deepest on our hearts
            <br/>Graven shall be thy name.
          </div>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">L. J. CIST.</span>
            </div>
        </div>



        <div>
            <div class="head">The Magnetizer; or, Ready for Any Body.</div>
            <p>BY THE AUTHOR OF “ THE VISION OF RUBETA.”</p>
          ACT. II.
          <p>Scene First.— The drawingroom at in Act 1, Scene 1. Enter <br/>Catharine, followed by
            Dulruse.</p>
            <p>Cath. You carry your presumption, sir, rather too far for a gen- <br/>tleman. Or, are
            you so dull you cannot take a hint?</p>
            <p>Dulr. So devoted that I will not take it. You have left the <br/>other room, Miss
            Clairvoir, to avoid me ; and I have followed, be- <br/>cause I will not be
            avoided.</p>
            <p>Cath. Sir! sir!</p>
            <p>Dulr. I say so, Miss Catharine. Love is not so easily repuls- <br/>ed.</p>
            <p>Cath. This is too insolent! Leave me, sir, this instant: and, for <br/>your odious
            pretensions—</p>
            <p>Dulr. But—</p>
            <p>Cath. Odious pretensions, sir,—if you dare repeat them, my <br/>father shall forbid you
            the house. Go, sir.</p>
            <p>Dulr. Madam, I cannot see what you mean by odious. If a <br/>sincere and respectful
            adoration—</p>
            <p>Cath. Of twenty-five thousand dollars and large expectations—</p>
            <p>Dulr. You mistake, you mistake. It is yourself, your bewitch- <br/>ing
            person, your exalted character, that I adore; money is of no <br/>consideration,
            where—</p>
            <p>Cath. It is so inconsiderable as with Miss Mildmay. Her poor <br/>five thousand, sir,
            are quite beneath the regards of an aspirer like <br/>Mr. Arnold Dulruse.</p>
            <p>Dulr. [Aside.] Damnation!</p>
            <p>Cath. You might as well swear louder, Mr. Dulruse. If you <br/>are ashamed that your
            meanness is detected, go and repeat it.</p>
            <p>Dulr. Miss Clairvoir, do not be so hasty ! Hear me. I did <br/>indeed once love your
            cousin—</p>
            <p>Cath. Oh sir!</p>
            <p>Dulr. But was it possible, when you were present—</p>
            <p>Cath. To adore her longer ? No! [Affecting pompousness.] <br/>Who sees the stars when
            the moon is in her glory? and when the <br/>golden sun arises in the orient, is not her
            silver round unnoticed in <br/>the west ? Is that the style, sir? Gold and silver, you
            see: a <br/>great difference. There; you now perceive that you are laughed <br/>at, and
            you turn pale with rage. To be serious: have you forgot- <br/>ten that there
            is a person in the world by the name of Walton ?</p>
            <p>Dulr. But my mother—</p>
            <p>Cath. Your mother ?</p>
            <p>Dulr. Don’t speak so scornfully, Miss Clairvoir; that mother <br/>may bo yours before
            long; yes, will be. Who is pale now? <br/>Come, Miss Catharine, let us talk reason. I
            have not only my <br/>m other’s assurance—</p>
            <p>Cath. But also your own, which is fully equal.</p>

            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page150"/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>

            <p>Dulr. But also your father approves of my passion. You may <br/>look incredulous. And
            what is more, he has not only taken me in- <br/>to favor, but Mr. Walton, he
            declares, shall never have you.</p>
            <p>Cath. It is false ; false as your pretended passion. I shall ask <br/>him this instant.
            [As she is going to the door, Dulruse puts him- <br/>self in the way.] Stand
            out of my way, sir.</p>
            <p>Dulr. But hear me.</p>
            <p>Cath. Let me pass, this instant, as you value your safety. I <br/>have been, I see, too
            backward, too forbearing. I wished to spare <br/>Miss Mildmay’s feelings, and I was
            silent; I did not care to involve <br/>Mr. Walton in a quarrel, and I forbore to tell
            him; and, for the <br/>sake of all concerned, I have withheld your preposterous and in-
              <br/>sulting declarations from Mr. Clairvoir: but, since this is misunder-
              <br/>stood, my patience is at an end; and the next word that you dare
            <br/>address me on this subject, you shall hear your answer from one <br/>that will make
            more impression on you. Let me pass, sir. [Exit.]</p>
            <p>Dulr. And the devil go with you, for a pert, insolent, purse- <br/>proud—Damnation! [Exit.]</p>
            <p>Scene II.—The dining-room at Mr. Clairvoir s. Enter Letty, <br/>looking
            for something.</p>
            <p>Letty. [Singing.]</p>
            <p>“Still so gently o’er me stealing, <br/>Memory will bring back the feeling"—</p>
            <p>Enter Dulruse. He starts, looks pleased, then goes behind her <br/>cautiously, and, as
            she concludes the second verse, puts his hand <br/>about her waist.</p>
            <p>Dulr. [Mimicking.] Fee-e-ling!</p>
            <p>Lett. With a vengeance ! [Extricating herself with a show of <br/>anger.] You are very
            free, Mr. Dulruse.</p>
            <p>Dulr. I always am, my dear; quite at home with such pretty <br/>rogues as you.
            Delicious song, that,—must have left quite a bou- <br/>quet on your lips: let
            me taste it. [Attempting to kiss her ]</p>
            <p>Lett. [Boxing his ears violently ] There, take that! And if <br/>you ’re so fond of
            bouquets, sir, you’d better let Miss Mildmay fur- <br/>nish you: you ’ll find
            too many thorns about my posy.</p>
            <p>Dulr. Hark you, child ! you may think yourself vastly witty; <br/>but, let me tell you,
            you are damned saucy.</p>
            <p>Lett. I came to look for Miss Clairvoir’s fan, sir, not to meet <br/>you. And now I’ve
            found it, I wish you more manners, and a <br/>good afternoon. [Curtsies contemptuously
            and is about to leave the <br/>room. Dulr. lays hold of her arm, and, in their
            struggles, he comes <br/>with his back against the door and closes it ] Let me go, sir,
            you’d <br/>better, for your own reputation.</p>
            <p>Dulr. Yours, you mean. The door is now shut, hussy; and, <br/>if you’d have me forgive
            you that blow, you’ll leave these airs for <br/>your betters.</p>
            <p>Lett. My betters, sir! And who are they ? Not you, nor your <br/>mother, I can tell
            you. Let me go.</p>
            <p>Dulr. You are very pert.</p>
            <p>Lett. You are very impertinent.</p>
            <p>Dulr. For a chambermaid, my little black-eyed vixen, you <br/>have—</p>
            <p>Lett. Too much penetration not to see through such a shallow <br/>ditch as you.</p>
            <p>Dulr. Come, come ! my angel of the bedquilts ; though your <br/>eyes do flash fire—</p>
            <p>Lett. They would find it hard to influence such a mouldy bit of <br/>tinder as you are.
            And so—[Struggling.]</p>
            <p>Dulr. Take that, Miss Impudence. [ Trying to kiss her.]</p>
            <p>Lett. No; that, Mr. Fool! [Trusting the fan in his face.]</p>
            <p>Dulr. Damn it, you minx; this is carrying the joke too far.</p>
            <p>Lett. Not farther, sir, than Miss Clairvoir did for you a minute <br/>ago. [Dulr. in
            confusion, lets go her arm. Letty opens the <br/>door. ] You have a high notion of your
            own capacity, Mr. Dulruse ; <br/>three women at once. And yet, let me tell you, you have
            n’t heart <br/>enough for one of them, though you have effrontery enough for all
            <br/>three. [He springs at her. She darts through the doorway. <br/>Then, seeing him
            pause, Letty puts back her head into the room.] <br/>And now hear a last word, sir,
            which, for your sake, more than my <br/>own, I wont speak as loud as you obliged Miss
            Clairvoir to do:<br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>He that has n’t wit enough to make the mistress listen, need not <br/>think to come
            over the maid; and the man that is so base as to <br/>cheat one lady and lie to another,
            is just worthy to attempt the hon- <br/>or of a poor servingmaid, but is too
            contemptible to put it ever in <br/>peril. Good day, sir. [Curtsies low, and exit,
            singing significant- <br/>ly,—while he stands unable to move, from confusion
            and rage :]</p>
            <p>“ but my feelings I smother: <br/>O thou hast been the cause of this anguish, my mother
            !"</p>
            <p>Dulr. [After a moment.] Bit on every side, by Haeven! <br/>[Exit, clenching his
            hands.]</p>
            <p>Scene Third.—St. John’s Square. The enclosure is seen. Enter, on
            <br/>the outside, Walton, walking leisurely, and in the opposite direction,
            <br/>Gantelet. Gantelet, as he comes in front of Mr. Walton, touch- <br/>es
            his hat respectfully ; Walton returns the salute, and is about to <br/>pass, but checks
            himself suddenly.</p>
            <p>Walt. So, Gantelet; is that you ?</p>
            <p>Gant. Aat Monsieur Walton sareveece. [Bowing.]</p>
            <p>Walt. Your master has returned then ?</p>
            <p>Gant. No, sare; Monsieur Rontolph haas stop aat Philadelphie.</p>
            <p>Walt. And sent you on. I should not have thought, my good <br/>Gantelet, that he could
            have spared you.</p>
            <p>Gant. [Bowing humbly.] Monsieur is ver’ complaison: de <br/>pauvre Gantelet is note
            really wort’ not ting.</p>
            <p>Walt. When does he return ?</p>
            <p>Gant. Dis eveneeng, sare: he stay aat Philadelphia for soam <br/>leetel affaire, soam
            bagatelle, and senda me on, in de morning, wid <br/>all hees effaics—hees bags, hees
            portmanteau, hees fusil, hees every <br/>ting.</p>
            <p>Wall. Did you leave Mr. Racy at bis lodgings ?</p>
            <p>Gant. Mon, monsieur. Ah! I me recall in dis moment, Mon- <br/>sieur Raacie
            waas gone out, all exprès for to see Monsieur Wul- <br/>tone.</p>
            <p>Walt. To see me ? When ? how long ago ?</p>
            <p>Gant. Wan, two, tree minoot; ver’ leetel vile.</p>
            <p>Walt. How unfortunate! I was just going to him. Well, if <br/>you should meet him,
            Gantelet, tell Mr. Racy that he will find me <br/>at his lodgings.</p>
            <p>Gant. Oui, monsieur. [He touches his hat respectfully, as Mr. Wal- <br/>ton moves on,
            and is about to depart in the opposite direction, when</p>
            <p>Enter Letty, in great haste, from the side at which Gantelet first <br/>appeared, i.
            e., facing Mr. Walton. She moves directly up to the <br/>tatler ; and Gantelet stops to
            watch the meeting.</p>
            <p>Lett. O, Mr. Walton ; I am so rejoiced to meet you, sir!</p>
            <p>Wall. Well, Letty, what is the matter ? Take breath. You <br/>need not wait, Gantelet.
            [Gant, behind Mr. Walton’s back, shakes <br/>his fist at Letty, who smiles in return
            maliciously. Exit Gant.]</p>
            <p>Lett. Oh, sir, I have just been, as fast as I could go, to Mr. <br/>Racy’s, and not
            finding him at home, I thought I would take the <br/>liberty to go to you; and I am so
            glad I lave met you, sir! There <br/>have been such doings at our house! [Fans herself
            with her <br/>apron.]</p>
            <p>Walt. What? Quick!</p>
            <p>Lett. Why, sir, there is Miss Mildmay, all in tears, poor thing <br/>and Miss
            Catharine—[running.]</p>
            <p>Walt. For Heaven's sake !</p>
            <p>Lett. So distressed! I beg pardon. You must know, Mr. <br/>Walton, that Mr. Clairvoir—I
            really don't know how to tell you.</p>
            <p>Walt. Letty! this is worse than murder: speak out, at once.</p>
            <p>Lett. Then, sir, the truth is, the devil is in the matter. [ Unty- <br/>ing
            the strings of her bonnet, and fanning violently.] Mr. Clair- <br/>voir has
            actually forbidden Miss Catharine to think any more about <br/>you.</p>
            <p>Walt. You dream.</p>
            <p>Lett. I wish I did, sir; and that we all did ; but the only dream- <br/>ers
            are Miss Catharine's father and Mrs. Dulruse, and that wretch, <br/>Mr. Dulruse, is at
            the bottom of the whole business.</p>
            <p>Walt. Go on, go on ; though I scarcely can believe you.</p>
            <p>Lett. Yet it is true, sir. It seems that you have said something <br/>about their silly
            magnetism that has displeased the old gentleman. <br/>He and the housekeeper have been
            talking about it over and over <br/>again this afternoon. What was said, I don’t know ;
            but suddenly<div class="pagebreak" id="#page151"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>Mr. Clairvoir comes out of the room, crying out, in a very determin- <br/>ed tone, “I'll do it”: he sees me on the stairs, tells me to call Miss <br/>Catharine:
            so I did; they had a conversation together; I felt un- <br/>easy ; I could
            not help entering the room; and I heard Mr. Clair- <br/>voir tell Miss
            Catharine “ that she was not to think of you any more, <br/>but he would provide a
            husband that had more brains, and was <br/>more worthy of her." Excuse me sir, they are
            his words, no ideas <br/>of mine.</p>
            <p>Walt. Never mind; go on.</p>
            <p>Lett. The rest, sir, is very little. The old man leaves the room, <br/>and I went out
            too ; and before I got up stairs I saw Mr. Dulruse <br/>go in. Now you must know, sir—
            But— No, it’s right that I <br/>should tell you. Mr. Dulruse, sir, has been making love
            to Miss <br/>Clairvoir for more than a week past. [ Walter falls back, and stands
            <br/>speechless. ] O, dear Mr. Walton! don’t look so pale about it: do <br/>you think
            Miss Catharine would think of such a thing as he! Lor', <br/>sir, he is beneath my
            contempt, let alone such a lady as Miss Clair- <br/>voir’s.</p>
            <p>Walt. But Catharine never told me!</p>
            <p>Lett. No indeed; she is not one of those ladies that love to have <br/>gentlemen fight
            about them. Had you heard what she said to Mr. <br/>Dulruse, at this interview, like a
            high-spirited lady as she is, you <br/>would not feel concern on that score.</p>
            <p>Walt. True, true, indeed: I don’t know how I could be so <br/>weak, as to think for a
            moment—</p>
            <p>Lett. Lord, sir, there he is! [While Walton and Letty have been <br/>talking, two or
            three persons hart crossed the scene, and, at last, Mr. <br/>Dulruse. He looks at the
            party suspiciously, and passes on, just us Let- <br/>ty notices him.]</p>
            <p>Wall. Where? who? Ah! [About to spring after Dulruse. <br/>Letty stops him.]</p>
            <p>Lett. For God's sake, Mr. Walton ! Think of Miss Catharine— <br/>and for such a
            man!</p>
            <p>Walt. You are right; let him go. You are a good and sensible <br/>girl, Letty. What
            next ?</p>
            <p>Lett. O sir, don’t flatter me, or I shall begin to think all men <br/>alike. Mr.
            Dulruse has been complimenting me at a prodigious <br/>rate, I can tell you, sir,—and I
            mean to tell somebody else too.</p>
            <p>Walt. What! a general lover ? But that is none of my busi- ness.</p>
            <p>Lett. No, sir? I should have thought it was. But you and <br/>Miss Catharine have such
            high notions of delicacy, you never will <br/>listen to other people’s secrets.</p>
            <p>Walt. Nor should you either, Letty. But you are a good girl, <br/>[Offers her money.] A
            shawl, or ring or two.</p>
            <p>Lett. No, sir; thank you; I have my pride, as well as my bet- <br/>ters.
            Wait till your wedding day. Come, you are going to flatter <br/>me again, Mr. Walton :
            don't turn my head. Well, sir, to finish <br/>my story, and quickly; for people are
            beginning to look at us:— <br/>When Mr. Dulruse had done with the mistress he comes to
            make <br/>love to the maid, though I believe he was in search of his mother. <br/>I gave
            him his dismissal as quickly as Miss Catharine had done, <br/>(you need not smile—I did,
            sir;) and then, without saying a word <br/>to anybody, I put on my things and ran all
            the way to Miss Catha- <br/>rine’s uncle's; for I knew if anybody could help
            her, it was Mr. <br/>Racy; and I think it high time he should interfere. Speak of the
            <br/>—old boy—I do declare here he is.</p>
            <p>Enter Racy.</p>
            <p>Racy. Eh, what the devil, Schuyler! Making love to my little <br/>Letty ? Too bad that!
            Hark you, child; don’t you let him teach <br/>you nonsense.'</p>
            <p>Lett. Not such a child as you take me for, Mr. Racy ; and if I <br/>were, I should not
            go to an old widower for instruction. [Curtsies <br/>coquettishly.]</p>
            <p>Racy. You imp! [Drives her off.)</p>
            <p>Lett. [Coming back.) Oh, Mr. Walton, please tell this old gen- <br/>tleman
            what I told you; but, pray, for Miss Catharine’s sake, don’t <br/>let him teach you
            wickedness. [Exit.]</p>
            <p>Racy. Ha, ha, ha! give an inch and they’ll take a yard. O, the <br/>devil! I forgot
            we're in the street. I wonder what makes the<br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>girls so free with me, Schuyler; eh, my boy ? From the mistress to <br/>the maid,
            they say just what they please to old Frank Racy.</p>
            <p>Walt. They know his good nature, sir.</p>
            <p>Racy. What, what! Now that’s but half what you mean; there <br/>is something more in
            the comers of your mouth. I say, Walt, do <br/>you know I was seeking you ?</p>
            <p>Walt. And I was in search of you, sir.</p>
            <p>Racy. Well, that’s odd; but, I’ll bet you a supper, I’ve the best <br/>news. Frank
            Randolph’s got back from Richmond! he will be <br/>here in an hour, you dog! his damned
            Parlez-vous came on this <br/>morning with all his luggage. There’s news for you,
            Long-legs. <br/>Gad! we’ll have a night of it. Why, how devilish grave you look !
            <br/>What is in the wind, now ?</p>
            <p>Walt. Let us move on and I’ll tell you. Your niece—</p>
            <p>Racy. What, what! I might have look'd for some curs’d cat- <br/>astrophe
            when a waitingmaid was in the plot. [Puts his arm <br/>through Walton's.) Well, well, my
            niece ? [Exeunt.]</p>
          END OF ACT II.
        </div>



        <div>
            <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading</div>
               <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XXII. <br/>Essays of Elia. By
              Charles Lamb.</p>
               <p>Of all the British essayists Charles Lamb is the most origi- <br/>nal—if
              we may be permitted to use comparatively a purely <br/>positive term. He is the
              founder of that school in which <br/>Douglas Jerrold and Cornelius Webbe have been the
              most <br/>successful disciples,—aped at second hand, or at twentieth <br/>hand, by the
              William Joneses of our own continent—a set of <br/>little people, who, wriggling
              hither and thither like the en- <br/>tozoa, grow fat, like them, on the
              substance of alien brains.</p>
               <p>Of all original men, too, Lamb, we think, has the fewest <br/>demerits. Of gross
              faults he has none at all. His merest <br/>extravagances have about them a symmetry
              which entitles <br/>them to critical respect. And his innumerable good qualities
              <br/>who shall attempt to depict ? For the present we shall let <br/>him speak
              entirely for himself in an account of his</p>
               <p>FIRST PLAY.</p>
               <p>At the north end of Cross-court there stands a portal, of some ar- <br/>chitectural pretensions, though reduced to humble use, serving at pres- <br/>ent for an entrance to a printing-office. This old door-way, if you are
              <br/>young, reader, you may not know was the identical pit entrance to old
              <br/>Drury—Garrick’s Drury—all of it that is left. I never pass it without
              <br/>shaking some forty years from off my shoulders, recurring to the eve- <br/>ning when I passed through it to see my first play. The afternoon
              <br/>had been wet, and the condition of our going (the elder folks and my- <br/>self) was, that the rain should cease. With what beating heart did
              <br/>I watch from the window the puddles, from the stillness of which I <br/>was
              taught to prognosticate the desired cessation ! I seem to remem- <br/>ber
              the last spurt, and the glee with which I ran to announce it.</p>
               <p>We went with orders, which my godfather F. had sent us. He kept <br/>the oil shop
              (now Davies’s) at the comer of Featherstone buildings, in <br/>Holborn. F. was a tall
              grave person, lofty in speech, and had preten- <br/>sions above his rank.
              He associated in those days with John Palmer, <br/>the comedian, whose gait and
              bearing be seemed to copy: if John <br/>(which is quite as likely) did not rather
              borrow somewhat of his man- <br/>ner from my godfather. He was also known
              to, and visited by, Sher- <br/>idan. It was to his house in Holborn that
              young Brinsley brought his <br/>first wife on her elopement with him from a
              boarding-school at Bath <br/>__the beautiful Maria Linley. My parents were present
              (over a quad- <br/>rille table) when he arrived in the evening with his
              harmonious charge. <br/>From either of these connexions it may be inferred that my
              godfath- <br/>er could command an order for the then Drury-lane theatre at
              pleas- <br/>ure—and, indeed, a pretty liberal issue of those cheap billets,
              in Brins- <br/>ley’s easy autograph, I have heard him say, was the sole remunera- <br/>tion which he had received for many year’s nightly illumination of the
              <br/>orchestra and various avenues of that theatre—and he was content it <br/>should
              be so. The honor of Sheridan’s familiarity—or supposed fa- <br/>miliarity—was better to my god-father than money.</p>
               <p>F. was the most gentlemanly of oilmen ; grandiloquent, yet courte- <div class="pagebreak" id="#page152"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>ous. His delivery of the commonest matters of fact was Ciceronian. <br/>He had
              two Latin words almost constantly in his mouth (how odd <br/>sounds Latin from an
              oilman’s lips!) which my better knowledge <br/>since has enabled me to correct. In
              strict pronunciation they should <br/>have been sounded vice versa—but in those young
              years they impres- <br/>sed me with more awe than they would now do, read
              aright from Sen- <br/>eca or Varro—in his own peculiar pronunciation,
              monosyllabically <br/>elaborated, or Anglicized, into something like verse verse. By
              an im- <br/>posing manner, and the help of these distorted syllables, he
              climbed <br/>(but that was little) to the highest parochial honors which St. An- <br/>drew’s has to bestow.</p>
               <p>He is dead—and thus much I thought due to his memory, both for <br/>my first orders
              (little wondrous talismen !—slight keys, and insignifi- <br/>cant to
              outward sight, but opening to me more than Arabian para- <br/>dises !) and
              moreover, that by his testamentary beneficence I came <br/>into possession of the only
              landed property which I could ever call <br/>my own—situate near the road-way village
              of pleasant Puckeridge, in <br/>Hertfordshire. When I journeyed down to take
              possession, and plant- <br/>ed my foot on my own ground, the stately habits
              of the donor descend- <br/>ed upon me, and I strode (shall I confess the
              vanity?) with larger <br/>paces over my allotment of three-quarters of an acre, with
              its com- <br/>modious mansion in the midst, with the feeling of an English
              freehold- <br/>er that all betwixt sky and centre was my own. The estate
              has pas- <br/>sed into more prudent hands, and nothing less than an
              agrarian can <br/>restore it.</p>
               <p>In those days were pit orders. Beshrew the uncomfortable mana- <br/>ger
              who abolished them!—with one of these we went. I remember <br/>the waiting at the
              door—not that which is left—but between that and <br/>an inner door in shelter—O when
              shall be such an expectant again !— <br/>with the cry of nonpareils, an indispensable
              play-house accompani- <br/>ment in those days. As near as I can recollect,
              the fashionable pro- <br/>nunciation of the theatrical fruiteresses then
              was, “ Chase some oran- <br/>ges, chase some numparels, chase a bill of the
              play—chase pro <br/>choose. But when we got in, and I beheld the green curtain that
              veil- <br/>ed a heaven to my imagination, which was soon to be
              disclosed—the <br/>breathless anticipations I endured ! I had seen something like it
              pre- <br/>fixed to Troilus and Cressida, in Rowe’s Shakespeare—the tent
              scene <br/>with Diomede—and a sight of that plate can always bring back in a
              <br/>measure, the feeling of that evening.—The boxes at the time, full of <br/>well
              dressed women of quality, projected over the pit; and the pilas- <br/>ters
              reaching down were adorned with a glistering substance (I know <br/>not what) under
              glass (as it seemed), resembling—a homely fancy— <br/>but I judged it to be
              sugar-candy—yet, to my raised imagination, di- <br/>vested of its homelier
              qualities, it appeared a glorified candy !—The <br/>orchestra lights at length arose,
              those “ fair Auroras !” Once the bell <br/>sounded. It was to ring out yet once
              again—and incapable of the an- <br/>ticipation, I reposed my shut eyes in a
              sort of resignation on the ma- <br/>ternal lap. It rang the second time.
              The curtain drew up—I was not <br/>past six years old and the play was Artaxerxes
              !</p>
               <p>I had dabbled a little in the Universal History—the ancient part of it <br/>—and here
              was the court of Persia. It was being admitted to a sight <br/>of the past. I took no
              proper interest in the action going on, for I un- <br/>derstood not its
              import—But I heard the word Darius, and I was in the <br/>midst of Daniel. All feeling
              was absorbed in vision. Gorgeous vests, <br/>gardens, palaces, princesses, passed
              before me. I knew not players. <br/>I was in Persepolis for the time, and the burning
              idol of their devotion <br/>almost converted me into a worshipper. I was awe-struck,
              and believ- <br/>ed those significations to be something more than
              elemental fires. It <br/>was all enchantment and a dream. No such pleasure has since
              visit- <br/>ed me but in dreams.—Harlequin’s invasion followed : where, I
              re- <br/>member, the transformation of the magistrates into reverend
              beldams <br/>seemed to me, a piece of grave historic justice, and the tailor carrying
              <br/>his own head, to be as sober a verity as the legend of St. Denys.</p>
               <p>The next play to which I was taken was the Lady of the Manor, <br/>of which, with the
              exception of some scenery, very faint traces are <br/>left in my memory. It was
              followed by a pantomime, called Lun’s <br/>Ghost—a satiric touch, I apprehend, upon
              Rich, not long since dead — <br/>but to my apprehension (too sincere for satire), Lun
              was as remote a <br/>piece of antiquity as Lud—the father of a line of
              Harlequins—trans- <br/>mitting his dagger of lath (the wooden sceptre)
              through countless <br/>ages. I saw the primeval Motley come from his silent tomb in a
              <br/>ghastly vest of white patch-work, like the apparition of a dead rain- <br/>bow. So Harlequins (thought I) look when they are dead.</p>
               <p>My third play followed in quick succession. It was the Way of the <br/>World. I think
              I must have sat at it as grave as a judge ; for, I re- <br/>member, the
              hysteric affections of good Lady Wishfort affected me<br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>like some solemn tragic passion. Robinson Crusoe followed; in <br/>which Crusoe,
              man Friday, and the parrot, were as good and authentic <br/>as in the story.—The
              clownery and pantaloonery of these pantomimes <br/>have clean passed out of my head. I
              believe, I no more laughed at <br/>them, than at the same age I should have been
              disposed to laugh at <br/>the grotesqne Gothic heads (seeming to me then replete with
              devout <br/>meaning), that gape, and grin, in stone around the inside of the old
              <br/>Round Church (my church) of the Templars.</p>
               <p>I saw these plays in the season 1781-2, when I was from six to seven <br/>years old.
              After the intervention of six or seven other years (for at <br/>school all play-going
              was inhibited) I again entered the doors of a the- <br/>atre. That old
              Artaxerxes evening had never done ringing in my <br/>fancy. I expected the same
              feelings to come again with the same oc- <br/>casion. But we differ from
              ourselves less at sixty and sixteen, than <br/>the latter does from six. In that
              interval what had I not lost! At <br/>the first period I knew nothing, understood
              nothing, discriminated <br/>nothing. I felt all, loved all, wondered all— <div class="lg">
                     <br/>Was nourished, I could not tell how—
              </div>
                  <br/>I had left the temple a devotee, and was returned a rationalist. The <br/>same
              things were there materially; but the emblem, the reference, <br/>was gone !—The green
              curtain was no longer a veil, drawn between <br/>two worlds, the unfolding of which
              was to bring back past ages to <br/>present a “ royal ghost,”—but a certain quantity
              of green baize, which <br/>was to separate the audience for a given time from certain
              of their fel- <br/>lowmen who were to come forward and pretend those parts.
              The <br/>lights—the orchestra lights—came up a clumsy machinery. The first <br/>ring,
              and the second ring, was now but a trick of the prompter’s bell <br/>—which had been,
              like the note of a cuckoo, a phantom of a voice, no <br/>hand seen or guessed at which
              ministered to its warning. The actors <br/>were men and women painted. I thought the
              fault was in them ; but <br/>it was in myself, and the alteration which those many
              centuries,—of <br/>six short twelvemonths—had wrought in men. Perhaps it was fortunate
              <br/>for me that the play of the evening was but an indifferent comedy, as <br/>it
              gave me time to crop some unreasonable expectations, which might <br/>have interfered
              with the genuine emotions with which I was soon af- <br/>ter enabled to
              enter upon the first appearance to me of Mrs. Siddons <br/>in Isabella, Comparison and
              retrospection soon yielded to the present <br/>attraction of the scene; and the
              theatre became to me, upon a new <br/>stock, the most delightful of recreations.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Studies in Religion.</div>
               <p>Studies in Religion. By the author of “ Words in a Sun- <br/>day School." New York :
              C. Shepard.</p>
               <p>This is a neat duodecimo of about 225 pages, without Intro- <br/>duction,
              or any clew to the author’s name, beyond what we <br/>find in the title. The work
              consists of twenty-four well- <br/>written and instructive essays, which
              from their brevity and <br/>character we may as well denominate sub-sermons or ser-
                <br/>monoids.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Short Patent Sermons.</div>
               <p>Short Patent Sermons. By Dow, Jr. Originally published <br/>in the New York Sunday
              Mercury. Vol. I. New York: <br/>Paige, Nichols, &amp; Krauth.</p>
               <p>These patent sermons have had a wide celebrity, and in <br/>great measure deserve it
              from their wit and bonhommie, to- <br/>tally devoid of offence. Who Dow Jr.
              is, we have never yet <br/>been able to say. For anything we know to the contrary,
              <br/>he may be our friend of the United States’ Journal. We have <br/>heard him
              discourse by the hour in a strain very much akin <br/>to that of the volume before
              us.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">My Uncle Hobson and I; or Slashes at Life with a Free
              Broad-Axe.</div>
               <p>My Uncle Hobson and I; or Slashes at Life with a Free <br/>Broad-Axe. By Pascal
              Jones. New York : D. Appleton <br/>&amp; Co.</p>
               <p>This is a handsomely printed duodecimo of about 270 pages. <br/>We have not had an
              opportunity of reading it thoroughly, <br/>but some of the chapters have much of that
              sort of humor <br/>which is found in the Chronicles of Pineville—that is to say
              <br/>in the worst portions of the Chronicles. The announcement <br/>on the cover that
              the book is an “ Interesting American <br/>work" is in bad policy and worse taste.</p>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div class="pagebreak" id="#page153"/>
        <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/>

        <div>
            <a href=""/>
            <div class="note" id="">We comply, this week, with the suggestion of some friends <br/>—that
            we should copy in the “ Broadway Journal” Hood’s <br/>magnificent ].</div>

            <div class="head">BRIDGE OF SIGHS.</div>

            <div class="lg">
               <br/>“ Drowned! Drowned!”—Hamlet,
            <br/>One more Unfortunate,
            <br/>Weary of breath, 
            <br/>Rashly importunate,
            <br/>Gone to her death !
            <br/>Take her up tenderly,
            <br/>Lift her with care ;—
            <br/>Fashion’d so slenderly,
            <br/>Young and so fair !
            <br/>Look at her garments
            <br/>Clinging like cerements;
            <br/>Whilst the wave constantly
            <br/>Drips from her clothing;
            <br/>Take her up instantly,
            <br/>Loving, not loathing —
            <br/>Touch her not scornfully ;
            <br/>Think of her mournfully,
            <br/>Gently and humanly ;
            <br/>Not of the stains of her,
            <br/>All that remains of her
            <br/>Now, is pure womanly.
            <br/>Make no deep scrutiny
            <br/>Into her mutiny
            <br/>Rash and undutiful ;
            <br/>Past all dishonor,
            <br/>Death has left on her
            <br/>Only the beautiful.
            <br/>Still, for all slips of hers,
            <br/>One of Eve’s family—
            <br/>Wipe those pale lips of hers
            <br/>Oozing so clammily.
            <br/>Loop up her tresses
            <br/>Escaped from the comb,
            <br/>Her fair auburn tresses;
            <br/>Whilst wonderment guesses
            <br/>Where was her home ?
            <br/>Who was her father ?
            <br/>Who was her mother ?
            <br/>Had she a sister ?
            <br/>Had she a brother ?
            <br/>Or was there a dearer one
            <br/>Still, and a nearer one
            <br/>Yet, than all other?
            <br/>Alas ! for the rarity
            <br/>Of Christian charity
            <br/>Under the sun !
            <br/>Oh ! it was pitiful!
            <br/>Near a whole city full,
            <br/>Home she had none.
            <br/>Sisterly, brotherly,
            <br/>Fatherly, motherly,
            <br/>Feelings have changed:
            <br/>Love, by harsh evidence,
            <br/>Thrown from its eminence;
            <br/>Even God’s Providence
            <br/>Seeming estranged.
            <br/>Where the lamps quiver
            <br/>So far in the river,
            <br/>With many a light
            <br/>From window and casement,
            <br/>From garret to basement,
            <br/>She stood, with amazement,
            <br/>Houseless by night.
            <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>The bleak wind of March
            <br/>Made her tremble and shiver;
            <br/>But not the dark arch,
            <br/>Or the black flowing river:
            <br/>Mad from life’s history,
            <br/>Swift to be hurl’d—
            <br/>Anywhere, anywhere
            <br/>Out of the world ?
            <br/>In she plunged boldly,
            <br/>No matter how coldly
            <br/>The rough river ran,—
            <br/>Over the brink of it,
            <br/>Picture it,—think of it,
            <br/>Dissolute Man !
            <br/>Lave in it, drink of it
            <br/>Then, If you can !
            <br/>Take her up tenderly,
            <br/>Lift her with care
            <br/>Fashioned so slenderly,
            <br/>Young and so fair ! 
            <br/>Ere her limbs frigidly
            <br/>Stiffen too rigidly,
            <br/>Decently,—kindly,—
            <br/>Smoothe, and compose them ;
            <br/>And her eyes close them,
            <br/>Staring so blindly !
            <br/>Dreadfully staring
            <br/>Through muddy impurity
            <br/>As when with the daring
            <br/>Last look of despairing
            <br/>Fixed on futurity.
            <br/>Perishing gloomily,
            <br/>Spurred by contumely,
            <br/>Cold inhumanity,
            <br/>Burning insanity,
            <br/>Into her rest.—
            <br/>Cross her hands humbly,
            <br/>As if praying dumbly,
            <br/>Over her breast!
            <br/>Owning her weakness,
            <br/>Her evil behaviour, 
            <br/>And leaving, with meekness,
            <br/>Her sins to her Saviour !
          </div>
        </div>



        <div>
            <div class="head">The Fine Arts.</div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">The National Gallery at the Rotunda.</div>
               <p>The National Gallery at the Rotunda.—The dispari- <br/>ty of wealth
              between the rich and the poor, has of late years <br/>attracted the attention of
              lovers of equality. The “ shallow <br/>benevolent” would remedy all the evils of life
              by re-model- <br/>ling the whole structure of society; they seem to think,
              with <br/>Alphonso the Seventh, that it is a pity the Almighty did not <br/>consult
              them while creating the universe—they could have <br/>shown Him how much better its
              moral structure might have <br/>been. These gentlemen seem to think that it is in the
              power <br/>of man to remove from the earth all sickness, pain, and po- <br/>verty ; they forget that it is declared by the highest autho- <br/>rity,
              that we “ shall have the poor always with us;" conse- <br/>quently that
              there must always be poor and rich. It would <br/>be well for society if these
              well-meaning persons, instead of <br/>wasting their energies in attempting things
              impossible, could <br/>be induced to confine their efforts to practical ameliorations.
              <br/>A little examination of the subject would soon convince them, <br/>that however
              great the difference between the pleasures of <br/>the rich and the pleasures of the
              poor, the difference is capa- <br/>ble of being brought down by education
              to very narrow li- <br/>mits; it would be found, that the enjoyments
              belonging to<div class="pagebreak" id="#page154"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
               </p>
               <p>the wealthy are confined to ostentatious display, and those <br/>accomplishments
              which require leisure for their acquire- <br/>ments.</p>
               <p>The Supreme Being, although He has been pleased to <br/>confer on but few the power
              of producing works of intellec- <br/>tual beauty, has yet given to almost
              all men the capacity, <br/>with a little cultivation, of appreciating and enjoying
              such <br/>works, independently of wealth or poverty. Take, for exam- <br/>ple, the pleasure to be derived from hearing fine Music. It <br/>is well known that
              in many parts of Germany—one of the <br/>poorest countries in Europe—all the people,
              whatever their <br/>stations in life, are equally capable of enjoying the composi- <br/>tions of Mozart and Beethoven. We have heard it related <br/>by a
              gentleman of great benevolence, taste, and talent, that <br/>in travelling once
              through a mountainous district of Germa- <br/>ny, where the people were so
              poor that they had no horses, <br/>he was much surprised to hear a fine voice before
              him on the <br/>road, singing one of Mozart’s compositions. On coming up <br/>with the
              singer he found a sturdy peasant, with a wheelbar- <br/>row, and on it a
              load of wood, enough for a horse, and in front <br/>of the wood a rude music stand,
              with a piece of music on it. <br/>This rude son of the soil was studying his part for
              the even- <br/>ing performance. He belonged to the village amateur ope- <br/>ratic company. All those villagers who had voices, learned <br/>to sing,
              while many of the others played upon different in- <br/>struments. One of
              the means of enjoyment which God had <br/>given them had been cultivated, and Mozart
              had lived as <br/>much for the peasants of the mountains, as for Joseph the
              <br/>Second, his patron (!), or the nobles of Vienna.</p>
               <p>Again: we see in England, among the poorest of the la- <br/>borers, a
              taste for the beautiful productions of Nature : each <br/>cottager, although his food
              be but the coarsest bread and his <br/>drink the simple spring water, has his patch of
              garden, and <br/>the woodbine that clusters over his door appears as beautiful
              <br/>and smells as sweet to him, as to his wealthy employer.</p>
               <p>There is another source of enjoyment as much within the <br/>reach of all persons as
              those already mentioned, but not equal- <br/>ly cultivated by the moderns:
              we mean the sense of the Beau- <br/>tiful. This sense, the most important
              aid to our intellectual <br/>enjoyment, was cultivated to the highest point by the
              Greeks <br/>and the Etruscans. The very earthenware utensils of the <br/>latter people
              are now sought after as models for the most <br/>costly porcelain, manufactured for
              the wealthy alone; yet the <br/>pleasure the Etrurian derived from contemplating the
              form <br/>of his earthenware pitcher, was no doubt greater than can <br/>ever be felt
              by the pampered possessor of its porcelain copy. <br/>All things animate or inanimate,
              have forms which may be <br/>beautiful or not beautiful, and to distinguish between
              these <br/>requires cultivation and study. What the course of study <br/>should be, is
              not exactly agreed upon ; but the mode adopt- <br/>ed by European
              governments for improving the taste of their <br/>manufacturers, has been, to open to
              them Public galleries, <br/>containing the choicest works of the pencil and the
              chisel. <br/>They have observed, that in France, where such galleries <br/>have been
              open to the people for generations, the manufac- <br/>tures have acquired
              an unrivalled degree of beauty, and the <br/>people a keen sense of the pleasure to be
              derived from the <br/>contemplation of works of Art. This is, however, a dollar
              <br/>and cent mode of viewing the subject: in a moral point of <br/>view, it has far
              higher claims to our attention, but we must <br/>defer enlarging upon this point until
              a future occasion.</p>
               <p>We have been led to the foregoing reflections by the re- <br/>cent opening
              in our Park of the City Gallery. The Pictures <br/>contained in the Rotunda were
              formerly, it will be remem- <br/>bered, in the possession of the late Lumon
              Reed, Esq. of <br/>Greenwich street. At his death they passed into the posess-<br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>sion of his family, who wished to dispose of them to some <br/>private
              institution, as they would not consent that the collec- <br/>tion should be
              divided. This was deemed by many gentle- <br/>men a favorable opportunity
              for founding a Public Gallery, <br/>which should become also the property of the
              public. A <br/>meeting was called at the suggestion of the Rev. Orville Dew- <br/>ey. It assembled at the residence of Mr. Jonathan Sturges, <br/>Mr.
              Ingham, we believe, being elected Chairman. Several <br/>proposals respecting the
              purchase were made, but the mode <br/>finally adopted was, that each gentleman present
              should sub- <br/>scribe as much as he felt inclined, and the deficiency,
              what- <br/>ever it might be, should be made up by Dollar Subscriptions
              <br/>from the people at large. Then it was that the fine spirit of <br/>liberality
              shone out preeminent. One gentleman present, <br/>whose hand ever follows the dictates
              of his generous heart, <br/>and whose warmest wishes have ever been for the prosperity
              <br/>of the Fine Arts, put his name down at once for fifteen hun- <br/>dred
              or two thousand dollars; others subscribed a thousand, <br/>some eight and some five
              hundred dollars, and by this means <br/>the purchase money was raised, all but about
              one thousand <br/>dollars. But it should be clearly understood, that however
              <br/>large the amount subscribed by individuals, it only entitles <br/>them to an
              equal vote with the dollar subscriber. So that <br/>the men who subscribed their
              hundreds, placed themselves, <br/>voluntarily, and for the sake of the Art, on a level
              with the <br/>working man who had put down his name upon the dollar <br/>list. Too
              much praise cannot be awarded to these true fos- <br/>terers of the
              beautiful art; while the many, and particularly <br/>the fashionable many, expend
              their so-called enthusiasm <br/>in wordy expletives and mawkish lamentation upon the
              fal- <br/>len state of the Arts in this country, a few gentlemen honor- <br/>ably distinguished as New York merchants, step forward, <br/>and give
              the only substantial proof of their interest in Pain- <br/>ters and the
              Painter’s Art. Again we say, all honor to these <br/>generous men ! their names should
              be placed in every artist’s <br/>studio, for remembrance and eulogy ; and our citizens
              in fu- <br/>ture times, while enjoying the delights and benefits of this
              <br/>liberal institution, should remember with gratitude those to <br/>whom they are
              indebted for its establishment.</p>
               <p>In furtherance of the objects of this public gallery—the <br/>objects being, to our
              mind, the general understanding and <br/>appreciation of fine works of Art—in order we
              say to further <br/>these desirable ends, we shall give a copious criticism on
              <br/>each picture in the gallery.</p>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="head">The Paintings at the American Art-Union.</div>
               <p>The Paintings at the American Art-Union.—The pic- <br/>ture marked No.
              11—property of the Artist—is called the <br/>“Death Struggle.” It is painted by C.
              Deas, of whom wo <br/>shall have more to say by and bye. The subject of the pic- <br/>ture we take to be as follows: A Trapper has been found <br/>trespassing
              upon the Indian hunting ground. He is met by <br/>an Indian—a quarrel ensues, and
              being both mounted a des- <br/>perate struggle commences. Being both bold,
              though wily <br/>and desperate men, we may suppose a long and cautious en- <br/>counter to have taken place—each being aware of the other’s
              <br/>prowess. At length, worn out by skirmishing, they close : <br/>wounds are
              inflicted on either side, but the Indian appears to <br/>have suffered the most. The
              issue of the conflict seems <br/>doubtful, but now a more fearful character is given
              to the <br/>contest. The horses, maddened by the wounds which had <br/>been dealt out
              alike to man and beast, break from the con- <br/>trol of their riders, and
              rush headlong towards a frightful <br/>precipice. The Trapper and the Indian seem to
              cling closer, <br/>each anxious so become the victor, though conscious that
              <br/>certain impending death will speedily conquer both. On, on, <br/>speed the
              horses; wilder and wilder they grow in their flight<div class="pagebreak" id="#page155"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>—the height is gained—without let or pause over they go ! <br/>Man and beast food
              for the Buzzards! But no! their down- <br/>ward progress is arrested by a
              boldly jutting rock. It is in this <br/>position that the artist has chosen to present
              them to the <br/>public.</p>
               <p>On the right hand of the spectator, a bold mass of rocks <br/>jut out from the main
              body, some two or three yards below <br/>the brink. On these rocks the horses and
              their riders have <br/>fallen. The situation of the Indian is by far the most pre- <br/>carious, his horse being upon the outer edge of the rocks, <br/>from
              which it is evident that its violent struggles will speed- <br/>ily
              dislodge it. The Indian has clasped the body of the <br/>Trapper, who holds on with
              his right hand, in which is <br/>his knife, to the limb of a huge tree, which stands
              boldly <br/>out on the extreme point of the land. A beaver, which <br/>had been
              hastily secured by the Trapper, and which was <br/>most probably the cause of the
              dispute, has fixed itself up- <br/>on the naked arm of the Indian, which it
              lacerates most ter- <br/>ribly. On the ground above, an Indian warrior is
              watching <br/>the combat with the most fearful interest depicted upon his
              <br/>face.</p>
               <p>It will be seen from this description, that the subject is <br/>treated with great
              boldness—that there is actual life in every <br/>portion of the picture. The figures
              of the Trapper and the <br/>Indian are drawn with masterly force, and the distinctive
              <br/>characteristics of the opponents preserved with admirable <br/>fidelity ; more
              particularly the features of the two races— <br/>for while the face of the Indian
              exhibits no other expression <br/>than that of tiger-like ferocity, in the face of the
              bold Trap- <br/>per may be discovered, mixed with unmistakeable evidences
              <br/>of indomitable firmness, an expression of horror at his ap- <br/>palling situation. The action of these figures is really ad- <br/>mirable. Every portion of the picture gives evidence of ra- <br/>pid
              improvement in the artist’s conception and execution ; <br/>and in no part is the
              improvement more visible than in the <br/>drawing and coloring of the horses. In his
              previous efforts <br/>the form was certainly there, but it was wooden, texture
              <br/>and all. But in this picture the anatomy is well made out, <br/>and the animals
              have flesh upon their bones, which seems <br/>to quiver as in agony and terror. The
              right eye of the Indian <br/>warrior, watching above, is badly drawn; it is what may
              be <br/>technically called, looking down the cheek; which, from <br/>his position,
              could not be.</p>
               <p>In whatever point we examine this picture—in color, ex- <br/>ecution, or a
              composition—we are compelled to acknowledge <br/>the high talents of the Artist. He
              has grasped the subject <br/>with the hand of a master. There is a bold, daring energy
              <br/>in the design, which gives unquestionable evidence of ori- <br/>ginality—a qualification but rarely to be met with among <br/>the artists of the
              present day; and he has worked out his <br/>design with an intensity of purpose, which
              proves that he <br/>has the true artistic feeling for his profession. There is,
              <br/>however, even now, too much carelessness in his execution. <br/>In the picture
              under notice, the masses of foliage in the <br/>hack ground seem to have been daubed
              on with the finger, <br/>and rubbed off with the coat sleeve.</p>
               <p>Mr. Deas is quite a young man ; he has a long life before <br/>him ; his prospects
              are most auspicious ; and if he be true to <br/>himself and to his Art, he will
              acquire a wide-spread, <br/>honorable, and lasting reputation.</p>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="head">Christ healing the Sick.</div>
               <p>Christ healing the Sick.—The good and the wise have <br/>appreciated, and in the way
              of patronage, have certainly <br/>done justice to this great and moral composition. It
              was in <br/>a philosophical and moral point of view that West ever con- <br/>sidered the department of art which he had embraced as a<br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>profession, and in this sense he always wished to employ it. <br/>This fact is
              nobly evinced in his leaving behind him so im- <br/>perishable a record of
              gospel dispensation as “ Christ Heal- <br/>ing the Sick”—a painting having
              for its basis the 14th and <br/>15th verses of the 21st chapter of Mathews, and
              depicting in <br/>the most vividly truthful manner some sixty individuals <br/>who
              resorted to the Jewish Temple in Jerusalem, about the <br/>year of our Lord 33, and
              there received, at Christ’s hands, a <br/>cure of their many different maladies.</p>
               <p>Mr. Morris, a well-known amateur, has been exhibiting <br/>this great picture through
              some of the states with very grat- <br/>ifying success. It is his intention
              to visit New York this <br/>fall or next spring, and we have no doubt that he will
              reap <br/>a profitable harvest from his speculation upon the good taste <br/>and piety
              of our citizens.</p>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="head">We are full of the expectation that the ensuing season will bring
              forth many beautiful things in the way of landscapes.</div>
               <p>We are full of expectation that the ensuing season will <br/>bring forth many
              beautiful things in the way of landscapes. <br/>The pleasant country is over-run by
              artists from our city, <br/>who are rifling nature in her loveliest and most secret
              haunts. <br/>However we poor town-tied denizens will forgive the thefts,
              <br/>willingly, if properly acknowledged upon canvass, for then <br/>we can revel in
              scenes which we may never be able to visit, <br/>and snuff up in imagination the
              incense of the flowers, <br/>which only bloom for us through the painter’s art.</p>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="head">Through the kindness of the owner</div>
               <p>Through the kindness of the owner, we have been admit- <br/>ted to a
              private view of one of the most exquisite pieces of <br/>sculpture that ever crossed
              the Atlantic. It is the work of <br/>the sculptor to the king of the Belgians. The
              subject is a <br/>female; the title, Coming from the Bath. As it is about to <br/>be
              exhibited, we shall defer our critical account of it. Thus <br/>much however, we will
              say, that in all the attributes of fe- <br/>male loveliness, delicacy and
              roundness of form, perfection of <br/>proportion, intellectuality, gentleness, and
              modesty, it could <br/>hardly be excelled.</p>
               <p>We are happy to say that this exquisite work of art is in <br/>the possession of an
              American gentleman, who saw it in <br/>Belgium, and being struck by its extraordinary
              merit, pur- <br/>chased it at a great price. We shall have more to say
              about <br/>it shortly.</p>
            </div>
        </div>


        <div>
            <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
            <p>The Bell Ringers at Palmo’s.—This very clever com- <br/>pany of wandering
            minstrels have been giving several con- <br/>certs during the past and
            present week at the Tabernacle, <br/>and also at Palmo’s Theatre. Since they last played
            here, <br/>they have travelled almost the entire length and breadth of <br/>this vast
            continent. They have also been to Havanna, Cuba, <br/>&amp;c., &amp;c. Their success has
            been everywhere most signal; <br/>indeed it could scarcely be otherwise, for their
            entertain- <br/>ments are so excellent in their way, and of so popular a
            char- <br/>acter, that they are calculated to please every description of
            <br/>audience. They have much improved since we last heard <br/>them—they have acquired
            a greater degree of dexterity, and <br/>they produce more striking effects. One of their
            most ef- <br/>fective pieces is undoubtedly the Blue Bells of Scotland, with
            <br/>variations. The variations consist of passages of great bril- <br/>liancy and difficulty, which are executed with a precision al- <br/>together remarkable.</p>
            <p>They were encored in several of their performances, and <br/>complied with the wish of
            the people who wanted to hear <br/>the same pieces, by playing entirely different pieces
            at each <br/>encore. A more absurd custom could not possibly exist. <br/>For what do
            people encore a song, if not for the desire to<div class="pagebreak" id="#page156"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>hear it again ? and if such is their wish, why do not public <br/>performers
            condescend to gratify them ? The custom should <br/>be at once abolished.</p>
            <p>Mrs. Timm sang two songs during the evening, but she <br/>seemed nervous, and did not
            acquit herself as well as we <br/>have heard her.</p>
            <p>Master Sconcia played two solos on the violin. He is a <br/>very clever lad, and
            displays much aptitude for the instru- <br/>ment, but he is on the wrong
            track. Why does he expose <br/>himself to such absurd comparison, by striving to play
            com- <br/>positions which Vieuxtemps and Ole Bul have made entire- <br/>ly their own. They are utterly beyond his power, and all <br/>that he can
            hope to accomplish at present, is to render them <br/>with as little caricature as
            possible. We speak more harsh- <br/>ly than we wish, but we do it in all
            kindness. We are sure <br/>that with proper care, Master Sconcia would grow up to be
            <br/>a fine violinist, but if he pursues his present course, his claim <br/>to public
            approbation will cease with his round jackets.</p>
            <p>We advise all our friends to go and hear the Bell ringers.</p>
        </div>



        <div>
            <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
            <a href=""/>
            <div class="note" id="">We continue our extracts from Mr. Murdoch's very inter- <br/>esting
            MS—“ The Stage.”</div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">American Dramatic Writing.</div>
               <p>American Dramatic Writing.—To keep alive a pure and <br/>elevated taste for the
              drama, it is important not only that we <br/>cherish the high classic excellence of
              Shakspeare and the <br/>writers of former times, but that we mould into dramatic
              <br/>form the materials of our own national history, and even <br/>those of
              contemporary life. The stage connot fulfill its whole <br/>office, if it does not
              present, in due proportion, the features <br/>of character as they exist, the story of
              man as he is, the pha- <br/>ses of American life.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Its Materials.</div>
               <p>Its Materials.—And what a world of fit material our <br/>eventful history affords,
              downward from the era of the Indian, <br/>the cavalier, the puritan, the Swede, the
              Hollander, each so <br/>graphically marked in character, action, and costume, aided
              <br/>by wild scenery, startling event, and stirring incident—whe- <br/>ther
              for the lofty style of the tragic pen, or the broad pencil <br/>of grotesque
              humor!</p>
               <p>Who yet has brought out, in the serious drama, the <br/>“ play,” properly
              so-called—the rich materials furnished by <br/>such sources, and by the still nearer
              men and times of the <br/>Indian and French wars, and even the period of the Revolu-
                <br/>tion ? Have not our young writers been too prone to cast <br/>their
              efforts into the mould of the classic tragedy, while they <br/>overlooked the nearer
              access to ‘ men’s business and bosoms,’ <br/>opened by dramatic character and incident
              ? There lies yet <br/>unexplored the whole mine of western life and character, so
              <br/>graphic in itself, so rich in situation and incident; the Roman <br/>grandeur of
              the life of our southern plantations, the quiet <br/>home scenes of rural and village
              life in the nooks and valleys <br/>of New England, so exuberant in quaint and
              picturesque <br/>peculiarity, in sly humor and local manners—yes, and so
              <br/>abundant, too, in instances of the loftiest heroism of romance, <br/>befitting
              the majestic features of her mountain scenery, and <br/>the sternness of her
              climate.</p>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="head">Its Character.</div>
               <p>Its Character.—It is the genius of her young writers that <br/>our country must look
              for a regenerated drama, breathing <br/>the spirit of freedom and of high-toned
              manhood, of pure and <br/>noble sentiment and generous feeling—an ideal of human
              <br/>life, such as may draw from every American heart the re- <br/>sponse
              which we give when we enter the studio of the pain- <br/>ter, who has just
              finished a faithful and speaking portraiture <br/>of our intimate friend. Yes, these
              are the very features: it<br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>is a perfect likeness. Let us have a drama of which we can <br/>say, ' Yes, this
              is our mode of life and character: this is true, <br/>this is real.’ Not that it is
              prosaic and literal, but true— <br/>true to the idea, true to the sentiment—a free not
              a close <br/>copy, but a genuine study of nature.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Its Sentiment.</div>
               <p>Its Sentiment.—I would by no means be understood, how- <br/>ever, as
              disposed to limit American dramatic writers so rigo- <br/>rously, to
              national themes, as to exclude all others. No: an <br/>important end of a national
              drama would be that of imbuing <br/>the mind of our people with appropriate national
              feeling, in <br/>regard to the forms of life and character in other countries.
              <br/>The direct and impartial vision which every American ought <br/>to turn upon the
              doings of men in other lands, should find <br/>fitting reflection in the language of
              our dramatic writers. <br/>The sentiments of the American, as he contemplates the
              <br/>usurpations perpetrated by custom, and the paraphernalia of <br/>ceremony, should
              breathe in their expression his native air <br/>of freedom and disdain. The mirror
              which he holds up to <br/>nature should be pure from every stain of conventional and
              <br/>‘ bated breath.’ Do I assert too much in saying that the <br/>American drama
              ought to be the treasury of free, noble sen- <br/>timent and glowing
              expression, for whatever concerns the <br/>moral and political life of man ?</p>

               <div>
                  <div class="head">Materials of American Tragedy.</div>
                  <p>Materials of American Tragedy.—It has been objected, <br/>by some writers on
                dramatic composition, that modern life, <br/>in no nation, furnishes the appropriate
                themes of the higher <br/>or tragic drama, and that a country so young as ours,
                cannot <br/>offer, in its whole territory, the requisite data. But this
                <br/>question has, I think, been settled by the perfect success of <br/>English
                authors, who have written on subjects drawn from <br/>no remoter era than that of
                the colonization of our own coun- <br/>try. The men of the English
                commonwealth, and of the <br/>times immediately preceding and subsequent, furnish in
                the <br/>vigorous, stern, and lofty stamp of character, of one party, <br/>the
                philosopic and intellectual elevation of another, and the <br/>very recklessness and
                unbridled license of a third, the most <br/>abundant and the most effective
                materials of mental and mo- <br/>ral delineation. They leave nothing
                wanting for the purpo- <br/>ses of graphic effect, rich character, bold
                relief, and vivid <br/>coloring. The whole of that portion of English and Ameri- <br/>can history, is thoroughly dramatic. The mere silent peru- <br/>sal of it by the solitary student, converts the imagination into
                <br/>a theatre, where the monarch and the meanest of his rebel- <br/>lious republican subjects, the courtier and the humble citi- <br/>zen,
                the devotee and the man of the world, the fanatic and <br/>the hypocrite, the hero
                and the saint, the cavalier and the <br/>puritan, the cultivated European, and the
                savage of the Ame- <br/>rican forest, all meet to fret their hour upon
                the busiest stage <br/>that the history of the world has recorded.</p>
                  <p>Regard, too, the “ pith and moment” of the great enter- <br/>prise then
                first agitating the modem world—the great ques- <br/>tion of political
                liberty, in which all the actors just enumera- <br/>ted were more or less
                involved, and there is stamped on that <br/>era an impress of interest as broad and
                deep as humanity it- <br/>self. It is a period which sheds its influence
                on every sub- <br/>sequent stage of man’s history.</p>
               </div>


               <div>
                  <div class="head">American Materials for "Mixed" Plays.</div>
                  <p>American Materials for “ Mixed” Plays.—But grant, <br/>for the moment, that the
                sources whence we might derive a <br/>national drama, are comparatively limited, in
                the deparment <br/>of purely tragic composition,—there still remains that pecu- <br/>liar form of dramatic writing, for which the genius of the
                <br/>Anglo-Saxon race has so marked a predilection, and in which, <br/>hitherto, it
                has so preeminently excelled,—I allude to the <br/>serious and serio-comic play, the
                sphere in which Shakspeare <br/>loved to move.</p>

                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page157"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>

                  <p>Our early history is peculiarly rich in the materials for the <br/>construction of
                this species of the drama. The varieties of <br/>national and individual character
                are, in this period, numer- <br/>ous and distinctly marked, to a degree
                unparalleled in other <br/>times, and in other regions of the world: nor is there
                any <br/>lack of event, or incident, or striking situation, or of field for <br/>the
                display of character and sentiment.</p>
                  <p>The remark applies equally to our own times. The last <br/>ten years afford, on our
                own continent, ample materials of <br/>every description for the composition of
                historical plays of a <br/>character which, were our authors awake to the value of
                the <br/>subject, might live to distant times.</p>
                  <p>The mixed play, in which the serious "business of life pre- <br/>dominates, but does not exclude the free working of humor <br/>and individuality
                in character and domestic incident, is the <br/>staple of the stage. The purely
                tragic and the merely comic <br/>are the extremes of life, and cannot sustain their
                interest, in <br/>dramatic representation, with that firmness and that uni- <br/>formity which belong to the other. It is in this department <br/>of
                the drama, that, as a nation, we are most deficient; and <br/>it is to this that our
                young authors should turn their atten- <br/>tion, as at once an inviting
                and a sure field of action,—for the <br/>writer, whether we regard his personal
                success, or the ef- <br/>fective aid he would render to the stage, by
                attracting to it <br/>the natural, patriotic feeling of the people.</p>
                  <p>Of the regular tragedy we have a large supply already <br/>furnished by the classic
                writers of England. Of broad com- <br/>ic delineation there will always
                be furnished enough to meet <br/>the transient demand for it. Of light and polished
                comedy, <br/>touched by the pen of classical elegance, England itself now
                <br/>affords no specimen. The reserve of sentiment, the smooth <br/>uniformity of
                character, and the tame monotony of life, <br/>which our day exhibits, leaves no
                point of effect, no striking <br/>light, no contrast in color for the pencil of the
                dramatist.</p>
                  <p>This poverty of production in classic comedy, we share in <br/>common with the
                mother country ; and above this disadvant- <br/>age we cannot rise. The
                evil is inwrought with the very <br/>texture of contemporary life. But in the
                department of his- <br/>toric and domestic plays we are rich in
                resources. Let our <br/>writers but develope them.</p>
               </div>


               <div>
                  <div class="head">American Melo-Drame.</div>
                  <p>American Melo-Drame.—Nor need American authors ne- <br/>glect that wide
                field of dramatic display which lies in the <br/>humbler sphere of spectacle, where
                scenery and costume and <br/>array, aided by music, effect so much to excite the
                feelings <br/>of wonder and delight in the juvenile spectator, and those <br/>whose
                confined mode of daily life allows so little scope for <br/>observation and variety,
                and whose faculties are necessarily <br/>athirst for action through the eye.</p>
               </div>


               <div>
                  <div class="head">Historic Melo-Drame.</div>
                  <p>Historic Melo-Drame.—The whole ancient world of his- <br/>tory lies open
                for such purposes to the dramatic writer; and <br/>the displays of Egyptian worship,
                and Grecian art, and Ro- <br/>man triumphs, and chivalric pomp, may all
                be converted in- <br/>to practical lessons in history, imparted through
                the senses, <br/>and imprinted indelibly on the memory. The scenes of Mex- <br/>ican splendor on our own continent, might form an appropri- <br/>ate sphere for similar effects.</p>
               </div>


               <div>
                  <div class="head">Domestic Pieces.</div>
                  <p>Domestic Pieces.—Let dramatic composition assume forms <br/>of truth and dignity,
                of utility and moral effect,—let them, <br/>even in their gayest displays,
                contribute something to the <br/>aliment of the mind ; and one source of objectien
                to the dra- <br/>ma will be entirely removed. We have a convincing proof
                <br/>of the truth of this assertion, in the unprecedented success of <br/>Popular
                domestic piece, entitled The Drunkard, or the <br/>Fallen Saved, as performed at the
                Boston Museum. This <br/>play, acted upwards of a hundred times, continues to
                  draw<br/>
                     <div class="columnbreak"/>
                     <br/>overflowing houses in consequence of the structure of the <br/>piece. It turns
                on scenes, and incidents, and characters, <br/>which appeal, incessantly, to the
                actual feelings and knowl- <br/>edge of the audience. It proves, more
                impressively than <br/>ever, that the drama has its foundation in the human heart,
                <br/>and cannot be eradicated from it; that the best way of reform- <br/>ing the theatre, is to let it take its natural way to the feel- <br/>ings of the people, through the medium of true delineations <br/>of life, which
                are always full of moral instruction. The <br/>crowded audiences which this piece
                attracts from all ranks <br/>and conditions of life, the sanction which its
                excellent effect, <br/>in a moral point of view, has drawn from the most influen-
                  <br/>tial minds, including those within the circle of the clerical
                <br/>profession itself,—all serve to show what dramatic writing <br/>may effect,
                when turned into the channels which we have <br/>suggested.</p>
                  <p>I can imagine no way in which a mind of noble qualities <br/>can impart more
                immediate, more extensive, or more per- <br/>manent benefit to a
                community like ours, than by fusing its <br/>best conceptions into the mould of the
                drama, and thus ren- <br/>dering them at once universally accessible, and
                universally <br/>influential and effective.</p>
               </div>


               <div>
                  <div class="head">Park Theatre.</div>
                  <p>Park Theatre.—On Tuesday evening Mr. &amp; Mrs. Chas. <br/>Kean appeared in
                Shakspeare’s comedy of “ Much Ado about <br/>Nothing.” Mrs. Kean’s exquisite
                performance of Beatrice <br/>is too well known in this city to require any comment.
                On <br/>this occasion her acting charmed us as much as ever, and <br/>left us in
                full possession of the opinion we have long enter- <br/>tained, that she
                need fear no rival in this and most other cha- <br/>racters in legitimate
                comedy. The great novelty of the even- <br/>ing was the first
                appearance—in this country at least—of Mr. <br/>C. Kean in comedy ; and we certainly
                felt much curiosity to <br/>see whether, like his great predecessor Garrick, he
                could be <br/>claimed by either of the antagonistic Muses as her legitimate
                <br/>offspring; and the result has brought us to the conclusion, <br/>that tragedy
                is decidedly his forte ; and that however well <br/>he may conceive and execute such
                characters as Benedick, <br/>Don Felix, and many others, he has one natural defect
                suffi- <br/>cient to mar, in a great measure, the effect of his perform-
                  <br/>ance of them. We allude, of course, to his voice. Where <br/>there
                is a want of euphony in this organ, it is sure to be <br/>more conspicuous, more
                noticeable, in dialogue of a colloquial <br/>nature, than it would be in the
                declamation of tragedy; and <br/>the reason is obvious. In the various passions
                pourtrayed in <br/>tragedy, there are so many transitions and modulations of
                <br/>the voice—(anger, terror, despair, love and melancholy, each <br/>producing an
                almost total change)—that let the imperfection <br/>be ever so great, we lose sight
                of it in the interest of the <br/>scene, and in our admiration of the author’s
                delineation. <br/>The quality of the voice is, indeed, a secondary considera- <br/>tion, and never detracts from our admiration of the genius of <br/>a
                great actor. We need only instance the cases of John Kem- <br/>ble and
                the elder Kean, the former particularly, whose de- <br/>fect in this
                respect was so great, that it gave one the idea, <br/>when hearing him, of a man
                afflicted with the asthma; and <br/>yet he was perhaps, the most noble tragedian
                England ever <br/>produced.</p>
                  <p>We have made these observations, not in any ill will to- <br/>wards Mr.
                Kean; quite the contrary. His conception of Be- <br/>nedick was that of
                an accomplished artist; ho sustained the <br/>spirit, wit, and raciness of the
                character admirably through- <br/>out ; and not a point was lost in his
                hands. He certainly <br/>possesses a true comic vein, and must always please a
                discri- <br/>minating audience.</p>
                  <p>We must not conclude our notice without mentioning Mr. <div class="pagebreak" id="#page158"/>
                     <br/>
                     <div class="columnbreak"/>
                     <br/>Bland, a gentleman engaged by Mr. Simpson as one of his <br/>stock company. Mr.
                Bland enacted the part of Don Pedro <br/>(the Prince)—by no means a difficult part,
                by the bye—but he <br/>shewed, at once, that he was an actor much above the ordi-
                  <br/>nary standard of those who do not come over here as stars. <br/>He
                delivered the poetry with excellent emphasis and discre- <br/>tion, and
                his action is easy, graceful, and gentlemanly. If we <br/>are not much mistaken, he
                is capable of shining in a higher <br/>walk ; but he must abide his time, we
                suppose. We under- <br/>stand he has since admirably played the Banished
                Duke in <br/>“As you Like it;” so that he evidently possesses versatility. <br/>We
                congratulate the manager and the public on his engage- <br/>ment.</p>
                  <p>The only other cast in the play worth mentioning was the <br/>Dogberry of Mr. Bass.
                He played it with much humor, and <br/>elicited the hearty laughter of the audience.
                After listening <br/>to him some few minutes, we thought he was somewhat like
                <br/>the late John Reeve ; and before he had finished, we set him <br/>down as one
                of the best imitators of that droll original we <br/>had ever seen.</p>
                  <p>The comedy was, altogether, well put upon the stage. <br/>There was a due attention
                to costume, scenery, &amp;c. for which <br/>the management deserve much credit.</p>
               </div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>

               <div>
                  <div class="head">The Harpers will immediately resume the publication of Humbolt's
                "Cosmos"</div>
                  <p>The Harpers will immediately resume the publication of <br/>Humbolt’s “ Cosmos” of
                which they have as yet issued only <br/>the fist Part. In London, the work is now
                being published <br/>in monthly numbers. The Appletons will soon have ready <br/>the
                works of Dante with Biography, Notes, etc., etc., in one <br/>large volume, and
                embellished with Flaxman’s designs. <br/>Great preparations are making in the way of
                Annuals and <br/>other Gift Books. Mr. Saunders has nearly ready his “ Mis- <br/>sionary Memorial”—Mr. Robert Hamilton his “ May-Flow- <br/>er”—Mr. John Keese “ The Opal”—Mr. T. S. Arthur “ The <br/>Snow-Flake”—and there
                are one or two others on the tapis. <br/>The two next months will bring forth a
                great variety of new <br/>books in every department.</p>
               </div>


               <div>
                  <div class="head">The "Chambersburg Times" does us the honor</div>
                  <p>The “ Chambersburg Times” does us the honor to make <br/>up the whole of its first
                page from a single number of “ The <br/>Broadway Journal. This would be all very
                well, had it not <br/>forgotten to give us credit for our articles, contributed and
                <br/>editorial—and had it not forgotten not to make certain im- <br/>provements in our compositions to suit its own fancy. Copy- <br/>ing,
                for example, a little poem of our own called “ Lenore”, <br/>the Chambersburg editor
                alters “the damned earth” into “the <br/>cursed earth.” Now, we prefer it damned,
                and will have it <br/>so.</p>
               </div>


               <div>
                  <div class="head">Grand Oratorio of the Seven Sleepers.</div>
                  <p>Grand Oratorio of the Seven Sleepers.—The perform- <br/>ance of this
                Oratorio, under the direction of Mr. George Lo- <br/>der, will take place
                at the Tabernacle on Thursday next, <br/>Sept. l8th. Those who read our remarks upon
                this fine <br/>work by Carl Loewe, in our last number, will need no fur- <br/>ther inducement to urge them to attend its performance.</p>
               </div>

               <div>
                  <div class="head">At the approaching Anniversary Soireé of the Manchester
                Athenæum</div>
                  <p>At the approaching Anniversary Soireé of the Manchester <br/>Athenæum, Thomas Noon
                Talfourd will preside, and Chas. <br/>Dickens, Eugène Sue and many other literary
                celebrities, <br/>will be present.</p>
               </div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">CARD OF REMOVAL. — Mr. W. A. KING, Pro- <br/>fessor of Music and Teacher of the
              Piano Forte and Organ, has <br/>Removed to the First House above Twenty-Fifth Street
              on the Rail- <br/>Road (4th Avenue.)</div>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">J. BALLARD, Professor of the GUITAR, SING- <br/>ING, and FLUTE, No. 135 Spring
              Street.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO-FORTES <br/>CHEAP FOR CASH.—The subscribers have on hand <br/>a handsome
              assortment, 6, 6 1/2 and 7 octave, mahogany and rosewood <br/>pianos, which they will
              variant and sell low for cash or approved pa- <br/>per. <br/>GLENN, ROGERS
              &amp; CO., Manufacturers, <br/>152 Fulton street, East of Broadway.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. <br/>H. WORCESTER, NO. 139 THIRD AVENUE, <br/>Corner of 14th Street,
              respectfully informs his friends and the <br/>public, that he has a good assortment of
              Piano Fortes, in Rosewood <br/>and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons
              wishing to pur- <br/>chase will find it to their advantage to call and
              examine before pur- <br/>chasing elsewhere.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">NEW NOVELS OF GREAT INTEREST, <br/>JUST PUBLISHED BY H. G. DAGGERS, <br/>30 ANN
              STREET, NEW YORK. <br/>THE COTTON LORD. By Mrs. Stone. A Ro- <br/>mance of the Rich
              and Poor, written by a Lady of brilliant ta- <br/>lents. 25 Cents. <br/>FRANKENSTEIN,
              by Mrs. Mary W. Shelley, wife of the illustri- <br/>ous poet. “ It is among
              the most exciting and terrible of modern ro- <br/>mances.”—Tribune. 25
              Cents. <br/>LAWRIE TODD, by John Galt, with an original Preface by the <br/>original
              Lawrie Todd, viz.: Grant Thorburn, Esq. “ Mr. Thorburn’s <br/>Preface is worth more
              than the price asked for the novel.” 25 Cents. <br/>THE NUN ; or, Life in a Convent.
              By one of the Sisterhood. “ A <br/>terrible exposition of the secret practices of
              Roman Catholics.” 25 c. <br/>POOR JACK. By Captain Marryatt, author of Midshipman
              Easy, <br/>Peter Simple, &amp;c. 25 Cents. <br/>N.B. All of the above will be sent for
              One Dollar to any person or- <br/>dering them through Postmasters, who are
              by law authorized to remit <br/>money to publishers. Any Postmaster ordering the above
              shall be <br/>presented with either novel he may select.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">SEVEN SLEEPERS. <br/>UNDER THE DIRECTION OF MR. GEORGE LODER. <br/>THE BRILLIANT
              ORATORIO OF THE SEV- <br/>EN SLEEPERS, will be performed at the TABERNACLE, on
              <br/>Thursday Evening, September 18th, commencing at 8 o’clock. <br/>Mr. H. C. TIMM
              will preside at the organ. <br/>The Solo parts will be performed by the following
              Ladies and Gen- <br/>tlemen : <br/>Antipater, Proconsul at Ephesus, Mr. S. Pearson,
              <br/>Honorio, his wife, Mrs. Strong. <br/>Martinus, Bishop at Ephesus, Mr. S. P.
              Cheney. <br/>Malchus, Mrs. E. Loder, <br/>Serapion, Miss Cheney, <br/>Johannes, Miss
              De Luce, <br/>Constantine, The Seven Sleepers, Mr. J. Johnson, <br/>Dionysius, Mr. S.
              O. Dyers, <br/>Marcianus, Mr. R. Andrews, <br/>Maximianus, Mr. D. S. B. Bennett.
              <br/>The Chorus of Shepherds—Chorus of Priests—Chorus of Warriors <br/>—and chorus of
              the Ephesian People, will be sustained by about one <br/>hundred and fifty performers
              selected with particular reference to their <br/>musical qualifications. <br/>A
              powerful orchestra has been engaged for the occasion. <br/>Tickets 50 cents each, for
              sale at the stores of <br/>Firth &amp; Hall, 1 Franklin Square. <br/>Atwill, 201
              Broadway. <br/>Saxon &amp; Miles, 205 Broadway. <br/>F. Riley, 297 Broadway.
              <br/>Scharfenburgh &amp; Luis, 361 Broadway. <br/>Firth, Hall &amp; Pond, 239
              Broadway. <br/>G. F. Nesbitt, cor. Wall and Water streets—at the door of the Tab-
              <br/>ernacle on the evening of the performance, or of <br/>H. MIGGS, 446
              Broadway.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">A. G. BAGLEY’S <br/>CELEBRATED IMPROVED EVER-POINTED <br/>GOLD PEN <br/>THIS PEN
              RECEIVED THE HIGHEST PRE- <br/>mium at the last Fair of the American Institute, and
              has been pro- <br/>nounced by the First Teachers of Penmanship in the
              country, to be <br/>infinitely superior to any Gold Pen ever before introduced to the
              Ame- <br/>rican public. The lasting properties of this Pen are undoubted,
              owing <br/>to the total absence of corrosibility from any of the inks in use; and the
              <br/>peculiar shape of the nibs—which was first introduced by Bagley— <br/>makes it
              more pleasant to use, renders it less liable to damage, more <br/>easy to repair, and
              prevents the necessity of the great care that other <br/>articles of the kind require.
              <br/>MANUFACTORY 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            </div>

            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page159"/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">A CARD. <br/>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANO- <br/>FORTE, ORGAN,
              &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street, <br/>where his terms for giving instruction
              can be ascertained. my17</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">MARTIN’S <br/>ILLUSTRATED FAMILY BIBLE, <br/>PART VIII. <br/>Published this Day,
              Sept. 8, <br/>Price Twenty-Five Cents. <br/>CONTAINING a magnificent Engraving of the
              “ Ar- <br/>rival of Rebecca.” The notes by the Rev. A. Fletcher, D.D., are
              <br/>practical and devotional, and possess the rare quality of containing <br/>much in
              few words ; the publication, as a work of art, has no equal; <br/>and the fast
              increasing sale is a proof that its merits are appreciated. <br/>Those who have not
              already subscribed are reminded, that a work <br/>embellished with Steel Engravings,
              the value consists in obtaining <br/>proof impressions, therefore early subscribers
              will have a decided ad- <br/>vantage. R. MARTIN &amp; CO. 26 John
              Street.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER. —JAMES <br/>PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near
              Elm. A <br/>Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms mode- <br/>rate. FOR SALE—A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a <br/>great
              bargain for cash.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal <br/>Street, N. Y. <br/>Instruments made with
              the most recent improvements, such as Iron <br/>Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6
              and 7 octaves. They are made <br/>from choice materials, and highly finished, with the
              most faithful <br/>workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the busines
              <br/>N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ. <br/>Piano Fortes on hire by the
              month.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly <br/>Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the
              attention of the musical public to <br/>the elegant and varied assortment he now has
              at his Old Establish- <br/>ment, comer of Cottage Place and Bleecker
              street, which he will sell <br/>at prices unusually low. <br/>J. P. having been
              actively engaged in the business for the last twen- <br/>ty years, and, for
              a large portion of that time manufacturing for two <br/>of the largest Music Stores in
              the city, feels warranted in saying that <br/>his instruments will bear a favorable
              comparison with those of the <br/>best makers in this country or Europe, and that they
              contain all the <br/>real improvements of the day. <br/>Second hand Pianos Bought,
              Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and <br/>Repaired. <br/>New York, April 23d, 1845.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, <br/>(formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart),
              No. 385 Broadway, <br/>will keep a complete assortment of the latest approved Grand
              Action <br/>Piano Fortes, of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
              <br/>guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, <br/>and to
              endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard <br/>prices. Piano Fortes
              Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on <br/>hire.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">THE BŒHM FLUTE. <br/>PHILIP ERNST, Teacher of the Flute and Gui <br/>tar , would
              inform the lovers of Music that he has now for sale <br/>several of the above
              celebrated instruments, constructed in every re- <br/>spect in accordance
              with those now in use at the Paris and London <br/>Royal Academies. To be seen at
              PHILIP ERNST’S Music Saloon, <br/>395 Broadway, near Walker.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">THIS DAY IS PUBLISHED, <br/>VERSE AND PROSE, by Thomas Hood—Part 1, <br/>forming No.
              16 of the Library or Choice Reading, beautifully <br/>printed Price 50 cents. <br/>“
              Of all the humorists, Hood was the most poetical. When deal- <br/>ing with
              the most familiar subjects, whether it might be a sweep be- <br/>wailing
              the suppression of his cry, or a mother searching through St. <br/>Giles’s for her
              lost infant, or a Miss Kilmansegg’s golden childhood— <br/>there was hardly a verse in
              which some touches of heart, or some play <br/>of fancy, did not beckon the laughing
              reader away into far other <br/>Worlds than the jester’s.”—London Athenaum. <br/>“ The
              smile and the sigh were ever blended together; the laugh at <br/>the grotesque idea
              and whimsical imagination, (rarely seeing objects <br/>as others saw them,) and the
              tear which must flow on such pathetic <br/>narratives as Eugene Aram or the Old Elm
              Tree. Without a parallel <br/>and original as Hood was in the ludicrous, his more
              enduring fame <br/>will rest on the exquisitely humane and simply
              compassionate.”—Lite- <br/>rary Gazette. <br/>“ He was the inventer of a
              new sort of guano to fertilize men’s <br/>minds, and to make them produce larger crops
              of good actions: or rath- <br/>er it was an intellectual compost that be
              invented, and the materials <br/>of which were satire softened by kindness, and
              ridicule tempered with <br/>good feeling.”—Hood’s Magazine for June. Published and for
              sale <br/>by WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.</div>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">POPULAR LITERARY NOVELTIES, <br/>RECENTLY ISSUED BY <br/>HARPER AND BROTHERS,
              <br/>NEW YORK. <br/>I. <br/>MISS BEECHER’S DOMESTIC ECONOMY. <br/>A Treatise on
              Domestic Economy, for the Use of young Ladies at <br/>Home and at School. By Catherine
              E. Beecher. Revised Edition, <br/>with many Engravings. 12mo. 75 cents. <br/>" A
              volume of especial value to the domestic circle, comprising a <br/>large amount of
              important instruction respecting the duties of do- <br/>mestic life and the
              educational training of females.”—Courier. <br/>II. <br/>THE DUTY OF AMERICAN WOMEN TO
              <br/>THEIR COUNTRY. <br/>1 vol. 18mo. 37 1/2 cents. <br/>This appeal might well be in
              the hands of every female in the <br/>land ; its design is to aid in the correction of
              abuses in several depart- <br/>ments of popular education. We therefore
              commend the volume to <br/>the especial notice of our readers.—Commercial Advertiser.
              <br/>III. <br/>HUMBOLDT’S COSMOS. <br/>Cosmos: a Survey of the general Physical
              History of the Universe. <br/>By Alexander Von Humboldt. (Publishing in Numbers.)
              <br/>“ A renowned production, by the greatest of scientific writers.”-— <br/>Courier.
              <br/>IV. <br/>DR. ABERCROMBIE’S NEW ESSAYS. <br/>Miscellaneous Essays. By John
              Abercrombie, M. D., author of " In- <br/>quiries into the Intellectual Powers,”
              &amp;c. 1 vol. 18mo. 50 cents. <br/>“ These essays will be read with pleasure and
              profit by all who will <br/>read them.”—Anglo-American. <br/>V. <br/>PRAISE AND
              PRINCIPLE; <br/>or, For what shall I Live ? By the Author of " Conquest and Self-
              <br/>Conquest.” 1vol. 18mo. 37 1/2 cents. <br/>The story is really admirable—equal to
              Sandford and Merton, and <br/>somewhat represents it in general tone and
              manner.—Broadway Jour- <br/>nal. <br/>VI. <br/>BARNES’S NOTES ON EPHESIANS, &amp;c.
              <br/>Notes, explanatory and practical, on the Epistles of Paul to the Ephe- <br/>sians, Philippians, and Colossians. By Albert Barnes. 1vol. 12mo.
              <br/>Engravings. 75 cents. <br/>VII. <br/>PLATO AGAINST THE ATHEISTS; <br/>With
              Critical Notes and Dissertations. By Tayler Lewis, L.L.D. of <br/>New-York University.
              1 vol. 12mo. $1,00. <br/>“ No more acceptable or timely contribution to the cause of
              sound <br/>classical education could possibly have been made than this. The
              <br/>leading object of the work, even paramount to its relation to education, <br/>
              seems to have been fo furnish an antidote to the progressive atheism of <br/>the
              present age.”— Courier Enquirer. <br/>VIII. <br/>TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO, <br/>Newly
              collected from valuable MSS. in the Geographical Societies of <br/>France and Italy,
              with copious notes and illustrations by Hugh Mur- <br/>ray, with Maps,
              &amp;c. 18mo. muslin. Price 50 Cents. <br/>IX. <br/>A PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES,
              <br/>Through the Valley of the Meuse, and the Forest of Ardennes. By <br/>C. Edward
              Anthon. 1vol. 75 cents <br/>" a very pleasing, and more than ordinary useful book of
              travels.” <br/>—Evangelist. <br/>" The volume is replete with antiquarian lore
              relating to the city of <br/>Charlemagne, and the renowned city of Treves. It is
              evidently the <br/>work of a scholar, and cannot fail to enlist a profound
              interest.—Oswe- <br/>go Advertiser. <br/>X. <br/>ENCYCLOPӔDIA OF DOMESTIC
              ECONOMY. <br/>A complete Repertory of all Matters connected with the Economy of
              <br/>Housekeeping. By T. Webster, Esq. Edited, with Additions, &amp;c., <br/>by an
              American Physician. Copiously Illustrated. $3, 50. <br/>" This is decidedly a book for
              the million: it contains all that pre- <br/>cise kind of information
              adapted to the use of families, and which one <br/>may seek for in vain
              elsewhere.”—New-York Evening Gazette.</div>
            </div>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page160"/>

          

            <div>
               <div class="ab">J. F. BROWNE &amp; CO. <br/>MANUFACTURERS OF THE <br/>IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION
              HARP, <br/>By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years with Erard,
              <br/>J.F. BROWNE respectfully informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has
              established himself for <br/>the manufacture and importation of these very beautiful
              instruments, at <br/>281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET. <br/>His arrangements
              are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices, thereby saving
              purchasers the high duties imposed by <br/>Tariff on these Instruments. <br/>J. F.
              Browne would observe, these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
              with all the modem improvements of London and <br/>Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy
              of tone, fineness of touch, and perfectness of mechanism. Particular care is taken to
              fit them for the ex- <br/>tremes of climate in this country, in which
              respect they will be found far superior to any of European manufacture, imported in
              the usual way. <br/>These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and
              professional talent in Europe; among the latter,he would mention N. C Bochsa, <br/>who
              invariably selects from this establishment. <br/>J. F. Browne begs to offer the
              opinions of some of the first professional talent in this country. <br/>Mr. J. F.
              Browne, Sir:—Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making a
              professional use of your Harps, and of testing <br/>their qualities, it affords me
              pleasure to certify, that in point of tone, workmanship, and above all, a solidity
              that stands proof against the in- <br/>constancy of our trying climate,
              they have in all cases given me the most entire satisfaction. I am yours, CHARLES
              THIBAULT, <br/>January, 1845. No. 40 Beach Street, N. Y. <br/>Dear Sir :—I write to
              exrress the delight I experienced in performing on one of your Harps at Sig. Casella’s
              Concert in this city. The <br/>mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly
              superior to any harp I have heard for many years. I remember my old Master,
              <br/>Bochsa, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no
              other. Yours, most truly, H. G. TRUST. <br/>Philadelphia, March 4th, 1844. <br/>&gt;Mr.
              J. F. Browne, Sir :—I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make I
              performed on at the St. George’s Society Concert, <br/>is, in brilliancy of tone,
              touch and elegance of workmanship, the finest I ever played on. This will apply to all
              your Harps. The Grand six <br/>and a half Gothic Double action, is a most splendid
              instrument. Yours, with respect, ELIZABETH SLOMAN. <br/>New York, January 16th, 1845.
              A pupil of N. C. Bochsa. <br/>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir :—Having at your request closely
              scrutinized your double-action Harps, I find they possess the best qualities of the
              <br/>first Makers in Europe combined. That the ease of touch, by which the most
              brilliant tone is obtained, the perfection and ease of modulation, <br/>they are
              superior to any I have used; their elegance of exterior must gratify the most refined
              taste. Your new Grand Gothic six and a half oc- <br/>tavo,is the most
              splendid effort of art yet produced in the musical world; it will give me great
              pleasure in recommending your Harps at every <br/>opportunity. Yours Truly, HENRY
              HORN. <br/>January 12th, 1854. An eminent professor, and Member of the Royal Academy.
              <br/>These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
              show the estimate of persons every way capable of making a <br/>correct decision. J.
              F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the Society of Arts, Philadelphia,
              for his splendid improvements in <br/>this delightful Instrument. <br/>Harps from 300
              to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.</div>
            </div>


          
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">THE <br/>SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER. <br/>B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
              <br/>Published monthly, at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year. <br/>THE
              MESSENGER has been established since <br/>1835, has a large subscription list, and is
              the principal organ of <br/>Southern opinion. <br/>Subscriptions received by John
              Bisco, at the office of the “ Broad- <br/>way Journal," 135 Nassau streeet.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE. <br/>THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE YEARS BY THE AMERICAN
              INSTI- <br/>TUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF HAND PENMANSHIP. <br/>GOLDSMITH’S
              WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY, <br/>No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK. <br/>GOLDSMITH’S
              PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan- <br/>tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and
              young) <br/>in 10 lessons of 1 hour each. <br/>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen
              Dollars, for a thorough course <br/>of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic,
              also Blanks and Sta- <br/>tionery. Payable at the commencement. <br/>Class
              Hours—9 A.M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P.M., daily, for gentlemen, <br/>and from 11 to 1
              o’clock, for ladies. Private instruction given. <br/>For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems of
              Penmanship,” elegantly bound. <br/>Price Five Dollars.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">MUSIC. <br/>A Rare Opportunity of Acquiring a Thorough Musical Education. <br/>G. H.
              DERWORT, Professor of Singing, Guitar and <br/>Piano Forte, has opened a class for
              Young Ladies, from 7 to 10 <br/>years of age, among whom are three of his own
              daughters, whom he <br/>proposes to thoroughly instruct in the art of Singing.
              <br/>Mr. Derwort’s system is the result of many years’ observation and
              <br/>experience, during which he has successfully taught in Germany, Lon- <br/>don, and New York. His method cannot fail to impart to his pupils <br/>a
              clear perception, and a thorough knowledge of the grammatical <br/>principles of
              music, with the ability to harmonize any simple given melody. <br/>Parents and
              Guardians are invited to call at his Rooms, 427 Broad- <br/>way, when every inquiry
              will be answered. <br/>Terms $20 per annum, payable quarterly in advance. Lessons
              <br/>three times a week. <br/>Private instruction as heretofore.</div>
            </div>

            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">WEDDING, VISITING, and PROFESSIONAL <br/>CARDS, engraved and printed at VALENTINE’S,
              1 Beekman <br/>Street—Lovejoy’s Hotel.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">MEDICI SERIES OF ITALIAN PROSE. <br/>PAINE AND BURGESS, 62 JOHN ST., HAVE <br/>just
              published, Nos 2 and 3 of the Medici Series of Italian Prose. <br/>The Florentine
              Histories. By Nicolo Machiavelli. In 2 vols. <br/>Translated by C. Edwards Lester,
              Esq. Price 50 cents per vol. pa <br/> per, 75 cents cloth. <br/>OPINION of jared
              sparks, esq. <br/>"With the Florentine Histories, I am well acquainted. Formed on
              <br/>the classical models of antiquity, it is executed with consummate skill, <br/>few
              historital compositions are so successful in attaining the two great <br/>ends of
              entertainment and instruction. The style is spirited, clear <br/>and vigorous, the
              narrative rapid and condensed, the <br/>reflections of the author, though brief and
              sententious, are always appropriate <br/>and often profound. <br/>There is probably no
              work within the same compass in which the <br/>instructive lessons of History can be
              studied with more profit and ef-fect."</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. The Subscribers, while return- <br/>ing thanks to their numerous
              friends and to the public, would, at <br/>me same time call attention to their Stock
              of Instruments, of six and <br/>seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood and
              mahogany cases. <br/>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department
              of <br/>the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements <br/>to
              the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, <br/>upon
              examination, equal to any in the market. <br/>STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway.
              <br/>Manufactory, 13th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.</div>
            </div>


            <div>
               <div class="ab">Our First Volume. A few copies of the first volume of the Broadway <br/>Journal are
              for sale at the office, either in numbers or neatly bound. <br/>AGENTS FOR THE
              BROADWAY JOURNAL. <br/>Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass. Colon Sc Adriance,
              Philadelphia- <br/>R.G.H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct. Thos. H. Pease, New Haven, Ct.
              <br/>M. Baullemet, Mobile, Ala. J. C. Morgan, New-Orleans. <br/>Robinson &amp; Jones,
              Cincinnati, O. W.W. Kingsley, New-London, Ct. <br/>D.M. Dewey, Rochester, N.Y. G. N.
              Beesley, Utica, N. Y. <br/>J. Robertaon, Syracuse, N. Y. H. B. Strang, Peekskill, N.
              Y. <br/>W.E. Russell, Schenectady, N.Y. Haliburton &amp; Dudley, Boston, Ms. <br/>Levi
              Willard, Troy, N.Y. S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass. <br/>G. Jones, Albany, N.Y. Peter
              Cooke, Hartford, Ct. <br/>S.F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N.Y. H. Esten, Providence, R.I.
              <br/>Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore, Md. Safford &amp; Park, Norwich, Ct. <br/>S. Hart,
              sen. Charleston, S. C.</div>
            </div>

        </div>
      </div>
    </div>
   <div class="back">
        </div>
</div>
