<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450802</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 2.      NEW YORK, SATURDAY, AUGUST 2, 1845.      NO. 4.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>EDITED BY
         
         <br></br>EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau St.
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">       
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">To Isa Singing</div>
         <div class="biblPage">49</div>
         <div class="head">To Isa Singing.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Upon thy lips now lies
            
            <br></br>The music-dew of love;
            
            <br></br>And in thy deep blue eyes,--
            
            <br></br>More mild than Heaven above--
            
            <br></br>The meekness of the dove.
            
            <br></br>More sweet than the perfume
            
            <br></br>Of snow-white jessamine,
            
            <br></br>When it is first in bloom,
            
            <br></br>Is that sweet breath of thine,
            
            <br></br>Which mingles now with mine.
            
            <br></br>Like an AEolian sound
            
            <br></br>Out of an ocean shell,
            
            <br></br>Which fills the air around
            
            <br></br>With music, such us fell
            
            <br></br>From lips of Isfrafel,      
            
            <br></br>Over thy lips now flow,
            
            <br></br>Out of thy heart, for me,
            
            <br></br>The songs, which none can know
            
            <br></br>But him who hopes to be
            
            <br></br>For evermore with thee.           
            
            <br></br>And like the snow-white Dove
            
            <br></br>Frightened from earth at even--
            
            <br></br>On tempests borne above--
            
            <br></br>My swift-winged soul is driven
            
            <br></br>Upon thy voice to heaven!
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">T. H. CHIVERS.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Business Man</div>
         <div class="biblPage">49</div> 
         <div class="head">The Business Man.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Method is the soul of business.--Old Saying.</div>
         
         <p>I am a business man. I am a methodical man. Method
            is the thing, after all. But there are no people I more heartily despise, than your eccentric fools who prate about method without understanding it; attending strictly to its letter,
            and violating its spirit. These fellows are always doing the
            most out-of-the-way things in what they call an orderly manner. Now here--I conceive--is a positive paradox. True
            method appertains to the ordinary and the obvious alone,
            and cannot be applied to the outre. What definite idea can
            a body attach to such expressions as "a methodical Jack o'
            Dandy," or "a systematical Will o' the Wisp?"
         </p>
         
         <p>My notions upon this head might not have been so clear
            as they are, but for a fortunate accident which happened to
            me when I was a very little boy. A good-hearted old Irish
            nurse (whom I shall not forget in my will) took me up one
            day by the heels, when I was making more noise than was
            necessary, and, swinging me round two or three times, d--d
            
         </p>
         <p>my eyes for "a skreeking little spalpeen," and then knocked my head into a cocked hat against the bed-post. This, I
            say, decided my fate, and made my fortune. A bump arose
            at once on my sinciput, and turned out to be as pretty an organ of order as one shall see on a summer's day. Hence that
            
            positive appetite for system and regularity which has made
            me the distinguished man of business that I am.
         </p>
         
         <p>If there is any thing on earth I hate, it is a genius. Your
            geniuses are all arrant asses--the greater the genius the
            greater the ass--and to this rule there is no exception whatever. Especially, you cannot make a man of business out of
            a genius, any more than money out of a Jew, or the best nutmegs out of pine-knots. The creatures are always going off
            at a tangent into some fantastic employment, or ridiculous
            speculation, entirely at variance with the "fitness of things,"
            and having no business whatever to be considered as a business at all. Thus you may tell these characters immediately
            by the nature of their occupations. If you ever perceive
            a man setting up as a merchant, or a manufacturer ; or going into the cotton or tobacco trade, or any of those eccentric pursuits; or getting to be a dry-goods dealer, or soapboiler, or something of that kind; or pretending to be a
            lawyer, or a blacksmith, or a physician--anything out of the
            usual way--you may set him down at once as a genius, and
            then, according to the rule-of-three, he's an ass.
         </p>
         
         <p>Now I am not in any respect a genius, but a regular business man. My Day-book and Ledger will evince this in a
            minute. They are well kept, though I say it myself; and,
            in my general habits of accuracy and punctuality, I am not
            to be beat by a clock. Moreover, my occupations have been
            always made to chime in with the ordinary habitudes of my
            fellow men. Not that I feel the least indebted, upon this
            score, to my exceedingly weak-minded parents, who, beyond
            doubt, would have made an arrant genius of me at last, if
            my guardian angel had not come, in good time, to the rescue. In biography the truth is everything, and in auto-biography it is especially so--yet I scarcely hope to be believed
            when I state, however solemnly, that my poor father put me,
            when I was about fifteen years of age, into the countinghouse of what he termed "a respectable hardware and commission merchant doing a capital bit of business!" A capiital bit of fiddlestick! However, the consequence of this fol
            ly was, that in two or three days, I had to be sent home to
            my button-headed family in a high state of fever, and with
            a most violent and dangerous pain in the sinciput, all round
            about my organ of order. It was nearly a gone case with
            me then--just touch-and-go for six weeks--the physicians
            giving me up and all that sort of thing. But, although I suffered much, I was a thankful boy in the main. I was saved
            from being a "respectable hardware and commission merchant, doing a capital bit of business," and I felt grateful to the
            protuberance which had been the means of my salvation, as
            well as to the kind-hearted female who had originally put these
            means within my reach.
         </p>
         
         <p>The most of boys run away from home at ten or twelve
            years of age, but I waited till I was sixteen. I don't know
            that I should have gone, even then, if I had not happened
            to hear my old mother talking about setting me up on my own
            hook in the grocery way. The grocery way!--only think of 
            
            that! I resolved to be off forthwith, and try and establish
            myself in some decent occupation, without dancing attendance
            any longer upon the caprices of these eccentric old people,
            and running the risk of being made a genius of in the end. In
            this project I succeeded perfectly well at the first effort, and
            by the time I was fairly eighteen, found myself doing an extensive and profitable business in the Tailor's Walking-Advertisement line.
         </p>
         
         <p>I was enabled to discharge the onerous duties of this profession, only by that rigid adherence to system which formed
            the leading feature of my mind. A scrupulous method characterised my actions, as well as my accounts. In my case, it
            was method--not money---which made the man: at least all
            of him that was not made by the tailor whom I served. At
            nine, every morning, I called upon that individual for the
            clothes of the day. Ten o'clock found me in some fashionable promenade or other place of public amusement. The
            precise regularity with which I turned my handsome person
            about, so as to bring successively into view every portion of
            the suit upon my back, was the admiration of all the knowing men in the trade. Noon never passed without my bringing home a customer to the house of my employers, Messieurs Cut and Comeagain. I say this proudly, but with
            tears in my eyes--for the firm proved themselves the basest of ingrates. The little account about which we quarreled and finally parted, cannot, in any item, be thought overcharged, by gentlemen really conversant with the nature of
            the business. Upon this point, however, I feel a degree of
            proud satisfaction in permitting the reader to judge for himself. My bill ran thus:
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Messrs. Cut and Comeagain, Merchant Tailors,
            
            <br></br>                      To Peter Proffit, Walking Advertiser, Drs.
            
            <br></br>July 10. To promenade, as usual, and customer brought home, $00 25
            
            <br></br>July 11. To    do           do.             do.                 25
            
            <br></br>July 12. To one lie, second class; damaged black cloth sold
            
            <br></br>            for invisible green,                                25
            
            <br></br>July 13. To one lie, first class, extra quality and size; recom-
            
            <br></br>            mending milled sattinet as broadcloth,              75
            
            <br></br>July 20. To purchasing bran new paper shirt collar or dickey,
            
            <br></br>            to set off gray Petersham,                           2
            
            <br></br>Aug. 15. To wearing double-padded bobtail frock, (thermo-
            
            <br></br>            meter 706 in the shade,)                            25
            
            <br></br>Aug. 16. Standing on one leg three hours, to show off new-
            
            <br></br>        style strapped pants, at 12 1/2 cts. per leg, per hour, 37 1/2
            
            <br></br>Aug. 17. To promenade, as usual, and large customer brought
            
            <br></br>            home, (fat man,)                                    50
            
            <br></br>Aug. 18. To      do.          do.          (medium size,)       25
            
            <br></br>Aug. 19. To      do,          do. (small man and bad pay,)       6  
            
            <br></br>                                                               $2 96 1/2
         </div>
         
         <p>The item chiefly disputed in this bill was the very moderate charge of two pennies for the dickey. Upon my word of
            honor, this was not an unreasonable price for that dickey.
            It was one of the cleanest and prettiest little dickeys I ever
            saw; and I have good reason to believe that it effected the
            sale of three Petershams. The elder partner of the firm, however, would allow me only one penny of the charge, and
            took it upon himself to show in what manner four of the same
            sized conveniences could be got out of a sheet of foolscap.
            But it is needless to say that I stood upon the principle of the
            thing. Business is business, and should be done in a business way. There was no system whatever in swindling me
            out of a penny--a clear fraud of fifty per cent.--no method in
            any respect. I left, at once, the employment of Messieurs Cut
            and Comeagain, and set up in the Eye-Sore line by myself--
            one of the most lucrative, respectable, and independent of
            the ordinary occupations.
         </p>
         
         <p>My strict integrity, economy, and rigorous business habits,
            here again came into play. I found myself driving a flourishing trade, and soon became a marked man upon 'Change.
            
            The truth is, I never dabbled in flashy matters, but jogged
            on in the good old sober routine of the calling--a calling in
            which I should, no doubt, have remained to the present
            hour, but for a little accident which happened to me in the
            prosecution of one of the usual business operations of the profession. Whenever a rich old hunks, or prodigal heir, or
            bankrupt corporation, gets into the notion of putting up a
            palace, there is no such thing in the world as stopping either of them, and this every intelligent person knows. The
            fact in question is indeed the basis of the Eye-Sore trade.
            As soon, therefore, as a building-project is fairly afoot by one
            of these parties, we merchants secure a nice corner of the
            lot in contemplation, or a prime little situation just adjoining
            or right in front. This done, we wait until the palace is halfway up, and then we pay some tasty architect to run us up
            an ornamental mud hovel, right against it; or a Down-East
            or Dutch Pagoda, or a pig-sty, or any ingenious little bit of
            fancy work, either Esquimau, Kickapoo, or Hottentot. Of
            course, we can't afford to take these structures down under a
            bonus of five hundred per cent, upon the prime cost of our
            lot and plaster. Can we? I ask the question. I ask it of
            business men. It would be irrational to suppose that we can.
            And yet there was a rascally corporation which asked me to
            do this very thing--this very thing! I did not reply to their
            absurd proposition, of course; but I felt it a duty to go that
            same night, and lamp-black the whole of their palace. For
            this, the unreasonable villains clapped me into jail; and the
            gentlemen of the Eye-Sore trade could not well avoid cutting
            my connexion when I came out.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Assault and Battery business, into which I was now
            forced to adventure for a livelihood, was somewhat ill adapted to the delicate nature of my constitution ; but I went to
            work in it with a good heart, and found my account, here as
            heretofore, in those stern habits of methodical accuracy which
            had been thumped into me by that delightful old nurse--I
            would indeed be the basest of men not to remember her well
            in my will. By observing, as I say, the strictest system in
            all my dealings, and keeping a well regulated set of books, I
            was enabled to get over many serious difficulties, and, in the
            end, to establish myself very decently in the profession. The
            truth is, that few individuals, in any line, did a snugger little
            business than I. I will just copy a page or so out of my
            Day-Book; and this will save me the necessity of blowing
            my own trumpet--a contemptible practice, of which no highminded man will be guilty. Now, the Day-Book is a thing
            that don't lie.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Jan. 1.--New Year's day. Met Snap in the street, groggy. Mem--he'll do. Met Gruff shortly afterwards, blind
            drunk. Mem--he 11 answer, too. Entered both gentlemen
            in my Ledger, and opened a running account with each.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Jan 2.--Saw Snap at the Exchange, and went up and trod
            on his toe. Doubled his fist, and knocked me down. Good!
            --got up again. Some trifling difficulty with Bag, my attorney, I want the damages at a thousand, but he says that,
            for so simple a knock-down, we can't lay them at more than
            five hundred. Mem--must get rid of Bag--no system at all.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Jan 3. Went tot he theatre, to look for Gruff. Saw him
            sitting in a side box, in the second tier, between a fat lady
            and a lean one. Quizzed the whole party through an opera
            glass, till I saw the fat lady blush and whisper to G. Went
            round, then, into the box, and put my nose within reach of
            his hand. Wouldn't pull it--no go. Blew it, and tried
            again no go. Sat down then, and winked at the lean lady,
            when I had the high satisfaction of finding him lift me up by
            the nape of the neck, and fling me over into the pit. Neck dislocated, and right leg capitally splintered. Went home in 
            
            high glee, drank a bottle of champagne, and booked the
            young man for five thousand. Bag says it'll do.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Feb. 15.--Compromised the case of Mr. Snap. Amount
            entered in Journal--fifty cents--which see.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Feb.16.--Cast by that villain, Gruff, who made me a present of five dollars. Costs of suit, four dollars and twenty-five
            cents. Nett profit--see Journal--seventy-five cents."
         </p>
         
         <p>Now, here is a clear gain, in a very brief period, of no less
            than one dollar and twenty five cents --this is in the mere
            cases of Snap and Gruff; and I solemnly assure the reader
            that these extracts are taken at random from my Day-Book.
         </p>
         
         <p>It's an old saying, and a true one, however, that money is
            nothing in comparison with health. I found the exactions
            of the profession somewhat too much for my delicate state
            of body ; and, discovering, at last, that I was knocked all out
            of shape, so that I didn't know very well what to make of
            the matter, and so that my friends, when they met me in the
            street, could'nt tell that I was Peter Proffit at all, it occurred 
            to me that the best expedient I could adopt, was to alter my
            line of business. I turned my attention, therefore, to MudDabbling, and continued it for some years.
         </p>
         
         <p>The worst of this occupation, is, that too many people take
            a fancy to it, and the competition is in consequence excessive.
            Every ignoramus of a fellow who finds that he hasn't brains
            in sufficient quantity to make his way as a walking advertiser, or an eye-sore-prig, or a salt and batter man, thinks, of
            course, that he'll answer very well as a dabbler of mud. But
            there never was entertained a more erroneous idea than that
            it requires no brains to mud-dabble. Especially, there is nothgin to be made in this way without method. I did only a retail business myself, but my old habits of system carried me
            swimmingly along. I selected my street-crossing, in the first
            place, with great deliberation, and I never put down a broom
            in any part of the town but that. I took care, too, to have a
            nice little puddle at hand, which I could get at in a minute.
            By these means I got to be well known as a man to be trusted ; and this is one-half the battle, let me tell you, in trade.
            Nobody ever failed to pitch me a copper, and got over my
            crossing with a clean pair of pantaloons. And, as my business habits, in this respect, were sufficiently understood, I
            never met with any attempt at imposition. I would'nt have
            put up with it, if I had. Never imposing upon any one myself, I suffered no one to play the possum with me. The
            rauds of the banks of course I couldn't help. Their suspension
            put me to ruinous inconvenience. These, however, are not
            individuals, but corporations ; and corporations, it is very
            well known, have neither bodies to be kicked, nor souls to be
            damned.
         </p>
         
         <p>I was making money at this business, when, in an evil mo_
            ment, I was induced to merge it in the Cur-Spattering--a somewhat an alogous, but, by no means, so respectable a profession. My location, to be sure, was an excellent one, being central, and I had capital blacking and brushes. My little dog, too, was quite fat and up to all varieties of snuff.
            He had been in the trade a long time, and, I may say, understood it. Our general routine was this:--Pompey, having rolled himself well in the mud, sat upon end at the shop
            door, until he observed a dandy approaching in bright boots.
            He then proceeded to meet him, and gave the Wellingtons a 
            rub or two with his wool. Then the dandy swore very much,
            and looked about for a boot-black. There I was, full in his
            view, with blacking and brushes. It was only a minute's
            work, and then came a sixpence. This did moderately well
            for a time;--in fact, I was not avaricious, but my dog was.
            I allowed him a third of the profit, hut he was advised to in-
            
            sist upon half. This I could'nt stand--so we quarreled and
            parted.
         </p>
         
         <p>I next tried my hand at the Organ-Grinding for a while,
            and may say that I made out pretty well. It is a plain, straight forward business, and requires no particular abilities. You can
             get a music-mill for a mere song, and, to put it in order, you
            I have but to open the works, and give them three or four
             smart raps with a hammer. It improves the tone of the thing,
            for business purposes, more than you can imagine. This
            done, you have only to stroll along, with the mill on your
            back, until you see tan-bark in the street, and a knocker
            wrapped up in buckskin. Then you stop and grind; looking as if you meant to stop and grind till doomsday. Presently a window opens, and somebody pitches you a sixpence,
            with a request to "Hush up and go on," &amp;c. I am aware
            that some grinders have actually afforded to "go on" for this
            sum; but for my part, I found the necessary outlay of capital
            too great, to permit of my "going on" under a shilling.
         </p>
         
         <p>At this occupation I did a good deal; but, somehow, I was
            not quite satisfied, and so finally abandoned it. The truth
            is, I labored under the disadvantage of having no monkey--
            and American streets are so muddy, and a Democratic rabble
            is so obtrusive, and so full of demnition mischievous little
            boys.
         </p>
         
         <p>I was now out of employment for some months, but at
            length succeeded, by dint of great interest, in procuring a sit
            uation in the Sham-Post. The duties, here, are simple, and
            not altogether unprofitable. For example:--very early in
            the morning I had to make up my packet of sham letters.
            Upon the inside of each of these I had to scrawl a few lines
            --on any subject which occurred to me as sufficiently mysterious--signing all the epistles Tom Dobson, or Bobby
            Tompkins, or anything in that way. Having folded and sealed all, and stamped them with sham post-marks--New Orleans, Bengal, Botany Bay, or any other place a great way
            off--I set out, forthwith, upon my daily route, as if in a very
            great hurry. I always called at the big houses to deliver the
            letters, and receive the postage. Nobody hesitates at paying for a letter--especially for a double one--people are
            such fools--and it was no trouble to get round a corner before
            there was time to open the epistles. The worst of this profession was, that I had to walk so much and so fast; and
            so frequently to vary my route. Besides, I had serious scruples of conscience. I can't bear to hear innocent individuals
            abused--and the way the whole town took to cursing Tom
            Dobson and Bobby Tompkins, was really awful to hear. I
            washed my hands of the matter in disgust.
         </p>
         
         <p>My eighth and last speculation has been in the Cat-Growing way. I have found this a most pleasant and lucrative
            business, and, really, no trouble at all. The country, it is
            well known, has become infested with cats--so much so of
            late, that a petition for relief, most numerously and respectably signed, was brought before the legislature at its last memorable session. The assembly, at this epoch, was unusually
            well-informed, and, having passed many other wise and
            wholesome enactments, it crowned all with the Cat-Act. In
            its original form, this law offered a premium for cat-heads,
            (fourpence a-piece) but the Senate succeeded in amending
            the main clause, so as to substitute the word """"tails" for
            "heads." This amendment was so obviously proper, tha
            the house concurred in it nem. con.
         </p>
         
         <p>As soon as the Governor had signed the bill, I invested my
            whole estate in the purchase of Toms and Tabbies. At first,
            I could only afford to feed them upon mice (which are cheap)
            but they fulfilled the Scriptural injunction at so marvellous
            
            a rate, that I at length considered it my best policy to be liberal, and so indulged them in oysters and turtle. Their
            tails, at the legislative price, now bring me in a good income;
            for I have discovered a way, in which, by means of Macassar oil, I can force three crops in a year. It delights me to
            find, too, that the animals soon get accustomed to the thing,
            and would rather have the appendages cut off than otherwise. I consider myself, therefore, a made man, and am
            bargaining for a country seat on the Hudson.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Song</div>
         <div class="biblPage">52</div>
         <div class="head">Song.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Hush! a spirit from afar
            
            <br></br>Quits its heavenly throne--
            
            <br></br>Glorious as the evening star
            
            <br></br>In the sky alone.
            
            <br></br>Hush! it is a spirit laden!
            
            <br></br>With a balm for pain;
            
            <br></br>And this snowy phantom, maiden,
            
            <br></br>Is called Hope by men.
            
            <br></br>See her wings are shadowing thee!
            
            <br></br>Softly!--let it come;
            
            <br></br>Prophet 'tis, to thee and me,
            
            <br></br>Of a happy home.
            
            <br></br>Softly! or its wings will close--
            
            <br></br>Now approaching near it,
            
            <br></br>Like a storm-sign to a rose.
            
            <br></br>Stalks another spirit.
            
            <br></br>Ebon-plumed as moonless night,
            
            <br></br>With no lights about;
            
            <br></br>Maiden, drive it from thy sight!
            
            <br></br>For its name is Doubt.
            
            <br></br>See its wings are shadowing thee.
            
            <br></br>Never let it come;
            
            <br></br>Prophet 'tis, to thee and me,
            
            <br></br>Of a troubled home.
            
            <br></br>Doubt the fallen seraph is,
            
            <br></br>Hope is gloomy never ;
            
            <br></br>Then the better angel kiss,
            
            <br></br>And hope on for ever.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">E. H. BURRINGTON.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">William Wirt</div>
         <div class="biblPage">52</div>
         <div class="head">William Wirt.</div>
         
         <p>Perhaps there was no individual in our country more highly endowed with intellectual gifts than the late William
            Wirt--the greatest public blunder of whose whole career
            was that late in life, and at the eleventh political hour he
            suffered himself to be announced as a candidate for the Presidency, by a party with whom he had not before acted.
            But, be this as it may, all must admit who knew him, that
            whatever Mr. Wirt did, he did conscientiously. We all
            know and feel that to "err is human," and we have yet to
            learn that error is a proof of selfishness. The Roman Cato,
            when he found that
            "This world was made for Caesar,"
            flew to suicide. He might have shunned the deed, and outlived Caesar, as Mr. Wirt did the excitement which made
            him a Presidential candidate, and still, like him, have served
            his country. "The post of honor is a private station" oftener than politicians are aware of; but still, without guile,
            they have often quit it to return to it without reproach. Unlit this event, Mr. Wirt pursued the even tenor of his profession through a long life, dignifying it with the official
            statesmanship of Attorney General of the United States, and
            not as a mere lawyer, who, like a drudge-horse, can only go
            in the gears of a particular vehicle, but adorning and illustrating it with literature and science. His knowledge of
            history, and of the ancient and modern classics, was as profound as his legal acquirements, while his political information and sagacity kept pace with his other improvements.
            His genius was of the first order, and he improved it with
            the most sedulous care. He exerted his mind at times as an
            author, then an orator, and daily as a lawyer, while his efforts in each department improved his general powers, and
            gave him that variety of information and knowledge which,
            when combined with genius, makes what Mr. Wirt really
            was, a truly great man. Not great only in politics, literature, or law, but great in each and all, like Lord Brougham.
            Many of his countrymen were his superiors in some departments of learning, as they may be said to have been his superiors in some natural endowments--but, for universality
            and variety of talent, he was not surpassed.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Wirt had none of the adventitious aids of high birth,
            fortune, and connexions to help him up the steep of Fame.
            He was compelled to force his own way, unaided and unfriended ; and, like many other great men of our country, he
            taught school for a maintenance while he studied law. It
            was during that time, while he was a student, or immediately after he was admitted to practice, that he wrote the
            letters of the "British Spy." The description of the novi
            homines, the new men, which he so eloquently gives in one
            of those letters, applied aptly to himself. The eloquence
            with which he describes the elevated purposes of oratory,
            exhibited his own devotion to the art, while it showed his
            capacity of excelling in it.
         </p>
         
         <p>It may be said to be almost the peculiar privilege of an
            American to win his own way by the gifts which Nature has
            given him, with the certainty that success will wait on merit. Wealth and family influence, it is true, have great
            weight in the start of a young man; but, in the long run,
            superior talents will gain the prize, no matter what may
            have been the early disadvantages of their possessor, provided the resolution to be true to himself comes not too late.
            The history of almost every departed, as well as of almost
            every living worthy of our country, proves this remark ; and
            it is right that it should be so. Perhaps this, more than any
            other feature in a Republic, tends to its durability, while it
            renders it glorious. The great mass of the people are seldom
            wrong in their judgments, and therefore it is that with them
            talents meet with a just appreciation whenever they become
            known--at least talents for oratory.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Wirt had all the qualification for obtaining the popular good will. He possessed a fine person, remarkable
            amenity of manners, colloquial qualities of the first order,
            wit at will, and he abounded in anecdotes, which he related
            with remarkable pleasantness and tact. A stranger, on entering an assemblage where Mr. Wirt was, would immediately on perceiving him, have supposed him a superior man.
            His person was above the middle height, with an inclination
            to corpulency ; his countenance was "sicklied o'er with the
            pale cast of thought;" his mouth was finely formed, and a
            physiognomist would have noted that the compression of his
            lips denoted firmness, and his smile good humored irony.
            He had a Roman nose, the eye of cerulean blue, with a remarkable arch expression when he was animated, and of
            calm thoughtfulness when his features were in repose. His
            forehead was not high; but it was broad, with the phreno
            
            logical developments strongly marked--particularly the poetic and perceptive faculties. His hair was sandy, and his
            head bald on the top, which, with a Byronian anxiety, he
            tried to hide by combing the hair up over the baldness; and
            it was much his custom, when engaged in an oratorical display, to preserve its adjustment by passing his hands over it.
            He was much more careful in this regard than is the eloquent
            and chivalric Preston, who, though he wears a wig, seems
            not only indifferent as to who knows it, but of the wig itself;
            for in the sturdy breeze which blew over the Canton Course,
            at the Baltimore Convention, it nearly left him--he the while
            apparently unconscious, as he fulminated to the vast and
            wrapt multitude. Well! the Carolinian may not love the
            laurel as Csesar loved it--because it hid his baldness--but he
            deserved to have it voted to him long ago for his eloquence.
         </p>
         
         <p>General Harrison used to tell, as he gladdened the hearth
            at the Bend with stories of the worthies past and present,
            how he remembered to have seen Patrick Henry, in the heat
            of his glorious declamation, twist the back of his wig until it
            covered his brows; and any one who has heard the Senator
            from Carolina, would say that the resemblance between
            himself and his illustrious relative, extended from great
            things to small.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the first glance at Mr. Wirt's countenance, when he
            was not engaged in conversation or business, the observer
            would have been struck with the true dignity of the man,
            whose mind seemed to hold all its energies in perfect control.
            His self-possession was absolute. When he arose to address
            the court or jury there was no hurry, no agitation about
            him, as we perceive in many men. On the contrary, he 
            stood collected, while his enunciation was deliberate and
            slow. He stated his position with great simplicity--in fact,
            it was generally a self-evident one, the applicability of which
            to the case, if it were intricate and doubtful, the hearer
            might in vain endeavor to trace; but when he heard the orator to the conclusion, he would wonder that he had fancied
            any uncertainty about it: for Mr. Wirt would lead him on
            by the gentlest gradations until he was convinced. It may
            be mentioned, too, that Mr. Wirt, like Mr. Clay, was a
            great taker of snuff, and he handed his box with a grace
            which would have rivalled even that of the Kentuckian.
            Lord Chatham, it was said, made his crutch a formidable
            weapon of oratory: "You talk of conquering America,
            sir,''said he, "I might as well pretend to drive it before:
            me with this crutch." And so Mr. Wirt made, and Mr.
            Clay makes, his snuff-box an oratorical weapon. Mr. Wirt's
            language was at times almost oriental--his figures being of
            the boldest, and his diction correspondent. His speeches in
            Burr's trial show this, though latterly he chastened, somewhat, both his diction and his thoughts. He sustained himself well in the highest flight of eloquence, his hearers having no fear that he would fall from his eminence, like him
            in the fable, with the waxen wings. On the contrary, the
            hearer felt confident of his intellectual strength, and yielded
            his whole feelings to him without that drawback we experience in listening to some of the ablest speakers, who often
            have a glaring imperfection, which is continually destroying
            the effect of their eloquence. Mr. Wirt studied oratory with
            Ciceronian care, and, in the recklessness with which he
            let fly the arrows of his wit, he much resembled the Roman.
            The power of ridiculing his adversary was Mr. Wirt's forte.
            The appropriate manner in which he applied an anecdote
            was admirable. After he had demonstrated the absurdity of
            his opponent's arguments, with a clearness that the most critical logician would have admired; after he had illustrated
            
            his position with all the lights of law,--that law whose seat,
            Hooker said, "is the bosom of God, and whose voice is the
            harmony of the world,"--and when Mr. Wirt had a strong
            case he explored every field of literature and science, bringing
            their joint sanction to his purposes;--after he had called up the
            truths of philosophy, the experience of history, and the beauties of poetry, all coming like spirits thronging to his call;
            after he had expatiated upon the cause with such reflections
            as you would suppose Barrow or Tillotson to have used
            when speaking of the "oppressor's wrong"; after he had
            done all this, Mr. Wirt would, if the opposite party deserved
            the infliction, pour forth upon him a lava-like ridicule, which
            flamed while it burned, and which was at once terrible and
            beautiful--terrible from its severity and truth, and beautiful
            from the chaste language in which it was conveyed.
         </p>
         
         <p>  Mr. Wirt always struck me as being very much like the
            late Prime Minister of England, Canning, in his mind. Canning wanted, and Wirt, in a degree, the power of calling up
            and controlling the stronger and deeper passions of our nature. He had not that withering scorn which Brougham
            possesses so strongly, nor could he rise above the tempset of
            popular commotion, as he tells us Patrick Henry could, and
            soar with "supreme dominion." He wanted deep passion.
            Comparing him with the leading orators of our country, it
            would be said that Clay far surpassed him in the power of
            controlling a miscellaneous assemblage, when the public
            mind was deeply agitated: that Pinckney, on a question of
            feudal lore,--Webster in profundity, and on constitutional
            law--Calhoun in chivalrous statesmanship, and Preston in
            the glow of vehement declamation--would have had the advantage over him. But, before an auditory who loved to mingle wit with argument, and elegance with strength, who
            would make truth more beautiful by the adornments of poetry, and poetry useful as the handmaid of truth, adding to
            all those exterior graces which make oratory so captivating
            --before such an auditory it may be said, without great hesitation, that Mr. Wirt would have surpassed either of them
            in general effect. Mr. Wirt's gesture, too, that of which the
            Grecian thought so much, was in keeping with his other excellences. The fault was that it was studied; and yet the
            art with which he concealed his art was consummate. It
            was only by the closest observation that it could be detected.
         </p>
         
         <p>For a long time, Mr. Wirt's chief opponent at the Baltimore bar, was Mr. Taney, the present chief justice of the
            United States. Mr. Taney removed to Baltimore from Frederick on the death of Mr. Pinckney, and there Mr. Wirt and
            himself were the great forensic rivals. No two men of the
            same profession could be more different in their intellectual
            endowments than were these gentlemen. They were as unlike in these regards as they were in their personal appearance. Mr. Taney was then thin. He stooped, and his voice was
            weak: and such was the precarious condition of his health,
            that he had to station himself immediately before and near
            the jury to make himself heard by them. Mr. Wirt always
            placed himself in front of the trial table, opposite the jury, in
            oratorical position. Mr. Taney's manner of speaking was
            slow and firm--never using the least rhetorical ornament,
            but pressing into the heart of the case, with powerful arguments, like a great leader with unbroken phalanx into the
            heart of a besieged city. His style was plain, unadorned,
            and so forcible and direct that it might be called palpable.
            With his snuff-box--for the chief justice then, too, used
            snuff--compressed in his closed hands, he reasoned for hours
            without the least attempt at wit or eloquence. And yet, at
            
            
            times, he was truly eloquent, from his deep yet subdued earnestness. In a question of bail, in the case of a youth who
            had shot at his teacher, I remember, though then a youthful
            student, that a crowded auditory were suffused in tears. It
            was the fervor of his own feelings, speaking directly, that
            made him eloquent. He did not appear to know that he
            was eloquent himself. It was an inspiration which came to
            him, if it came at all, unbidden--and which would no more
            answer to his call than Glendower's
            "Spirits from the vasty deep."
         </p>
         
         <p>One of the most interesting cases ever witnessed at the
            Baltimore Bar, was a trial in a mandamus case, in which
            the right to a church was contested. Mr. Duncan had been
            established in the ministry in Baltimore by a number of
            Scotch Presbyterians in an obscure edifice. His talents drew
            such a congregation that it soon became necessary to build a
            larger one. It was done ; and, in the progress of events, the
            pastor preached a more liberal doctrine than he had at first
            inculcated. His early supporters remained not only unchanged in their faith, but they resolved to have it preached to
            them by one with whom they could entirely agree upon religious matters. The majority of the congregation agreed
            with Mr. Duncan. A deep schism arose in the divided flock
            which could not be healed, and which was eventually, by a
            writ of mandamus, carried before a legal tribunal. Mr. Taney
            was counsel for the old school side, and Mr. Wirt for the defendants. The court-room, during the trial, was crowded
            with the beauty and fashion of the Monumental City. It
            was such a display of eloquence, and a full appreciation of
            it, as is seldom witnessed. Mr. Wirt was always happy in
            making a quotation ; and in concluding this cause he made
            one of his happiest. After alluding to the old school members, who, as it has been said, were Scotchmen, and after
            dwelling upon the tragedy of Macbeth, the scenes of which
            are laid in Scotland, he described their preacher as being in
            the condition of Macbeth's guest; and said, after a stern rebuke to them, that though they should succeed in their
            cause, which he felt confident they would not, they would feel
            like the guilty Thane:
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>"This Duncan
            
            <br></br>Hath borne his faculties so meek, hath been
            
            <br></br>So clear in his great office, that his virtues
            
            <br></br>Will plead like angels trumpet-tongued against
            
            <br></br>The deep damnation of his taking off."
         </div>
         
         <p>This quotation was made with such oratorical effect that
            there was a deep silence when Mr. Wirt took his seat, which
            was succeeded by repeated outbreaks of applause. Mr. Wirt
            gained the case.
         </p>
         
         <p>As an author, Mr. Wirt's merits are very high. His
            "British Spy" contains sketches of some of our first men,
            drawn with a graphic power which makes us regret that he
            did not oftener direct his fine mind to the delineation of character. He was eminently calculated for a biographer. His
            high tone of moral feeling would have prevented him from
            becoming the apologist of vice, no matter how high were its
            endowments; while his great admiration of virtue and talent
            would have made him the enthusiastic eulogist of those qualifications which render biography so attractive and so useful.
            The great fault of his "Life of Patrick Henry" is exaggeration. His mind became heated and inflated as he contemplated the excellences of Henry as an orator and a man;
            and he overcolored that, which, told with more simplicity,
            would have been more striking. The effects of Henry's eloquence being so wonderful in themselves, narrated in a plainer way, would have more forcibly struck the mind. What
            they borrowed from the poetry of the biographer, seems
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Like gilding refined gold, painting the lily,
               
               <br></br>Or throwing a perfume on the violet."
            </div>
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="wwirt">Wirt</span>'s "Old Bachelor" is deserving of high commendation. It is written in numbers, after the manner of the
            Spectator, Guardian, and Adventurer, and has much of the
            eloquence of style which has contributed so largely to the
            popularity of those celebrated works. It treats of various
            subjects--oratory, poetry, morality, &amp;c.--and abounds in reflections happily suited to the condition of young men who
            are entering the learned professions. It is not sparse of wit,
            while it shows the author's familiar acquaintance with the old
            worthies of English literature--those who drank of the
            "well of English undefiled."
         </p>
         
         <p>It should not be neglected to be said of Mr. Wirt that he
            was one of those who, in early life, from the pressure of an
            unfriended condition upon a mind of excessive sensitiveness,
            fell, for a while, into reckless despondency, alternated by
            wayward fits of intellectual energy, which had an unfortunate influence upon his habits. Such has often been the situation of men like him, who had the "fatal gift" without
            any other gift--no friendly home--no cheering voice. Alas!
            the records of genius for wretchedness are surpassed only by
            the records of the lunatic asylum. In fact, its history often
            illustrates and deepens the saddest story on the maniac's
            wall. But, to the glory of Mr. Wirt, it is known that his
            energies prevailed, that friends came, that religious hope,
            which had formerly visited him like the fitful wanderings of
            a perturbed spirit, at last made her home by his hearth,
            where a beautiful and gifted family grew up around him,
            until, full of honors and of years, and of the faith that is beyond them, he was gathered to his fathers.
         </p>
         
         <p>When contemplating the moral and intellectual character
            of Mr. Wirt, it has been regretted that he did not turn away
            from the thorny paths of the law, and devote the whole
            force of his mind to general literature ; but how could he,
            with the poor rewards of literature, support those nearest and
            dearest to him? Yet, had circumstances allowed him to
            have done so, he would have been one of the first literary
            men of our country. I have frequently heard Mr. Wirt when
            opposed to some of our most eminent men, and this slight
            sketch is drawn from opinions then entertained and expressed. I presented, while he lived, the tribute of my admiration, not to the politician, not to the candidate for the Presidency, but to the author of the "British Spy," "The Old
            Bachelor," "The Life of Henry," a great lawyer and acute
            statesman, a consummate advocate, and last, though not
            least, a Christian gentleman: and now that he is dead, I
            would fain garner to his memory a worthy testimonial--but
            the will must be taken for the deed.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">F. W. THOMAS.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Sonnet-To Science</div>
         <div class="biblPage">54</div>
         <div class="head">Sonnet--To Science.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Science! true daughter of Old Time thou art!
            
            <br></br>Who alterest all things with thy peering eyes.
            
            <br></br>Why prey'st thou thus upon the poet's heart,
            
            <br></br>Vulture, whose wings are dull realities?
            
            <br></br>How should he love thee? or how deem thee wise,
            
            <br></br>Who wouldst not leave him in his wandering
            
            <br></br>To seek for treasure in the jewelled skies,
            
            <br></br>Albeit he soared with on undaunted wing?
            
            <br></br>Hast thou not dragged Diana from her car?
            
            <br></br>And driven the Hamadryad from the wood
            
            <br></br>To seek a shelter in some happier star?
            
            <br></br>Hast thou not torn the Naiad from her flood,
            
            <br></br>The Elfin from the green grass, and from me
            
            <br></br>The summer dream beneath the tamarind tree?
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Critical Notices</div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Lost Pleiad</div>
            <div class="biblPage">55</div>
            <p>The Lost Pleiad; and other Poems. By 
               <span class="person" id="thchivers">T. H. Chivers</span>, M. D.
               New-York: Edward O. Jenkins.
            </p>
            
            <p>This volume is evidently the honest and fervent utterance
               of an exquisitely sensitive heart which has suffered much
               and long'. The poems are numerous, but the thesis is one-death--the death of beloved friends. The poet seems to
               have dwelt among the shadows of tombs, until his very soul
               has become a shadow. Here, indeed, is no mere Byronic
               affectation of melancholy. No man who has ever mourned
               the loss of a dear friend, can read these poems without instantly admitting the palpable truth which glows upon every
               page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The tone of the composition is, in these latter days, a
               marvel, and as a marvel we commend it to our readers. It
               belongs to the first era of a nation's literature--to the era of
               impulse--in contra-distinction to the era of criticism--to the
               Chaucerian rather than to the Cowperian days. As for the
               trans-civilization epoch, Doctor 
               <span class="person" id="thchivers">Chivers</span>' poems have really
               nothing of affinity with it -- and this we look upon as the
               greatest miracle of all. Is it not, indeed, a miracle that today a poet shall compose sixty or seventy poems, in which
               there shall be discoverable no taint--absolutely none--of
               either 
               <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span>, or 
               <span class="person" id="pbshelley">Shelley</span>, or 
               <span class="person" id="wwordsworth">Wordsworth</span>, or 
               <span class="person" id="stcoleridge">Coleridge</span>, or
               
               <span class="person" id="atennyson">Tennyson</span>? In a word, the volume before us is the work of
               that rara avis, an educated, passionate, yet unaffectedly simple-minded and single-minded man, writing from his own
               vigorous impulses--from the necessity of giving utterance to
               poetic passion--and thus writing not to mankind, but solely
               to himself. The whole volume has, in fact, the air of a rapt
               soliloquy.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have leisure this week only to give, without comment, a few extracts at random--but we shall take an opportunity of recurring to the subject.</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>I hear thy spirit calling unto me
               
               <br></br>From out the Deep,
               
               <br></br>Like Archytas from out Venetia's Sea,
               
               <br></br>While I here weep;
               
               <br></br>Saying, Come, strew my body with the sand,
               
               <br></br>And bury me upon the land, the land!
               
               <br></br>Oh, never, never more! no, never more!
               
               <br></br>Lost in the Deep!
               
               <br></br>Will thy sweet beauty visit this dark shore,
               
               <br></br>While I here weep;
               
               <br></br>For thou art gone forever more from me.
               
               <br></br>Sweet Mariner! lost--murdered by the Sea!
               
               <br></br>Ever--forever more, bright, glorious One!
               
               <br></br>Drowned in the Deep!
               
               <br></br>In Spring-time--Summer--Winter--all alone--
               
               <br></br>Must I here weep;
               
               <br></br>Thou Spirit of my soul! thou light of life!
               
               <br></br>While thou art absent, 
               <span class="person" id="pbshelley">Shelley</span>! from thy wife!
               
               <br></br>Celestial pleasure once to contemplate
               
               <br></br>Thy power, great Deep!
               
               <br></br>Possessed my soul; but ever more shall hate,
               
               <br></br>While I here weep,
               
               <br></br>Crowd out thy memory from my soul, Oh, Sea!
               
               <br></br>For killing him who was so dear to me!
               
               <br></br>He was the incarnation of pure Truth,
               
               <br></br>Oh, mighty Deep!
               
               <br></br>And thou didst murder him in prime of youth,
               
               <br></br>For whom I weep;
               
               <br></br>And, murdering him, didst more than murder me.
               
               <br></br>Who was my Heaven on earth, Oh, treacherous Sea!
               
               <br></br>My spirit wearied not to succor his,
               
               <br></br>Oh, mighty Deep!
               
               <br></br>The oftener done, the greater was the bliss;
               
               <br></br>But now I weep;
               
               <br></br>And where his beauty lay, unceasing pain
               
               <br></br>Now dwells--my heart can know no joy again!
               
               <br></br>God of my fathers! God of that bright One
               
               <br></br>Lost in the Deep!
               
               <br></br>Shall we not meet again beyond the sun--
               
               <br></br>No more to weep?
               
               
               <br></br>Yes, I shall meet him there--the lost--the bright--
               
               <br></br>The glorious 
               <span class="person" id="pbshelley">Shelley</span>! spring of my delight!
               
               <br></br>Ah, like Orion on some Autumn night
               
               <br></br>Above the Deep;
               
               <br></br>I see his soul look down from Heaven--how bright!
               
               <br></br>While here I weep!
               
               <br></br>And there, like Hesperus, the stars of even
               
               <br></br>Beacon my soul away to him in Heaven!
            </div>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>When thou wert in this world with me,
               
               <br></br>Bright Angel of the Heavenly lands!
               
               <br></br>Thou wert not fed by mortal hands,
               
               <br></br>But by the Nymphs, who gave to thee
               
               <br></br>The bread of immortality--
               
               <br></br>Such as thy spirit now doth eat
               
               <br></br>In that high world of endless love,
               
               <br></br>While walking with thy snowy feet
               
               <br></br>Along the sapphire-paven street,
               
               <br></br>Before the jasper-walls above,
               
               <br></br>And list'ning to the music sweet
               
               <br></br>Of Angels in that heavenly Hymn
               
               <br></br>Sung by the lips of Cherubim
               
               <br></br>In Paradise, before the fall,
               
               <br></br>In glory bright, outshining all
               
               <br></br>In that great City of pure gold,
               
               <br></br>The Angels talked about of old.
               
               <br></br>Because of thine untimely fate,
               
               <br></br>Am I thus left disconsolate!
               
               <br></br>Because thou wilt return to be
               
               <br></br>No more in this dark world with me,
               
               <br></br>Must these salt tears of sorrow flow
               
               <br></br>Out of my heart forever more!
               
               <br></br>Forever more as they do now!
               
               <br></br>Out of my heart forever more!
               
               <br></br>Thou wert my snow-white Jessamine--
               
               <br></br>My little ANGel-Eglantine!
               
               <br></br>My saintly Lily! who didst grow
               
               <br></br>Upon my mother's arms of snow--
               
               <br></br>Of whom thou wert the image true--
               
               <br></br>Whose tears fell on thy leaves for dew--
               
               <br></br>All but those deep blue eyes of thine--
               
               <br></br>They were the miniatures of mine,
               
               <br></br>Thou Blossom of that heavenly Tree,
               
               <br></br>Whose boughs are barren now for thee!
               
               <br></br>The sweetest bud she ever bore!
               
               <br></br>Who art transplanted to the skies
               
               <br></br>To blossom there forever more
               
               <br></br>Amid the Flowers of Paradise.
            </div>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Thus shall thou leave this world of sin,
               
               <br></br>And soar into the sky,
               
               <br></br>Where angels wait to let thee in
               
               <br></br>To immortality.
               
               <br></br>And those who had nowhere to rest
               
               <br></br>Their wearied limbs at night,
               
               <br></br>Shall lay their heads upon God's breast,
               
               <br></br>And sleep in sweet delight.
               
               <br></br>There, Death's dark shades no more shall be
               
               <br></br>The mystic veil between
               
               <br></br>The World which we desire to see,
               
               <br></br>And that which we have seen.
               
               <br></br>There, father, brother, husband, wife--
               
               <br></br>There, mother, sister, friend--
               
               <br></br>Shall be united, as in life,
               
               <br></br>In joys that never end.
               
               <br></br>No pangs shall there disturbs the thrills
               
               <br></br>Which animate thy breast ;
               
               <br></br>But Angels, on the Heavenly Hills,
               
               <br></br>Shall sing thee into rest.
               
               <br></br>No slanderous tongue shall there inflame
               
               <br></br>Thy heart with words of gall;
               
               <br></br>For all shall be in Heaven the same,
               
               <br></br>And God shall be in all.
            </div>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>As graceful as the Babylonian willow
               
               <br></br>Bending, at noontide, over some clear stream
               
               <br></br>In Palestine, in beauty did she seem
               
               <br></br>Upon the cygnet-down of her soft pillow;
               
               <br></br>And now her breast heaved like some gentle billow
               
               <br></br>Swayed by the presence of the full round moon--
               
               <br></br>Voluptuous as the summer South at noon--
               
               <br></br>Her cheeks as rosy as the radiant dawn,
               
               <br></br>When heaven is cloudless! When she breathed, the air
               
               <br></br>Around was perfume! Timid as the fawn,
               
               <br></br>And meeker than the dove, her soft words were
               
               <br></br>Like gentle music heard at night, when all
               
               <br></br>Around is still--until the soul of care
               
               <br></br>Was soothed, as noontide by some waterfall.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>The poems of Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="thchivers">Chivers</span> abound in what must undoubtedly be considered as gross demerit, if we admit the prevalent canons of criticism. But it may safely be maintained
               
               that these prevalent canons have, in great part, no surer
               foundation than arrant conventionality. Be these things as
               they may, we have no hesitation in saying that we consider
               many of the pieces in the volume before us as possessing merit of a very lofty--if not of the very loftiest order.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading</div>
            <div class="biblPage">56</div>
            <p>Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XV.
               Tales from the German of 
               <span class="person" id="hzschokke">Heinrich Zschokke</span>, by 
               <span class="person" id="pgodwin">Parke
                  Godwin
               </span>. New York: Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>The soil of this country, as far as its literature is concerned,
               is undergoing a remarkable culture. Every variety of implement is at work upon it: ploughing, hoeing, harrowing, besprinkling and be-showering it, after the most wonderful
               fashion. We hope the crop may be answerable to these
               anxious preliminaries; among which, as one of the most
               hopeful, is to be counted 
               <span class="person" id="hzschokke">Herr Zschokke</span>--whom we have in
               various tales of humor, sentiment and wisdom, in the collection before us.
            </p>
            
            <p>As in the opening piece, "The Fool in the Nineteenth
               Century," 
               <span class="person" id="hzschokke">Zschokke</span> is said to have delineated himself, it
               may be considered as, in many respects, furnishing a key-note
               to the author and his method of composition. Several of the
               tales are intended to exhibit the conventions, false usages, deceits, and mal-practices of society under the direct light of
               Nature. "I wished to see," says the Baron Olivier, who, by
               obedience to his own instincts and constructions, comes to be
               regarded as the 'Fool in the Nineteenth Century': "I wished to see," says the Baron, "whether one could live in the
               nineteenth century in a European city [read an American as
               well,] without embracing all its humbugs, and all the prescribed notions of honor, manners, justice and respectability." The result of which course of proceeding is, that the
               honest Baron is set down by all the world as a wonderfully
               queer fellow.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Queer fellow! truly," quoth he, "that is the proper name
               for all those who do not succumb to the common-places and
               disorders of the age. Diogenes of Sinope, was regarded as a
               fool; Cato the Censor, was considered a pedant by the
               Romans; Columbus was pointed at as a crazy man in the
               streets of Madrid ; divides was condemned to the Inquisition ; Rousseau driven from his asylum among the Bernese ;
               and Pestalozzi held as more than half a fool, because he associated with beggars and dirty children, rather than with
               the be-powdered and be-queered world! And that I should
               be called a queer fellow,--I that presume only to speak, to
               think, and to act, naturally and intelligently, according
               to my right derived from God--is it not rather a reproach to
               ye yourselves?" So much for the Wise Fool; who at the
               close of his history, sums up his case with the world in a page
               of manly and eloquent statement.
            </p>
            
            <p>The other tales are of various character and merit--all of
               a popular cast, and with a sprinkling of the better salt of human nature, to savor the reader's humanity. But one that
               has particularly taken our fancy, is the History and Adventures of the famous Jack Steam: who is indebted for his introduction to the American public, to the accomplished wife
               of the editor. And, in the words of the introduction, she proves
               in herself a hearty relish for the humorous--a command of
               the easy, fluent and unembarrassed style which that species
               of composition demands. In a word, she has made Jack
               Steam English, without depriving it of its German spirit--a
               high merit in translation. We wish we had space to follow
               the illustrious and versatile Steam through all the varieties
               of fortune, sometimes trudging along the path to school, then
               mounted on the people's shoulders and riding them like a great
               donkey: then suddenly unhorsed, and pursued by their most
               
               blest execrations; then up again, like an India-rubber man, to
               a better elevation than before, till he is borne by his biographer into full possession of the chief-burgo-mastership of
               Lalenburg, where the historian leaves him in despair of do ing justice to his extraordinary position--shrinks, in fact, as
                he acknowledges, "from the gigantic undertaking of becoming
               the Plutarch of this hero," and demands that he may be allowed "to take fresh breath, that he may write with greater
               vigor hereafter," should he ever find courage to return to the
                subject.
            </p>
            
            <p>Jack Steam was, in fact, the son of the deceased burgo master, Peter Steam, "one of the greatest men of his century."
               Peter's lofty and philanthropic spirit had never disturbed the
               peace of Europe. In sagacity, he surpassed all his contemporaries; in judgment, he was infallible; in decision, per fectly correct; and in sallies of wit, there never was one like
               him. And he was all this upon the simple ground that he was
               first magistrate of the town. Not what he had actually done,
               but what he might have done, would, if it were written, fill
                whole folios, and he take rank, if not above, still near to the
               most commanding princes in the history of the world. He died
               too early for the fortunes of Lalenburg, and only the virtues
               of his successor, Mr. Burgomaster Tobias Crack, could mitigate the just, but silent scorn of the States, for the loss of the
               great Peter Steam. The pedigree of Jack Steam, (for a
               busy-body, great man and politician,) was thus, it will be
               seen, of the first complexion. If the reader knew of all that
               passes in the city of Lalenburg in this authentic history, he
               would say that Lalenburg was New York, and Jack Steam
               ----. But we must leave the book, reluctantly ; accrediting
               Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="pgodwin">Godwin</span> for good editorial service and an excellent collection.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Fortune Hunter</div>
            <div class="biblPage">56</div>
            <p>The Fortune Hunter; or The Adventures of a Man About
               Town. A Novel of New-York Society. By Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="acmritchie">Anna
                  Cora Mowatt
               </span>, author of Fashion, etc. New-York; William Taylor.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have received this novel at too late a period to do more
               than mention it this week, and make an extract front its
               pages. Hereafter we shall do it that full justice which is
               demanded by the celebrity and varied talent of its fair author. As a specimen more of manner than matter, we copy
               the whole of Chapter IV:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Oh! Love, young Love,bound in thy rosy bands!"
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">
               <span class="person" id="ggbyron">BYRON</span>.
            </div>
            
            <p>"Pray, Miss Walton--Arria--pray do not so quicken your pace,"
               said Mr. Chadwick, a few moments after he and Miss Walton had left
               the house of the Clintons.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Excuse me ; I was hurrying home, like another Cinderella--for
               the hour at which I was order----at which I promised to return, has
               already struck. Had we not better make haste?"
            </p>
            
            <p>"Must you, then, abridge a pleasure which I have so seldom en-
               joyed--so long anticipated, that of acting as your protector, and----
               being alone with you?" said he, in a tremulous voice.
            </p>
            
            <p>Arria replied not, but her step--perhaps unconsciously--became
               slower. More than a square further they walked in perfect silence.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Arria!"</p>   
            
            <p>"Mr. Chad"----</p>
            
            <p>" Say Edgar, rather; have we not known each other long enough
               for you to call me by that name? To me it seems as though you had
               been a familiar spirit, ever since I learned to dream of woman. You
               are the Egeria that, in my earliest youth, I pictured to myself, and
               thought I could love--the one being in whom I find my beau ideal, in
               manhood, and whom, therefore, I do love! Am I presumptuous in saying this! Have I hoped too much, because you evinced toward me
               the same frank and affectionate manner with which you delight your
               triends? Was it all my own hopeful folly, when I fancied sometimes
               that I had awakened your--your--sympathy? Nay, that was not the
               word I should have used, for I know how fully you sympathize with
               
               all around you. I--you-- dear Arria! Will you not permit me to call
               you by that name?"
            </p>
            
            <p>The timid glance--the moist eye a moment lifted to his--the trem- 
               bling arm he held within his own--these spoke all that Arria's tongue
               refused to express.
            </p>
            
            <p>"I have not, then, deceived myself!" murmured Edgar, in a voice
               tremulous with happiness. "You listen to me--you do not turn away?
               You--oh! you have been all the world to me, and you permit me to 
               hope that I am something to you. The thought of you, Arria, has for
               many anxious months formed my whole happiness. Do you believe it
               in my power to form yours? Will you trust it in my keeping?"
            </p>
            
            <p>"If I can always make you feel as joyful as now, my happiness
               will be secured," half whispered Arria.
            </p>
            
            <p>"You will consent, then, ever to remain near me, and cheer my
               hours of solitude ; ever to teach me such sweet and holy lessons of
               truth and goodness as I have already learned from your lips--to give
               me some foretaste of that abode of future happiness, in the reality of
               which only the existence of such beings as you are could make me be- 
               lieve? And what have I to offer in return?"
            </p>
            
            <p>Edgar fancied he heard Arria breathe "your love!"-- but it was
               the expression of her countenance rather than the movement of her
               lips which conveyed the idea.
            </p>
            
            <p>"I have only the wealth of the heart to lay at your feet," he continued, with a touch of humor which was natural to him: "and that
               will not purchase ' house and lands,' and all else that, if we had the
               fairy's wishing cap, we might desire. I am but a young student, with
               all the gold I may ever possess not yet disencumbered from the rough
               soil of my brains. But as I am now, even so was my father thirty
               years ago, and he rides in his carriage to-day. I have health, I have
               energy, and I hope ordinary abilities. Is not this all that a young man
               in this happy land need desire? Some foreigner says that it is as easy
               for an American to make a fortune when he has none, as it is for him
               to spend one if he chances to have one left to him. I think my prospects bright while Arria smiles, and should they ever be darker"----
            </p>
            
            <p>"Her smile must brighten them still?"</p>
            
            <p>"It shall--it will! Come the worst that Fate can send, that smile
               shall disarm her wrath. With you to protect, what an incentive shall I
               have for exertion! And have I indeed secured to myself such a lifelong source of joy! I can hardly credit my own happiness. Ah! Arria, will you never repent that you consented to become the light of the
               poor student's home?"
            </p>
            
            <p>"Shall I ever love him less? You question my love when you ask."</p>
            
            <p>"I would as soon question"</p>
            
            <p>   "Hush! Speak lower; we are just home. Bid me a hasty good
               night! I am afraid that that is Mrs. Lemming at the window."
               " You shall not thus fear her long, loveliest and best beloved!"
            </p>
            
            <p>"Hush! hush!" whispered Arria timidly. Leave me now, I beg
               of you."
            </p>
            
            <p>"Adieu, then, mine own Arria--mine for ever!"</p>
            
            <p>"Adieu, de-- dear Edgar!</p>
            
            <p>She had hardly uttered the words before the door opened and she
               sprang into the house. But they resounded in Edgar's ears when he
               sought his pillow that night in his dreams ; in his dreams they were
               re-uttered in the same tenderly harmonious tone: and when the morning sun fell brightly on the placid countenance of the sleeper, he
               awoke to spring up, repeating to himsel, "de--dear Edgar!"
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XVI.
               Prose and Verse. By 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Thomas Hood</span>. Part I.
            </p>
            
            <p>This collection is designed to embrace 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Hood</span>'s more earnest
               writings--in the words of the editor, "those which were
               written most directly from the heart, which reflect most
               faithfully his life and opinions." Heretofore his lighter effusions, his puns and quibbles, are all that the American public have had an opportunity of appreciating.
            </p>
            
            <p>Part I. contains the Preface to 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Hood</span>'s own ; The Pugsley
               Papers; The Dream of Eugene Aram ; Black, White, and
               Brown; I remember--I remember; The Portrait; Literary
               Reminiscences; My Apology; The Lost Heir; An Undertaker ; Miss Killmansegg ; Fair Ines; A Ballad ; Ruth ; Autumn ; A Song ; and the Ode to Melancholy ;--a very judicious selection. We shall speak of it again hereafter. In
               the meantime we quote a few well-considered words from
               the Preface of the American editor:
            </p>
            
            
            
            <p>The grand law of morality which protects the rights of the author,
               and distributes his works to the world in accordance with those rights,
               will be found to be the just measure by which his writings can be received with any advantage. A complicated system of checks and
               counter checks--all of them necessary--depends upon the recognition
               of that primary right. The due responsibility of the author, the force
               of his character depends upon it. A just competition, the sacred right
               to be free and equal" between the native and the foreign author,
               depend upon it. A proper Nationality in our case depends upon it.-Follow out the system where you will, it will be found, here as elsewhere, that only the just and right are profitable."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Waverley Novels</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>The Waverley Novels ; with the Author's latest Corrections
               and Additions. Complete in Five Vols., (3340 pp.) for
               Two Dollars and Fifty Cents. Vol. III. Philadelphia:
               Carey &amp; Hart.
            </p>
            
            <p>This volume contains Kenilworth; the Pirate; the Fortunes
               of Nigel; Peveril of the Peak; and Quentin Durward. In
               New-York the work is for sale by Messrs. Burgess, Stringer &amp; Co.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">Pictorial History of the World</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>Pictorial History of the World. By 
               <span class="person" id="jfrost">John Frost</span>, LL. D.
               No. VI. of this beautifully printed work is published--for
               sale by Messrs. Burgess, Stringer, &amp; Co.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Godolphin Arabian</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>The Godolphin Arabian ; or the History of a ThoroughBred. A Sporting Romance. By 
               <span class="person" id="esue">Eugene Sue</span>. NewYork: E. Winchester.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have read this tale with great interest. It is in Sue's
               best manner--full of a rich pathos--and in all respects excellent, without being intense.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">Praise and Principle</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>Praise and Principle ; or For What shall I Live? By the
                 "Author of Conquest and Self-Conquest," "Woman an
                 Enigma," etc. New-York: Harper ip Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>A duodecimo of some 250 pages, neatly bound. The story
               is really admirable--equal to Sandford and Merton--and
               somewhat resembling it in general tone and manner.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Wandering Jew</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>The Wandering Jew. By 
               <span class="person" id="esue">Eugene Sue</span>. No. XV. New-
               York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>Here is a vast amount of reading matter furnished for three
               cents. The story proceeds with interest.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mrs. Caudle's Curtain Lectures</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Caudle</span>'s Curtain Lectures. New-York: E. Winchester.
            </p>
            
            <p>A complete collection. Of course it is unnecessary to say
               one word in behalf of the unfortunate Caudle.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>Blackwood's Edinburgh Magazine. No. CCCLVJI. New
               American Edition. Vol. XXI--No. 1. New-York: Leonard Scott Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>This, the July No., commences a new volume, and contains
               some excellent papers -- among others, "House-Hunting in
               Wales," and a continuation of the "Suspiria de Profundis."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Breach of Promise</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>The Breach of Promise. A Novel. By the Author of "The
               Jilt," "Cousin Jeffrey," etc. New- York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is No. 57 of the "Library of Select Novels." "The
               Jilt" is one of the best fictions of its class, and the "Breach
               of Promise" has a strong family resemblance.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">Life in Dalecarlia</div>
            <div class="biblPage">57</div>
            <p>Life in Dalecarlia. The Parsonage of Mora. By 
               <span class="person" id="fbremer">Frederika Bremer</span>. Translated by 
               <span class="person" id="whowitt">William Howitt</span>. New-York:
               Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is No. 58 of the "Library of Select Novels," and one
               of the best compositions of its noted authoress. It is peculiarly wild and entertaining.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">An Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy</div>
            <div class="biblPage">58</div>
            <p>An Encyclopoedia of Domestic Economy, &amp;c. New-York:
               Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This will be completed in 12 numbers, embracing 1000 engravings. No. 7 is issued.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Treasury of History</div>
            <div class="biblPage">58</div>
            <p>The Treasury of History. No. VII. New- York: Daniel
               Adee.
            </p>
            
            <p>This, we presume our readers know, is the valuable work of
               
               <span class="person" id="smaunder">Maunder</span>. The republication will be completed in twelve
               numbers.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p21">
         <div class="biblTitle">Bridal Ballad</div>
         <div class="biblPage">58</div>
         <div class="head">Bridal Ballad.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>The ring is on my hand,
            
            <br></br>And the wreath is on my brow ;
            
            <br></br>Satins and jewels grand
            
            <br></br>Are all at my command,
            
            <br></br>And I am happy now.
            
            <br></br>And my lord he loves me well,
            
            <br></br>But, when first he breathed his vow,
            
            <br></br>I felt my bosom swell--
            
            <br></br>For the words rang like a knell,
            
            <br></br>And the voice seemed his who fell
            
            <br></br>In the battle down the dell,
            
            <br></br>And who is happy now.
            
            <br></br>But he spoke to re-assure me,
            
            <br></br>And he kissed my pallid brow,
            
            <br></br>While a reverie came o'er me,
            
            <br></br>And to the church-yard bore me,
            
            <br></br>And I sighed to him before me,
            
            <br></br>Thinking him dead D'Elormie,
            
            <br></br>"Oh, I am happy now!''
            
            <br></br>And thus the words were spoken,
            
            <br></br>And this the plighted vow,
            
            <br></br>And, though my faith be broken,
            
            <br></br>And, though my heart be broken,
            
            <br></br>Behold the golden token
            
            <br></br>That proves me happy now!
            
            <br></br>Would God I could awaken!
            
            <br></br>For I dream I know not how.
            
            <br></br>And my soul is sorely shaken
            
            <br></br>Lest an evil step be taken,--
            
            <br></br>Lest the dead who is forsaken
            
            <br></br>May not be happy now.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">EDGAR A. POE.</div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Department</div>
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">French Opera</div>
            <div class="biblPage">58</div>
            <p>French Opera.--La Juive has been produced at the Park
               in a style of unexampled splendor. It is essentially a show
               piece, and as such it is very imposing. Its success in Paris
               and London was very great, but although the scale of production was of much greater extent in both those cities than
               it could be here, yet for magnificence of appointments and
               costume, and correctness of detail, La Juive as produced by
               the French company here, has scarcely been excelled in Europe. The scene of the opera is laid in Germany; the time
               about the fifteenth century. The characters are as follows:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">  Eleazer, a Jew goldsmith,   -   -   -   M. Arnaud.
               
               <br></br>Rachel, the Jewess,   -   -   -   -   -  M'lle Calve.
               
               <br></br>Cardinal de Brogny, President of Council, M. Douvry.
               
               <br></br>Prince Leopold,       -   -   -   -   -   M. Coeuriot.
               
               <br></br>Princess Eudoxia,   -   -   -   -   -    Md'me Casini.
               
               <br></br>The Grand Provost of the City of Constance, - M. Garry.
               
               <br></br>Emperor Sigismond,   -   -   -   -   -    Montassier.
               
               <br></br>Albert, a Captain in the Emperor's Guard,   -   Jules.
               
               <br></br>A Nobleman, attendant of the Emperor,   -   - Chaffary.
            </div>
            
            <p>Leopold, prince of the empire, and husband to Eudoxia,
               has become deeply enamored of Rachel, the daughter of
               
               Eleazer, a Jew goldsmith. The scene opens in the city of
               Constance, a short time previous to the triumphal entry of
                the emperor Sigismond, who is on his way home, having
                completely routed the Hussites. The people are feasting,
               frolicking, and drinking on this great holiday. The Provost
               has decreed that no hand shall be lifted in labor during the
               day. Presently the sound of a hammer is heard proceedin
               from the house of the Jewish goldsmith. He and his daughter are torn from the house, and would have fallen victims
               to the bitter hatred of the populace, but for the interference
               of Rodolph, who, disguised as a Jew, and wearing the distinguishing badge of that persecuted people, comes to their
               assistance. The officer of the guard recognizes the Prince, and
               compels the people to retire. Rodolph, having deceived Eleazer as to his religion, is a welcome visiter at the house. On
               the evening of that eventful day, when the Jewish household are partaking of the evening meal, the Princess Eudoxia
               is ushered in. She purchases some valuable ornaments to present to her husband, and directs the Jew to bring them to the
               grand banquet on the morrow. When the Princess and the
               Jew depart, Rodolph urges Rachel to fly--acknowledges
               himself a Christian, and threatens if she refuses, to give himself up to the sanguinary law, which consigns both Jew and
               Christian to death if acknowledging a mutual passion. She
               at last consents, but as they are about to leave the house, they
               are met by the Jew returning. Eleazer discovers the perfidy
               of Rodolph, and would have killed him, but for the prayers
               of Rachel; however, both father and daughter spurn the
               deceiver from the house with scorn and contumely.
            </p>
            
            <p>At the banquet scene, whither the Jew and his daughter
               proceed by the command of the Princess, Rachel discovers in
               the husband of Eudoxia, the pretended Jew, her recreant lover.
               They are both condemned to death. However, urged by
               the prayers of Eudoxia, and prompted by her own deep love,
               which even her wrongs could not destroy, Rachel acknowledges herself alone guilty, and the Prince is pardoned.
            </p>
            
            <p>Previous to the period at which our story begins, the President of the council, Cardinal de Brogny, then in power in
               Rome, had caused Eleazer to be most unjustly banished from
               that city, and the Jew, in revenge for such injury, had stolen
               from the Count--not then a priest--his only daughter. This
               child, now grown to womanhood, was the condemned Jewess--condemned, too, to a fearful death by her own father.
               Eleazer and Rachel are led, with much pomp and ceremony
               to the place of execution. Rachel is about to be cast in the
               boiling cauldron, when the Jew discloses to the Christian
               Cardinal the fearful secret, which, in his bitter hatred he had
               stored up for years. But too late, too late--for triumphing
               in the agony of his enemy, he rushes to his fearful doom, and
               perishes with his adopted child. The opera thus concludes.
            </p>
            
            <p>We must Isay that Mad'lle Calve, as Rachel, exceeded
               our expectations, for the character is not in her line, and we
               therefore did not look for much ; we were sure that what
               she did she would do well, for she is too good an artist to
               do any thing badly. But Mad'lle Calve caught much of the
               spirit of the part, and only wanted the physique to render her
               execution all that could be desired. Her singing and acting
               in the duet with Rodolph, in the 2d Act, were truly admirable, as also in the trio which follows. Her dressing was, as
               usual, admirable.
            </p>
            
            <p>Md'me Cassini appears still too nervous to do herself justice. She evidently sings much better than her present performances would lead the public to suppose. If she would
               strive to cast off the diffidence which now so evidently oppresses her, she would be heard to much greater advantage,
               and her acting would necessarily become less awkward and
               
               
               constrained. She cannot but feel that the public is kindly
               disposed towards her, and would gladly second her improved
               efforts. Take courage, then, Maadme.
            </p>
            
            <p>M.Arnaud made up for the Jew most admirably, and sang
               with his usual fine taste. On this occasion, however, two
               faults were very prominently displayed--namely, a too constant use of the falsetto, and a too great contrast caused by
               an injudicious, and too frequent use of his full power.--
               Shouting upon good and strong notes is a very general fault
               with singers in this country ; Antognini has fallen into it,
               and Perozzi and Valtellina were much condemned for it.--
               We trust that M. Arnaud will ponder and improve.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Coeuriot we were glad to see had recovered from his
               recent illness, with voice and energy quite unimpaired. He
               is a great favorite with the public, and independent of his
               excellent singing, his acting is full of force and passion, and
               forms the very life of the piece.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Garry did the little he had to do with much care and
               skill.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Douvry sings with much skill; his taste is excellent,
               and his judgment is not to be cavilled at, but he has an unfortunate habit of singing out of tune. We believe that he
               might avoid it by taking proper care, for it only occurs at
               intervals. He has a voice of good compass, but the music
               awarded to the Cardinal is too low for him. We are entirely opposed to any innovations upon the music written by the
               composer, but in this or any similar case, where the music
               is beyond the range of the voice of the person who is entrusted with its execution, we could forgive some flight alteration for the improved effect.
            </p>
            
            <p>The chorusses were given with much precision, and the
               effect was commensurate with the effort. The Band was,
               as usual, excellent. The brass, to be sure, was very predominant, but the fault rests more with the composer's partition than with the band or its leader.
            </p>
            
            <p>The French press has endeavored, by puffing and raving
               to an extraordinary extent, to elevate Halevy to the rank of
               classical composers. Upon what grounds they founded their
               opinions, we are at a loss to discover. Halevy is undoubtedly a man of ability ; he understands his business, but he
               evidently possesses no original genius. Out of Paris his
               music has been characterized as heavy and labored. We
               find it not only heavy and labored, but boisterous and noisy ;
               wanting in that species of melody which goes home to the
               heart: that melody which, being the offspring of an ardent
               temperament, a vivid imagination, and a deep appreciation
               of the beautiful, rather than the result of study, decides at
               once upon the originality of thought in the composer. That
               there are several pieces of great beauty in the Opera, we
               freely acknowledge. Indeed, it would be strange if some
               beauties could not be found in a work of some four hours'
               duration; but the little that is good, while it affords a pleasing relief to the hearer, only serves to render the cumbersome whole the less endurable. The music, generally, is in
               truth well suited to a melo-dramatic spectacle, being but little elevated above the music usually devoted to that class of
               entertainment.
            </p>
            
            <p>The instrumentation, while it displays the writer's perfect
               acquaintance with the elements of the Orchestra, is in the
               worst possible school. Its chief characteristic is noise. The
               brass instruments are used incessantly; sometimes, to be sure,
               with masterly effect, as in the drinking chorus in the 1st Act;
               but there is a total want of repose--the ear is never rested.
               How unlike the delicious partition of Auber, Herold or Meyerbeer! Their scores display the true artistical coloring;
               
               their musical chiaro oscuro is perfect, and we experience
               feelings of delight while hearing them, similar to those
               which affect us while gazing upon a delicious landscape by
               Salvator Rosa--not that we would affect to draw any comparison ; we speak only of the effect of the perfect unity.
            </p>
            
            <p>The "getting up" of the Opera is indeed admirable.-The costumes are rich and true to the period ; the magnificent suits of armor make a very imposing appearance, and
               the banners, &amp;c., &amp;c., add to the general effect. As a spectacle, we doubt if it has ever been equalled upon the American stage.
            </p>
            
            <p>The next Opera to be produced is Meyerbeer's "Huguenots."</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <div class="biblTitle">An Apology for Church Music</div>
            <div class="biblPage">59</div>
            <p>An Apology for Church Music and Musical Festivals, by
               
               <span class="person" id="ehodges">Edward Hodges</span>, Mus. Doct. of Sidney Sussex College,
               Cambridge.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Standard proceeds with a quotation from the "Life of Mary
               Graham," which is excellent but not to the point, seeing that it is
               an eulogy upon sacred music, rather than a deprecation of it, and
               concludes with a touching exhortation to those who are affected
               by it not to mistake the feelings excited by music only, for the influence of genuine religious sentiments: after which the article
               proceeds,
            </p>
            
            <p>"And now one word to church music generally--a word which we think
               it the more imperative to otter, because we have observed a strong disposition amongst some of the best ministers of the Church, to increase its quantity
               by chaunting, to the organ, the ' Te Deum,' the ' Jubilate,' the ' Nunc dimittas,' [dimittis] and other portions of the church service, so eloquent, so full
               of masculine dignity in their composition, that music, or any other added ornament, cannot fail to deform them. The word that we would say, we shall
               put into the form of a question. Has church music proved favorable to devotion amongst the humbler classes? Has the addition of an organ increased the congregation of country churches? Nay, has it not had the reverse effect? Has it not deprived the people frequently of the interest
               which they took in what we may intelligibly, though not properly call as a
               distinction, the vocal part of the church service? Our own experience certainly concludes unfavorably to the use of instrumental music in Divine
               worship; and for a reason which we have hinted above, we wish to see all
               the musical part of the service within the old limits, which were sufficient
               to give rest to the clergyman.
            </p>
            
            <p>"To return to the Westminster festival. Might it not be as well held in
               Westminster Hall as in Westminster Abbey, where all occasion of offence
               would be removed! The purpose of the celebration is good; the celebration
               itself blameless: the only objection is to the place--why not change the place?
               Why set an example of treating lightly the reverence due to sacred things?
               One more last word. We know to what irritable race musical people belong ; and therefore we declare that we shall not defend in controversy any
               of the opinions which we have advanced above. Our fair readers, of all
               ages, and sexes, and professions, may call us Goths, with a perfect assurance
               that they will not be answered."
            </p>
            
            <p>However, notwithstanding the "assurauce" with which the foregoing paragraph terminates, the editor was induced to bestow yet
               more last words upon the subject in his paper of April 2. This effect was elicited by the remonstrances of a correspondent who
               signs himself "an Humble Churchman," who had adduced several
               pertinent quotations from the works of the Rev. 
               <span class="person" id="wjones">W. Jones</span>, of Naylaud, one of which shall be here introduced.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Music will need no other recommendation to our attention, as an important subject, when it shall be understood, as I mean to show in the first
               place, that it derives its origin from Gad himself; whence it will follow,
               that so far as it is God's work it is His property, and may certainly be applied as such to His service. The question will be, whether it may be applied to any thing else."
            </p>
            
            <p>The signal excellence of this pious sentiment will, I am sure, be
               a sufficient justification of its insertion in this place, notwithstanding
               it does in a manner anticipate the orderly course of the subject.
               The editor of the Standard comments upon the letter thus:
            </p>
            
            <p>"The great respect in which we hold the opinions of our correspondent,
               'An Humble Churchman,' causes us to deviate, though very reluctantly,
               from the resolution which we avowed at the time, not to defend in controversy our opinions upon the subject of church music. Upon a careful perusal of our correspondent's letter, however, we discover, as we think, that
               our dispute may be brought within a very narrow compass. Is the enjoyment derived from music, sensual or intellectual? If it be sensual merely,
               then all the extraordinary effects ascribed to music are, plainly, objections to
               its admission as a part of an intellectual service. Now, we agree with our
               correspondent that the reception of musical sounds, through the agency of
               the senses, is not, alone, conclusive--that the pleasure derived from those
               sounds is purely sensual; but when we find that the pleasure is just as great
               where the sounds do not and cannot, in any way, convey any definite idea to the
               understanding, we must conclude that with the senses it begins and ends--in
               other words, that it is purely sensual; and that such it is, appears plainly enough to us from the fact, that it acts as powerfully upon irrational animals as
               rational; and that those of our own species, who delight in music, are as
               much affected by it when it is accompanied by the words af an unknown language,
               or unaccompanied by any words whatever. This appears to us as decisive
               against the intellectual character of music. The question then is, as to the
               convenience of an alloy of what is not intellectual, infused into ' the singing
               of the heart and of the understanding.' Some are excited by music; some
               are excited by dancing ; some are excited by opium, and by less innocent
               means of intoxication. Under excitement produced by any of these means,
               
               
               their devotions may appear to themselves more sincere, and to others more
               fervent; but the heart of man, 'deceitful above all things,' never deceives
               itself more completely, or perhaps more fatally, than when it mistakes the
               fever of excitement for the steady plow of piety.
            </p>
            
            <p>"As to our correspondent's reference to the Jewish ritual, we would remind him that other means of excitement than music were permitted in that
               ritual ; wisely permitted according to the purpose of the Jewish dispensation,
               and to the state of the peculiar people to whom that dispensation was given:
               according, we may add, to the state of the surrounding country. The Gospel, however, without changing the object of man's adoration, or the moral
               purpose of man's improvement, introduced a system of worship not more
               strongly contrasted in the glorious comprehensiveness of its objects, than in
               the severe simplicity of its forms. It is the Gospel of the poor, as well as
               of the rich--of the rude, as well as of the refined; as such it was dispensed
               by its Divine Author: as such it ought to be dispensed by his servants.
               There is not one word in the noble liturgy of our own Church, which is not
               as plain to the comprehension of the most ignorant as of the most learned;
               not one word, which gravely addressed to the general understanding, may
               not, under the grace of Divine Providence, reach the understanding and the
               heart too, of the humblest worshipper. What needs there then the aid of
               music? We had almost said, what justification is there for exposing men to
               the danger of mistaking animal sensation for a masculine devout conviction?
               Our own experience certainly has been, that the introduction of instrumental
               music is the reverse of beneficial, more particularly in country churches; otherwise we should not have alluded to a subject so much out of the province of
               a daily newspaper. But we think, we must repeat it, that the church organ
               has done much to fill Dissenting chapels, and to repel the humbler classes of our
               fellow-subjects to much worse places than Dissenting chapels. We have no
               wish to see our Cathedrals closed, or to have their choirs silenced. Let
               those who delight in music, and are satisfied that music aids their devotions,
               repair to those Cathedrals they are generally of the higher and middle classes, and therefore will feel little inconvenience. But let us, the poor, unlearned, rude, and humble, still have the severe simplicity of our parochial
               service
            </p>
            
            <p>" Our correspondent will observe that our objections are all strictly practical ; and he, at least, will not charge us with any spirit of Puritanism. We
               can assure him that as far as respects the effect of church music upon the
               class to which we ourselves belong, we have merely stated the result of very
               general, not local, observations, continued through a great number of
               years.
            </p>
            
            <p>"This allusion to the subject must be final, on our part; but we anxiously
               hope that it may be taken up by others better qualified than we are, and who
               can command a field of discussion more worthy of the subject."
            </p>
            
            <p>Nevertheless this allusion was not final, for a few days afterwards appeared some further remarks upon the subject, wherein
               the Editor shewed some tendency to shift his ground, and fell back
               upon one of Queen Elizabeth's injunctions to the clergy, (of which
               more hereafter,) as his army of reserve. Again he was induced
               to touch upon the matter in consequence of what fell from the
               Duke of Newcastle in the House of Lords ; on which occasion the
               Editor reiterated his recommendation to hold the festival in some
               other place than Westminster Abbey.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p24">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Drama</div>
         <div class="biblPage">60</div>
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>At Niblo's Mrs. Mowatt concluded her engagement on the
            26th ult. Her last appearance was as the Duchess in "Faint
            Heart Never Won Fair Lady," and Katherine, in "Katherine and Petruchio." The former of these pieces is one of
            the best things of its kind. It has all the neat epigrammatic
            spirit of the French Vaudeville--the ingenuity of its construction is remarkable--its incidents are vivid yet natural--its
            characters are well sustained--its sentiments are occasionally
            noble--and, upon the whole, we know nothing of the same
            nature which combines so much of truthfulness with so much
            of pure jeu d'esprit. Not its least merit is its unity to effect.
         </p>
         
         <p>Nothing, we think, could be better than Mrs. Mowatt's
            personation of the Duchess. The part, to be sure, affords
            little opportunity for histrionic display--but the astonishment
            at Ruy Gomez' audacity--this astonishment at first merged
            in indignation--then gradually becoming admiration--and
            this suddenly converted into love--were points so admirably
            managed by the fair actress, as to leave nothing to desire.
            The beautiful lips of Mrs. Mowatt have, we fear, a singular
            facility in the expression of contempt.
         </p>
         
         <p>In Ruy Gomez Mr. Crisp was intolerable. He entirely
            misconceives the character. The Spaniard, as designed by
            Planche, is a dashing, ardent, chivalric cavalier, urged to the
            extreme of audacity by the madness of his passion, but preserving through all a true dignity, and the most uncompromising respect for the lady of his love. Mr. Crisp makes
            him an impudent trickster--at times even a vulgar chuckling
            mountebank--occasionally a simpering buffoon. The Marquis of Santa Cruz was well represented by Nickerson.
            Miss Taylor spoke and stepped more like a chambermaid
            
            than a prince.
         </p>
         
         <p>Even of the "Katherine and Petruchio," as 
            <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>
            conceived it, we have no very exalted opinion. The whole
             design of the play is not only unnatural but an arrant im possibility. The heart of no woman could ever have been
            reached by brute violence. But, as this drama originally
            stood, it contained many redeeming traits of nature and
            truth. These, it was the opinion of Cibber, interfered with
            the spirit of the thing, and accordingly he left them out--or
            if one or two were suffered to remain, our modern managers
            unsparingly uprooted them. The "Katherine and Petruchio"
            of Niblo's, is absolutely beneath contempt--a mere jumble
            of unmeaning rant, fuss, whip-smacking, crockery-cracking,
            and other Tom-Foolery of a similar kind. With a play of
            this character nothing could be done--and, as far as we could
            perceive, nothing was.
         </p>
         
         <p>In taking leave of Mrs. Mowatt for the present, we have
            only again to record our opinion that, if she be true to herself, she is destined to attain a very high theatrical rank.
            With the one exception of mere physical force, she has all
            the elements of a great actress. Her conceptions of character are good. Her elocution is excellent, although still susceptible of improvement. Her beauty is of the richest and most
            impressive character. Her countenance is wonderfully expressive. Her self-possession is marvellous. Her step is
            queenly. Her general grace of manner has never, in our
            opinion, been equalled on the stage--most decidedly it has
            never been surpassed. These qualities alone would suffice
            to assure her a proud triumph--but she possesses a quality
            beyond all these--enthusiasm--an unaffected freshness of
            the heart--the capacity not only to think but to feel.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the Park the French operatic troupe have been delighting large, fashionable, and intellectual audiences, La Juive
            has been the attraction. The admirable manner in which it
             is brought upon the stage, cannot be too highly commended.
            For farther comments on this opera, we refer the reader to
            our Musical Department.
         </p>
         
         <p>At Castle Garden, Pico has been singing--delightfully of
            course -- and Herr Cline has been performing his usual
            wonders upon the tight rope. The audiences have been
            large and very respectable.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the Chatham, a vast number of people without coats,
            have been thrown into raptures by the representation of
            "The Female Horsethief," in which the leading character is
            one Margaret Catchpole, and the leading incident her riding
            en homme a very lazy and very stupid little horse.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         <div class="biblTitle">Editorial Miscellany</div>
         <div class="biblPage">60</div>
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany</div>
         
         <p>Few American writers have been received with more favor than Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="cmathews">Mathews</span> in England. The notices his writings have called forth have been remarkable (we remember
            particularly one by 
            <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Douglas Jerrold</span>, whose sympathy is an
            honor to any man,) for a spirit of generous appreciation of his
            good qualities, and the interest and faith shown in the development of the man. A critic in Tail's Magazine thus
            speaks of the volume of Poems on Man.
         </p>
         
         <p>This is a slight book in its exterior form, and the frame-work of
            the intention of it is slighter still. The American writer, Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="cmathews">Cornelius Mathews</span>, is the secretary of the Author's Copy-right Protection
            Club in New York ; and is known in his own country by the "Motley
            Book" "Puffer Hophins," and other humorous prose works of the like
            order, indicating a quick eye and a ready philosophy in the mind that
            waits on it; generous sympathies towards humanity in the mass ; and
            a very distinct and characteristic nationality. He has written also a
            
            powerful fiction called "Behemoth." The small volume before us
            consists of poems: and both for their qualities and defects, they are
            to be accounted worthy of some respectful attention. To render clearer the thought which is in us, we pass to general considerations. The
            contrast between the idea of what American poetry should be, and
            what it is, is as plain as the Mississippi on the map. The fact of the
            contrast faces us. With abundant flow and facility, the great body of
            American verse has little distinct character of any kind, and still less
            national character. There is little in it akin to the mountains and
            rivers, the prairies and cataracts among which it arises. This sound
            from the forest is not of them. It it as if a German bullfinch, escaped
            from the teacher's finger into the depth of the pines, sate singing his fragment of Mozart in learned modulation, upon a rocking, snowy branch.
            And we find ourselves wondering how, in the great country of America,
            where the glory of liberty is so well comprehended, and where nature rollsout her waters and lifts her hills, as in attestation of a principle worthy of
            her beauty,--the poetry alone should persist in being lifeless, flat, and im,
            itative, as the verse of a court-rhymer when he rests from the bow of office
            among the fens of Essex. It is easier to set this down as a fact (and
            the American critics themselves set it down as a fact), than to define
            the causes of it. And the fact of the defective nationality of the literature of a young country, suggests the analogy of another fact--the
            defective individuality attributable to a young person: and the likeness may be closer than the mere analogy expresses. Nationality is
            individuality under the social and local aspect; and the nationality
            of a country's literature is the individuality of the writers of it in the
            aggregate. It is curious to observe, that the ' wild oats' sown in literature by the youthful author as by the youthful nation, are, generally
            speaking, as barely tame as any stubble of the fields. Perhaps there
            is a bustling practicalness in both cases, which hinders that inner process of development necessary to the ulterior expression. Perhaps
            the mind, whether of the nation or of the man, must stand, before the
            cream rises. However this may be, we have given utterance to no
            novel form of opinion on the subject of American poetry in the mass.
            And let no one mistake that opinion. We do not forget--how should
            we?--such noble names as 
            <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>'s may nobly lead, as Whittier's
            may add honor to; we believe in the beautiful prophecy of beauty contained in the poems of 
            <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span>. But in speaking of these poets, we do
            not speak of poetry in the gross; and in speaking of some of these,
            the English critic feels, unawares, that he would fain clasp the hand
            of an American poet, with stronger muscles in it, and less softened by
            the bath. Under which impression we are all the readier, let our
            readers understand, to meet the hand of Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="cmathews">Mathews</span>, while it presents to us the slender volume called ' Poems on Man, in his various
            aspects under the American republic.
         </p>
         
         <p>" The volume is ' dedicated to the hopeful friends of humanity, by
            their servant, the author.' It consists of short poems in various metres, and with no connecting link associated in the reader's mind,-descriptive, as the title indicates, of the different ages and conditions
            of men in the republic ; and remarkable, as we have hinted, for their
            very defects. For the poems are defective precisely in that with
            which the verse-literature of the country overflows,--we mean grace
            and facility. They are not graceful, but they are strong. They give
            no proof of remarkable facility in composition; and we are tempted
            sometimes to think of the writer, that he is versed better in sympathy
            and aspirations, thanin rhythms and rhymes. His verses are occasionally incorrect, and are frequently ragged and hard. His ear is not
            ' tuned to fine uses,' and his hand refuses to flatter unduly the ear of
            his audience. But he writes not only 'like a man,' but like a republican and American. Under this rough bark is a heart of oak; and peradventure a noble vessel, if not a Dodonean oracle, may presently be had
            out of it. The wood has a good grain, the timber is of large size; and
            if gnarled and knotted, these are the conditions of strength, and perhaps
            the conclusions of growth ; it is thus that strong trees grow, while slim
            grasses spring smoothly from the ground. And the thoughtful student
            of the literature of America will pause naturally and musingly, at the
            sight of this little book, and mark it as something ' new and strange,'
            considering the circumstances of the soil.
         </p>
         
         <p>  After quoting from the poems of the Child, the Citizen,
            the Merchant, and the Reformer, the Magazine concludes:
         </p>
         
         <p>However the reader may be inclined to be critical (and perhaps
            he will be more inclined than the critic), upon these extracts,--however he may be struck by the involutions and obscurities which to 
            some extent disfigure them,--he will be free to admit that the reverence for truth, the exultation in right, the good hope in human nature,
            which are the characteristics of this little book, and that the images
            of beauty which mingle with the expression of its lofyt sentiment,--are
            not calculated, when taken together, to disturb the vision and prophecy of such among us as are looking at this hour towards America, as
            the future land of freemen in all senses, and of poets in the highest of
            all.
         </p>
         
         <p>The British Critic thus comments on the advertising advantages afforded by the various London Daily papers:</p>
         
         <p>The Morning Chronicle has this advantage as an advertising medium, that it is the single organ of a great party, and therefore is read
            not only by that party but by the other parties, curious always to learn
            what are the designs and doings of their opponents. The Chronicle is
            not nearly so crowded with advertisements as is the Times, and therefore those that appear there are more certain to be seen ; while it possesses this important further recommendation, that it publishes no
            supplements wherein to hide the larger portion of its advertisements
            from human eye. The conclusion to which we have arrived, therefore, from a review of the circumstances, is, that all those classes of
            advertisements which may be termed general, or addressed to the
            world at large, as distinguished from those addressed to particular
            persons--in other words, for announcements intended to catch the eye,
            the Chronicle is a better medium than the Times ; the latter deserves
            the preference for such as persons are likely to seek; and for this reason, that nobody would find an advertisement in the Times by accident, but everybody goes to the Times to look for an advertisement.
         </p>
         
         <p>The same remark applies to the Morning Herald and the Morning
            Post. But the latter being the especial journal of fashion, is peculiarly
            fitted for certain classes of advertisements addressed to the fashionable, and is ill fitted for general announcements. Tradesmen appealing
            to the beau monde, and publishers, will find the Post one of their best
            journals; but for all matters of business, or announcements addressed
            to men of business, it is worthless.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of the evening papers, the best medium for advertising is unquestionably the Sun. In London there is a very absurd prejudice against
            the evening papers. Here everybody reads the morning papers, and
            few look into an evening one. The inhabitant of London appears to
            consider that London is all the world ; he forgets that the evening
            papers, though not patronised here, are very largely read in the country, and therefore are really very excellent localities for an advertisement, particularly as the number is small, and each one is sure to take
            the eye of the reader.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of all the evening papers the Sun is the best, not only as having the
            largest circulation, but as being much consulted throughout the provinces for its early information. This characteristic has given to the
            Sun, although a party paper, a less exclusive circle of readers than
            any of its contemporaries, save the Times, and an announcement
            there thus finds its way to all parties, sects, and ranks in the country.
            It is seen in every newsroom, and read at almost every inn. The Sun
            therefore, is good for advertisements of all kinds. The Standard
            enjoys a highly respectable circulation, and is well adapted for advertisements directed to the higher classes. The Globe is especially patronised at the inns, and by the commercial classes, and is therefore
            a good medium for business advertisements.
         </p>
         
         <p>At a late meeting of the Directors of the London and Croy-
            don Atmospheric Railway,
         </p>
         
         <p>"Mr. Joseph Samuda, one of the patentees of the atmospheric railway, said he would undertake to work fifteen trains per day each way,
            at an average travelling speed of forty miles an hour, from one end of
            the line to the other; the average weight of each train being from
            thirty to forty tons. Mr. Gibbon, the acting engineer of the Dalkey
            railway, said that the atmospheric system worked with a precision
            and regularity which did not belong to the locomotive. During the
            greater part of Sunday last ten trains were running per hour, each train
            weighing about forty tons. The cost of working is ten to twelve in
            favor of the atmospheric system over the locomotive."
         </p>
         
         <p>The Hon. 
            <span class="person" id="rtconrad">Robert T. Conrad</span>, of Philadelphia, author of
            "Aylmere," is engaged, we learn, on another drama--probably a tragedy. "Aylmere" was well received, and has much
            merit. Mr. Forrest gave Judge 
            <span class="person" id="rtconrad">Conrad</span> a thousand dollars
            for it.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>We beg leave to thank our friends for the cordial support
            they are now affording us. The biographical sketch of
            William Wirt, commencing on the fourth page of this number, is from the pen of the well-known author of "Clinton
            Bradshaw," "East and West," "Howard Pinckney," etc.,
            etc. As a biographical sketcher Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="fwthomas">Thomas</span> is unsurpassed ;
            and he has kindly promised us a succession of such papers as
            the one now published. For the Song, commencing "Hush!
            a spirit from afar!" we are indebted to the British Critic.
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="tcampbell">Campbell</span>, the poet, according to a writer of recollections
            in the Dublin University Magazine, was an adept in the use
            of literary Billingsgate. We have heard some proficients,
            but never met with a better specimen than this. Of course
            the whole story is to be taken of 
            <span class="person" id="tcampbell">Campbell</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span>, Northcotte and all, with a bag of salt. "Of all the false, vain, selfish blackguards," said 
            <span class="person" id="tcampbell">Campbell</span>, "that ever disgraced human nature, 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> was the falsest, vainest, and most selfish.
            He would sacrifice a million of men, had he the power to do
            so, to procure even one moment's enjoyment for himself. He
            would worm himself into your confidence only to betray you,
            and commit the basest act of ingratitude without a blush or
            sigh for its commission. I remember when I edited the
            New Monthly, 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> used to write occasionally for it.
            Somehow he got acquainted with Northcote, the sculptor
            fellow--a conceited old booby, to be sure, but still a respectable man, as it is said, well to do in the world, puffed up a
            good deal with absurd vanity, and reduced by 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> to the
            charming belief that bis reminiscences were worth remembering and being remembered. Well, he persuaded this
            old stone-cutting donkey to invite him once a week to his
            house, and got liberty from him to retail his weekly gossip
            for the edification of the million. I published some of his
            papers in the Magazine; they were pungent; they satisfied
            the prurient curiosity of old maids and gossips ; they sold remarkably well, and Northcote began to fancy himself a second
            Johnson. One morning before I was up, I received a letter
            from this old fool, complaining bitterly of the insertion in the
            Table Talk of some horribly severe remarks on----and----.
            
         </p>
         <p>He swore by every thing that men believe and disbelieve,
            that he had never spoken as was represented--that 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span>
            was betraying and belying him, and that henceforth the
            ' blackguard penny-a-liner' should be excluded from his
            house. I was rather amazed at this. The fact is, I did not
            care a rush what appeared in the Magazine, so that it told
            and sold ; and, as 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> put his name to the nonsense, I did
            not suppose he would dare to fabricate anything. Northcote,
            however, asserted that he had, and to pacify the old fool, I
            wrote him a letter, assuring him that 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> should never
            again write a line for the New Monthly. One expression which I used, excited 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span>'s rage to an extent scarcely credible--' the infernal 
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span>.' Oh! how he foamed and
            swore when he read this. But I did not value his passion
            at a button; though, I admit, I kept out of his way for a
            week, as I was told he intended to assault me. There is not
            a more degraded or disagreeable office for a literary man of
            any position, than to edit a magazine. It is a constant
            round of Billingsgate and fighting with his publisher, and an
            uninterrupted series of lies and sneaking statements to the
            various contributors."
         </p>
         
         <p>The recent congress of German booksellers at Leipsic, it
            is said, have taken steps to establish a literary agency on this
            side of the Atlantic, (New York is mentioned as the city,) for
            the sale and protection of the current German literature. The
            
            sale of German books of general literature, in the original
            language, is hardly, we should think, as yet of sufficient importance to render this measure necessary. With the exception of elementary school books, the bible, and a few standard
            works, the demand might perhaps be more cheaply supplied
            by the home editions. But if the design be, to protect translations, the agency may become, at once, very useful and important. There is nothing more disreputable than the careless, ignorant, and wilfully malicious manner in which foreign
            writers are frequently treated. It certainly should be a privilege of the author to name his own translator: a privilege
            which should be protected by copy-right. Foreign agents,
            both French and German, might not only be of service to the
            writers of their own countries, but might benefit our own
            people by introducing to their attention, with care and judgment, and simultaneously with the original publication, the
            best specimens of the continental literature. An intimate
            knowledge of the men of letters of Europe might wean our
            readers and writers from their frequent slavish subserviency
            to an imitation of English authors.
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="ltieck">Tieck</span>'s readings at Berlin must he something of a bore, as
            any man's would be, who held an audience for three hours
            without respite, with matters they might be fully put in possession of, by reading, in half an hour. The Berlin correspondent of the Foreign Quarterly Review says: "
            <span class="person" id="ltieck">Tieck</span>
            continues to give readings ; which, in spite of his wonderful
            talent in interpreting dramatically the great masterpieces,
            people are pretty unanimous in voting excessively wearisome. They are wearisome because of the frivolous etiquette which reigns in the salon ; wearisome, because Shakspeare himself, if he were to read for three hours, without a
            minute's pause, would in the end be fatiguing. But 
            <span class="person" id="ltieck">Tieck</span> is
            surrounded by a set of persons who take a pride in the infliction. They sit and listen with religious silence, if not with
            religious fervor. They languish in ennui; and would not
            move a leg, or cough, or turn in their chairs, for any small
            consideration!"
         </p>
         
         <p>Taglioni, hints the London Athenaeum, is growing old ; a
            sad thing, as 
            <span class="person" id="ssmith">Sydney Smith</span> has told us, in the case of a dancer: "When youth is gone all is gone." We trust a suggestion of the circumstance will allay the anxiety for her appearance on the American stage. It is quite too much our
            fate to get foreign singers and dancers and actors before us,
            and pay roundly for them,-only when they are superannuated.
            When a stage player begins to break down in Europe he
            thinks of America. It is time that our managers should compliment their audiences, if not by the production of some native novelties, at least by the introduction of foreigners of
            some pith and vitality. In the midst of universal life and
            energy, our literature and art have been, for the most part,
            feeble and decrepid, an anomaly that, as 
            <span class="person" id="tcarlyle">Carlyle</span> would say,
            should be forthwith picked out.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Lwei Frauln," is the title of the Countess 
            <span class="person" id="ihahnhahn">Hahn Walin</span> s last novel. That authoress is about to visit England, as
            
            <span class="person" id="fbremer">Frederica Bremer</span> is said to be coming to the United States.
            
            <span class="person" id="gsand">George Sand</span>, we think we saw it stated, was going to Constantinople. Female genius is restless and migratory.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Dr. Dressel, at Rome," says the Foreign Quarterly,
            "has lately made a very successful attempt to apply the
            Daguerreotype to the copying of ancient MSS. and palimpsests. In less than eleven minutes he produced a most perfect copy of forty-two folio lines of a half obliterated Greek
            MSS. of the 12th century."
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Arago has submitted to the French Academy an important
            improvement for speed and safety.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p26">
         <div class="biblTitle">To Correspondents</div>
         <div class="biblPage">63</div>
         <p>To Correspondents.-- We regret that 
            <span class="person" id="aseymour">Agnes Seymour</span> should have
             cause to suspect us of neglect. "Eudocia," was handed, for immediate insertion in the Journal, to the former associate editor, who still
            retains the MS. As soon as we can procure it of him, it shall be
            carefully transmitted, as desired--or if.
         </p>
         
         <p>Again--many thanks to the author of the Correspondence with a Governess. We sincerely value his (or is it not her?) good opinion. A
            volume embodying all the poems mentioned, will probably be published
            by Wiley &amp; Putnam, in the fall. We have reason to complain of our
            Boston agents--but will apply a remedy to that grievance forthwith.
            No. 2 of the Correspondence was published in the Journal of the 19th
            ult.
         </p>
         
         <p>We doubt the originality of the "Grecian Flute," for the reason that
            it is too good at some points to be so bad at others. Unless the author
            can re-assure us, we decline it.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">63</div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">MEDICI SERIES OF ITALIAN PROSE.</div>
            
            <p>Paine &amp; Burgess, New York, will publish on Monday,
               THE CHALLENGE OF BARLETTA, AN HIStorical Romance of the Times of the Medici, by 
               <span class="person" id="mdazeglio">Azeglio</span>. Translated by 
               <span class="person" id="celester">C. Edwards Lester</span>, U. S. Consul at Genoa. Author of "The
               Glory and Shame of England," &amp;c. &amp;c. Price 50 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>The above work is regarded by European critics as the best romance in the Italian language.</p>
            
            <div class="ab"> IN PRESS:
               
               <br></br>The Florentine Histories, by 
               <span class="person" id="nmachiavelli">Machiavelli</span>,
               
               <br></br>The Citizen of a Republic, by Ceba, a Genoese.
               
               <br></br>The Autobiography of 
               <span class="person" id="valfieri">Altieri</span>.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">IN PREPARATION.
               
               <br></br>The Artist. The Merchant and the Statesman. By 
               <span class="person" id="celester">C. Edwards
                  Lester
               </span>.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THIS DAY IS PUBLISHED,</div>
            
            <p>VERSE AND PROSE, by 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Thomas Hood</span>--Part 1,
               forming No. 16 of the Lirrary of Choice Reading, beautifully
               printed. Price 50 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Of all the humorists, 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Hood</span> was the most poetical. When dealing with the most familiar subjects, whether it might be a sweep bewailing the suppression of his cry, or a mother searching through St.
               Giles's for her lost infant, or a Miss Kilmansegg's golden childhood--
               there was hardly a verse in which some touches of heart, or some play
               of fancy, did not betoken the laughing reader away into far other
               worlds than the jester's."--London Athenaeum.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The smile and the sigh were ever blended together; the laugh at
               the grotesque idea and whimsical imagination, (rarely seeing objects
               as others saw them,) and the tear which must flow on such pathetic
               narratives as Eugene Aram or the Old Elm Tree. Without a parallel
               and original as 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Hood</span> was in the ludicrous, his more enduring fame
               will rest on the exquisitely humane and simply compassionate."--Literary Gazette.
            </p>
            
            <p>"He was the inventer of a new sort of guano to fertilize men's
               minds, and to make them produce larger crops of good actions: or rather it was an intellectual compost that he invented, and the materials
               of which were satire softened by kindness, and ridicule tempered with
               good feeling,"--Hood's Magazine for June. Published and for sale
               by                    WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE
               SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published monthly, at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since
               1835, has a large subscription list, and is the principal organ of
               Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the "Broadway Journal," 135 Nassau streeet.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. B. CARY &amp; CO.,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">ARTISTS,</div>
            
            <p>Manufacturers of ornamental show
               CARDS adapted for Utility, as well Adornment, for stores in all
               kinds of business. Specimens may be seen in the leading stores of the
               principal cities of the Union.
            </p>
            
            <p>Agents for Boston: Messrs. Sowle &amp; Shaw. Mr. J. L. Lazarus is
               now visiting the Eastern States, all orders received by him will meet
               with prompt attention. 34 Beekman-Street, (late 323 Broadway.)
            </p>
            
            <p>Observe! Our names are printed at the foot of each card, and
               we caution the public that imitators are in the field.
            </p> 
            <div class="ab">Jy 26</div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">HARPER &amp; BROTHERS' LAST PUBLICATIONS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">1.
               
               <br></br>HARPER'S ILLUMINATED BIBLE. No. 34.
               
               <br></br>Price Twenty-Five Cents,
            </div>
            
            <p>Comprising portions of the minor prophets to the 9th chapter of Amos .
               The embellishments to this number include some of unsurpassed beauty.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">II.
               
               <br></br>HARPER'S ILLUMINATED SHAKSPEARE,
               
               <br></br>Nos. 61 and 62. Price Twenty-Five Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes " Measure for Measure" and the commencement of the "Tempest"--with the eqquisite designs after Kenny Meadows, Weir, and others. It should be recollected that this edition of
               Shakspeare combines the best features of the two best London editions, by 
               <span class="person" id="cknight">Charles Knight</span> and Tyas--rendering it the most perfect ever
               presented to the public.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">III.
               
               <br></br>TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO,
            </div>
            
            <p>Newly collected from valuable MSS. in the Geographical Societies of
               France and Italy, with copious notes and illustrations by 
               <span class="person" id="hmurray">Hugh Murray</span>, with Maps, &amp;c. 16mo. muslin. Price 50 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>This well-known production, which forms No. 173 of " The Family
               Library," has long been regarded as unique in geographical science.
               Marco Polo has justly been styled the " Herodotus of the Middle
               Ages." and the discoverer of the Asiatic continent ; his explorations
               in the Chinese empire alone have never been exceeded, even to the
               present day.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IV.
               
               <br></br>THE SEERESS OF PREVORST. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>"A work replete with startling new facts on Mesmerism: the most
               remarkable on the subject we have yet seen."-- Post.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">v.
               
               <br></br>JOHN RONGE AND THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES.
               
               <br></br>Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>" A subject of the most absorbing interest throughout the whole
               whole European Continent."
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VI.
               
               <br></br>DR. LEVER'S LATEST WORK-THE NEVILLES OF
               
               <br></br>GARRETSTOWN. Complete, price 12 1-2 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>"Equal to the best works of the favourite author of Charles O'Mal
               ley."
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VII.
               
               <br></br>
               <span class="person" id="gprjames">JAMES</span>'S NEW WORK--THE SMUGGLER. 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new production of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="gprjames">James</span> is founded on on some stirring
               incidents of past times on the Southern Coast of England ; it is characterised by all the author's peculiarities of style, the story being intersected by many episodical involutions, which impart to it additional
               interest.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VIII.
               
               <br></br>DE ROMAN. BY 
               <span class="person" id="esue">EUGENE SUE</span>. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>"Picturesque bold, and highly dramatic--equal to any of his previous works."-- Sun.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">IX.
               
               <br></br>PRAISE AND PRINCIPLE--Or, For What shall I Live?
            </div>
            
            <p>By the author of "Conquest and Self-Conquest,'' " Woman an Enigma," &amp;c. 18mo. cloth gilt. Price 48 1-2 Cents. A charming volume,
               elegantly written, well sustained in its interest, and rife with excellent
               moral teaching.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">x.
               
               <br></br>CYCLOPEDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY. No. 8. Pr. 26 Cts.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">xi.
               
               <br></br>MISS 
               <span class="person" id="fbremer">BREMER</span>'s NEW WORK--THE PARSONAGE OF MO-
               
               <br></br>RA, OR LIFE IN DALECARLIA. Price One Shilling.
            </div>
            
            <p>In this new work 
               <span class="person" id="fbremer">Frederika Bremer</span> presents many of her pretty and
               picturesque scenes, add introduces many of her high minded and romantic characters, with their spirit stirring colloquies: the story also
               includes interesting sketches of those Northern subterranean worlds--
               the copper mines of Fahlua.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XII.
               
               <br></br>EVELINA, by Miss 
               <span class="person" id="fburney">Burney</span> (since 
               <span class="person" id="fburney">Madame D'Arblay</span>). New
               
               <br></br>edition, 18mo. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This renowned production has long been considered as a classic of
               our language. The work appeared anonymously, the disclosure of
               the authorship of which, it will be remembered, led to the deeply interesting scene which ensued between the father and daughter--their
               mingled surprise and delight.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XIII.
               
               <br></br>DR. 
               <span class="person" id="jcopland">COPLAND</span>'S MEDICAL DICTIONARY. No. 10. 60 Cts.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes a series of topics of vital interest to the
               Medical faculty of the country. The design and execution of this popular production, evince the most censummate skill and research ; every person who desires a thorough digest of Medical Science, must ap
               preciate its high value.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XV.
               
               <br></br>PROF. 
               <span class="person" id="tlewis">LEWIS</span>'S PLATO ON ATHEISTS. Price $1 50.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
            
            <p>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANO-
               FORTE, ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street,
               where his terms for giving instruction can be ascertained. my 17
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER.</div>
            <p>--JAMES
               PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near Elm. A
               Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms moderate. FOR SALE--A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a
               great bargain for cash.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">--V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
               Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made
               from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful
               workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the busines.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ.</p>
            
            <p>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>--JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy St Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to
               the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, corner of Cottage Place and Bleecker street, which he will sell
               at prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twenty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two
               of the largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that
               his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the
               best makers in this country or Europe, and that they contain all the
               real improvements of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
               Repaired.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, April 23d, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div> 
            <p>The Subscribers, while returning thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at
               the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and 
               seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood and mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
               the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
               to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
               upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>Manufactory, 13th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>--THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
               (formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway,
               will keep a complete assortment of the largest approved Grand Action 
               Piano Fortes, of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
               guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish,
               and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard 
               prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on
               hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <p>PHILIP ERSNT, Teacher of the Flute and Gui-
               tar, would inform the lovers of Music that he has now for sale
               several of the above celebrated instruments, constructed in every re- 
               spect in accordance with those now in use at the Paris and London 
               Royal Academies. To be seen at PHILIP ERNST'S Music Saloon, 
               395 Broadway, near Walker.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PLEASANT SUMMER READING.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">FOR TRAVELLERS AND OTHERS
               
               <br></br>1. Eothen ; or Traces of Travel in the East..................50
               
               <br></br>     "The picked book of the season."
               
               <br></br>2   Mary Schweidler, The Amber Witch.........................37
               
               <br></br>     " A beautiful and pure fiction."
               
               <br></br>3   Undine and Sintrum. By Fouque............................50
               
               <br></br>     " The rarest essence of romantic genius."
               
               <br></br>4   Imagination and Fancy. By 
               <span class="person" id="jhlhunt">Leigh Hunt</span>.....................50
               
               <br></br>     "A delicate volume of illustrative criticism."
               
               <br></br>5   The diary of Lady Willoughby.............................25
               
               <br></br>     "Though a fiction, of profound religious interest."
               
               <br></br>6   
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span>'s Table Talk, on Men, Things, &amp;c. 2 parts. ... 75
               
               <br></br>     "Most brilliant papers of a sparkling writer."
               
               <br></br>7   Headlong Hall and Nightmare Abeby........................38
               
               <br></br>     "Lively and piquant satirical sketches."
               
               <br></br>8   The French in Algiers....................................37
               
               <br></br>     "Full of stirring incident and anecdote."
               
               <br></br>9   Ancient Moral tales from the Gesta Rom...................38
               
               <br></br>     "The stories are very beautiful and moral."
               
               <br></br>10   Crescent and the Cross. 
               <span class="person" id="ewarburton">Dy E. Warburton</span>, 2 parts. . .  1 00
               
               <br></br>     "A truiy delightful work from first to last."
               
               <br></br>ll   The Age of Elizabeth. By 
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">W. Hazlitt</span>.....................50
               
               <br></br>     " Full ol originality and genius."
               
               <br></br>12   Journal of an African Cruiser...........................60
               
               <br></br>     "Quite a refreshing and delightful work."
               
               <br></br>13   Tales. By 
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">Edgar A. Poe</span>..................................50
               
               <br></br>     "Characteristic tales of thrilling interest."
               
               <br></br>14   Letters from Italy. By 
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">J. T. Headley</span>. ..................50
               
               <br></br>     "The best book of travels ever published here."
               
               <br></br>Published and for sale by
               
               <br></br>Jy 26                WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.</div>
            
            <p>THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE YEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTI-
               TUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
               
               <br></br>No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            </div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH'S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course
               of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours--9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M., daily, for gentlemen,
               and from 11 to 1 o'clock, for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale "
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">Goldsmith</span>'s Gems of Penmanship," elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PAINE AND BURGESS,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">62 JOHN STREET, N. Y.,</div>
            
            <p>ARE just sending to press a New Series of Choice
               Works, selected from the Prose Literature of Italy. Translated
               and Edited by 
               <span class="person" id="xcelesterxx">Edwards Lester</span>, U. S. Consul at Genoa, auther of the
               "Glory and Shame of England," &amp;c., &amp;c. This series will be made
               up of original translations of the best works of the best Italian writers,
                with original notes and sketches in illustration of the Genius, the Lives
                and Times of the Authors. Five vols. are ready for the Press.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">1. Ettore Fieramosca, or the Challenge of Barletta, an Historical
               
               <br></br>Romance of the Times of the Medici, by 
               <span class="person" id="mdazeglio">Agegbio</span>.
               
               <br></br>2 and 3, The Florentine Histories, by 
               <span class="person" id="nmachiavelli">Machiavelli</span>.
               
               <br></br>4, The Autobiography of 
               <span class="person" id="valfieri">Alfieri</span>.
            </div>
            
            <p>These numbers will he issued in quick succession, in beautiful style,
                and sold for fifty cents per volume. The object of this series is to
               make known to the American people the Literature of Italy.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A. G. BAGLEY'S</div>
            
            <div class="ab">CELEBRATED IMPROVED EVER-POINTED
               
               <br></br>GOLD PEN.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS PEN RECEIVED THE HIGHEST PREmium at the last Fair of the American institute, and has been pronounced by the First Teachers of Penmanship in the country, to be
               infinitely superior to any Gold Pen ever before introduced to the American public. The lasting properties of this Pen are undoubted, owing
               to the total absence of corrosibility from any of the inks in use; and the
               peculiar shape of the nibs--which was first introduced by Bagley--
               makes it more pleasant to use, renders it less liable to damage, more
               easy to repair, and prevents the necessity of the great care that other
               articles of the kind require.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">MANUFACTORY, 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
               
               <br></br>Jy 26
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BERTINTS METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work
               yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
               The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies are given in such progressive order, that they
               enlist the interest of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly
               through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often
               made irksome in other instruction books. The time has arrived when
               a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is
               only by the study of such methods as 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s that pupils will be enabled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good
               musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ; the
               rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and
               each lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations
               from professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of
               
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s Method over all others yet published in this country, most
               of them hiving used the foreign copies previously. It will only be
               necessary to give a few of the names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Boston.                  
               
               <br></br>Messr. G. J. Webb,      
               
               <br></br>J.G. Maeder,             
               
               <br></br>H T. Hach,               
               
               <br></br>E. L. White,             
               
               <br></br>David Paine,             
               
               <br></br>A.Kurek,                 
               
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.             
               
               <br></br>New-York.
               
               <br></br>  Messrs. H. C. Timin,
               
               <br></br>W. Alpers,
               
               <br></br>U. C. Hill,
               
               <br></br>F. H. Brown,
               
               <br></br>Philadelphia.
               
               <br></br>B. C. Cross,
               
               <br></br>Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>Albany--O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>  Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the
               work. American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H.
               OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p27">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">64</div>
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co..............Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance,.........Philadelphia, Pa.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. Huntington,..........Hartford, Cl.
            
            <br></br>Georoe Jones................. Albany, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Thomas H. Pease...............New-Haven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>L.  Willard,..................Troy.
            
            <br></br>M.  BAULLEMET,................Mobile, Al.
            
            <br></br>J. C. Morgan, . . ............New Orleans.
            
            <br></br>Robinson &amp; Jones,........ Cincinnati, O.
         </div>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>