<div>
   <div class="front">
          
        </div>
   <div class="body">
          
              <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
VOL. 1. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JANUARY 11, 1845. N° 2.
</p>
         <p>Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the busi-
<br/>ness of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by con-
<br/>sent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</p>
         <p>Locke.
Reviews.
THE DRAMA OR EXILE, AND OTHER POEMS : By Elizabeth Barrett
Barrett, Author of “ The Seraphim,” and other Poems. New York:
Henry G. Langley.
(Concluded.)
</p>
         <p>MISS BARRETT has need only of real self-interest in her
<br/>subjects, to do justice to her subjects and to herself. On the
<br/>other hand, “A Rhapsody of Life’s Progress,” although
<br/>gleaming with cold corruscations, is the least meritorious,
<br/>because the most philosophical, effusion of the whole:—this,
<br/>we say, in flat contradiction of the “ spoudiotalon kai philo-
<br/>sophikotaton genos" of Aristotle. “ The Cry of the Human”
<br/>is singularly effective, not more from the vigour and ghast-
<br/>ly passion of its thought, than from the artistically-con-
<br/>ceived arabesquerie of its rhythm. “ The Cry of the Chil-
<br/>dren,” similar, although superior in tone and handling, is
<br/>full of a nervous unflinching energy—a horror sublime
<br/>in its simplicity—of which a far greater than Dante might
<br/>have been proud.	“ Bertha in the Lane,” a rich bal-</p>
         <p/>
         <p>lad, very singularly excepted from the wholesale commenda-
<br/>tion of the “Democratic Review,” as “perhaps not one of
<br/>the best," and designated by Blackwood, on the contrary, as
<br/>“ decidedly the finest poem of the collection,” is not the very
<br/>best, we think, only because mere pathos, however exquisite,
<br/>cannot be ranked with the loftiest exhibitions of the ideal.
<br/>Of “ Lady Geraldine’s Courtship,” the magazine last quoted
<br/>observes that “ some pith is put forth in its passionate parts.”
<br/>We will not pause to examine the delicacy or lucidity of the
<br/>metaphor embraced in the “ putting forth of some pith but
<br/>unless by “ some pith” itself, is intended the utmost con-
<br/>ceivable intensity and vigour, then the critic is merely damn-
<br/>ing with faint praise. With the exception of Tennyson’s
<br/>“ Locksley Hall,” we have never perused a poem combining
<br/>so much of the fiercest passion with so much of the most
<br/>ethereal fancy, as the “ Lady Geraldine’s Courtship,” of Miss
<br/>Barrett. We are forced to admit, however, that the latter
<br/>work is a very palpable imitation of the former, which it
<br/>surpasses in plot or rather in thesis, as much as it falls below
<br/>it in artistical management, and a certain calm energy—lus-
<br/>trous and indomitable—such as we might imagine in abroad
<br/>river of molten gold.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>It is in the “ Lady Geraldine” that the critic of Blackwood
<br/>is again put at fault in the comprehension of a couple of pas-
<br/>sages. He confesses his inability “to make out the con-
<br/>struction of the words, ‘ all that spirits pure and ardent are
<br/>cast out of love and reverence, because chancing not to
<br/>hold.’” There are comparatively few American school-boys
<br/>who could not parse it. The prosaic construction would run
<br/>thus:—“all that (wealth understood) because chancing not
<br/>to hold which, (or on account of not holding which) all pure
<br/>and ardent spirits are cast out of love and reverence.” The
<br/>“ which” is involved in the relative pronoun “ that”—the
<br/>second word of the sentence. All that we know is, that Miss
<br/>Barrett is right:—here is a parallel phrase, meaning—“ all</p>
         <p/>
         <p>that (which) we know,” etc. The fact is, that the accusa-
<br/>tion of imperfect grammar would have been more safely, if
<br/>more generally, urged: in descending to particular exceptions,
<br/>the reviewer has been doing little more than exposing him-
<br/>self at all points.</p>
         <p>Turning aside, however, from grammar, he declares his
incapacity to fathom the meaning of
She has halls and she has castles, and the resonant steam-eagles
Follow far on the directing of her floating dove-like hand—
With a thunderous vapour trailing underneath the starry vigils,
So to mark upon the blasted heaven the measure of her land.
</p>
         <p>Now it must be understood that he is profoundly serious in
<br/>his declaration—he really does not apprehend the thought
<br/>designed—and he is even more than profoundly serious, too,
<br/>in intending these his own comments upon his own stolidity,
<br/>for wit:—“ We thought that steam-coaches generally follow-
<br/>ed the directing of no hand except the stoker’s, but it, certain-
<br/>ly, is always much liker a raven than a dove.” After this,
<br/>who shall question the infallibility of Christopher North?
<br/>We presume there are very few of our readers who will not
<br/>easily appreciate the richly imaginative conception of the
<br/>poetess:—The Lady Geraldine is supposed to be standing in
<br/>her own door, (positively not on the top of an engine), and
<br/>thence pointing, “ with her floating dove-like hand,” to the
<br/>lines of vapour, from the “resonant steam-eagles,” that de-
<br/>signate upon the “ blasted heaven,” the remote boundaries of
<br/>her domain.—But, perhaps, we are guilty of a very gross ab-
<br/>surdity ourselves, in commenting at all upon the whimsical-
<br/>ities of a reviewer who can deliberately select for special ani-
<br/>madversion the second of the four verses we here copy:</p>
         <p>“ Eyes, he said, now throbbing through me! are ye eyes that did undo me ?
Shining eyes like antique jewels set in Parian statue-stone!
Underneath that calm white forehead are ye ever burning torrid
O’er the desolate sand desert of my heart and life undone?”
</p>
         <p>The ghost of the Great Frederic might, to be sure, quote
<br/>at us, in his own Latin, his favorite adage, “De gustibus
<br/>non est disputandus;”—but, when we take into consideration
<br/>the moral designed, the weirdness of effect intended, and
<br/>the historical adaptation of the fact alluded to, in the line
<br/>italicized, (a fact of which it is by no means impossible that
<br/>the critic is ignorant), we cannot refrain from expressing our
<br/>conviction—and we here express it in the teeth of the whole
<br/>horde of the Ambrosianians—that from the entire range of
<br/>poetical literature there shall not, in a century, be produced
<br/>a more sonorous—a more vigorous verse—a juster—a nobler
<br/>—a more ideal—a more magnificent image—than this very
<br/>image, in this very verse, which the most noted magazine of
<br/>Europe has so especially and so contemptuously condemned.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ The Lady Geraldine” is, we think, the only poem of its
<br/>author which is not deficient, considered as an artistical
<br/>whole. Her constructive ability, as we have already sug-
<br/>gested, is either not very remarkable, or has never been pro-
<br/>perly brought into play :—in truth, her genius is too impetu-
<br/>ous for the minuter technicalities of that elaborate Art so
<br/>needful in the building up of pyramids for immortality.
<br/>This deficiency, then—if there be any such—is her chief
<br/>weakness. Her other foibles, although some of them are, in
<br/>fact, glaring, glare, nevertheless, to no very material ill pur-
<br/>pose. There are none which she will not readily dismis</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page18"/>
in her future works. She retains them now, perhaps, be-
cause unaware of their existence.
</p>
         <p>Her affectations are unquestionably many, and generally
<br/>inexcusable. We may, perhaps, tolerate such words as
<br/>“ ble,” “ chrysm,” “ nympholeptic,” “ oenomel,” and “ chry-
<br/>sopras”—they have at least the merit either of distinct mea-
<br/>ning, or of terse and sonorous expression ;—but what can be
<br/>well said in defence of the unnecessary nonsense of “ ’ware”
<br/>for “ aware”—of “ ’bide,” for “ abide”—of “ ’gins,” for “ be-
<br/>gins”—of “ ’las,” for “ alas”—of “ oftly,” “ often,” and “ of-
<br/>test,” for “ often,” “ more often,” and “ most often”—or of
<br/>“erelong” in the sense of “long ago”? That there is au-
<br/>thority for the mere words proves nothing; those who em-
<br/>ployed them in their day would not employ them if writing
<br/>now. Although we grant, too, that the poetess is very usu-
<br/>ally Homeric in her compounds, there is no intelligibility of
<br/>construction, and therefore no force of meaning in “ dew-pal-
<br/>lid,” “ pale-passioned,” and “ silver-solemn.” Neither have
<br/>we any partiality for “drave” or “supreme,” or “ lament”; and
<br/>while upon this topic, we may as well observe that there
<br/>are few readers who do anything but laugh or stare, at such
<br/>phrases as “ L. E. L.’s Last Questio”—“ The Cry of the Hu-
<br/>man”—“Leaning from my Human”—“Heaven assist the
<br/>human”—“ the full sense of your mortal”—“ a grave for your
<br/>divine”—“ falling off from our created”—“ he sends this gage
<br/>for thy pity’s counting”—“ they could not press their futures
<br/>on the present of her courtesy”—or “ could another fairer
<br/>lack to thee, lack to thee ?” There are few, at the same
<br/>time, who do not feel disposed to weep outright, when they
<br/>hear of such things as “ Hope withdrawing her peradven-
<br/>ture”—“ spirits dealing in pathos of antithesis”—“ angels in
<br/>antagonism to God and his reflex beatitudes”—“ songs of
<br/>glories ruffling down doorways”—“God’s possibles”—and
<br/>“ rules of Mandom.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p> We have already said, however, that mere quaintness with-
<br/>in reasonable limit, is not only not to be regarded as affecta-
<br/>tion, but has its proper artistic uses in aiding a fantastic ef-
<br/>fect. We quote, from the lines “To my dog Flush,” a
<br/>passage in exemplification :</p>
         <p>Leap! thy broad tail waves a light!
Leap! thy slender feet are bright,
</p>
         <p>Canopied in fringes !
<br/>Leap! those tasselled ears of thine
<br/>Flicker strangely, fair and fine,</p>
         <p>Down their golden inches !
And again—from the song of a tree-spirit, in the “ Drama
of Exile
</p>
         <p>The Divine impulsion cleaves
<br/>In dim movements to the leaves
<br/>Dropt and lifted, dropt and lifted,</p>
         <p>In the sun-light greenly sifted,—
In the sun-light and the moon-light
Greenly sifted through the trees.
Ever wave the Eden trees,
In the night-light and the noon-light,
With a ruffling of green branches,
Shaded off to resonances,
Never stirred by rain or breeze.
</p>
         <p>The thoughts, here, belong to the highest order of poetry,
<br/>but they could not have been wrought into effective expres-
<br/>sion, without the instrumentality of those repetitions—those
<br/>unusual phrases—in a word, those quaintnesses, which it
<br/>has been too long the fashion to censure, indiscriminately,
<br/>under the one general head of “ affectation.” No true poet
<br/>will fail to be enraptured with the two extracts above quo-
<br/>ted—but we believe there are few who would not find a
<br/>difficulty in reconciling the psychal impossibility of refrain-
<br/>ing from admiration, with the too-hastily attained mental
<br/>conviction that, critically, there is nothing to admire.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Occasionally, we meet in Miss Barrett’s poems a certain
<br/>far-fetchedness of imagery, which is reprehensible in the
<br/>extreme. What, for example, are we to think of</p>
         <p>Now he hears the angel voices
Folding silence in the room?—
undoubtedly, that it is nonsense, and no more; or of
How the silence round you shivers
While our voices through it go?—
again, unquestionably, that it is nonsense, and nothing
beyond.
</p>
         <p>Sometimes we are startled by knotty paradoxes; and it is
<br/>not acquitting their perpetrator of all blame on their account
<br/>to admit that, in some instances, they are susceptible of</p>
         <p>solution. It is really difficult to discover anything for appro-
-bation, in enigmas such as
That bright impassive, passive angel-hood,
or—
The silence of my heart is full of sound.
At long intervals, we are annoyed by specimens of repul-
sive imagery, as where the children cry ;
How long, O cruel nation,
Will you stand, to move the world, on a child's heart—
Stifle down with a mailed heel its palpitation? etc.
Now and then, too, we are confounded by a pure plati-
tude, as when Eve exclaims:
Leave us not
In agony beyond what we can bear,
And in abasement below thunder mark!
or, when the Saviour is made to say:
So, at last,
He shall look round on you with lids too straight
To hold the grateful tears.
</p>
         <p>“ Strait” was, no doubt, intended, but does not materially
<br/>elevate, although it slightly elucidates, the thought. A very
<br/>remarkable passage is that, also, wherein Eve bids the infant
<br/>voices</p>
         <p>Hear the steep generations, how they fall
Adown the visionary stairs of Time,
Like supernatural thunders—far yet near,
Sowing their fiery echoes through the hills!
</p>
         <p>Here, saying nothing of the affectation in “adown;” not
<br/>alluding to the insoluble paradox of “ far yet near;" not
<br/>mentioning the inconsistent metaphor involved in the “ sow-
<br/>ing of fiery echoes;" adverting but slightly to the misusage
<br/>of “ like,” in place of “ as,” and to the impropriety of mak-
<br/>-ing any thing fall like thunder, which has never been known
<br/>to fall at all; merely hinting, too, at the misapplication of
<br/>“ steep,” to the “ generations,” instead of to the “ stairs”—
<br/>a perversion in no degree to be justified by the fact that so
<br/>preposterous a figure as synecdoche exists in the school
<br/>books;—letting these things pass, for the present, we shall
<br/>still find it difficult to understand how Miss Barrett should
<br/>have been led to think the principal idea itself—the abstract
<br/>idea—the idea of tumbling down stairs in any shape, or
<br/>under any circumstances,—either a poetical or a decorous
<br/>conception. And yet we have seen this very passage quoted
<br/>as “ sublime,” by a critic who seems to take it for granted,
<br/>as a general rule, that Nat-Leeism is the loftiest order of
<br/>literary merit. That the lines very narrowly missed sub-
<br/>limity, we grant; that they came within a step of it, we
<br/>admit;—but, unhappily, the step is that one step which,
<br/>time out of mind, has intervened between the sublime and
<br/>the ridiculous. So true is this, that any person—that even
<br/>we—with a very partial modification of the imagery—a mod-
<br/>ification that shall not interfere with its richly spiritual tone
<br/>—may elevate the quotation into unexceptionability. For
<br/>example: and we offer it with profound deference —</p>
         <p>Hear the far generations—how they crash,
From crag to crag, down the precipitous Time,
In multitudinous thunders that upstartle,
Aghast, the echoes from their cavernous lairs
In the visionary hills !
</p>
         <p>We have no doubt that our version has its faults—but it
<br/>has, at least, the merit of consistency. Not only is a moun-
<br/>tain more poetical than a pair of stairs; but echoes are
<br/>more appropriately typified as wild beasts than as seeds;
<br/>and echoes and wild beasts agree better with a mountain
<br/>than does a pair of stairs with the sowing of seeds—even
<br/>admitting that these seeds be seeds of fire, and be sown
<br/>broadcast “ among the hills,” by a steep generation while
<br/>in the act of tumbling down the stairs—that is to say, of
<br/>coming down the stairs in too violent a hurry to be capable
<br/>of sowing the seeds as accurately as all seeds should be
<br/>sown ; nor is the matter rendered any better for Miss Bar-
<br/>rett, even if the construction of her sentence is to be under-
<br/>stood as implying that the fiery seeds were sown, not imme-
<br/>diately by the steep generations that stumbled down the
<br/>stairs, but mediately, through the intervention of the “ super-
<br/>-natural thunders” that were occasioned by the “ steep gen-
<br/>-erations” that tumbled down the stairs.</p>
         <p>The poetess is not unfrequently guilty of repeating herself.
<div class="pagebreak" id="#page19"/>
         </p>
         <p>The “ thunder cloud veined by lightning” appears, for in- stance, on pages 34 of the first, and 228 of the second vol- 
<br/>ume. The “silver clash of wings” is heard at pages 53 of
<br/>the first, and 269 of the second ; and angel tears are discov-
<br/>ered to be falling as well at page 27, as at the conclusion of
<br/>“ The Drama of Exile.” Steam, too, in the shape of Death’s
<br/>White Horse, comes upon the ground, both at page 244 of the
<br/>first and 179 of the second volume—and there are multitudi-
<br/>nous other repetitions both of phrase and idea—but it is the
<br/>excessive reiteration of pet words which is, perhaps, the most
<br/>obtrusive of the minor errors of the poet. “ Chrystalline,”
<br/>“ Apocalypse,” “ foregone,” “ evangel,” “ ’ware,” “ throb,”
<br/>“ level,” “ loss,” and the musical term “ minor,” are forever
<br/>upon her lips. The chief favorites, however, are “ down”
<br/>and “ leaning,” which are echoed and re-echoed not only ad infinitum, but in every whimsical variation of import. As Miss Barrett certainly cannot be aware of the extent of this mannerism, we will venture to call her attention to a few—
<br/>comparatively a very few examples.</p>
         <p>Pealing down the depths of Godhead—
And smiling down the stars—
Smiling down, as Venus down the waves—
Smiling down the steep world'very purely—
Down the purple of this chamber—
Moving down the hidden depths of loving—
Cold the sun shines down the door—
Which brought angels down our talk—
Let your souls behind you lean gently moved —
But angels leaning from the golden seats—
And melancholy leaning out of heaven—
And I know the heavens are leaning down—
Then over the casement she leaneth—
Forbear that dream, too near to heaven if leaned—
I would lean my spirit o’er you—
Thou, O sapient angel, leanest o'er—
Shapes of brightness overlean thee—
They are leaning their young heads—
Out of heaven shall o’er you lean—
While my spirit leans and reaches—
Leaning from my human—
When it leans out on the air—
etc. etc. etc.
</p>
         <p>In the matter of grammar, upon which the Edinburgh
<br/>critic insists so pertinaciously, the author of “ The Drama of
<br/>Exile” seems to us even peculiarly without fault. The na-
<br/>ture of her studies has, no doubt, imbued her with a very
<br/>delicate instinct of constructive accuracy. The occasional
<br/>use of phrases so questionable as “from whence” and the
<br/>far-fetchedness and involution of which we have already spoken, are the only noticeable blemishes of an exceedingly
<br/>chaste, vigorous and comprehensive style.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In her inattention to rhythm, Mrs. Barrett is guilty of an
<br/>error that might have been fatal to her fame—that would
<br/>have been fatal to any reputation less solidly founded than
<br/>her own. We do not allude, so particularly, to her multipli-
<br/>city of inadmissible rhymes. We would wish, to be sure,
<br/>that she had not thought proper to couple Eden and succeed-
<br/>ing—glories and floorwise—burning and morning—thither
<br/>and tether—enclose me and across me—inisdoers and flow-
<br/>-ers—centre and winter—guerdon and pardon—conquer and
<br/>anchor—desert and unmeasured—atoms and fathoms—opal
<br/>and people—glory and doorway—trumpet and accompted—
<br/>taming and overcame him—coming and woman—is and trees
<br/>—off and sun-proof—eagles and vigils—nature and satire
<br/>—poems and interflowings—certes and virtues—pardon
<br/>and burden—thereat and great—children and bewildering—
<br/>mortal and turtle—moonshine and'sunshine. It would have
<br/>been better, we say, if such apologies for rhymes as these
<br/>had been rejected. But deficiencies of rhythm are more seri-
<br/>-ous. In some cases it is nearly impossible to determine
<br/>what metre is intended. “ The Cry of the Children” cannot
<br/>be scanned: we never saw so poor a specimen of verse. In
<br/>imitating the rhythm of “ Locksley Hall,” the poetess has
<br/>preserved with accuracy (so far as mere syllables are con-
<br/>cerned) the forcible line of seven trochees with a final caesura.
<br/>The “double rhymes" have only the force of a single long syl-
<br/>lable—a caesura; but the natural rhythmical division, occur-
<br/>-ring at the close of the fourth trochee, should never be forced to occur, as Miss Barrett constantly forces it, in the middle of
<br/>a word, or of an indivisible phrase. If it do so occur, we must sacrifice, in perusal, either the sense or the rhythm. If she
<br/>will consider, too, that this line of seven trochees and a
<br/>caesura, is nothing more than two lines written in one—a
<br/>line of four trochees, succeeded by one of three trochees and
<br/>a caesura—she will at once see how unwise she has been in
<br/>composing her poem in quatrains of the long line with alter-nate rhymes, instead of immediate ones, as in the case of</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Locksley Hall.” The result is, that the ear, expecting the
<br/>rhymes before they occur, does not appreciate them when
<br/>they do. These points, however, will be best exemplified
<br/>by transcribing one of the quatrains in its natural arrange-
<br/>ment. That actually employed is addressed only to the eye.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Oh, she fluttered like a tame bird
<br/>In among its forest brothers
<br/>Far too strong for it, then, drooping,</p>
         <p>Bowed her face upon her hands—
And I spake out wildly, fiercely,
Brutal truths of her and others !
I, she planted in the desert,
Swathed her ’wind-like, with my sands.
</p>
         <p>Here it will be seen that there is a paucity of rhyme, and
<br/>that it is expected at closes where it does not occur. In fact,
<br/>if we consider the eight lines as two independent quatrains,
<br/>(which they are), then we find them entirely rhymeless.
<br/>Now so unhappy are these metrical defects—of so much im-
<br/>portance do we take them to be, that we do not hesitate
<br/>in declaring the general inferiority of the poem to its proto-
<br/>type to be altogether chargeable to them. With equal rhythm
<br/>“ Lady Geraldine” had been far—very far the superior poem.
<br/>Inefficient rhythm is inefficient poetical expression; and ex-
<br/>pression, in poetry,—what is it ?—what is it not ? No one
<br/>living can better answer these queries than Miss Barrett.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We conclude our comments upon her versification, by quo-
<br/>ting (we will not say whence—from what one of her poems)
<br/>—a few verses without the linear division as it appears in
<br/>the book. There are many readers who would never sus-
<br/>pect the passage to be intended for metre at all.—“ Ay !—
<br/>and sometimes, on the hill-side, while we sat down on the
<br/>gowans, with the forest green behind us, and its shadow cast
<br/>before, and the river running under, and, across it from the
<br/>rowens a partridge whirring near us till we felt the air it
<br/>bore—there, obedient to her praying, did I read aloud the
<br/>poems made by Tuscan flutes, or instruments more various
<br/>of our own—read the pastoral parts of Spenser—or the sub-
<br/>tle interflowings found in Petrarch’s sonnets;—here’s the
<br/>book !—the leaf is folded down!”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>With this extract we make an end of our fault-finding—
<br/>and now, shall we speak, equally in detail, of the beauties of
<br/>this book ? Alas ! here, indeed, do we feel the impotence of
<br/>the pen. We have already said that the supreme excel-
<br/>lence of the poetess whose works we review, is made up of the
<br/>multitudinous sums of a world of lofty merits. It is the multi-
<br/>plicity—it is the aggregation—which excites our most pro-
<br/>found enthusiasm, and enforces our most earnest respect.
<br/>But unless we had space to extract three fourths of the vol-
<br/>umes, how could we convey this aggregation by specimens ?
<br/>We might quote, to be sure, an example of keen insight in-
<br/>to our psychal nature, such as this:</p>
         <p>I fell flooded with a Dark,
In the silence of a swoon—
When I rose, still cold and stark,
There was night,—I saw the moon :
And the stars, each in its place,
And the May-blooms on the grass,
Seemed to wonder what I was.
And I walked as if apart
From myself when I could stand—
And I pitied my own heart,
</p>
         <p>As if I held it in my hand
<br/>Somewhat coldly,—with a sense
<br/>Of fulfilled benevolence.</p>
         <p>Or we might copy an instance of the purest and most radi-
-ant imagination, such as this :
So, young muser, I sat listening
To my Fancy’s wildest word—
On a sudden, through the glistening
Leaves around, a little stirred,
Came a sound, a sense of music, which was rather felt than heard.
Softly, finely, it inwound me—
From the world it shut me in—
Like a fountain falling round me
Which with silver waters thin,
Holds a little marble Naiad sitting smilingly within.
</p>
         <p>Or, again, we might extract a specimen of wild Dantesque
<br/>vigor, such as this—in combination with a pathos never ex-
<br/>-celled :</p>
         <p>Ay! be silent—let them hear each other breathing
For a moment, mouth to mouth—
Let them touch each others’ hands in a fresh wreathing
Of their tender human youth !
Let them feel that this cold metallic motion
Is not all the life God fashions or reveals—
Let them prove their inward souls against the notion
That they live in you, or under you, O wheels!
Or, still again, we might give a passage embodying the
<div class="pagebreak" id="#page20"/>
most elevated sentiment, most tersely and musically thus ex-
pressed :
And since, Prince Albert, men have called thy spirit high and rare,
And true to truth, and brave for truth, as some at Augsburg were—
We charge thee by thy lofty thoughts and by thy poet-mind,
Which not by glory or degree takes measure of mankind,
Esteem that wedded hand less dear for sceptre than for ring,
And hold her uncrowned womanhood to be the royal thing!
</p>
         <p>These passages, we say, and a hundred similar ones, ex-
<br/>emplifying particular excellences, might be displayed, and
<br/>we should still fail, as lamentably as the skolastikos with his
<br/>brick, in conveying an idea of the vast totality. By no indi-
<br/>vidual stars can we present the constellatory radiance of the
<br/>book.—To the book, then, with implicit confidence we appeal.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>That Miss Barrett has done more, in poetry, than any wo-
<br/>man, living or dead, will scarcely be questioned:—that she
<br/>has surpassed all her poetical contemporaries of either sex
<br/>(with a single exception) is our deliberate opinion—not idly
<br/>entertained, we think, nor founded on any visionary basis. It
<br/>may not be uninteresting, therefore, in closing this examina-
<br/>tion of her claims, to determine in what manner she holds
<br/>poetical relation with these contemporaries, or with her im-
<br/>mediate predecessors, and especially with the great excep-
<br/>tion to which we have alluded,—if at all.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>If ever mortal “ wreaked his thoughts upon expression” it
<br/>was Shelley. If ever poet sang (as a bird sings)—impulsively
<br/>—earnestly—with utter abandonment—to himself solely—
<br/>and for the mere joy of his own song—that poet was the au-
<br/>thor of the Sensitive Plant. Of Art—beyond that which is
<br/>the inalienable instinct of Genius—he either had little or dis-
<br/>dained all. He really disdained that Rule which is the ema-
<br/>tion from Law, because his own soul was law in itself. His
<br/>rhapsodies are but the rough notes—the stenographic memo-
<br/>randa of poems—memoranda which, because they were all-
<br/>sufficient for his own intelligence, he cared not to be at the
<br/>trouble of transcribing in full for mankind. In his whole life
<br/>he wrought not thoroughly out a single conception. For this
<br/>reason it is that he is the most fatiguing of poets. Yet he
<br/>wearies in having done too little, rather than too much; what
<br/>seems in him the diffuseness of one idea, is the conglomerate
<br/>concision of many;—and this concision it is which renders him
<br/>obscure. With such a man, to imitate was out of the ques-
<br/>tion ; it would have answered no purpose—for he spoke to
<br/>his own spirit alone, which would have comprehended no
<br/>alien tongue;—he was, therefore, profoundly original. His
<br/>quaintness arose from intuitive perception of that truth to
<br/>which Lord Verulam alone has given distinct voice:—“ There
<br/>is no exquisite beauty which has not some strangeness in its
<br/>proportion." But whether obscure, original, or quaint, he
<br/>was at all times sincere. He had no affectations.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>From the ruins of Shelley there sprang into existence, af-
<br/>fronting the Heavens, a tottering and fantastic pagoda, in
<br/>which the salient angles, tipped with mad jangling bells,
<br/>were the idiosyncratic faults of the great original—faults
<br/>which cannot be called such in view of his purposes, but
<br/>which are monstrous when we regard his works as address-
<br/>ed to mankind. A “ school” arose—if that absurd term
<br/>must still be employed—a school—a system of rules—upon
<br/>the basis of the Shelley who had none. Young men innu-
<br/>merable, dazzled with the glare and bewildered with the
<br/>bizarrerie of the divine lightning that flickered through the
<br/>clouds of the Prometheus, had no trouble whatever in heap-
<br/>ing up imitative vapors, but, for the lightning, were content,
<br/>perforce, with its spectrum, in which the bizarrerie appear- ed without the fire. Nor were great and mature minds un-impressed by the contemplation of a greater and more ma-ture; and thus gradually were interwoven into this school
<br/>of all Lawlessness—of obscurity, quaintness, exaggeration—
<br/>the misplaced didacticism of Wordsworth, and the even more
<br/>preposterously anomalous metaphysicianism of Coleridge.
<br/>Matters were now fast verging to their worst, and at length,
<br/>in Tennyson, poetic inconsistency attained its extreme. But
<br/>it was precisely this extreme (for the greatest error and the
<br/>greatest truth are scarcely two points in a circle)—it was
<br/>this extreme which, following the law of all extremes,
<br/>wrought in him—in Tennyson—a natural and inevitable re-
<br/>vulsion, leading him first to contemn and secondly to investi-
<br/>gate his early manner, and, finally, to winnow from its mag-
<br/>nificent elements the truest and purest of all poetical styles.
<br/>But not even yet is the process complete; and for this rea-
<br/>son in part, but chiefly on account of the mere fortuitousness
<br/>of that mental and moral combination which shall unite in
<br/>one person (if ever it shall) the Shelleyan abandon, the Ten-</p>
         <p/>
         <p>nysonian poetic sense, the most profound instinct of Art, and
<br/>the sternest Will properly to blend and vigorously to control
<br/>all;—chiefly, we say, because such combination of antago-
<br/>nisms must be purely fortuitous, has the world never yet
<br/>seen the noblest of the poems of which it is possible that it
<br/>may be put in possession.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>And yet Miss Barrett has narrowly missed the fulfilment
<br/>of these conditions. Her poetic inspiration is the highest—
<br/>we can conceive nothing more august. Her sense of Art is
<br/>pure in itself, but has been contaminated by pedantic study
<br/>of false models—a study which has the more easily led her
<br/>astray, because she placed an undue value upon it as rare—
<br/>as alien to her character of woman. The accident of having
<br/>been long secluded by ill health from the world has effected,
<br/>moreover, in her behalf, what an innate recklessness did for
<br/>Shelley—has imparted to her, if not precisely that abandon
<br/>to which I have referred, at least a something that stands
<br/>well in its stead—a comparative independence of men and
<br/>opinions with which she did not come personally in contact
<br/>—a happy audacity of thought and expression never before
<br/>known in one of her sex. It is, however, this same accident
<br/>of ill health, perhaps, which has invalidated her original
<br/>Will—diverted her from proper individuality of purpose—and
<br/>seduced her into the sin of imitation. Thus, what she
<br/>might have done we cannot altogether determine. What
<br/>she has actually accomplished is before us. With Tenny-
<br/>son’s works beside her, and a keen appreciation of them in
<br/>her soul—appreciation too keen to be discriminative;—with
<br/>an imagination even more vigorous than his, although some-
<br/>what less ethereally delicate; with inferior art and more fee-
<br/>ble volition; she has written poems such as he could not
<br/>write, but such as he, under her conditions of ill health and
<br/>seclusion, would have written during the epoch of his pupil-
<br/>dom in that school which arose out of Shelley, and from
<br/>which, over a disgustful gulf of utter incongruity and absur-
<br/>dity, lit only by miasmatic flashes, into the broad open mea-
<br/>dows of Natural Art and Divine Genius, he—Tennyson—is
<br/>at once the bridge and the transition.</p>
         <p>AGINCOURT, by G.P. R. James. [Republished by the Harpers.]
</p>
         <p>This is the title of Mr. James’s last novel, or rather, it is
<br/>the last one that we have seen ; there may be a later one.
<br/>Mr. James has published many volumes, by the help of a
<br/>rapid amanuensis, and the best natured readers hat ever an
<br/>author was blessed with. The books that bear his name on
<br/>their title-page, exceed, in reading matter, the entire litera-
<br/>ture of the Greeks. And yet, tried by a very low standard,
<br/>Mr. James cannot be called an author. If any of his admi-
<br/>rers claim this distinction for him, we should be glad to
<br/>know the beings that owe their existence to him. There are
<br/>many famous authors, whose names are never seen on the
<br/>title-page, of a book. Mr. James and a thousand like him,
<br/>have produced many books ; yet who will speak of them as
<br/>authors a century hence ?</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We read with amazement the catalogue of Scuderi’s and
<br/>Calprenede’s romances, and wonder where they found their
<br/>readers; but what will posterity say to the catalogue of
<br/>what is called the modern school of Romance, to the Jameses,
<br/>and Ainsworths, and Mrs. Gores ? leaving out the Mrs. Sher-
<br/>woods and Charlotte Elizabeths ? We took up a book a few
<br/>months since, with Mr. James’s name in the title-page, and
<br/>read it through, without discovering, until we reached the
<br/>last chapter, that we had read out of Arrah Neil, by Mr.
<br/>James, into the St. James’s of Mr. Harrison Ainsworth, a part
<br/>of each being bound together: the reading was so much alike,
<br/>and the James and the St. James being all the time at the
<br/>top of the page, that we never perceived that they were dif-
<br/>ferent books, by different authors. There is a class of novel
<br/>readers now, as there was in the time of Crebillon, jun., who
<br/>will read any thing that any body will write, provided it be
<br/>in the form of a story with a thread to it. This is essential.
<br/>It matters not how slender the thread may be; their curiosity</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page21"/>
         </p>
         <p>will hang upon it, if it will hang of itself; but a chain ca-
<br/>ble could not hold the attention of such readers, if a link were
<br/>wanting. A book that is read for the sake of the story may
<br/>as well be written by Professor Ingraham, or Eugene Sue, as
<br/>by Fielding, or Walter Scott. As the confirmed tippler is in-
<br/>different to the quality of his drink, if it only produces inebria-
<br/>tion. We have seen respectable looking ladies, and even
<br/>men, courageous enough to read a James’s novel in a steam-
<br/>boat cabin or a rail-road car. We knew a gentleman who
<br/>read Darnley twice. He is quite as remarkable a person, in
<br/>his way, as the man who read the Monnikins once. We
<br/>also know a country gentleman, who lives in a gothic castle
<br/>somewhere in New Jersey, who always enquires, whenever
<br/>he comes to town, which is about once a fortnight, whether
<br/>there is any thing new by James ? The last time he asked
<br/>this question, we replied, “ Yes, a new title."</p>
         <p/>
         <p>To review a new novel by Mr. James would be an entire
<br/>loss of time. His claims to notice were long ago determined.
<br/>His position in the literary word is as well defined as though
<br/>he had been dead a century. He must be a huge favourite
<br/>with his own countrymen, who pay a guinea and a half
<br/>apiece for his novels. His is one of “ the silver springs where
<br/>England drinks;" and he drinks their gold in return. With
<br/>us his novels sell for a shilling sterling ; but if we had to
<br/>pay the home price for them, as we ought to do, his trans-
<br/>atlantic readers Would be exceeding few. But he has his
<br/>regular customers, like an old established shop, and when he
<br/>gives up business, we have no doubt but that he will sell the
<br/>good-will of his readers to some young beginner in the same
<br/>line; we shall see an advertisement in the Times, one of
<br/>these days, something after this style:	“ A RARE CHANCE.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>For sale low, the good-will of a novel-producing establish-
<br/>ment, with a steady set of customers. A skilful amanuensis
<br/>and a large book of quotations will be included in the sale.
<br/>For particulars apply to G. P. R. James, Esquire, Historio-
<br/>-grapher to the Queen.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Mr. James’s style is so stretchy, and his stories are so ea-
<br/>-sily drawn out, that we have often thought he must employ
<br/>in some manner the universal caoutchouc in their composi-
<br/>-tion. We know a gentleman, who once, for lack of better
<br/>business, acted as Mr. James’s amanuensis, and put upon pa-
<br/>-per some half a dozen of his romances. He says that Mr.
<br/>James used to pour them out like a mountebank pulling rib-
<br/>-bons from his mouth, and apparently with as little mental
<br/>exertion. They kept coming continually, but the heap did
<br/>not increase,—the two ends of his stories seemed fastened
<br/>together, and were continually revolving round a pivot, pro-
<br/>-ducing motion, but no increase.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The first chapter in either of Mr. James’s books will afford
<br/>a good example of the manner in which he makes up his
<br/>volumes. Agincourt opens with this wordy catalogue of the
<br/>features of a cloudy night, which any young lady who is
<br/>mistress of the alphabet might do as well.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ The night was black as ink.” This leaves nothing more
<br/>to be said on the subject; it includes every shade of darkness.
<br/>But terseness of description like this, would not enable Mr.
<br/>James to spin out three volumes every three months, or of-
<br/>tener, so he goes on with his description. “ Not a solitary
<br/>twinkling star looked out through that wide expanse of
<br/>shadow, which our great poet (who is our great poet ?) called
<br/>the ' blanket of the dark;' clouds covered the Heaven;
<br/>the moon had not risen to tinge them even with gray ; and
<br/>the sun had too long set to leave one faint tinge of purple
<br/>upon the western sky. Trees, houses, villages, fields, and
<br/>gardens, all lay in one profound obscurity, and even the
<br/>course of the high road itself, required eyes well accustomed
<br/>to night-traveling, to be able to distinguish it, as it wandered</p>
         <p>through a rich part of Hampshire, amid alternate woods and
meadows.”
</p>
         <p>In the next sentence, the force of habit is described so mi-
<br/>-nutely and profoundly, that it appears as if Mr. James had
<br/>just discovered a new principle, which he was labouring to
<br/>make perfectly plain to his readers. “Habit is more our
<br/>master than we know, and often rules our external demeanour
<br/>whenever the spirit is called to take council in the deep
<br/>chamber within, showing upon the surface, without any ef-
<br/>fort on our part to hide our thoughts, a very different aspect
<br/>from that of the mind’s business at the moment.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We continually meet with descriptions like this, which
<br/>reads like a tailor’s bill of particulars, but leaves no more im-
<br/>pression on the mind than an invoice of merchandise.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Clothed in the most splendid array with which he had
<br/>been able to provide himself, his tight-fitting hose displaying
<br/>to the highest advantage his graceful, yet powerful limbs,
<br/>with the coat of black silk, spotted with flowers of gold, cut
<br/>wide, but gathered into numerous plaits or folds round the
<br/>collar and the waist, and confined by a rich girdle to the
<br/>form, while the sleeves, fashioned to the shape of the arm,
<br/>and fastened at the wrist, showed the contour of the swelling
<br/>muscles;—over his shoulder he wore a short mantle of em-
<br/>broidered cloth, trimmed with costly fur, the sleeves of
<br/>which, according to the custom of the day, were slashed
<br/>down the inner side, so as to suffer the arm to be thrust out
<br/>from them, while they, more for ornament than use, hung
<br/>down to the bend of the knee. On his feet he wore the riding
<br/>boots of the time, thrust down to the ankle; and—in accord-
<br/>ance with a custom, then new in the courts of France and
<br/>Burgundy, but which, ere long, found its way to England—
<br/>his heavy sword had been laid aside, and his only arm was
<br/>a rich hiked dagger, suspended by a gold ring from the clasp
<br/>of his girdle. His head was covered with a small bonnet, or
<br/>velvet cap, ornamented with a single long white feather,
<br/>showing that he had not yet reached the knightly rank, and
<br/>round it curled in large waves his glossy dark brown hair.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Nothing more can be said about the attire of this tremen-
<br/>-dous figure, without going into the particulars of his under-
<br/>-clothes, which we rather wonder at his not doing. But not
<br/>yet tired of his clothier-like description, he immediately
<br/>branches off upon the dresses of the six servants who stood
<br/>ready to accompany their master to the dwelling of the
<br/>Count of Charalois.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Mr. James has one very great merit; he never makes use
<br/>of foreign terms, but employs only words that can be found
<br/>in English dictionaries.</p>
         <p>The Fine Arts.
THE ART UNION PICTURES.
(Second Notice.)
</p>
         <p>Among the landscapes was a river scene by Jesse Talbot,
<br/>which would have been a very effective picture if it had
<br/>been reduced in its dimensions at least two thirds. The
<br/>finest landscapes that have ever been painted are small.
<br/>The thumb nail is wide enough to represent as much gran-
<br/>deur as the eye is capable of receiving from nature. All our
<br/>landscape painters make woful mistakes in the size of their
<br/>canvass. Nearly all of Cole’s paintings are too large for any
<br/>drawing-room; and unless seen from a proper distance, the
<br/>foreground of a large landscape must always produce a dis-
<br/>-agreeable effect; and when a large picture is hung at a suf-
<br/>-ficient distance to give a good effect to the foreground, the
<br/>best part of it is lost entirely. A life size representation of
<br/>nature in a landscape is impossible, except in the scenery of</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page22"/>
         </p>
         <p>a theatre, and not often there. There is a very good copy
<br/>of one of Claude’s seaports, at the exhibition room of the
<br/>American Art-Union, which should never be exceeded in
<br/>size by a painted landscape. The tone of a small picture is
<br/>not only more easily preserved than that of a large one, but
<br/>much greater freedom of touch can be given, because elabo-
<br/>rateness of detail is not necessary to prevent a coarse unfin-
<br/>ished aspect. Mr. Talbot’s landscapes are always pleasing,
<br/>and we discern from year to year a very marked improve-
<br/>ment in his productions. If he will forget that he ever saw
<br/>one of Cole’s pictures, and look quietly at Nature with a
<br/>clear eye, and make his own interpretations of her language,
<br/>without asking the aid of any other commentator than his
<br/>own heart, she will reward him as she does all who seek
<br/>communion with her in the integrity of their instincts. The
<br/>river in Mr. Talbot’s picture is quite as liquid as any of
<br/>Cole’s, whose rivers and lakes are either mud or glass.
<br/>It is surprising that a painter who has been so often upon
<br/>the water as Mr. Cole, should never have been able to retain
<br/>a distinct idea of its quality. Transparency, wetness, and
<br/>motion, seem never to have struck him as the peculiar pro-
<br/>perties of water. His lakes are large mirrors, his rivers
<br/>stone or slime.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>A marine painter should be cradled upon the sea, like
<br/>Vernet. Probably Moses could have painted flowing water
<br/>so naturally that you could have heard it ripple.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>There were several little pictures in the distribution, by
<br/>Bonfield, of Philadelphia, who must have led an amphibious
<br/>life in his boyhood. His sea pieces are so full of life and
<br/>motion, that you step aside in passing them to get out of
<br/>reach of the spray. The ship at anchor strains her cable so
<br/>naturally, swayed by the tide and the wind, that you expect
<br/>every moment that she will part from her moorings. His
<br/>water is salt, and full of life. You feel that it is the fishes’
<br/>element. But it has a defect which must be owing to the
<br/>painter having drawn his inspirations from the Delaware; it
<br/>is never clear, and his skies and clouds are of that disagree-
<br/>able yellowish hue peculiar to English coast scenery. These
<br/>reveal the secret of his birth. An artist whose eyes were
<br/>first opened in our transparent atmosphere, could never paint
<br/>such skies as we see in Mr. Bonfield’s pictures. His vessels,
<br/>too, are all foreign, with American flags at their mast heads.
<br/>But these trifles do not weigh against the world of truth and
<br/>feeling which pervade his paintings. It is with the eye as
<br/>with the tongue, the first impression which we receive from
<br/>Nature will always remain by us. If we are born under a
<br/>cloudy sky, a dull atmosphere will always be pleasantest to
<br/>us. Mr. Bonfield paints from Nature, but not from our
<br/>Nature. But there was a very fine little snow piece in the
<br/>distribution, by this artist, which had a genuine American
<br/>aspect. The appearance of early morning was. beautifully
<br/>given, and the fleecy pink clouds floating in an atmosphere
<br/>of pearly light, contrasted with the dazzling whiteness of
<br/>the snow, and the dark green evergreens, produced a most
<br/>charming and harmonious effect.</p>
         <p>The Art Union has distributed a good many of Mr. Bon-
field’s pictures, but never a poor one that bore his name.
</p>
         <p>One of the most promising landscapes among the pictures
<br/>distributed, was a view of Northeast Lake, Mount Washing-
<br/>-ton, by Wotherspoon, a name new to us among artists. But it
<br/>cannot remain long unknown if its possessor uses his talents
<br/>to any acconnt.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Calculating,” a small interior by T. Hicks, was an admi-
<br/>rable little picture, very finely colored, but lacking in inte-
<br/>rest from the head of the principal figure being entirely hid-
<br/>den by his hat.</p>
         <p>




</p>
         <p>“A lazy fisherman” by Chapman, might have been called a
<br/>lazy painter with equal truth. The landscape part of the pic-
<br/>ture looked as though it had been done with a white-wash
<br/>brush. It is a matter of surprise that an artist of his repu-
<br/>tation should allow such a performance to leave his hands.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The same remarks might be applied to the landscapes
<br/>of Mr. Oddie, which have generally something in them to
<br/>admire ; a modest adherence to nature in parts, but in parts
<br/>the most unaccountable negligence. We cannot understand
<br/>why an artist of Mr. Oddie’s talents should give so little
<br/>finish to his performances. As sketches they are full of pro-
<br/>mise, but as paintings they are always defective.</p>
         <p>MONUMENTS TO MR. CLAY.
</p>
         <p>The defeat of Mr. Clay is likely to result in good to a class
<br/>of citizens who could have expected nothing in the same way
<br/>from his election. If half the plans which have been propo-
<br/>sed for erecting monuments in his honour should be carried
<br/>out, all the architects and sculptors in the country will have
<br/>abundant employment for the next ten years; and the whig
<br/>states will present the appearance of a chess-board, so nu-
<br/>merous will be the obelisks and columns, erected in them.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We understand that a meeting of Mr. Clay’s friends was
<br/>held at the Astor House, a few evenings since, at which
<br/>William B. Astor presided, and that it was determined to
<br/>employ Mr. Crawford to execute a statue of the great states-
<br/>man ; and that ten thousand dollars were subscribed for that
<br/>purpose. This is all very liberal, and very proper. Mr. Craw-
<br/>ford has gained his reputation by hard work, and he can
<br/>be safely entrusted with such a commission. But if there is
<br/>to be a more public testimonial to Mr. Clay, in the shape of
<br/>a monument, we trust that proposals will be issued for plans,
<br/>that the best talent in the country may be employed, and
<br/>that our young artists may have an opportunity to show what
<br/>they are capable of doing.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>There is not probably another city in the world of the size
<br/>of New York, which cannot boast of a single monument
<br/>erected to commemorate some event in its history. The
<br/>merchants of our city have built an Exchange, at a cost
<br/>greatly exceeding that of the Royal Exchange in London,
<br/>which is not enriched by the slightest trophy of art, to
<br/>commemorate the names of any of the illustrious men, by
<br/>whose wisdom and patriotism the city and the state have
<br/>grown in wealth and importance, or to indicate the uses to
<br/>which it is devoted; while the Royal Exchange in London,
<br/>is profusely decorated with emblematical figures, and statues
<br/>of all the monarchs that have reigned in England. We no-
<br/>where see finer private residences than in this city; no town
<br/>on the continent will compare with New York, in the num-
<br/>ber of elegant houses, and in the evidences of a liberal out-
<br/>lay for individual comfort; but there are few that have less
<br/>proofs of a liberal outlay for the public good.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We have heard nothing recently about the Washington
<br/>Monument; and unless some other plan should be adopted
<br/>than that which has been exhibited, we hope never to hear
<br/>of it again. Mayor Harper is deserving of a monument
<br/>himself, for preventing its foundation from being laid in
<br/>Union Square. If such a disgrace were to be inflicted upon
<br/>this city as the erection of a monument after Mr. Pollard's
<br/>absurd model, it should be put as much out of sight as possi-
<br/>ble. Gothic churches, in the nineteenth century, are suffi-
<br/>ciently out of character; but a Gothic monument, in honour
<br/>of Washington, is the very sublime of nonsense. The idea
<br/>would have been every way worthy of the original wise
<br/>men of Gotham.</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page23"/>
MISS DELIA WEBSTER,
</p>
         <p>This dangerous person it appears has been condemned to
<br/>confinement in the state prison of Kentucky by the gallant
<br/>people of that state. If the age of chivalry has passed away,
<br/>it is at least some consolation to know that the age of gal-
<br/>lantry remains. It is reported in the newspapers that the
<br/>jury who convicted Miss Webster, recommended her to mer-
<br/>cy on the score of her sex, but we hardly think that this can
<br/>be true. The Kentuckians are too brave a people to allow so
<br/>dangerous a person as this young lady to go at large among
<br/>them. The chivalrous Carolinians assembled in great mul-
<br/>titudes in Charleston, to defend themselves from a gray-head-
<br/>ed old man and his young daughter, but they allowed him
<br/>to escape without doing him any personal violence. The
<br/>Kentuckians have proved themselves a much more chival-
<br/>rous people in their conduct towards Miss Webster, who be-
<br/>ing a stranger among them, and engaged in the disreputa-
<br/>ble and unfeminine business of teaching children for her sup-
<br/>port, was a person much to be dreaded. What makes the
<br/>gallantry of the Kentuckians appear in a more amiable light,
<br/>is the confession of guilt on the part of Miss Webster in a
<br/>letter to her former pastor in Massachusetts, dated in the
<br/>Lexington jail, where she had the entire freedom of the cell,
<br/>the gallant people having very kindly omitted to manacle
<br/>her limbs ; a favor which was not shown to the Methodist
<br/>preacher who was suspected of being a participator in her
<br/>guilt. “ I have twenty fellow prisoners,” says Miss Web-
<br/>ster ; “ Mr. Fairbanks, the methodist preacher, is heavily
<br/>ironed, and in a small dungeon with fifteen others, mostly
<br/>blacks. Two of his companions are to be executed in a few
<br/>days.” We put this on record that we may be able to point
<br/>triumphantly to the gallantry of the Kentuckians, in refusing
<br/>to put irons upon Miss Webster, in case any malignant fo-
<br/>reigner should ever disparage the working of our “ domestic
<br/>institutions."</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Miss Webster it appears is the daughter of a Vermont
<br/>farmer, who has always been strongly opposed to the aboli-
<br/>tionists, but the inhabitants of Lexington must have looked
<br/>upon her with a good deal of distrust when they remember-
<br/>ed the heavy abolition vote which her state gave at the last
<br/>election; and accordingly, when they could no longer shut
<br/>their eyes to her enormous guilt, they very wisely shut her
<br/>up in prison.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“On one occasion,” says Miss Webster in her letter,
<br/>“ perhaps when over excited, I remarked in company, that if
<br/>all the black population could be banished from our loved
<br/>country, I would cheerfully go myself to the wild and desert
<br/>shores of Africa to teach them that they have immortal
<br/>souls. This was perhaps an imprudent remark. If so, par-
<br/>don me. It is the only one I am guilty of. At the time I
<br/>felt it, and even now I know not that I am prepared to re-
<br/>call it.” She not only confesses her guilt, but she justifies
<br/>it. A very dangerous person.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“All I need here is friends,” says Miss Webster. She
<br/>probably wants to bribe the upright judges of that gallant
<br/>State. “I have only one hundred and fifteen dollars by me.
<br/>This will not do much towards paying lawyers. The fees
<br/>of lawyers already amount to seven hundred and fifty dollars.
<br/>These expose themselves to great censure by appearing at
<br/>all on this exciting occasion.” Great censure probably from
<br/>the other members of the profession for working so cheap.
<br/>We are happy to find by this part of Miss Webster’s letter
<br/>that the profession maintains its dignity in Kentucky by tak-
<br/>ing all it can get, even from a friendless woman in jail, con-
<br/>fined on suspicions of having an intention of going cheerfully
<br/>to the wild and desert shores of Africa to teach the blacks
<br/>that they have immortal souls.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Miss Webster, we believe, is still in prison, at least we have
<br/>seen no account of her release, and of course her situation as
<br/>principal of the Female Academy of Lexington is vacant.
<br/>Here is a desirable situation for some northern woman of
<br/>proper accomplishments. The successor of Miss Webster in
<br/>the Female Academy will have the happiness of knowing
<br/>that in the event of her ever becoming her successor in jail,
<br/>she will have the entire freedom of her dungeon without any
<br/>of the hindrances of double chains about her wrists and
<br/>ancles.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>It was in a Lexington that the first blood was shed in the
<br/>cause of American Independence. It was very proper there-
<br/>fore that the first imprisonment of a helpless woman for her
<br/>sympathies in the same cause should take place in a town
<br/>of the same name. But lest future historians should con-
<br/>found the two places, in narrating these illustrious events,
<br/>we think that the name of one of them should be changed.</p>
         <p>THE DUTCH AND THE PURITANS:
Or, NEW YORK VERSUS MASSACHUSETTS.
</p>
         <p>New York and Pennsylvania are continually making wry faces at
<br/>the arrogance of New England, in boasting of her Pilgrim Fathers, as
<br/>though they alone were entitled to any credit, in the colonial history
<br/>of the country. Plymouth Rock is a morsel too hard for the diges-
<br/>tion of Dutch stomachs. They are always uneasy when it is named,
<br/>and the happy hit of Mr. Reyburn, in calling it the Blarneystone of
<br/>America, caused more merriment among the Stuyvesants, and people
<br/>with a Van to their names, than any witticism that has been uttered
<br/>since the days of Walter the Testy.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The arrogance of the New Englanders is not to be commended, but
<br/>we do not comprehend the wisdom of sectional jealousies towards the
<br/>Pilgrim stock. History has no parallel to the founding of Plymouth
<br/>Colony. It is a fact which concerns not Massachusetts alone, but the
<br/>whole earth. The May-flower brought to this continent a more pre-
<br/>cious freightage than any other vessel ever discharged upon its shores.
<br/>The name of no other ship that brought colonists to America has
<br/>become immortal. The May-flower will bloom forever; it is too
<br/>brightly embroidered in our history, too firmly woven in song and story.
<br/>The names of no other settlers upon our shores are as familiar as
<br/>those of Plymouth. Carver, Standish, Brewster, and White, are
<br/>household words. Any child can tell you who and what they were.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The New Englander may be allowed to boast of his Pilgrim Fathers ;
<br/>but the New Yorker, and every other American, should also boast of
<br/>the Pilgrim Fathers. It is by no means a clear case, that the United
<br/>States would now be an Independent Nation, had the Pilgrims never
<br/>landed at Plymouth. Massachusetts is the inheritor of the name, but
<br/>all mankind are inheritors of the fame of the Pilgrim Fathers. All
<br/>the blustering and boasting of Massachusetts could never convince
<br/>the world of the greatness of her founders, if their own acts did not establish it. The founders of the other Colonies were adventurers—
<br/>but the founders of Massachusetts were pilgrims; here is all the dif-
<br/>ference. New England makes no boasts—she simply points to her
<br/>men and their acts. They do not take from the altitude of others,
<br/>because they tower so high themselves. “ There they are,” as Judge
<br/>Warren said the other day, “ aristocrats cradled on a rock, not rocked
<br/>in a cradle.” And aristocrats they are of the highest grade, who dig,
<br/>and sow, and reap; who earn their patents of nobility in the work-
<br/>shop, the field, and the ocean.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In the early days of the Republic, before sectional jealousies began
<br/>to break out, like foul sores in our system, the nation willingly yielded
<br/>itself to the guidance of Massachusetts mind, and prospered. During
<br/>the first forty years after the adoption of the Constitution, Massa-
<br/>chusetts had more than twice as many Representatives in the National
<br/>Cabinet as New York had, and treble the number of Pennsylvania.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Although our vast territory is now pretty well irrigated with streams
<br/>from the Pilgrim stock, we can ill afford to spare a drop which flows
<br/>from that source; there is too little of similar blood in the country.
<br/>In looking upon the Pilgrims, we are too apt to see nothing but their
<br/>religious faults, which were glaring enough; and even their descend-
<br/>ants as frequently laud them for their foibles as for their virtues. But
<br/>the peculiar trait of the Pilgrims was their opposition to tyranny. It
<br/>is this which has set them apart from other men. If a love of free-
<br/>dom were a common quality, such men as William Tell would not</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page24"/>
         </p>
         <p>rise so high above the heads of the multitude. Great men must al-
<br/>ways stand alone. It is only by a cone that a great altitude can be
<br/>reached, and the higher you ascend the less room will be found.
<br/>Whoever reaches the top must stand alone. This Excelsior is an
<br/>unsocial cry. Mankind, in extolling such men as the Pilgrims, pro-
<br/>nounce themselves slaves. The Pilgrims were not remarkable men
<br/>to each other ; William Tell would have hailed them as mates, not
<br/>men to wonder at and talk about.</p>
         <p>But we are wandering from our purpose. We intended only to make
a few remarks introductory to a speech from somebody else.
</p>
         <p>An amusing instance of the complacency of New England pride oc-
<br/>curred at the dinner of the New York Historical Society last month.
<br/>To give importance to their festival, they had invited Mr. Adams, the
<br/>old man eloquent, as the newspapers call him, without adding, as they
<br/>ought to do, the next line of the sonnet from which the phrase is quo-
<br/>ted, “ once president.” All the talk, all the speeches, and all the toasts,
<br/>or nearly all, were about New England, and the Pilgrims. The givers
<br/>of the feast were entirely overlooked, and the guests with great cool-
<br/>ness, toasted themselves. It was like the case of the famous Ameri-
<br/>can-Parisian Colonel, whose titled guests refused to acknowledge him
<br/>as an acquaintance, while they ate his supper and drank his wine. This
<br/>was all in bad taste, to say the least of it, and it was no wonder that
<br/>some sturdy New Yorkers took offence at the quiet contempt of their
<br/>guests. Dutch blood, though slow to rise, at last began to boil, and a
<br/>member of the society jumped upon his feet, and, proposing the follow-
<br/>ing toast, reminded his fellow members that New York had a history
<br/>as well as New England.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“NEW YORK—The Empire Colony of the old Thirteen Provinces. Her
<br/>motto still 'EXCELSIOR.’ May her Eagle in his proudest flight, never forget
<br/>the gallant trials which first nerved his pinion.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Notwithstanding the lateness of the hour, Mr. President, (said the
<br/>gentleman who offered this toast,*) I claim your indulgence for a few
<br/>words, in explanation of the sentiment I have just offered. [Hear.]
<br/>Commenting sportively to the friend by my side, upon the ingenious
<br/>avoidance to-night of any allusion to those who entertained the plant-
<br/>ers of Plymouth rock for twelve years, in Old Amsterdam, or the his-
<br/>torical associations of those who have to-day entertained their de-
<br/>scendants for as many hours in New Amsterdam, it was suggested by
<br/>a fellow-member that the proceedings of this celebration would wear rather an awkward aspect when given to the world. Our anniversary
<br/>festival would seem to be held rather in commemoration of Massa-
<br/>chusetts than of New York. [Hear, hear.] Another gentleman oppo-
<br/>site to me has also suggested that inasmuch as this Society has been,
<br/>from time to time, liberally aided by the State Legislature, it were
<br/>positively disrespectful to the people who are represented in that
<br/>Legislature, if no special reference to their past history should be
<br/>made, upon an occasion like the present. [Hear, hear—speak louder.]</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The able discourses upon early New York, delivered before this
<br/>Society more than a generation since, by Governeur Morris and De
<br/>Witt Clinton, and some fifteen years later by Chancellor Kent and
<br/>Gulian C. Verplanck—names not yet wholly forgotten by the present
<br/>population of New York—induced a hope, in the early part of the
<br/>evening, that by some allusion, either to these productions or to
<br/>the past history which those productions illustrate; or, finally, to the
<br/>names of those eminent New Yorkers themselves, the office which I
<br/>have thus hastily undertaken would be measurably fulfilled.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The majority of the company, however, have, I presume, like my-
<br/>self, been so much interested in the eloquent commentaries upon
<br/>the local annals of Massachusetts, and the ever-memorable excellence
<br/>of her pilgrim fathers, that the hours have sped on in perfect forget-
<br/>fulness of our forefathers. [Hear, hear.] Sir, we have heard much
<br/>to-night of "the pure Anglo-Saxon stock,” and of the men who first
<br/>settled on the Eastern outer-casing of this continent. We have heard
<br/>little of those who struck inwardly to its heart, and grappled at once
<br/>with its strong vital pulsations at the head of its tide-waters. We
<br/>have heard nothing, sir, since we left yonder church, of those bold Bel-</p>
         <p/>
         <p>gic navigators, whose flag led that of Britain on every sea; those
<br/>devoted Huguenots who sprang with such vigor from beneath the
<br/>shadow of despotism, that they made but one bound from luxurious
<br/>France to this then savage wilderness; those brave English cavaliers,
<br/>who, recoiling from Puritan intolerance with the same spirit as did
<br/>the Huguenots from Papal bigotry, came hither with little but cloak
<br/>and rapier, to carve out their fortunes amid the forests of New York.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>A trinity of good blood, that in producing God-like men would mate
<br/>with the Anglo-Saxon the world over. But here, [Hear, hear, and vo-ciferous cheers.] sir, I wish I could recall now the eloquent language
<br/>of Governeur Morris, when he speaks of the fusion of these three
<br/>races upon a soil which had already nurtured the noblest and most powerful race of Aborigines upon this continent—the Roman like and far-conquering Iroquois ! That I could recall, too, his predictions
<br/>of what those blended forces of best manhood must accomplish, in a
<br/>region whose natural resources afford a field for all the most powerful
<br/>energies of civilization ! He looked upon the Susquehannah connect-ing us with the Chesapeake; upon the Genessee connecting us with
<br/>the Gulf of St. Lawrence ; upon the Alleghany linking us with the
<br/>sea of Mexico; upon the great Lakes binding us to the boundless West; upon the Hudson uniting us with the civilized world: He turned from the bloody school of our energies, in a hundred and fifty years of border wars, and imagined those same indomitable powers applied to the arts of peace ! [Cheers.]</p>
         <p>* Mr. C. F. Hoffman.
</p>
         <p>Sir, the curious speculative theory of that philosophic statesman
<br/>is now History. Yes, sir, it has been history or more than twenty
<br/>years. [Prolonged cheering.] Sir, the men of New York were act-
<br/>ing History while those in other States were writing it for us and our
<br/>children. Am I extravagant? It must be so, sir, or how else could
<br/>our own brilliant early annals become overlaid, as they are, by the
<br/>purely local, and to us comparatively foreign themes of the Ply-
<br/>mouth Rock and the Pilgrim Fathers ! [A voice.] “We must look
<br/>nearer home," some gentleman observes ; our gazetteers and school
<br/>histories are certainly nearly all prepared by New Englanders igno-
<br/>rant of our annals, and unsympathizing in our story. Why, I saw
<br/>a new octavo Gazetteer this very day, in which several pages are
<br/>gravely quoted from Knickerbocker’s New York, as veritable history.
<br/>[A laugh.] But I will "look nearer home,” as the gentleman invites
<br/>me. Sir, the successful mingling of those wondrous waters has raised
<br/>such a wave as almost to wash from the memory of the present gen-
<br/>eration the deeds of colonial enterprise upon which Mr. Morris pre-
<br/>dicted his generous prophecy. We hear much of “ the Empire State,”
<br/>we forget "the Empire Colony”—the province where the two most
<br/>powerful nations of Europe so long contended for empire. We forget that with a population less than that of cither Massachusetts or Vir-
<br/>ginia, here was the great seat of English executive and colonial power,
<br/>in time of peace ; and here, as Chancellor Kent has so happily termed
<br/>it, "the Flanders of North America,” in time of war. Mr. President,</p>
         <p/>
         <p>the old military glory of New York should not be thus forgotten!
<br/>Surely, the martial spirit of our fathers has cost enough in years gone
<br/>by ! That martial spirit which, leaving so few non-combatants, made
<br/>! the Revolution within our borders truly a civil war: That spirit of action which compelled every New Yorker to take up arms for king
<br/>or colony,—which furnished regiment alter regiment to the Crown,
<br/>and treble the number to the Confederacy; which blazed forth with
<br/>all its desperate energies, in the death-grapple of brothers at
<br/>Oriskany, and which is traceable in the gallantry of New York’s
<br/>exiled sons down to the field of Waterloo ! Surely that military spirit
<br/>of the storied past should not be forgotten, while we enjoy its nest
<br/>fruits in the prosperous present. [Never, never ; three cheers.]</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ The battle-field of America !” Why, sir. the border conflicts
<br/>with naked savages of all the States put together, would not fill up
<br/>the military page of our history, even previous to—[A voice, “ the
<br/>Revolution,”] not the Revolution—no, sir, nor what is called " the
<br/>old French War,”—but previous to the year of grace, 1700 ! [Hear.]</p>
         <p> Is it too late ? or will gentlemen yet bear with me for a few
moments, in a rapid enumeration of a few solid facts. [Go on, go on.]
</p>
         <p>I will go on. We have heard much to-night of what our Eastern
<br/>neighbours have endured for the promotion of doctrine,—it may be
<br/>healthful to hear what our fathers did for the protection of home.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>You have heard from our Orator, before we came to the table, that
<br/>the Dutch Hollanders penetrated to Albany, in 1609, the same year
<br/>that the French, under La Roche, reached Lake George. You are
<br/>aware, too, that both France and Holland laid a claim to the interme-
<br/>diate country predicated upon these several discoveries. It may be
<br/>necessary to remind you, though, that to enforce their claim the
<br/>French soon commenced supplying the Hurons, and other Canadian
<br/>Indians, with fire-arms,—while the Dutch were equally on the alert
<br/>to furnish the Iroquois* with Europern weapons to repel them. For
<br/>nearly thirty years the French were more or less successful, in making
<br/>inroads upon this Province ; but in 1650 the Iroquois beat them back
<br/>to Montreal, stormed the garrison of Trois Rivieres, and carried off
<br/>the commandant prisoner. Those victors were "Natives” of New
<br/>York. [Cheers.] Yes! in thirty years her strong soil had already
<br/>produced a crop of men from the aboriginal stock, capable of con-
<br/>tending with veterans who had fought under the greatest captains of
<br/>modern Europe. But I must not delay with comments upon the hur-
<br/>ried enumeration which may yet try your patience. In 1666, De
<br/>Tracy, De Chaumont, and De Courcelles, with twelve hundred
<br/>French soldiers, two pieces of cannon, and a thousand Indians and
<br/>camp followers, descended upon the Mohawk and carried off many
<br/>Iroquois prisoners, which were afterwards sent to the galleys in
<br/>France. The northern and western barrier of the Province seemed
<br/>giving away, and its ultimate subjection to the arms of France seemed
<br/>inevitable, when in 1685 M. de la Barre descended with a force of
<br/>seventeen hundred men, upon Sackett’s Harbor—yet three years
<br/>afterwards, in 1688, we again find twelve hundred New York Indians
<br/>under the walls of Montreal. [Cheers.] "
<br/>I give you four days to
<br/>decide,” said their leader to the French commandant, “ I give you
<br/>four days to decide, whether you accept the terms of pence offered
<br/>you by New York, or be driven into the sea.” They did accept them !
<br/>[Cheers.]</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In 1690 we find the French again within fifteen miles of Albany,—
<br/>they succeeded in burning Schenectady—but a few months afterwards
<br/>these red New Yorkers are again upon the island of Montreal, and
<br/>though repulsed, they left their traces in blood and ashes, cut off one
<br/>of the outposts, killed the commandant, and carried off several offi-
<br/>cers.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In 1691 the adventurous Frenchmen again penetrated to the Mo-
<br/>hawk, and again in the same year the Iroquois have driven them from
<br/>our borders, on Champlain and Ontario.</p>
         <p>“The only way to conquer the Iroquois,” said M. De Nonville to
Louis XIV., “ is by the previous conquest of New York.”
“ The only way to save New York,” said Leisler, the people’s Gov-
ernor, " is by the previous conquest of Canada.”
</p>
         <p>In 1692, a fleet was commissioned by the Court of France to reduce
<br/>the City of New York, and get the mastery of the Hudson ; and an
<br/>army transported from France to strike at Albany, by the way of
<br/>Canada; but while these forces are crossing the Atlantic, the New
<br/>York Indians have again driven the French within the defences of
<br/>Montreal.</p>
         <p>In 1693 the French are repulsed from Schenectady by Peter Schuyler,
* Called also "Mingoes” and "Five Nations."
<div class="pagebreak" id="#page25"/>
at the head of two hundred and ninety white, and two hundred and
fifty red, New Yorkers. [Cheers and a laugh.]
</p>
         <p>In 1695 we find a command of three hundred French soldiers obtain-
<br/>ing an advantage over the New York confederates at Oswego, while
<br/>five hundred, who made their descent by the way of Lake Champlain,
<br/>are beaten back with loss.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In 1696, one of the best appointed armies that ever displayed upon
<br/>this continent, landed at Oswego, under command of the veteran
<br/>general Count de Frontenac. Cannon, mortars, grenades, four heavy
<br/>battalions of musqueteers, with a commissariat amply provided,—an
<br/>army led on by an array of Counts, Barons, Chevaliers, and private
<br/>gentleman volunteers, each with his following of servants and camp
<br/>equipage, penetrated in their batteaux, from Oswego into Lake Onon-
<br/>dago, on whose banks they built a fort, and then proceeded to ravage
<br/>the country. So active was the Baron de Beckancourt, the Chevalier
<br/>de Grais, de Mesnil, and other French nobles, all bent upon distin-
<br/>guishing themselves in this wild and, as they thought, romantic war-
<br/>fare, that all that portion of New York cultivated by our demi-civil-
<br/>ized tribes, was reduced to desolation, by their ravages. A fearful
<br/>famine succeeded ; yet again and again is the red arm of the Iroquois
<br/>felt in Canada, till the peace of Ryswick brought a breathing spell
<br/>to both colonies.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In 1710 the Province of New York is again converted into an armed
<br/>camp. The troops of Connecticut and New Jersey being mustered at
<br/>Wood Creek with her own, to prevent the French from breaking
<br/>through to the Atlantic, by way of the Hudson.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In 1711, four thousand Provincials, with six hundred Iroquois, mus-
<br/>tered at Albany, while the old border struggles are renewed till the
<br/>peace of Utrecht, in 1713.</p>
         <p>In 1727 the Province is again in arms, under Governeur Burnet,
marching upon the French, at Niagara.
</p>
         <p>In 1746 Saratoga is surprised by the French and Hurons, and thirty
<br/>families are cut off in a night,—while in the same year the New York
<br/>confederates carry off a whole garrison, from within ten leagues of
<br/>Montreal; and thus the frontier war continued to rage till the treaty
<br/>of Aix-la-Chapelle brought a temporary peace to the Province.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>1755 brings us to the battle of Lake George, where Sir William
<br/>Johnson won his spurs, and where eight hundred of the invaders,
<br/>under Dieskau, were left dead upon the field.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The assault of the Marquis of Montcalm, on Fort Ontario, with
<br/>four thousand troops, follows ; and the massacre of Fort William
<br/>Henry, at Lake George, with the devastation of German Flats, on the
<br/>Mohawk, by the invaders, brings us to (1758) the duplicate battle of Lake George, when seventeen thousand men under Abercrombie, were
<br/>defeated by the French; the reduction of Fort Frontinac, on Lake Ontario, by three thousand provincials; the fight with the galleys, on
<br/>Lake Champlain, and the different affairs of Crown Point and Ticon-
<br/>deroga.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In 1776, the empire Colony, where European competitors have so long
<br/>contended for the mastery of this northern continent, became her-
<br/>self—the aspirant for Empire. Need I enumerate our storied fields of the Revolution? To set them justly before you—to trace the spirit that animated many of them, I should begin with the popular movements for liberty in New York, long years preceding the Decla- ration of Independence ! But I must not dilate upon the incidental branches of my theme. It is the military story, too,—not the politi-
<br/>cal, annals of New York, that I am attempting thus hastily to illus-trate. Within the seven years of the Revolution, the Battle of Long ;
<br/>Island, the Battle of White Plains, the Storming of Stoney Point, the
<br/>affair of Fort Montgomery, the Burning of Kingston, the sanguinary
<br/>struggles of Cherry Valley and the Mohawk, with Oriskany, the
<br/>bloodiest field of all our Revolutionary conflicts, and Saratoga, the
<br/>most glorious, crowd in with Niagara, Saratoga, and Crown Point, to
<br/>mark their names yet again upon the blazing tablet of our military
<br/>annals. [Great sensation.]</p>
         <p/>
         <p>1814—And yet again, [Continued cheers,] and yet again the events
<br/>at Erie and Sackett’s Harbor, at Champlain and Niagara, come in to
<br/>swell the record of deeds of arms, and approve New York the Battle
<br/>field of the Union, the Flanders of American history. [Vociferous
<br/>cheering.]</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Sir, I am grateful for the patience with which, at this late hour, I
<br/>have been listened to by the company, but I make no apology for thus
<br/>detaining them. It is good to remember—it is good for peoples, as
<br/>well as individuals, to remember who they are, what they are, and
<br/>how they came thus. There is no one to speak for us ; it is time we should speak for ourselves. Our neighbors have been writing history while we have been acting it. I respect, I reverence, sir, the zeal
<br/>with which they preserve their own annals, but it is full time we should
<br/>see that they so write them as not to overlay and obliterate ours.
<br/>Their generalizations about "the pure Anglo-Saxon race” have al-
<br/>ready become naturalized here ; the specific phrase of "our Pilgrim
<br/>Fathers" is rapidly following; sir, the history of this State is no his-
<br/>tory of “ the Puritan Anglo-Saxon,” and save as the descendants of
<br/>those earnest-souled, vigorous-minded men who fought side by side with
<br/>us, in the Revolution, our provincial annals are no more to be merged
<br/>in those of Massachusetts than they are in those of Virginia. The
<br/>bird that bears excelsior in his beak was fledged on our own soil.
<br/>He never began his soarings from Plymouth Rock. He dressed his
<br/>plumage in our own lakes, and his pinions were nerved in the air of
<br/>our own mountains.</p>
         <p>GOOD ADVICE.
</p>
         <p>The market is always overstocked with good advice; but
<br/>nobody knows how abundant the article is so well as an
<br/>editor of a newspaper. To all our friends who have gene-
<br/>rously extended their aid to us in the way of advice, we re-</p>
         <p/>
         <p>turn our hearty thanks, and will endeavor to profit by their
<br/>innumerable and conflicting opinions. Some gentlemen who
<br/>are not of sufficient consequence to be fallen a-foul-of them-
<br/>selves, recommend us to be very massacrante, and spare nei-
<br/>ther sex nor condition in our criticisms; others are of opinion,
<br/>that the only true course for an editor is to be calm, quiet,
<br/>and dignified; to study the weathercock of popular favor, and
<br/>strive to keep always before the wind. A gentleman writes
<br/>us a short hasty note, in a red-pepper looking hand, in these
<br/>words:</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Dear Sir—I like your plan much; go ahead. Cut up
<br/>everything; slash away right and left—don't leave an error
<br/>standing on its legs. Yours, in haste,	Gr. C.</p>
         <p>P. S. There is one author that you mus’nt say anything
ill about—Mr.——, he is a friend of mine.”
</p>
         <p>Another kind friend has sent us a long letter, containing
<br/>a set of rules to be observed in our critical capacity; but
<br/>whether they are meant in earnestness or jest, we cannot
<br/>determine. But we will print them for the benefit of others,
<br/>who may not, like ourselves, have any settled principles in
<br/>criticism.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Sir—I perceive that you have established a Critical
<br/>Journal, and not doubting but that you may need assistance
<br/>in your undertaking, I send you the following rules, which I
<br/>drew up for myself and an associate in a Quarterly Review,
<br/>which was projected but never published. They are en-
<br/>tirely at your service, and I hope will do you much good.”</p>
         <p>RULES FOR CRITICISM.
</p>
         <p>Rule 1. In regard to an Author's first appearance.—It
<br/>will always be safe to condemn every author on his first
<br/>appearance, without being at the trouble of examining his
<br/>productions. And as this can be done in very concise and
<br/>biting terms, it will afford a good opportunity for a young
<br/>practitioner to try his hand; the chances are, that good will
<br/>result from such a course. As nobody will read an author’s
<br/>first book, which has been condemned without reservation,
<br/>the critic will gain credit for smartness without anybody ever
<br/>suspecting that it is not deserved. There is but little danger
<br/>from this course, because unknown authors are generally the
<br/>most obscure of all unknown people, and as they will have
<br/>no friends to advocate their cause, they will be too much
<br/>cowed ever to do it themselves. It will generally, too, be
<br/>the most just way of proceeding with a young author, al-
<br/>though the justice of it is not a thing of much consequence,
<br/>as first attempts in authorship, like first attempts in every-
<br/>thing else, are generally immature and ill executed. It is a
<br/>well-known historical fact, that Rome was not built in a day,
<br/>and it takes time even to make an author. But if it should
<br/>turn out that your criticism was unjust, and instead of crush-
<br/>ing a small genius, you should arouse a great one, the world
<br/>will think well of you for having called into action talents
<br/>which might else have been lulled to sleep by the syren
<br/>strains of flattery.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Rule 2. In regard to Publishers.—If a book is issued by
<br/>a young publisher, the above rule will apply with a slight
<br/>modification. It must always be remembered, that a pub-
<br/>lisher may, at some time or other, have it in his power to
<br/>serve you; and it will therefore be good policy to treat him
<br/>with more consideration than you would a mere author, un-
<br/>less you happen to have some personal knowledge of his
<br/>circumstances, and know him to be destitute of capital and
<br/>powerful friends. Respecting a rich and flourishing pub-
<br/>lisher, I can hardly deem it neeessary to give any direction,
<br/>for I cannot suppose that any critic would be so ignorant of
<br/>the first principles of his profession, as not to perceive the
<br/>importance of conciliating the good will of those who have</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page26"/>
         </p>
         <p>it in their power to serve him, either by sending him copies
<br/>of valuable works, or by publishing for him when he wants
<br/>to become an author himself. But the critic must not feel
<br/>himself under an obligation to read even the publications of
<br/>a rich house. It will be sufficient to say of a book, that the
<br/>name of the publisher is a warrant of its merit, or that no
<br/>library can be complete without it—which you may safely
<br/>do, for libraries would be reduced to very small dimensions
<br/>if they contained nothing but good books.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Rule 3. Wherever a book differs from all others that you
<br/>have read, and having no standard to compare it with, you
<br/>are at a loss for an opinion, but are determined, notwith-
<br/>-standing, to give one.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>To the mere neophyte this may be a perplexing situation,
<br/>but to an experienced critic it has as few difficulties as any
<br/>other. Let the spirit of the book alone to take care of itself,
<br/>or to be handled by some more daring or more competent
<br/>hand, and proceed after verbal errors: every book contains
<br/>enough of these to damn it, if it were judged by them
<br/>alone. It will be a hard case if you do not find a dozen
<br/>or two of misapplied prepositions, or a superfluous con-
<br/>-junction or two. And when you have exhausted these,
<br/>there will still be typographical errors in abundance to
<br/>fall back upon; after which, if your review should lack
<br/>either length or malice, you will still have the paper, the
<br/>title, the letter press, the size of the volume, the binding,
<br/>and the publisher to help you out. Every fault discovered
<br/>in a book helps to hinder its sale and answers the end of
<br/>criticism, which is to make the critic and not the author ap-
<br/>-pear to advantage.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Rule 4. When an author makes you feel his merit, but
<br/>either from envy, or personal dislike, or a desire to injure his
<br/>publisher, you are determined to roast him.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Malicious people have generally good inventive powers,
<br/>and are never at a loss for a method to do an ill-natured turn.
<br/>In any other case than that of a critic, we should consider it
<br/>impertinent to offer advice ; but our critics are so little used
<br/>to thinking for themselves, that we fear our instructions are
<br/>needed even here. There are difficulties in this case, it must
<br/>be admitted, for a jockey who should try to prove that a horse
<br/>is a mule, would be in danger of being laughed at for an ass
<br/>himself. Therefore the safest way to proceed will be to try
<br/>the book by negatives, and condemn it for not being what the
<br/>author never intended to make it. By this process you will
<br/>compel even the author himself to acknowledge the truth of
<br/>your criticism; and with those who depend upon you for
<br/>their own opinions, you will be regarded as a profound,
<br/>splendid, and brilliant reviewer. Of all the differ-ent methods
<br/>of reviewing a book, this affords the widest margin for a dis-
<br/>-play of your own learning and humor? because it does not
<br/>confine you to the work under notice, but enables you to
<br/>quote liberally from the last book that you may have read.
<br/>If the book you quote from should happen to be on a differ-
<br/>ent subject from that which you are reviewing, it will help
<br/>to make the author appear very ridiculous, by showing how
<br/>unlike he is to somebody else. If, for instance, you were
<br/>reviewing “ A Tale of a Tub,” by comparing it with the
<br/>“ Tales of my Landlord,” or “ Crabbe’s Tales," or the “ Can-
<br/>-terbury Tales,” or “Hogg's Tales,” you would prove to the
<br/>satisfaction of the meanest comprehension, that it was not
<br/>only destitute of all merit as a tale, and that the name was a
<br/>misnomer, but that it was in every respect a ridiculous
<br/>work.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Nothing is easier than to make another person appear
<br/>ridiculous, but it is not always easy at the same time not to
<br/>make yourself appear so; therefore, great caution must al-</p>
         <p/>
         <p>ways be observed in cutting up an author, not to inflict
<br/>wounds upon yourself. In a review, the main object is to make the reviewer, not the reviewed, appear to advantage.
<br/>The critic must therefore glean all the wit and information
<br/>I that he can out of the book he is reviewing, and intersperse
<br/>them through his article, without naming the source of their origin. The very highest effort of a reviewer is to place
<br/>himself between the public and the author, so that the au-
<br/>-thor may be entirely lost sight of by the time his article
<br/>draws to a close.	 H.</p>
         <p>SKETCHES OF AMERICAN PROSE WRITERS.*
NO. 1.
WILLIAM. A. JONES.
</p>
         <p>There are several very good reasons why a series of arti-
<br/>cles should be written on the American Prose Writers. In
<br/>the first place many of them are very clever men, and
<br/>deserve this formal recognition of their merits; and it is one of the most natural of all impulses, that leads us, while we
<br/>are day after day feasting on their intellectual beef and trifle,
<br/>to offer up a few words of grace in a complimentary criticism.
<br/>In the second place, many of our best prose writers are com-
<br/>-paratively unknown, and it will be doing the public a greater
<br/>service than the writers themselves, to speak of their merits.
<br/>In the third place, it may happen that a few of these authors
<br/>may be partially misunderstood, and criticism surely needs
<br/>no apology when it is employed in removing any of the im-
<br/>-pediments which beset the discovering of truth. In the
<br/>fourth place we hold the prose writers to have quite as good
<br/>a claim to be celebrated as the poets of whom so much has
<br/>latterly been said. In the fifth, a native author has certain-
<br/>ly a right, in the present state of things, to all the crumbs he
<br/>can get. In the sixth place, the public like this kind of
<br/>biographical and gossipping table talk. And the seventh—a
<br/>reason which we should hold sufficient were all the rest
<br/>good for nothing—contributors must write and magazines
<br/>must be filled, come what will of it.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We shall establish no order of precedence in the men or
<br/>women we write about, nor set up any standard of exclusive-
<br/>ness further than what we have just indicated in this very
<br/>sentence, that the authors and authoresses shall be men or
<br/>women, with some kindling vitality in them—not mere walk-
<br/>ing gentlemen and ladies, hobby-de-hoys or copy-book
<br/>misses.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Without more ado in the way of preface, we plunge our
<br/>arms into the huge chest in which we have collected our
<br/>material, and out of the heap of volumes, magazines, pamph-
<br/>-lets, files of newspapers, there thrown together, a richer col-
<br/>llection than you will find on the shelves of any bookseller,</p>
         <p/>
         <p>we extricate a huge bundle, strongly corded and labelled af-
<br/>ter our fancy, “ Manifold and excellent illustrations of En-
<br/>-glish literature—foreign and at home, old and recent, by
<br/>William A. Jones.” There are at least, if drawn out from their hiding places, and printed in book form, a thousand
<br/>pages of them, and quantity no less than quality shall be our
<br/>harvest for asserting the claims, for the first time among critics, of a fresh American author.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>What has he written and how has he written, are the first
<br/>questions when a new name is mentioned in literature—First
<br/>the facts, then the comment, and lastly the conclusion.—</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Though we consider the mere quantity that an author writes
<br/>by no means the best proof of his merits, and remember that
<br/>even the greatest reputations are generally sustained by a</p>
         <p>* To be followed by a series of articles from different pens on American
prose writers, since the Revolution.
<div class="pagebreak" id="#page27"/>
         </p>
         <p>very few pages, which are all that the great public are ac-
<br/>-quainted with, yet as an incidental proof of capacity, especi-
<br/>-ally in the present circumstances of reading and writing, it
<br/>is quite necessary that an author show, by his power of sus-
<br/>-taining himself, that he has not blundered or stumbled into
<br/>literature, or got there by sheer impudence and trickery. An
<br/>ordinary man may borrow with ingenuity, or be stung by the
<br/>passion of the moment to produce a few vivid words, but we
<br/>may not call him an author. The perfection of literature
<br/>requires both art and nature. It is possible that a man in
<br/>conversation may display higher powers of wit, humour or
<br/>sentiment; than another may in writing, or a man may write
<br/>mechanically as every decently educated person now-a-days
<br/>can, without feeling. Neither of these deserve the name of
<br/>authors.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>How much has he written, then, is a fair question. We
<br/>have a great horror of making notabilities out of nothing, so
<br/>we proceed to give an account of Mr. Jones’s labours, an im-
<br/>-posing word, by which what ought to be called the recreations
<br/>of genius, pass current with a dull minded world.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Mr. Jones’s earliest papers were written for the American
<br/>Monthly Magazine, while it was edited by Park Benjamin,
<br/>and were soon after collected and published with a few oth-
<br/>-ers from the New Yorker in a volume, entitled The Analyst,
<br/>in 1840. The peculiarity of this volume was its exhibition
<br/>of the early development of the critical faculty, proving, as
<br/>has been proved since in very many cases, that there is at
<br/>times an early harvest for the judgment as well as for the
<br/>apparently more youthful fancy and sentiment. One of the
<br/>most remarkable examples of this, is in a case pointed out
<br/>by Mr. Jones himself in a paper on the early maturity of Ge-
<br/>-nius, that of Owen Felltheim, who was as wise as Bacon
<br/>and pointed as La Bruyere at the age of nineteen.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The matter is easily explained. Whatever a man can do
<br/>in literature or in active life, what is most characteristic of
<br/>him, he is apt to do with the first salient spring of youth and
<br/>ripened physical energy, before the sinews are hardened by
<br/>time, or the heart by the world. This is true generally. Of
<br/>that large portion of books which is built up on the pas-
<br/>-sion of love, it is always true. Special circumstances may
<br/>supply to some minds, in other cases, what the difference of
<br/>years could not teach the dull and sluggish. Some men may
<br/>learn more of the rash policy of the world from family and
<br/>friends, in the few opening years of life, than others who pass
<br/>their whole time among courts and statesmen. It is not the
<br/>largeness of the landscape that informs us, but the power of
<br/>vision.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The “ Analyst” came into the world from the head of its
<br/>author, like Minerva, without any apparent gestation. Its
<br/>observation was not the less acute nor its knowledge the less
<br/>wise. It discusses serious questions of morals, character and
<br/>studies, with but few errors of judgment for the hand of time
<br/>to correct, and none of the heart. There were some traces
<br/>of bookishness in it, of course. It was evident that the wri-
<br/>ter had read Hazlitt, and the moralist. There was a smack
<br/>of this good relish in the style, nor was the author disposed
<br/>to withhold his acknowledgements. But with all this there
<br/>was abundant self reliance, ample indication of original
<br/>power, and no trace of what Mr. Poe calls American cribbage.
<br/>The method of the book was inferior to the matter—a good
<br/>sign and a comparatively rare one in our native literature.—
<br/>Not that rudeness and awkwardness are commendable things
<br/>in themselves, or that it is not a higher proof of genius, as in
<br/>the case of Nathaniel Hawthorne, that the just conception
<br/>should mould the just style, but that the matter is the more
<br/>essential thing of the two, and that a charlatan and preten-</p>
         <p/>
         <p>der may secure the one, the outward, by care or thievery, but
<br/>cannot pass off any false claim to the inner. Much as Mr.
<br/>Jones has since written, though he has gained greater scope
<br/>and maintains a longer flight, and attained considerable
<br/>skill, yet a defect of manner still occasionally mars his wri-
<br/>-tings. He cannot feign a sentiment, or write out of his
<br/>element. It is only on a subject of which his heart is full
<br/>that he writes very clearly and without impediment. Should
<br/>any man write on any other ? Certainly not in the Millen-
<br/>-nium, but should not is changed into must, while money con-
<br/>-tinues to be so essential an article as it is at present, and
<br/>magazines pay by the page.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The next literary appearance of our author, was in a se-
<br/>-ries of papers in DR. HAWKES’ Church Record on the old En-
<br/>-glish Literature, undertaken in pursuance of the constant
<br/>ever-present aim of that distinguished divine to do all in his
<br/>power, by the pulpit, education, the press, for liberal studies.
<br/>There appeared week after week for more than a year
<br/>sketches of old divines, like Donne, Fuller and Jeremy Tay-
<br/>-lor, and the later Barrow, South, Berkeley and Sterne ; bio-
<br/>-graphies of lzaak Walton’s Saints, and many others as good
<br/>and worthy, sketches of the sacred poets Quarles and Cra-
<br/>shaw, and a few narratives of men after the writer’s own heart,
<br/>like Steele and Felton. These papers are now inaccessible
<br/>to the general reader, and good as MSS. for all publishing
<br/>purposes. They should be reset, an omission here and there
<br/>supplied, and “ written in a book”—a book that would form
<br/>a choice companion to the library, useful as D’Israeli’s miscel-
<br/>-lanies for its facts, and more interesting inasmuch as it has
<br/>more heart. Books of this kind, a mixture of the critical, bi-
<br/>-ographical and personal, will always have their charm with
<br/>the educated as well as the novices in letters. We take up
<br/>one of these papers, and it is as winning and uniting as the
<br/>eloquent conversation of a friend pointing out to us that
<br/>which is among the richest of all treasures, an unopened mine
<br/>of wealth in the library. Blessings on these takers-down
<br/>of misappreciated volumes, these openers of the ponderous
<br/>jaws of unread folios !</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Let those who would see more of our author, read the pa-
<br/>-pers signed J. in “ Arcturus” and look over a file of the “ Bos-
<br/>-ton Miscellany’’ and the “ De-mocratic Review,” in the De-
<br/>cember number of which is a paper on Children’s Books
<br/>which is a very fair and right Honourable picture of the wri-
<br/>-ter’s mind.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The characteristics of Mr. Jones’s writings are a fine vein
<br/>of sentiment, manly, delicate, and unerring in knowledge and
<br/>tone of truth, and a sagacious critical acumen which is gui-
<br/>-ded by the heart not the head, and hence, like the remarks
<br/>of the child of nature in Mrs. Inchbald’s tale, seems some-
<br/>-times very odd among the plausibilities and conventialisms
<br/>of the world. This writer is so very odd as sometimes to
<br/>speak exactly what he thinks, however strangely the matter
<br/>may stare out on the page among the polished devices of
<br/>modern typogaphy. Many of his remarks, it must be con-
<br/>-fessed, would read better (to most people) a hundred years
<br/>hence in an autobiography, when this personal matter both of
<br/>praise and censure offends no one, than at the present day.
<br/>His writings are to be read with a mental comment and due
<br/>consideration of the individual character that lurks beneath.
<br/>There is a worldly tact in criticism seemingly fair and full
<br/>—some would call it ingeniously plausible—which is the
<br/>beau ideal of the craft that he seldom reaches. He is ear-
<br/>-nest, vigorous, dogmatic, and when he gets out of the range
<br/>of his sympathies and experience, sometimes wrong. His
<br/>affections are first of all with the true authors of sentiment,
<br/>Sterne, Goldsmith, Mackenzie, Jean Paul and Dickens.—</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page28"/>
         </p>
         <p>Harmony of style as the index of harmony of feeling and
<br/>the passions is his delight. He cares more for the natural
<br/>unstudied traits of character, developed in harmony of prose
<br/>or poetical numbers, as in a song or sonnet, than in the lof-
<br/>-tier flights of the muse. He never talks in his criticisms of
<br/>a constructive work of art. The Drama and the Epic are
<br/>out of his range. He reads the minor poets and essayists, and
<br/>is content with perfect beauty in miniature without a thought
<br/>of the great masters. He, perhaps, undervalues their native
<br/>labors, if we may infer this from the neglect of them in his
<br/>various criticisms. He is not a constructive critic, a phrase
<br/>which he would use in reference to his treatment of Ameri-
<br/>-can Literature. That is to say, he does not attempt to se-
<br/>-lect the elements of the future and build up a school of na-
<br/>-tionality. He looks upon literature and books as personal
<br/>affairs. If he is hit and pleased, he says so—but there is
<br/>much that does not touch him.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Criticism and its opportunities after all afford but an in-
<br/>-sufficient means of developing our author’s character. He
<br/>has humour, feeling, acute discrimination seen and acknow-
<br/>-ledged by his intimates, but what does a stranger know of
<br/>them. He reads his articles, perhaps, with indifference, and
<br/>complains that the critic’s measure is a foot rule out of all
<br/>proportions. It is no foot rule at all. Yet we can conceive
<br/>of others, skilled in the honest language of nature, who de-
<br/>-tect the character of the writer, who feel when he is at
<br/>home and speaking from himself, and who set aside the oc-
<br/>-casional job work as “ leather and prunella.” With such our
<br/>critic will gain a deep and permanent reputation. It is a
<br/>customary phrase, with these good and true men, “I al-
<br/>-ways read an article in the magazines that bears the name
<br/>of William A. Jones.”	D.</p>
         <p>STREET SWEEPING.
</p>
         <p>At the crossings of our principal streets during the last
<br/>month or two of muddy weather, little foreigners, girls and
<br/>boys with naked feet, have been busily employed with
<br/>stumpy brooms, clearing a passage for the Israelites out of
<br/>Wall street, and others, to pass over the black sea of our
<br/>highways, dry-shod. These foreign children seem to do this
<br/>on purpose to reproach our Native American corporation and
<br/>street-inspectors; for they do not look as though they enjoyed
<br/>a salary, and I have rarely seen anybody drop them a penny.
<br/>It must be pure benevolence or pure waggishness in these
<br/>little creatures, which leads them to this cruel employment
<br/>at this season of the year. How red their feet look ! It is
<br/>one of the most beautiful contrasts conceivable, to see a little
<br/>girl of the tender age of seven or eight years in the depth of
<br/>winter, without a shoe or stocking upon her feet, sweeping
<br/>the mud from a crossing, at the risk of being crushed beneath
<br/>the wheels of an Omnibus, that a stout hearty man, in dou-
<br/>-ble-soled boots and a thick coat, may step over without soil-
<br/>-ing his leather. And then to see the little creature hold up
<br/>her hand and ejaculate “ please give me a penny to buy me
<br/>some bread,” while the gentleman walks off very stiffly and
<br/>buttons up his coat closer, to keep out the wind, without
<br/>heeding the prayer of the pretty little scavenger; and then to
<br/>see how cheerfully she will fall to her work again, and
<br/>nothing daunted by her ill success, make the same appeal to
<br/>the same kind of man again the next minute ! Some of these
<br/>children must pick up at least a five-pence in the run of a
<br/>very wet day. But we have a misgiving at the heart that
<br/>they do not always earn that magnificent sum. A little pale-
<br/>faced urchin ran after us the other day, and begged for a pen-
<br/>-ny, just to encourage him, he had been sweeping all day, and
<br/>had not received a penny.</p>
         <p>Original Poetry.
THE EPITAPH.
What means this glosing epitaph,
Unless its errand be to shame,
As with a mocking devil’s laugh,
The frail delusion of such fame
As but embalms an empty name ?
As columns, when the roof is gone
Which they were reared to hold on high,
Are merely idle shafts of stone
Which, forced to tell an endless lie,
Do but deride the passer-by ;—
So stand these legends in Death’s halls:
Vain figures on a dial-plate
Whereon no gnomon’s shadow falls ;
Poor inch-deep characters, that prate
Of Empire over Time and Fate.
When eye, and tongue, and heart are null.
What profits then the laurel wreath
Twined loathsome round a grinning skull ?
Food crammed between a corpse’s teeth
To win a deeper sneer from Death !
O high Ambition ! can there be
An epitaph in league with Time ?
Is life a ship’s track in the sea ?
Are all these hopes and aims sublime
Mere architecture of frail rime ?
Doth God implant for worse than naught
This huge desire of memory? Cannot some monument be wrought,
Which from its moveless height shall see
The pyramids’ last obsequy ?
To be a glimpse of summer sent
Into the bleak hearts of the poor;
To make God’s sunshine evident,
By opening Eden’s humble door
To souls where darkness reigned before;
To make this cloudy life a part
Of the eternal grace beyond;
</p>
         <p>To forge the vague dreams of the heart
<br/>Into a mighty sceptre-wand
<br/>Whose touch makes freemen of the bond;</p>
         <p>Methinks a life thus spent should rear
A monument in Fate’s despite,
Whose epitaph would grow more clear
As Truth’s sun rose and scattered light,
Full and more full, from Heaven’s glad height.
Let it be graven on my tomb :—
“ He came and left more smiles behind,
One ray he shot athwart the gloom,
He helped one fetter to unbind,
Men think of him and grow more kind."
JAMES RUSSELL LOWELL.
Rockwood, Feb. 7, 1844.
A STREAMLET.
Sings ever thus this clear rejoicing stream,
That rising in the green hills far away,
</p>
         <p>Through all the starry night, and sunny day,
<br/>Glides calmly on, “like sweet thoughts in a dream,"
<br/>Through rural Talleys sparkling in the gleam
<br/>Of many-colored flowers, and ever gay
<br/>With songs of summer birds, and merry play
<br/>Of laughing children, on whose faces beam,</p>
         <p>Their natural birth-right, joy and innocence.
Like thine, glad stream ! oh, might my journey be!
To all, some little good would I dispense,
Ever pursue with a glad voice, like thee,
My way unto the end, then vanish hence,
Without a murmur, in the great salt sea!
J.A.
<div class="pagebreak" id="#page29"/>
NOTICES OF NEW BOOKS.
</p>
         <p>The Principles and Practice of Obstetric Medicine and Sur-
<br/>-gery, in reference to the process of Parturition, with 100 illustra-
<br/>tions, on Steel and Wood. By Francis H. Ramsbotham, M. D.,
<br/>Fellow of the Royal College of Physicians, &amp;c. Second edition,
<br/>enlarged. London : John Churchill, 1844.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We do not notice this important work to make its merits
<br/>known to the profession, or the public, but to point out one
<br/>of the many evils which we inflict upon ourselves, by deny-
<br/>-ing to foreign authors the right to control their own works.
<br/>In books of this class, it is of the last importance, not less
<br/>to the student than to the author, that their publication
<br/>should be superintended by himself or his agent. If they
<br/>are worth having at all, it is important that they should be
<br/>had correctly. The author states his grievances, arising
<br/>from our system of republication, very quietly but forcibly,
<br/>in the preface of the second edition of his work.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>" Very soon after the book was published in England, it was also
<br/>edited, with lithographic drawings, at Philadelphia ; and, although it
<br/>cannot but be a source of gratification to an author, to consider his
<br/>observations worthy of being dressed in a new garb, and circulated
<br/>over the Western hemisphere, still, I think I have some reason to
<br/>complain of the mode in which this has been done, in the present in-
<br/>-stance. It was put forth without the name of any ostensible Ameri-
<br/>-can editor, merely with the notification of its being 'the first Ameri-
<br/>-can edition, revised,’ as though I had myself superintended it, and
<br/>sanctioned its appearance. And the revision consists in the omission
<br/>of some of my annotations, and all the Appendix, except the article
<br/>on ‘ Suspended Animation,’ which is subjoined to one of the pages ;
<br/>with the introduction, also, of numerous typographical errors, some
<br/>of them completely changing the sense of the passage, and others so
<br/>glaring as to lend in no small degree, to bring the writer into ridicule.
<br/>I look upon this as a just cause for animadversion ; for if our transat-
<br/>-lantic brethren choose to appropriate to themselves our publications,
<br/>they should, at the least, reprint them as they appear here, and use
<br/>such ordinary care that the character of the work may not suffer in
<br/>their hands. 14 New Bond street. Oct. 1844.”</p>
         <p>CONVERSATIONS ON SOME OF THE OLD POETS. By JAMES RUSSELL
LOWELL. Cambridge : Published by John Owen, 1845.
</p>
         <p>We have only time this week to notice the outside of this
<br/>new book. It makes a forcible appeal to the eye by its
<br/>illuminated cover, which is one of the best specimens of
<br/>that kind of illustration which we have seen from the Ameri-
<br/>-can press. Its contents may he safely trusted in without
<br/>criticism. Wiley &amp; Putnam have the work for sale.</p>
         <p>Rome, as seen by a New Yorker in 1843-4: In press. Wiley &amp;
Putnam.
</p>
         <p>REPUBLICATION.—D. Appleton &amp; Co. have in press, The
<br/>Life and Correspondence of Thomas Arnold, D.D., the two
<br/>volumes of the English Edition in 1 vol. 12mo.</p>
         <p>Varieties.
</p>
         <p>AN IMPORTANT DISCOVERY IN ART.—The “Art Union,” a
<br/>monthly paper, published in London, contains the following
<br/>singular announcement.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Our readers will, perhaps, remember that, several months ago, we
<br/>announced a remarkable discovery, by which, in a few days, a large
<br/>and elaborate line-engraving might be so accurately copied that there
<br/>should be no perceptible difference between the original and the copy:
<br/>that an engraving on steel or copper might be produced from an im-
<br/>-pression of the print—the original plate never having been seen by the
<br/>copyist; and that the steel plate so produced should be warranted to
<br/>yield from 10,000 to 20,000 impressions. We slated also, that it was
<br/>stated to us, that the producer would undertake to supply a Bank of
<br/>England note so exactly copied that the person who signed and issued
<br/>it should not be able to swear which was the original and which the
<br/>copy.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We have resolved to test this (alleged) invention ; and have placed
<br/>in the hands of the party referred to a foreign print (the plate never
<br/>having been in England), and selected a subject which may be seen
<br/>in many shop windows at this moment—so that any person may com-
<br/>-pare the copy with the original. A proof has been laid before us in
<br/>an unfinished state,—not, therefore, altogether satisfactory, but still,
<br/>we think, so wonderful a production that we feel justified in anticipa-
<br/>-ting its complete success—at least in so far as to give one of them
<br/>with each number of the Art-Union for January. Our subscribers
<br/>will then be as well able as ourselves to judge of it. We shall say
<br/>how many we have printed, and communicate all we know on the
<br/>subject.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>At present we can only say, that within seven days after we placed
<br/>a proof of the print in the hands of the party referred to, he placed in
<br/>our hands the copy of it, on the steel; that the original engraving was
<br/>the work of at least a year ; and that the copy is already so marvel-
<br/>lously accurate that we are much disposed to have faith in his pledge that, when finished, we shall not be able to distinguish the original
<br/>proof from a proof of the copy, of which he undertakes to furnish
<br/>between 10,000 and 15,000 impressions, if we need them.”</p>
         <p>We shall receive a copy of the promised engraving by
the next steamer, and will inform our readers more about it hereafter.
ENGLISH OPINIONS OF AMERICAN ARTISTS.—The November
“Art Union,” contains the following notice:
“PAINTINGS BY AMERICAN ARTISTS.—A few painlines by American
</p>
         <p>Artists have been sent to this country, as tests with a view to deter-
<br/>-mine whether contributions from our brethren on the other side of the
<br/>Atlantic wonld be favorably received and generously criticised in
<br/>England. We have seen these examples at the agency-office of
<br/>Messrs. Wiley and Putnam, in Waterloo-place. They possess consid-
<br/>erable merit, and are evidence that the Arts are progressing in Ameri-
<br/>-ca ; but they are not of a nature to “ tell’’ in an exhibition-room. We
<br/>shall rather withhold the opinion we are asked to give until we have
<br/>more sufficient opportunities to warrant judgment. But we feel per-
<br/>-fectly sure that no apprehension need be entertained of undue or unfair
<br/>treatment if really good works be sent to our galleries here ; at least,
<br/>there will be no attempt to lessen the merit they possess by placing
<br/>them disadvantageously before the critic. We should regard such a
<br/>course as in the highest degree disgraceful. We cannot but add, how-
<br/>ever, that, to obtain honors beside the productions of British Artists,
<br/>the works must be more meritorious than those we have heretofore
<br/>seen.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This is very cautious, and apparently friendly: but as we
<br/>do not know what the works were, or by whom executed,
<br/>we cannot well judge of the Editor's motives in withholding
<br/>the opinion which, it seems, he was requested to give. But
<br/>we can hardly approve of this begging the opinions of Bri-t-
<br/>ish critics on the merits of American productions. An</p>
         <p/>
         <p>American artist should be content with the approbation of
<br/>his own countrymen, and if he should fail to obtain that, he
<br/>can hardly hope to be better received in a foreign country.
<br/>The works of an American painter must needs be subjected
<br/>to a very severe test in London. The greatest disadvantage
<br/>they would labor under would be a want of sympathy in the
<br/>critic. Pictures are as much imbued with national pecu-
<br/>liarities as books, or any other productions which require
<br/> expression, and these cannot be appreciated justly by stran-
<br/>gers. The same authority in speaking of Henry Inman’s
<br/> portraits of Wordsworth and Dr. Chalmers, pronounces them
<br/>perfect likenesses, and says that they may vie with the best
<br/>productions of the best British Artists. We never had any doubt that Mr. Inman would meet with success in England;</p>
         <p/>
         <p>his style is essentially of the English school; and from the
<br/>judgment pronounced upon his works, we may judge of
<br/>their standard of excellence. There can be little question
<br/>that we can boast of better painters in the United States
<br/>than can be found in England. We understand that Mr.
<br/>Inman has sent for his family to join him, which looks like
<br/>his receiving good encouragement in his profession.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Carlyle’s Preface to Emerson’s Essay.—A year or two
<br/>ago, one of Carlyle’s books, Past and Present, was published
<br/>in Boston for the benefit of the author. It was prefaced by
<br/>a few brief, but telling words, from Mr. Emerson, stating the
<br/>circumstances of its publication, and begging American pub-
<br/>-lishers to be honest for once, and allow the author to receive
<br/>the benefit of his own labours. The appeal was heeded by
<br/>some of our publishers, but disregarded by one at least, who
<br/>immediately issued a cheap edition of the work, which must
<br/>have diminished, very seriously, the author’s profits. Mr.
<br/>Carlyle has now done the same good turn for Mr. Emerson
<br/>in London, and we trust with better success than followed
<br/>the appeal of Mr. Emerson here. We should be exceeding-
<br/>ly mortified to be compelled to acknowledge that we had</p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page30"/>
less honesty here than in England, but we shall be glad, for
humanity's sake, to find an instance of honesty somewhere.
The following is Mr. Carlyle’s preface. It is a biting sa-
-tire on “ the trade.”
“ Here is a new volume of Essays by Emerson; concerning which I
am to certify, that this English edition of them seems to be correctly
</p>
         <p>printed; that the English Publisher is one appointed by the Author
<br/>himself, and is under contract with him as to the pecuniary results.
<br/>To Emerson’s readers in England, I am to certify so much ; leaving the
<br/>inference from it to their own honourable and friendly thought. To
<br/>unauthorized reprinters, and adventurous spirits, inclined to do a little
<br/>in the pirate line, it may be proper to recall the known fact, which
<br/>should be very present to us all, without recalling, that theft in any
<br/>sort is abhorrent to the mind of man;—that theft is theft, under what-
<br/>-ever meridian of longitude, in whatever ' nation,’ foreign or domestic,
<br/>the man stolen from may live ; and whether there be any treadmill or
<br/>gallows for his thief, or no apparatus of that kind ! such suggestion
<br/>may, perhaps, have its weight with here and there an incipient adven-
<br/>-turous spirit, meditating somewhat in the piccaroon or pirate line, and
<br/>contribute to direct him into better courses; who knows ? For other
<br/>spirits, no longer open to such suggestions, the present Publisher trusts
<br/>that he has suggestions of a much more appropriate, intelligible, and
<br/>effectual kind in readiness, if needed.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Very happily, the Author himself is not, in his economies, depen-
<br/>-dent on this claim now made for him, or on any such ; yet it will be
<br/>handsome in the British nation to recognize it a little ! The labourer
<br/>is worthy of his hire. Yes; and he that brings us (not in his sleep, fancy !) new fire from the Empyrean—new tidings of such,—he too,
<br/>one would imagine, is worthy that we should leave him the exiguous
<br/>sixpence a copy, which falls to his share in the adventure, and not
<br/>steal it from him !</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ More, on this rather paltry department of the business, I had not
<br/>to say; and to touch on any other department of it was not in my com-
<br/>-mission at present. I will wish the brave Emerson a fair welcome
<br/>among us again; and leave him to speak with his old friends, and to
<br/>make new.	T. Carlyle.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This is an admirable plan ; probably every English author
<br/>whose works are worth reprinting in this country, has some
<br/>friend among our own authors, who might do for him what
<br/>these essayists have done for each other. We hope that
<br/>somebody else may be induced to try it, and who knows, but
<br/>an international copyright might thus be established without
<br/>the aid" of Congress. But in all such cases the price of the
<br/>book, should be sufficiently low to destroy any very great
<br/>temptation to dishonesty. While we are persuading men to
<br/>be honest, it will be well not to tempt them to be otherwise.</p>
         <p>The Drama.
</p>
         <p>WE can afford but little space in our Journal to dramatic
<br/>affairs. Indeed, we believe there are few things which the
<br/>public cares so little about, as the gossip of the Theatres.
<br/>Whether Miss Somerville was perfect in the character of
<br/>Clara, or Mr. Stanley dressed becomingly in the part of Duke
<br/>Aranza, cannot particularly concern any body but those im-
<br/>-portant personages themselves. But we intend, nevertheless,
<br/>to devote a portion of our columns to the amusements of
<br/>this city, and the Theatres will, of course, be included among
<br/>them. Whatever interests the people is the legitimate ob-
<br/>-ject of our study, and the less creditable the object may be,
<br/>the greater is the necessity of its being looked after. Dra-
<br/>-matic entertainments were never popular on this side the
<br/>Atlantic. We frequently hear the palmy days of the
<br/>Drama spoken of, but we should be at a loss to name them.
<br/>The same, with a very slight qualification, may be said of
<br/>England. In France it has always been different. The
<br/>French have a love for dramatic representations, which the
<br/>English have not. Since the days of Queen Elizabeth, the
<br/>Theatre has always been in disrepute. Any species of
<br/>amusement, which the professedly religious feel themselves
<br/>compelled to avoid, can never be esteemed popular. It is the
<br/>religious sentiment of a country which gives the key note to
<br/>its morals; and whatever lacks the approval of the best
<br/>minds in a nation, must at last come to naught. The Thea-
<br/>-tre has long, always rather, been under the ban of what the
<br/>world calls good men. Though Doctor Johnson went to</p>
         <p/>
         <p>London with a play in his pocket, and with a player for a
<br/>companion, yet he soon got himself clear from the Theatre,
<br/>and began to teach morals. He felt that it was a disreputa-
<br/>-ble connexion ; and yet the Theatre was more respectable in
<br/>his day, than it ever was before or since. Garrick was the
<br/>greatest dramatic genius that the English stage ever posses-
<br/>-sed ; and while he lived he helped to render it popular, but
<br/>he had no sooner left it, than the stage began to fall. The
<br/>Kembles did nothing towards supporting it, but rather helped
<br/>to hasten its downward progress, by loading it with mum-
<br/>-meries and machinery. Mere respectability of character
<br/>adds nothing to the respectability of a profession. Nothing
<br/>short of genius can do any thing for a calling which is not in
<br/>itself respectable. A dolt-head and a genius are alike in the
<br/>pulpit. It is the profession which confers respectability upon
<br/>them. People go to hear one as readily as the other. Ac-
<br/>-cordingly we find that the church remains the same, let
<br/>its ministers be what they may. But the stage goes up
<br/>or down with the characters of those who tread it. When
<br/>Kean appeared, though a man of bad morals, yet, being a
<br/>genius, the drama seemed to revive ; and it sunk as soon as
<br/>he was gone.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>With us the stage has never been indigenous. There have
<br/>been but few American actors, and not one American drama-
<br/>tist. The whole atmosphere of our Theatres is essentially
<br/>English. All the plays present English scenes, English
<br/>characters, English thoughts, delivered in English accents.
<br/>The music, too, is all foreign, and when you enter the doors
<br/>of one of our play-houses, you appear to have stepped into
<br/>another country. If a cockney should fall asleep in the
<br/>Haymarket and awake in the Park Theatre, he would be
<br/>hardly conscious of a change. There are no greater difficul-
<br/>ties attending success in the dramatic profession than in any
<br/>other, and if it were popular or respectable, we should have
<br/>an American stage, as we have an American bar, an Ameri-
<br/>can pulpit, and an American press. Mr. Forest has done
<br/>well for himself, but he has done nothing for his profession
<br/>in this country. If he were a man of genius, the stage
<br/>would have been in better repute among us, since he appear-
<br/>ed upon it. Instead of rising, it has gradually fallen in public
<br/>estimation since his first appearance. We do not pretend to
<br/>argue for or against the stage; but simply to give our views
<br/>of its actual condition. Those who decry the Theatre most
<br/>loudly, are generally persons who never visit one, and know
<br/>nothing about it. There are four or five Theatres in New
<br/>York, which, to exist at all, must be frequented by a great
<br/>number of people ; and these frequenters of the Theatre are
<br/>generally young persons whose minds are in the fittest con-
<br/>dition to receive impressions. It is very plain, then, that the
<br/>professed philanthropist should look into this matter, and if
<br/>he finds that the theatre cannot be abolished, it is his duty
<br/>to strive to render it as little injurious as possible, and by
<br/>sometimes visiting it, learn to counteract its influences. We
<br/>shall hereafter give a report of the Theatres in their turn.</p>
         <p>Italian Opera house.
</p>
         <p>Our Italian company have struggled through the slough
<br/>of despond, and, by the means of Semiramide, have risen
<br/>to the bright heaven of success. This most charming work
<br/>of Rossini was produced on the 3d instant, to a very crowded
<br/>house. It has been repeated since then three times, and on
<br/>each occasion to still increasing audiences.</p>
         <p>The Opera of Semiramide has always been considered
one of the finest compositions of the great Italian Maestro.
<div class="pagebreak" id="#page31"/>
         </p>
         <p>It abounds with passages of great beauty; the concerted
<br/>pieces, duos, quartettes, etc., etc., are exquisite specimens of
<br/>the author’s style. The instrumentation is brilliant, inge-nious, and varied, displaying great knowledge of effect in
<br/>the happy combinations to produce light and shade. The
<br/>chief characteristic of the music is extreme difficulty, which
<br/>pervades all the roles equally. The music, however, to our
<br/>taste, lacks depth and intensity of sentiment,—it is super-
<br/>ficial, and inflated ; even the most popular of its melodies
<br/>being overloaded with fioriture. There is not, in the whole
<br/>range of musical composition, a work which more severely
<br/>tests the education of singers, than the one under notice.
<br/>It is written with admirable fidelity, for the genius of the
<br/>particular voices, namely: The pure soprano, contralto,
<br/>tenor, and bass. Whether it was wise to attempt such a
<br/>composition with the company at present in this city, must
<br/>be a subject for after reflections.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Opera of Semiramide was composed some twenty-
<br/>two or three years ago, Madame Colbran taking the princi-
<br/>-pal role. It was written at a period when he could produce
<br/>four or five, and even six, Operas in the year, with perfect
<br/>facility. What an inexhaustible imagination must Rossini
<br/>have possessed in his youth !</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The plot of the Opera has been so frequently detailed in
<br/>the daily papers, that we will spare our readers the trouble
<br/>of re-perusing it, and will proceed at once to notice the per-
<br/>-formance.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Borghese is in no way equal to the music of Semiramide.
<br/>She is deficient in power and compass. Her mezza voce is of
<br/>the thinnest possible quality, and to produce even a moderate
<br/>power, she is compelled to resort to false intonation: indeed,
<br/>to speak the truth, we never heard in the range of any voice
<br/>so much disagreeable and faulty intonation. Her style is ex-
<br/>-tremely ornate, but correctness is too frequently sacrificed
<br/>for brilliancy, and good taste is immolated at the altar of
<br/>popular gullibility. What would be otherwise pure and good
<br/>in her method, is disfigured by that senseless vibration of the
<br/>voice, which Mdlle. Borghese uses on every note and in every
<br/>situation. The tendency of her voice to sharpen on all the
<br/>upper notes, is painfully evident in this opera, and must in-
<br/>-crease still further, if she persists in the practice of forcing
<br/>her voice beyond its natural power. We must condemn in
<br/>the strongest terms, the unartistlike liberties which she takes
<br/>with the ideas of the composer ; we believe that we do not
<br/>exaggerate when we say that she did not sing in the whole
<br/>opera eight consecutive notes as set down for her. We consider
<br/>this altogether inexcusable. The beautiful scena (accompa-
<br/>-nied by chorusses of females) “ Bel raggio lusinghier' was
<br/>probably her best performance on each occasion.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Madame Pico has not the range of a pure contralto voice,
<br/>in consequence of which the music has to be transposed
<br/>higher to accommodate her compass. This practice of trans-
<br/>-position is always an injury to the continuity of the idea of the
<br/>author, the key of the various pieces being chosen always
<br/>with a reference to the whole work. It also breeds confusion
<br/>in the orchestra, rendering it difficult and sometimes impos-
<br/>-sible for the particular wind instruments to execute with ef-
<br/>-fect, or even in tune, the passages set down for them. Should
<br/>this confusion be observed by the audience, the singer is ne-
<br/>-ver to blame, but all the indignation is vented upon the in-
<br/>-nocent orchestral performers.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Setting aside the want of compass and also the want of
<br/>power of voice, we cordially award much praise to Madame
<br/>Pico. With one or two exceptions she adhered faithfully to
<br/>her author, and sung with much feeling and depth of passion.
<br/>Her execution is finished and artistical, and she seldom inter-</p>
         <p/>
         <p>lards her music with extraneous ornaments. Her intonation
<br/>is seldom faulty, but her intervals are sometimes so incorrect-
<br/>-ly taken, that we are almost inclined to attribute the mis-
<br/>-takes to the want of a true ear. This error was particularly
<br/>evident in the andante movement of her duett with Borghese
<br/>in the second act—“ Giorno d'orrore,”—in the third bar of
<br/>which she made the sequences fifths instead of sixths; also in
<br/>the thirty-fifth and fifty-third bar, she sang G natural instead
<br/>of G sharp on each occasion. These are a few out of many
<br/>errors which we could point out if we had space. Although
<br/>this andante has been encored every time, it was, beyond a
<br/>doubt, the worst performed piece in the Opera. Both ladies
<br/>sang out of tune, the one sharp and the other flat, more espe-
<br/>-cially in their interpolated cadence. But it is a pretty move-
<br/>-ment, and tickles the ear. Pico cannot be compared in any
<br/>way with Borghese as an actress; her manner is constrained,
<br/>her action awkward, and her walk ungraceful in the extreme.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>It would be a charity if the character of Idreno were
<br/>omitted from the opera. Signor Perogzi is altogether incom-
<br/>-petent to sing any of the music. In proof of our assertion
<br/>we would merely say, that he only took part in such con-
<br/>-certed music as was necessary to the action of the opera; and
<br/>that what he did sing he altered to suit his voice, to conceal
<br/>the inflexibility of his vocal organ, or its want of education.
<br/>He omitted the Aria Ah ! dov e il cimento, also the Aria La
<br/>speranza piu soave.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Signor Valtellina gave us real pleasure by his masterly
<br/>performance of Assur. He is the only artist among the com-
<br/>-pany of whom we can truly say that he respected his au-
<br/>-thor. His music is exceedingly florid and difficult, and its
<br/>compass ranges very high for a bass voice, but he sang it in
<br/>fine taste, with good emphasis and passionate energy, and in
<br/>short in admirable style. He occasionally sang flat, but the
<br/>fault was more with the high range of the music, than with the
<br/>singer. His acting, too, was bold, energetic, and artist-like.
<br/>He is undoubtedly the feature of the opera.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Signor Meyer acquitted himself in a very creditable man-
<br/>ner. He is always correct in his music, and were he to edu-
<br/>-cate his voice and subdue its somewhat harsh and grating
<br/>quality, he would be a still more efficient member of the
<br/>company.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The chorusses were indifferently well performed. Some
<br/>were omitted which we think ill judged, as they form a re-
<br/>lief to the numerous successive solos. In the Coro di Sacer-
<br/>doti, which is a grand and effective piece, the whole of the
<br/>beautiful movement for the male voices, in A minor, was
<br/>omitted. We should be glad to know why ?</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The performance of the band has somewhat improved
<br/>since the first night, but even now it is by no means worthy
<br/>of its distinguished members. The only redeeming points in
<br/>the overture were the solos, by Messrs. Kyle and Groenevelt.
<br/>These gentlemen, with Mr. Weise on the Oboe, are truly ad-
<br/>mirable throughout the opera. They are artists in point of
<br/>execution, taste and undeviating correctness. The orchestra
<br/>is imperfect. It wants more bass, another Oboe, and more
<br/>brass.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The chief fault in the performance is the entire absence
<br/>of the pianissimo, and the consequent impossibility of a
<br/>forte or even a sforzando. This is a great error and should
<br/>be corrected immediately.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The scenery is very beautiful, particularly the last; the
<br/>dresses are in good keeping, and in short the whole getting
<br/>up of the piece is highly creditable to the management.</p>
         <p>The company commence a new engagement next week,
we understand.
<div class="pagebreak" id="#page32"/>
A CARD
NO. 203 BROADWAY-
The Proprietor of this well known Establishment once more makes his annual salutation to his customers and the public, and respectfully
begs leave to introduce to their attention his unusually line assortment of Illustrated Books,
CHOICE ENGRAVINGS AND FANCY GOODS.
</p>
         <p>He would also state, that in view of his intention speedily to resign the Book Department of his business, in which he has been successfully
<br/>engaged in the City for the last twenty years, the present is probably the last Card he will have occasion to offer to the public, and he is
<br/>determined to sell at lower prices and smaller profits than ever.</p>
         <p>EXHIBITION!—A valuable and Interesting Collection of OIL PAINTINGS is exhibited in a Gallery connected with the Store
Admission there one shilling.
</p>
         <p>POSTSCRIPT. Per the Acadia—The Bijou Almanac for 1845; the Illuminated Almanac for 1845 ; the Ruminated Calendar for 1845 ; the
<br/>Forget-me-not for 1845, in velvet, elegant; Ackerman’s Manual of Colors; Cawse on Old Painting, last edition; Fielding on Painting and on
<br/>Engraving ; Hayter’s Perspective ; Bright’s Advanced Drawing Book ; Procession to the Royal Exchange ; Comic Album ; Beauties of the
<br/>Opera ; Clans of Scotland, part 10 ; Splendidly Illuminated Album Titles ; The Love Gift for 1845 ; Belle of the Hunt; Going to Cover ;
<br/>Female Equestrians; Newhaven Fisherwomen; Foig-a-Ballagh; Opening the Royal Exchange; the Death Bed of Wesley, colored;
<br/>Momentous Question, colored ; Lord Morpeth; Sly’s Mechanical Prints; Satirical Sketches ; Punch’s Locomotive ; and Bits of Fun.
<br/>December, 1844.	WM. A. COLMAN, No. 203 Broadway.</p>
         <p>SPLENDID BOOKS
SUITABLE FOR PRESENTS.
JUST received by the subscribers, a large assortment
</p>
         <p>of Splendidly Illustrated and Standard Books, all of which are
<br/>offered for sale at reduced prices. In their collection may be found
<br/>many costly works never before offered for sale in the United States.
<br/>Among them are the following :</p>
         <p/>
         <p>DANIELS’ ILLUSTRATIONS OF ORIENTAL SCENERY—
<br/>coloured in the most beautiful manner, in imitation of the original
<br/>drawings. 6 vols. elephant folio, elegantly bound; original cost,
<br/>$1200 ; reduced to $300.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>SELBY’S BIRDS OF GREAT BRITAIN— (in the style of Au-
<br/>-dubon’s Birds of America). 2 vols. elephant folio; original cost,
<br/>$600; reduced to $180.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>CHAMBERLAYNE’S DRAWINGS OF THE OLD MASTERS
<br/>—being fac similes of the most celebrated of the Roman, Floren-
<br/>-tine, and Venetian Schools. Folio; original cost, $105; reduced
<br/>to $28,00.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>CORONATION OF GEORGE THE FOURTH—illustrated with
<br/>splendidly coloured Drawings, in which the portraits are taken
<br/>from life. Folio; original cost, $262 ; reduced to $75,00.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>PLOOS VAN AMSTEL’S IMITATION OF DRAWINGS OF
<br/>THE PRINCIPAL DUTCH AND FLEMISH MASTERS—
<br/>consisting of 100 engravings. 3 vols. folio ; original cost, $315;
<br/>reduced to $90,00.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>MEYRICK'S PAINTED ILLUSTRATIONS OF ANCIENT
<br/>ARMS AND ARMOR—the plates illuminated with Gold and Sil-
<br/>-ver. 3 vols. folio; original cost, $105; reduced to $65,00.</p>
         <p>A Catalogue embracing 25,000 volumes of valuable Books, in every
department of knowledge, may be had gratis, on application.
BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, 7 Astor House.
The Exploring Expedition.
LEA &amp; BLANCHARD are preparing for publication,
</p>
         <p>and will shortly issue, the Narrative of the United States
<br/>Exploring Expedition, during the years 1838, 1839, 1840, 1841, and
<br/>1842, by CHARLES WILKES, U.S.N., Commander of the Expedi-
<br/>tion, etc., etc., in five magnificent large imperial octavo volumes,
<br/>with an Atlas of Large and Extended Maps. Price Twenty-five
<br/>Dollars to Subscribers, done up in beautiful Extra Cloth Binding.</p>
         <p>The First Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for
the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of MERCAN-
TILE and EPISTOLARY WRITING, guaranteed to all (old and young)
in 10 lessons of one hour each. TERMS—FIVE DOLLARS.
</p>
         <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, FIFTEEN DOLLARS, for a thorough
<br/>course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
<br/>Stationary. Payable at the commencement.</p>
         <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen,
and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
For sale “ GOLDSMITH’S GEMS OF PENMANSHIP,” elegantly bound.
Price Five Dollars.
</p>
         <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27, 1844.
<br/>GOLDSMITH’S GEMS OF PENMANSHIP.—The Chirographic art is
<br/>much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
<br/>Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
<br/>volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
<br/>of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.</p>
         <p>From the New York Express.
</p>
         <p>GOLDSMITH’S GEMS OF PENMANSHIP.—We have seen the original, as
<br/>executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
<br/>wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
<br/>to be “ more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.</p>
         <p>PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY
AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
</p>
         <p>Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
<br/>the Medal, four first Premiums, and two “ Highest Honors,” at the
<br/>Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
<br/>the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
<br/>at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
<br/>the score of economy.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American In-
<br/>-struments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polish-
<br/>-ing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received
<br/>promptly attended to.</p>
         <p>GRAHAME’S UNITED STATES.
THE HISTORY OF THE UNITED STATES OF
NORTH AMERICA, from the plantation of the British Colonies
till their revolt and Declaration of Independence. By JAMES GRA-HAME, ESQ. In four volumes.
</p>
         <p>The work will be put to press as soon as two hundred and fifty
<br/>copies are subscribed for. It will be printed in an elegant style, equal
<br/>to the last London edition, in four volumes octavo, and delivered to
<br/>subscribers at two dollars a volume, in extra cloth binding. Subscribers names received and the books delivered by</p>
         <p>WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, New York.
LEWIS RATES, SIGN AND ORNAMENTAL PAINTER,
NO. 45 WILLIAM STREET,
(BASEMENT OF THE LEATHER MANUFACTURER’ BANK.)
Block Letter Signs, Transparencies, Banners, &amp;c., Executed in the
neatest manner.
Prospectus of the Broadway Journal,
To be Published every Saturday.
</p>
         <p>THE BROADWAY JOURNAL will differ from any of the weekly Peri-
<br/>-odicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
<br/>original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
<br/>Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
<br/>Intelligence.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
<br/>be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
<br/>have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Par-
<br/>-ticular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
<br/>to make it worthy of patronage.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
<br/>best writers in the country ; but it is hoped that a free channel be-
<br/>-ing opened through which true-hearted men may “ let loose their
<br/>thoughts,” will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
<br/>talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
<br/>our periodical literature.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political par-
<br/>ty, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or meas-
<br/>-ures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate.
<br/>It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octavo form of
<br/>16 pages, double columns.</p>
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum—Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.
A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.
All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor
of the Broadway Journal, and all letters on business to
JOHN BISCO, PUBLISHER, 153 BROADWAY.
JOHN DOUGLAS, PRINTER, 68 ANN STREET.
</p>
      </div>
        </div>
   <div class="back">
          
          <div>
            
              
                <span class="person"/>
                
                  
                
                
                  
                
              
            
          </div>
        </div>
</div>
