<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            VOL. I. NO. 14.	NEW YORK, SATURDAY, APRIL 5, 1845.	Published at
            Three Dollars per Annum.	153 BROADWAY, by
            Single Copies, 6 1-4 cents.	C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.	John
            Bisco.
            
         </p>
         <p>Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by content or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</p>
         <p>Locke.
            REVIEWS.
            Undine and Sintram. No. 3 of Wiley &amp; Putnam’s Library of Choice
            Reading.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Undine of Fouqué is too widely known and universally admired to require a word of commendation at this
            day, but Sintram and his Companions, by the same author,
            is comparatively unknown to American readers. It appears
            from the author’s preface, that the tale was immediately
            suggested by Albrecht Durer’s wood-cut of " The Knight,
            Death, and Satan,” and that the wild harmonies of Ole Bull
            had some influence in shaping it forth. A story so begot and
            so brought forth, must needs be wild, mysterious, and startling. An aura like a witch-element pervades the pages, and
            as we turn over the leaves a sensation of terror is imbibed,
            seemingly, at our fingers' ends. The tale opens with the following wild and startling chapter :—
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>" In the Castle of Drontheim there were many knights assembled to
            hold council on the affairs of the kingdom; and alter their debate,
            they remained till past midnight carousing together around the huge
            stone table in the vaulted hall. A rising storm drove the snow mildly
            against the rattling windows, all the thick oak doors groaned, the
            massive locks shook, the castle clock slowly and heavily struck the
            hour of one.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>" At that instant a boy, pale as death, with disordered hair and closed eyes, rushed into the hall, uttering a wild scream of terror. He
            stopped behind the richly carved seat of the mighty Biorn, clung to
            the knight with both his hands, and shrieked in a piercing voice,
         </p>
         <p>'My knightly father ! Death and another are closely pursuing me.'
            
         </p>
         <p>"An awful stillness reigned suddenly in the whole assembly, broken only by the agonized shrieks of the boy. But one of Biorn's numerous retainers, an old esquire, known by the name of Rolf the Good,
            advanced toward the terrified child, took him in his arms, and half
            chanted this prayer: ‘Oh, Father! help Thy servant! I believe,
            and yet I cannot believe.’ The boy, as if in a dream, at once loosened his hold of the knight; and the good Rolf bore him from the
            hall unresisting, yet still shedding hot tears, and murmuring confused
            sounds.
         </p>
         <p>“ The lords and knights looked at one another in mute amazement,
            until the mighty Biorn said, in a fierce but scornfully-deriding tone,
            
         </p>
         <p>'	Do not suffer yourselves to be disturbed by the appearance of that
            strange being. He is my only son ; and has been in this state since
            he was five years old : he is now twelve. I am, therefore, accustomed to see him so, though, at the first, I too was disquieted by it. The
            attack comes upon him only once in the year, and always at this
            same time. But forgive me* for having spent so many words on my
            poor Sintram, and let us pass on to some worthier subject for our discourse.’
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>" Again there was a silence during some minutes. Then a solitary
            voice begun here and there to attempt renewing their former conversation, but without success. Two of the youngest and most joyous
            spirits begun a drinking song; but the storm howled and raged so
            wildly without, that their mirth was soon checked. And now they
            all sat silent and motionless in the lofty hall; the lamp flickered under
            the vaulted roof; the whole party of knights looked like pale, lifeless
            images, dressed up in gigantic armour.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>"Then arose the chaplain of the castle of Drontheim, the only
            priest among the knightly throng, and said, ' Sir Biorn, our eyes and
            thoughts have all been directed to you and your son in a wonderful
            banner ; but so it has been ordered by the providence of God. You
            perceive that we cannot withdraw them, and you would do well to tell
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>us exactly what you know concerning the fearful state in which we
            have seen your boy. Perchance, such a solemn narration, as I look
            forward to, might be of much use to our disturbed minds.’
         </p>
         <p>Biorn cast a look of displeasure on the priest, and answered,
            'You are more concerned in the history, than either you or I could
            desire. Excuse me, if I am unwilling to trouble these light-hearted
            warriors with such a rueful tale.’	
            " But the chaplain approached nearer to the knight, and said, in a
            
         </p>
         <p>firm yet very mild tone, ‘ Sir knight, up to this moment it rested with
            you to relate, or not to relate it: but now that you have so strangely
            hinted at the share which I have had in your son’s calamity, I must
            positively request that you will repeat word for word how every thing
            came to pass. My honour demands such an explanation, and that
            will weigh with you as much as with me.’
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ In stern compliance, Biorn bowed his haughty head, and began the
            following narration This time seven years, I was keeping Christmas-feast with my assembled followers. We have many venerable
            old customs which have descended to us by inheritance from our forefathers ; as, for instance, that of placing a gilded boar’s head on the
            table, and making thereon knightly vows of daring and wondrous deeds.
            Our chaplain there, who iu those days used frequently to visit me,
            was never a friend to keeping up such traditions of the ancient heathen world. Men of his sort were not much in favour in those olden
            times.’
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>‘“My excellent predecessors,’ interrupted the chaplain, ‘were
            infinitely more concerned in obtaining the favor of God, than that of
            the world, and they were not unsuccessful in their aim. By that
            means they converted your ancestors ; and if I can in like manner be
            of service to you, even your jeering will not vex me.’
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ With looks yet darker, and an involuntary shudder, the knight
            resumed : ' Yes, yes; I know all your promises and threats concerning an invisible Power; and how they are meant to persuade us to
            part more readily with whatever of this world’s goods we may possess. There was a time when such belonged to me ! Occasionally
            a strange fancy seizes me, and I feel as if ages had passed over me
            since then, and as if I were alone the survivor, so fearfully is every
            thing changed. But now I recall to mind, that the greater part of this
         </p>
         <p>noble company knew me in my days of happiness, and have seen mv
            wife, my lovely Verena.’	'	1
            
         </p>
         <p>“ He pressed his hands on his eyes, and many thought that he wept
            The tempest was now lulled ; the soft light of the moon shone through
            the windows, and her beams played on his wild features. Suddenly
            he started up, so that his heavy armour rattled with a fearful sound
            and he cried out in a thundering voice, ‘ Shall I turn monk, because
            she has become a nun ? No, crafty priest: your webs are too thin to
            catch flies of my sort.’
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ ‘ I have nothing to do with webs,’ said the chaplain. ‘In all
            openness and sincerity have I put heaven and hell before you during
            the space of six years; and you gave full consent to the step which
            the holy Verena took. But what all that has to do with your son’s
            sufferings, I have yet to learn ; and I wait for your further narration.’
         </p>
         <p>“ ' You may wait long enough for that,’ said Biorn with a sneer.
            ‘ Sooner shall-----’
            “ ‘ Swear not!’ said the chaplain in a loud commanding tone ; and
            his eyes flashed almost fearfully.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ ‘ Hurra,’ cried Biorn in wild affright; ‘ hurra ! Death and his
            companion are let loose !’ and he dashed madly out of the chamber,
            and down the steps. The loud wild notes of his horn were heard summoning his retainers, and presently the clatter of horses’ feet gave to.
            ken of their departure.
         </p>
         <p>“ The knights retired silent and shuddering; while the chaplain
            remained alone at the huge stone table, engaged in earnest prayer.”
            
         </p>
         <p>HumAn Magnetism ; its Claim to Dispassionate Inquiry. Being an
            Attempt to show the Utility of its Application for the Relief of Human Suffering. By W. Newnham, Esq., M. R. S. L., author of the
            “ Reciprocal Influence of Body and Mind,” etc. New York : Wiley
            and Putnam.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is a work of vast importance and high merit, but one
            of which (on account of its extent of thesis) it is almost impossible to speak otherwise than cursorily, or at random,
            within the limits of a weekly paper.
         </p>
         <p>The title explains the subject in its generality. The origin
            of the work is thus stated in an Introductory Chapter:
            
         </p>
         <p>“ About twelve months since I was asked by some friends to write
            a paper against mesmerism—and I was furnished with materials by a
            highly esteemed quondam pupil, which proved incontestibly that under some circumstances the operator might be duped—that hundreds
            of enlightened persons might equally be deceived—and certainly went
            far to show that the pretended science was wholly a delusion, a system of fraud and jugglery by which the imaginations of the credulous
            were held in thraldom through the arts of the designing. Perhaps in
            an evil hour I assented to the proposition thus made—but on reflection
            I found that the facts before me only led to the direct proof that certain phenomena might be counterfeited; and the existence of counterfeit coin is rather a proof that there is somewhere the genuine standard gold to be imitated.”
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page210"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>Now the fallacy here is obvious, and lies in a mere variation of what the logicians style “ begging the question.”
            Counterfeit coin is said to prove the existence of genuine—
            but this is no more than the truism that there can be no
            counterfeit where there is no genuine—just as there can be
            no badness where there is no goodness—the considerations
            being purely relative; but, because there can be no counterfeit where there is no original, does it in any manner follow
            that any undemonstrated original exists ? In seeing a piece
            of gold we know it to be counterfeit by comparison with
            coins admitted to be genuine; but were no coin admitted to
            be genuine, how should we establish the counterfeit, and
            what right should we have to talk of counterfeits at all ?
            Now in the case of mesmerism our author is merely begging
            the admission.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Such reasoning as this has an ominous look in the very
            first page of a scientific work—and accordingly we were not
            surprised to find Mr. Newnham’s treatise illogical throughout. Not that we do not thoroughly coincide with him in his
            general views—but that we attain (for the most part) his
            conclusions by different, and we hope more legitimate routes
            than his own. In some important points—his ideas of prevision, for example, and the curative effects of magnetism—
            we radically disagree—and most especially do we disagree
            with him in his (implied) disparagement of the work of
            Chauncey Hare Townshend, which we regard as one of the
            most truly profound and philosophical works of the day—a
            work to be valued properly only in a day to come.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We hope, however, that nothing here said by us will influence a single individual to neglect a perusal of the book of
            Mr. Newnham. It should be read, as a vast store-house of
            suggestive facts, by all who pretend to keep pace with modern philosophy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In saying above that we disagree with the author in some
            of his ideas of the curative effects of magnetism, we are not
            to be understood as disputing, in any degree, the prodigious
            importance of the mesmeric influence in surgical cases:—that
            limbs, for example, have been amputated without pain
            through such influence, is what we feel to be fact. In instances such as that of Miss Martineau, however, we equally
            feel the weakness of attributing the cure to magnetism.
            Those who wish to examine all sides of a question would do
            well to dip into some medical works of authority before forming an opinion on such topics. In the case of Miss Martineau
            we beg leave to refer to the “London Lancet,” for March,
            1845, page 265 of the edition published by Burgess &amp;
            Stringer.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A History or the Society or Friends, compiled from its standing
            records, and other authentic sources, by William R. Wagstaff, M. D.
            Part 1. New York and London. Wiley &amp; Putnam. 1845.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is an attempt to give a History of the Society of
            Friends, in a form adapted to popular tastes, although we infer from the author’s preface, that he designed it with a view
            to instruct the members of the Society rather than the public
            at large. The present volume relates solely to the history of
            the sect in Europe; the author intimates that in a second
            part he will give a full account of the trials and privations to
            which the Society were subjected in this western world.
            The book is distinguished by the external beauty peculiar to
            all the publications of Messrs. Wiley &amp; Putnam.
         </p>
         <p>Blackwood’s Magazine, for March. New American edition. Leo-
            nard Scott &amp; Co., 142 Fulton street.
            
         </p>
         <p>In addition to many articles of great interest, this number
            of Blackwood contains another of North’s specimens of British
            Critics, in which Dryden is dismissed after a most uncom-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>fortable handling, and Pope is genially and reverently dealt
            with. It is in the very happiest vein of “ Crusty Christopher;’’ who herein manifests as little crustiness as ever did
            any critical professor.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Republication of the London Lancet. Editor, Thomas Wakely,
            M. P., Sub-editor, Henry Bennet, M. D. New American series.
            Published monthly at five dollars per annum, by Burgess &amp; Stringer:
            New York.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Messrs. B. &amp; S. have issued the numbers of the re-published “Lancet” for January, February, and March, 1845.
            Their edition is unabridged, and embodies, beyond a doubt,
            the most authentic and valuable medical and surgical information to be found, periodically, in any work in the world.
            The reputation of “ The Lancet” is higher than that of any
            other similar journal. Not merely to physicians is the work
            indispensable, but to all persons who wish to keep up with
            the facts of the day. Most assuredly facts concerning human vitality are not less important, nor of less general interest than others.
         </p>
         <p>The Palais Royal. A Historical Romance. By John H. Mancur,
            author of “ Henri Quatre,” &amp;c. New York: Wm. H. Colyer.
            
         </p>
         <p>Some of Mr. Mancur’s novels have been very naturally
            mistaken for those of James, to whom, both in manner and
            in his material generally, he bears even too remarkable a
            resemblance. “ The Palais Royal" is founded upon events
            in the lives of Mazarin and De Retz, and is a novel of far
            more than ordinary interest and value. Its great defect is
            the total lack of originality.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A Letter to the Boston Association of Congregational Ministers,
            touching certain matters of their Theology. By Theodore Parker,
            Minister of the Second Church in Roxbury. Boston : Little and
            Brown. 1845.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Liberal Christianity,” according to the showing of Mr.
            Parker, does not differ very materially from the liberalism
            exercised by the followers of St. Ignatius. We shall not be
            surprised, after reading Mr. Parker’s Letter, to hear next
            that the ruined nunnery in Charleston has been rebuilt and
            converted into an inquisition on the conservative principle of
            the good old times; or that some of our liberal friends have
            been indulging in the old fashioned pastime of an auto da fè.
            If the “ Boston Association" should ever condescend to make
            replies to the string of questions which Mr. Parker has put to
            them, (and we do not see how they can avoid doing so,)
            we hope to have the privilege of reading them.
         </p>
         <p>Lecture on Immigration and the Right of Naturalization.
            By Thomas L. Nichols. New York: Burgess, Stringer, &amp; Co. 1845.
            A very earnest appeal in behalf of the right of foreigners
            to naturalization in our country.
            The Takino of Naboth’s Vineyard, by David Lee Child. New
            York: S. W. Benedict &amp; Co., 16 Spruce street. 1845.
            
         </p>
         <p>The name of the author of this pamphlet will remove all
            doubts as to the meaning of Naboth’s Vineyard. Every body
            will understand that Naboth is Mexico, and the Vineyard
            Texas.
         </p>
         <p>New Orleans as I found it. By H. Didimus. New York ; Harper
            and Brothers.
            
         </p>
         <p>This is the title of one of the freshest, most piquant,
            and altogether most agreeable volumes which have been
            written by an American—for an American we take the author to be:—the name given is a pseudonym, of course. Professedly, his design is that of sketching some incidents of a
            first visit to New Orleans in the winter of 1835-36; but these
            incidents are in fact but a nucleus for very amusing gossip of
            all kinds, intermingled not unfrequently with some matter of
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page211"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>far loftier pretension than gossip. The book is that of a
            thoughtful, polished and well-informed man. We are promised a continuation.
         </p>
         <p>Look to the End ; or The Bennetts Abroad. By Mrs. Ellis, author
            of the Women of England. New York: Harper A Brothers.
            
         </p>
         <p>The fine abilities of Mrs. Ellis have been long appreciated, and we need say nothing about them in general. In
            “ The Bennetts Abroad” she has imagined a plain English
            family emerging from the utmost common-places of a London
            life into all that is beautiful in continental travel. The elder
            members of the party serve only as make-weights to the true
            design, which is that of depicting the influence to be exercised
            over a youthful and highly sensitive mind by the beautiful in
            itself—and with this object a lovely girl is supposed to be the
            youngest member of the family. The danger to be apprehended from too habitual an indulgence even in the sentiment
            of Beauty—that is of physical Beauty—is imagined to be
            counteracted by encouraging an appreciation of moral loveliness.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In all this there is much to be disputed—but no one can
            dispute the interest which is excited in the reader’s mind by
            the author's endeavor to develope her theory.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Le Livre des Petits enfants, ou recueil de récit mis à la portée du
            premier áge. Avec Vocabulaire. Nouvelle edition, revue et augmentée. New York: Wiley &amp; Putnam. 1845.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A very admirable little book, well adapted for the use of
            children in making their initiatory steps towards a knowledge of the French tongue. The Vocabulary contains literal
            meanings of all the words introduced in the reading, including
            the verbs in all their inflections.
         </p>
         <p>Examination of a Reply to Hints on the Reorganization of the Navy.
            Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            
         </p>
         <p>The lieutenants of the navy receive some home thrusts in
            this well-written pamphlet, in which the author stoutly and
            rightly reasserts the claims of surgeons, as well as of all other
            officers, to a definite rank in the service. We find the following amusing account of the uses to which a jackass and a
         </p>
         <p>precedent may be put.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ For many years, and probably even now, it was common in Chili
            to entrust the making of butter to a jackass trotting round a circle,
            with the cream contained in dried skins tied to his back: and when
            some Americans introduced a churn to the notice of the people, they
            admitted it was quite ingenious, but inasmuch as it was not the custom
            of the country to use such a machine, as there was no precedent there
            for its use, they preferred the assistance of the jackass and the oldfashioned way of making butler.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Don Froila and his two Daughters ; an Historical Romance of
            the Middle Ages. By Agnes Strickland. Boston : Saxton &amp; K It.
            For sale by Judd &amp; Taylor, 2 Astor House.
         </p>
         <p>This tale is published in an exceedingly neat pocket vo-
            lume, and sold at the low price of 25 cents.
            Alnwick Castle, with other Poems. By Fitz. Greene Halleck.
            New York : Harper &amp; Brothers.
            
         </p>
         <p>The merits of Mr. Halleck have been long definitely settled, at least so far as regards the poems now before us.
            We have only to wish that in writing a new poem be would
            give us an opportunity of praising him anew.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Book of the Army: comprising a general Military History of
            the United States from the period ot the Revolution to the present
            lime, with particular accounts of all the Celebrated Battles. Compiled from the best authorities. By John Frost, L. L. D. Professor of Belles Lettres in the High-School of Philadelphia. New
            York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Frost has been long known as one of our best Belles
            Lettres scholars, and one of our most judicious and indefatigable compilers. There are many of his books, however,
            which are entitled to high consideration for as much of ori-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>ginality as is consistent with history—for thoughtful comment—and for a very careful bringing up of the historic material to the latest dates, from the most authentic records.
            Of this class of his books, the “ Book of the Army” is one.
            Its object is thoroughly detailed in its title. We may add
            that it is designed as a pendant to the “ Book of the Navy,”
            lately published by the same author.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Elements of Entomology, prepared for the use of Schools and Colleges, by W. S. W. Ruschenberger, M. D., Surgeon in the U. S. Navy, Src. With plates. Philadelphia: Grigg &amp; Elliott.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is one of Dr. Ruschenberger’s “First Books of Natural History.” They are re-arrangements from the valuable
            text of Milne Edwards and Achille Comté.
         </p>
         <p>Keeping House and House-Keeping. A Story of Domestic Life.
            Edited by Mrs. S. J. Hale. New York. Harper &amp; Brothers.
            
         </p>
         <p>This is an ingeniously conceived and well managed narrative of ordinary life—without any thing of that pure namby-pamby, or rather pure drivel which we have been
            ashamed to see applauded, of late days, on the ground, forsooth, of being natural or truthful. Mrs. Hale is a woman of
            great force of thought and remarkable purity of style. She
            writes invariably well.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Book of Common Prayer, and Administration of the Sacraments j and other Rites and Ceremonies of the Church in the U.
            S. of America: together with the Psalter, or Psalms of David.
            New York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is a truly beautiful stereotyped edition of the standard
            Episcopal Prayer-Book. We have only to speak of its mechanical execution, which is every thing that can be desired.
            The paper is luxurious—the type bold and clear—the binding
            exceedingly durable and neat.
         </p>
         <p>History of France, from the earlier period down to the present
            time ; by M. Michelet. Translated by G. H. Smith. D. Appleton
            and Co. 200 Broadway.
            
         </p>
         <p>The second number of this standard work, containing 100
            pages of closely printed matter, in double columns, from
            clear type on handsome paper, has just been issued at the
            low price of twenty-five cents. This number reaches to the
            close of the twelfth century. It is one of the best and cheapest historical works that have been republished in many
            years.
         </p>
         <p>Plagiarism—Imitation—Postcript to Mr. Poe’s Reply TO THE
            Letter of Outis.	
            
         </p>
         <p>It should not be supposed that I feel myself individually
            aggrieved in the letter of Outis. He has praised me even
            more than he has blamed. In replying lo him, my design
            has been to place fairly and distinctly before the literary
            public certain principles of criticism for which I have been
            long contending, and which, through sheer misrepresentation,
            were in danger of being misunderstood.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Having brought the subject, in this view, to a close in the
            last Journal, I now feel at liberty to add a few words of postscript, by way of freeing myself of any suspicion of malevolence or discourtesy. The thesis of my argument, in general,
            has been the definition of the grounds on which a charge of
            plagiarism may be based, and of the species of ratiocination
            by which it is to be established: this is all. It will be seen
            by any one who shall take the trouble to read what I have
            written, that I make no charge of moral delinquency against
            either Mr. Longfellow, Mr. Aldrich, or Mr. Hood indeed,
            lest in the heat of argument, I may have uttered any words
            which may admit of being tortured into such an interpretation, I here fully disclaim them upon the spot.
         </p>
         <p>In fact, the one strong point of defence for his friends has
            been unaccountably neglected by Outis. To attempt the re-
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page212"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>butting of a charge of plagiarism by the broad assertion that
            no such thing as plagiarism exists, is a sotticism, and no
            more—but there would have been nothing of unreason in rebutting the charge as urged either against Mr. Longfellow,
            Mr. Aldrich, or Mr. Hood, by the proposition that no true
            poet can be guilty of a meanness—that the converse of the
            proposition is a contradiction in terms.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Should there be found any one willing to dispute with me
            this point, I would decline the disputation on the ground that
            my arguments are no arguments to him.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It appears to me that what seems to be the gross inconsistency of plagiarism as perpetrated by a poet, is very easily
            thus resolved :—the poetic sentiment (even without reference
            to the poetic power) implies a peculiarly, perhaps an abnormally keen appreciation of the beautiful, with a longing for
            its assimilation, or absorption, into the poetic identity. What
            the poet intensely admires, becomes thus, in very fact, although only partially, a portion of his own intellect. It has
            a secondary origination within his own soul—an origination
            altogether apart, although springing, from its primary origination from without. The poet is thus possessed by another’s thought, and cannot be said to take of it, possession.
            But, in either view, he thoroughly feels it as his own—and
            this feeling is counteracted only by the sensible presence of
            its true, palpable origin in the volume from which he has
            derived it—an origin which, in the long lapse of years it is
            almost impossible not to forget—for in the mean time the
            thought itself is forgotten. But the frailest association will
            regenerate it—it springs up with all the vigor of a new
            birth—its absolute originality is not even a matter of suspicion—and when the poet has written it and printed it, and
            on its account is charged with plagiarism, there will be no
            one in the world more entirely astounded than himself. Now
            from what I have said it will be evident that the liability to
            accidents of this character is in the direct ratio of the poetic
            sentiment—of the susceptibility to the poetic impression; and
            in fact all literary history demonstrates that, for the most
            frequent and palpable plagiarisms, we must search the works
            of the most eminent poets.	E. A. P.
         </p>
         <p>THOUGHTS OF A SILENT MAN.
            No. 4.
            
         </p>
         <p>In a foregoing paper I spoke of sympathy as existent between kindred souls, in a much more perfect state than the
            world was willing to allow. The recently published correspondence between Schiller and Goethe, affords the most
            beautiful exposition of this spiritual recognition that the annals of literature have ever recorded. Literary friendships,
            as they are called, are too often mere leagues growing out
            of community of interests, or attachments formed from the
            necessity of insatiate vanity. Inferior minds sometimes make
            themselves essential to superior ones, by ministering to unsuspected weakness; and a man willing to play the jackal
            will rarely fail in finding a lion to wait upon. A connection
            of this kind deserves not the name of friendship; yet the
            world never discriminates, and when the tie of mutual interest is severed between two such pseudo-friends, commonplace people exclaim at the instability of men of genius. No
            one can read the correspondence of the two minds to whom I
            have alluded, without feeling sensible of the nobler bond of
            union which true sympathy alone can weave, while the very
            suddenness of the recognition between them is the best proof
            of its genuineness.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Schiller had occasion to ask the literary aid of Goethe in
            behalf of a new periodical, and accordingly indites a letter of
            formal respect, filled with the most reverential appreciation
            of Goethe’s Anakism, yet containing not a single word of
            flattery or servility. Goethe returns a frank and hearty response. giving not a mere assent to Schiller’s proposition, but
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>professing the genial grasp of mental companionship. In
            less than two months afterward we find Schiller opening his
            heart to his new friend, with all the confidingness of a woman. How fearlessly and unjealously does he disclose the
            benefits he has derived from his recently formed attachments.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ On much about which I could not obtain harmony with myself,
            the contemplation of your mind (for thus I must call the full impression of your ideas upon me) has kindled a new light. I needed the
            object—the body to many speculative ideas, and you have put me on
            the track of it.”
         </p>
         <p>Mark Goethe’s somewhat oracular reply.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Pure enjoyment and real benefits can only be reciprocal, and it
            will give me pleasure to uul'old to you at leisure, what my intercourse
            with you has done for me—how I, too, regard it as an epoch in my
            existence—and how content I am to have gone on my way without
            particular encouragements, as it now appears as if we. after so unexpected a meeting, are to proceed forward together. I have always
            prized the honest and rare earnestness visible in all you have done
            and written. All that relates to me, and is in me, I will gladly impart.
            For as I feel very sensibly that my undertaking far exceeds the measure of the faculties of one earthly life, I would wish to repose much
            with you, and thereby give it not only endurance but vitality.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Now there may be something approaching to too much
            self-reliance in the one, and perhaps too little self-appreciation in the other ; but they both write from genuine feeling.
            There is no courtly flattery in the younger bard, no gratified
            vanity in the crowned poet. There never was a more genial
            yielding up of the soul to sudden and secret sympathy. There
            was no measured routine of civilities to be trodden before
            they could join hands at the shrine of friendship.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ However strong,” says Schiller, “ has been my desire to enter
            into a closer relation with you than is possible between the spirit of a
            writer and his most attentive reader, yet I now perceive clearly that
            the different paths in which you and I moved, could not have brought
            us together with advantage sooner than just at this time. But now I
            can hope that we shall travel together the rest of the way, and with
            greater profit, inasmuch as the last travellers who join company, have
            always the most to say to one another.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>When we regard the character of the men and the position they occupied in the world of letters, the picture of a
            pure and beautiful literary friendship becomes complete, and
            we turn with a feeling of refreshment from the cold, hard,
            narrow selfisms of society to the rich development of soul in
            such a union. Their correspondence, which lasted ten years,
            and closed only with the death of Schiller, is like a manysided mirror, reflecting every object that passes before it, in
            every variety of light and shade; while the pure clear atmosphere in which such souls live, and move, and have their
            being, gives almost magical distinctness to each image. No
            breath of selfishness or distrust ever rests for an instant on its
            bright surface. The glimpses which it affords us of Goethe’s
            magnificent vanity (for he was a man who made even his
            weaknesses almost sublime) seem necessary to the proper
            illustration of Schiller’s exquisite humility; and the hierarch
            of German literature never appears in so amiable a point of
            view as when cordially accepting and adopting his friend’s
            close and quick-sighted criticisms.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Yet, as in my former paper, I ventured to assert that such
            sympathy could only grow to perfectness in persons of opposite sex, so now I dare affirm that this very correspondence
            is a proof of my theory. Genius assimilates, though it does
            not confound sex, and while it gives something of manly
            strength to woman, it always imparts much feminility of
            perfection and feeling to man, especially if it exists with a
            delicately organized physical structure.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Goethe, with his robust physique, his wide perceptive faculties, his enterprise, his towering independence of soul, his
            easy, graceful yet despotic exercise of mental domination,
            affords a perfect contrast to Schiller, who was feeble in
            health, self-distrustful, eminently tender in his imaginativeness, and full of up-looking reliance upon the stronger spirit
            ol his friend. Had they both possessed only strongly marked
            masculine traits of character, their union could never have
            been so perfect. Now it has some of the best characteristics
            of Platonic affection. Goethe was the strong man, self-dependent, self-subsistent, yet needing companionship: Schiller
            was the tender womanish nature, strong in principle, and
            perhaps with a latent power of self-reliance, but happier and
            better in its gentle dependence on a bolder nature. Advice,
            counsel, dictation, suggestion, and a sort of watchful guardianship, these are Goethe’s duties; deference, devotion, nay,
            the very outward ministry, for which women seem so essen-
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page213"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>tially fitted, comes from Schiller; it is Schiller who sends
            the frequent box of biscuits—Goethe now and then furnishes
            his friend a fish, snared in the free waters, but the remembrance of household tastes comes from the womanlike affection of the gentler spirit.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is no mere fanciful speculation. Perfect similarity is
            not sympathy; each must find in the other what is wanting
            in itself. There need be no inferiority in mind, yet there
            must be differences in mental and moral qualities. Men judge
            of their own sex through their consciousness, and they judge
            of women through their imagination. Both faculties may
            be erring guides, but the latter is more likely to be right
            than the former, since it usually gives a much more exalted
            view of human nature. The love of a high-souled man is
            one of the noblest, most unselfish, and loftiest feelings of
            which humanity is capable. The love of woman, even of the
            most gentle, as well as of the highest nature, is exacting, for
            even as she is willing to give all, so she is not content with
            less than the sacrifice of all things to her. Considerateness,
            tenderness, the entire devotion of a life, are but as grains of
            incense in her eyes. She would fain give as much as she
            could, and therefore nothing can be offered which her love
            does not deserve. She may be humble in all things else, but
            she is always appreciating towards her own affections, and
            hence her utter unreasonableness in all love affairs. But her
            friendship is another thing. All the superiority which man’s
            stronger nature gives him over her in love, her greater purity
            affords her over him in friendship. No where is there more
            devotion, more disinterestedness, more ready self-sacrifice,
            than in a woman’s friendship; no where more teazing, annoying, heart-stirring pettiness of exaction than in her love;
            and the man who would have a full appreciation of woman’s
            nature, as well as a full enjoyment of her sweet presence,
            must be her dearest friend, but never her devoted lover.
         </p>
         <p>RUDOLPH HERTZMAN.
            RURAL ARCHITECTURE.*
            
         </p>
         <p>“Every man’s proper mansion and home, the theatre of
            his hospitalie, the seat of self-fruition, the comfortablest part
            of his own life, the noblest part of his son’s inheritance, a
            kind of private princedom; nay, to the possessor himself an
            epitome of the whole world, may well deserve by these attributes, according to the degree of the master, to be decently and delightfully adorned ;” says quaint old Sir Henry Wotton. And there are few who will not echo his sentiments,
            although it happens unfortunately, that there are few that
            build houses who sufficiently comprehend their own condition to know when their proper mansions are decently and delightfully adorned according to their degree ; they are, therefore, obliged to call in the aid of a professional gentleman to
            instruct them in the selection of their seats of self-fruition.
            For our own selves, we would as soon think of calling
            upon a broker to choose a wife for us, as to seek the aid of a
            professional gentleman in the matter of building a house, or
            adorning our grounds with trees. A man who is not capable of deciding whether a Greek temple, or a Swiss cottage,
            be the best adapted to his wants, and the necessities of the
            climate he lives in, is not worthy of a house at all, and instead of applying to an architect for the plan of a mansion,
            he should apply to the county officers for admission into the
            Alms-House. The individual who cares so little whether
            he spends his precious hours in a tabernacle fitted up in the
            style of the renaissance, or in the no style of a modern carpenter and plasterer, or who is so indifferent to the kind of
            trees that shall shelter him from the sun and the wind, as to
            pay a fee to an artist to select them for him, should never
            be allowed to live in a house of his own, but should occupy
            a back room in a boarding house, and eat such food as his
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>*A treatise on the theory and practice of landscape gardening,
            adapted to North America, 2d edition by A. J. Downing. New York
            and London,  Wiley and Putnam.—Cottage Residences. A series of
            designs for rural cottages and cottage villas, by A. J. Downing, 2d edition New York and London, Wiley and Putnam.
         </p>
         <p>landlady might choose for him, and at such hours as she
            might appoint.
            
         </p>
         <p>But there are men who can build houses, and afford to live
            on ornamented farms, who yet possess not the smallest degree of love for art or nature, and acknowledge themselves
            incompetent to decide whether the Italian style, or the gingerbread style of building be the more delightful, or whether
            a clump of yew trees or a grove of poplars would form the
            finer feature in a landscape. They are the people whose
            empty heads and full purses have made the fortune of many a
            “ Capability Brown,” and will make the fortunes of many
            more. To all such, books like those by Mr. Downing, are a
            real blessing. A man’s house and grounds should possess some
            of his idiosyncracies of character, but how can they when
            they are the products of a hired artificer in taste ? It is ten to
            one that a professional landscape gardener would neglect to
            plant a peperidge tree in our grounds if we should employ
            him to decorate them, or forget to fringe our plantation of red
            maples with a row of dwarf cedars, or deem it of no importance that two or three sassafras trees should be sprinkled
            among the pines and hemlocks, to relieve the dark foliage
            of these evergreens with their light and joyous verdure in
            summer, and their gamboge leaves in the fall. But without
            these leafy darlings of ours we would as soon have no
            grounds; and as for living in a gingerbread, crocketed, turreted cottage, we would sooner live in a tub with some Alexander or other always in our sunshine. To the nomadic
            tribes of our cities, who change their residences every May
            day, it cannot be a matter of much consequence what kind
            of houses serve for their temporary abodes; and it is, perhaps, fortunate for them that the houses which they inhabit
            are so built and furnished as to prevent anything like local
            attachments being formed ; but to the farmer and the country gentleman whose houses are to be the theatres of their
            hospitalities, the comfortablest part of their whole lives,
            nay, the epitome to them of the whole world, it is a matter of
            great importance what kind of place they inhabit. Therefore, we would advise every gentleman before he employs an
            architect to build him a bouse, or an artist to decorate his
            grounds, to try and ascertain from himself what his wants are,
            and give utterance to them in his own way. It will conduce
            much more to his comfort to live in a house of his own devising, than to inhabit one which a stranger may model for
            him. In one case his house will be a part of himself, his
            thoughts and habits will assimilate to it, and his children
            will continually find something in it to remind them of their
            father ; it will make no material difference if it be grotesque,
            or awkward, or misproportioned; it will be genuine; and
            you need never fear that you will be liked the less for it; as
            Sir Lucius says: “ When affection guides the hand he must
            be a brute who would find fault with the style ;” in the other
            case, you would never feel at home in your own house, you
            would feel like a stranger, where you were a master, because
            you would always be inhabiting another man’s house ;
            your paying for it would not make it your own, though it
            would give you a legal right to hold it. The old baronial
            castles and English manor houses, which we are so fond of
            reproducing in this country, derive their chief charm from
            their genuineness of expression ; they were built by their
            owners, who employed no dilettanti artist to frame a design
            for them, but in their uncultured honesty they gave orders to
            have such mansions or castles built as suited then: circumstances. Therefore, they have a character of their own
            which appears delightful in our eyes, because it seems natural and appropriate ; but the moment that we attempt to
            adopt them to our own uses, their beauty vanishes and they
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page214"></div>
            appear incongruous and out of place.
            
         </p>
         <p>An age of ignorance and semi-barbarism is much more favorable to the development of good taste than one of high
            culture, unless the culture be very high, because then men
            give expression to their honest feelings without any regard
            to precedents. We therefore find that the most picturesque
            and charming forms of artistic expression in dress and architecture, were made in those good old times when learning
            was at its very lowest ebb, or rather when there was no
            learning at all, excepting such as men received directly from
            nature, as Moses received his laws directly from God. People who travel much about the world, or have much commerce with books, are the least reliable of all authorities in
            matters of taste ; because a great variety of examples and precepts must have the effect to destroy their instinctive perceptions of fitness, and fill their minds with incongruous images.
            We see that the greatest of English architects, Sir Christopher Wren, had less of the advantages of travel and
            study of foreign models than any of the slender builders who
            have succeeded him ; yet none of them has equalled him in invention ; he built St. Paul’s without having seen St. Peter’s,
            or having the advantage of Stuart and Trevett’s Athens.
            The pyramids were erected without examples, as were the
            Cathedrals and Castles of the 13th century. Ictinus of
            Athens never saw a perfect temple until he built one himself,
            and the Romans invented their own arches. Therefore,
            if we would find a genuine style, we must seek for it in the
            uncontaminated period of a nation’s existence, and if we entertain the hope of producing a great architect on our own
            continent we must look for him in our back-woods where
            our great sculptor has come from. Art does not produce art.
            Rude nature has always produced the best artists.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Swiss chalet, the English cottage, the Italian villa,
            the French chateau, the Indian hut, the Chinese pagoda, the
            Hindoo temple, the Greek temple, the Moresque alcazar, the
            Turkish seraglio, the Baronial castle, the Monkish abbey,
            were all genuine forms of expression which had no types
            in nature or art: they grew out of the necessities of the
            people who erected them: they are, therefore, gratifying to
            contemplate, because, though differing so widely, they appear fit and proper. But, we should be satisfied to contemplate them, for we can never adapt them to our wants or
            the necessities of our climate and laws. But it is the misfortune of an upstart to have an ambition to appear different
            from what he is, and as it cannot be denied that we are,
            mainly, a nation of upstarts, we have an easy solution of the
            otherwise incomprehensible mystery of baronial castles, Chinese pagodas, Swiss chalèts, Gothic churches, plaster priories, and English cottages, that we see scattered about the
            country on the tops of hills, by the side of running streams,
            and even in the crowded by-ways of our cities, as though the
            miracle of the house of Loretto had been repeated a thousand times on our continent. A barbarian and an ignoramus will consult only their own wants, and with the same
            disregard for precept and example which the beaver and
            oriole manifest in building their dam and nest, will adapt
            their dwellings to their necessities ; but the half enlightened
            Christian, who was born in a log hut, and has made his fortune in a narrow brick store, in the peaceful occupation of
            selling drugs or ten-penny nails, is troubled with ambitious
            longings after the way of life which some chivalrous robber
            led in the good old times of ignorance and barbarism ; or he
            has been fascinated by stories of the monks of old, and he
            sends for an architect to build him a castle after the plan of
            Front de Bœuf’s, or a priory with an embattled roof, and a
            little tower into which he can scarce squeeze himself, with
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>loop-holes for bow-men to shoot arrows; another has a romantic taste, and has read of love in a cottage and of rural
            delights, and he must have an English cottage; another affects the Italian villa; and another the Turkish seraglio.
            Thus we have in the same degree of latitude which admits
            of but one style of building, the flat roofs of the tropics, the
            sharp gables of the north, the minarets of the east, and the
            low-roofed cot of the quiet vales of England. But amid all
            this confusion and affectation, may be found here and there,
            the genuine expression of honest ignorance and refined learning, which are generally alike in essentials, but only differ in
            execution.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Downing has given ten designs for “ cottage residences”
            in the second edition of his book of that name, and in his
            larger volume on landscape gardening and rural architecture,
            he has given a great many examples of rural habitations, in all
            manner of styles from every part of the world, but he has not
            given one example of an American country house. Yet we have
            an American style of rural architecture, as expressive and as
            beautiful as any in England or Italy. For although we may
            justly pride ourselves upon our national intelligence, we
            have had some ignorant classes among us, who have grown
            up and gone to their rest in the rural districts of the old
            States, without having been tainted by too close an intimacy
            with foreign picture books, or by foreign travel, and who have
            left behind them mementoes of their existence, as free from
            affectation as a bird’s-nest, or the hive of a bee. These are
            the old stone farm-houses built by the Dutch, and Huguenot,
            and English stock on parts of Long Island, on Staten Island,
            in the Jerseys, and on the banks of the Hudson. Many of
            these ante-revolutionary edifices still remain, as remarkable
            specimens of architectural adaptation as are to be found in
            any country. They show in their details a profound ignorance of art, but in their forms and expression, they show
            what the highest art only can show, a simple adaptation of
            means to wants. A great many of them, particularly in
            New Jersey, have the mansard roof, a form better adapted
            to our climate than any other, and which, after being many
            years in vogue, has at length given way before the influences
            of Loudon’s Encyclopedia. The roofs of these old houses, in
            nine cases out of ten, project about five feet on the side facing
            the south, and form a natural piazza, as purely beautiful as
            the Grecian portico. It is a matter of no little surprise that
            an artist, in giving examples of rustic houses, should shut
            his eyes to the only existing type of an American country
            mansion, and in its place recommend the foreign models that
            were designed for another soil, another climate, and another
            condition of society.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Downing’s smallest book contains much valuable information, and many wholesome precepts, which entitle it to
            respectful consideration, but many of his examples are
            strangely at variance with his principles.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ The expression of purpose in architecture is conveyed
            by features in a building, or by its whole appearance, suggesting the end in view, or the purpose for which it is intended.” Cot. Res. page 19. This is very good, and it would
            lead us to expect great simplicity and purity of thought in
            one of the author’s designs; but in the example of his own
            house at Newburgh, we observe two octagonal blind towers
            which have puzzled us exceedingly to guess at their uses.
            Perhaps they may be cases for depositing fishing rods—we
            can conceive of no other use for such appendages.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ In expressing our architectural ideas by the medium of a certain
            style of language, we shall succeed best, and our efforts will afford
            more real delight, the more near we approach to the nature of the
            circumstances under which the style or circumstances originated.
            Thus, if we talk pure Greek and build a Grecian temple for a dwelling, we shall be little understood, or perhaps only laughed at by our
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page215"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>neighbors. It is not much better in the present day to recite an epic
            poem by building a cathedral, or a heroic one by constructing a castle
            for our habitation. Let us rather be more sensible, though not less
         </p>
         <p>graceful in our architectural utterance, and express a pleasant, every
            day language in an old English mansion, a rural Gothic cottage, or an
            Italian villa.” Cot. Res. page 32.
            
         </p>
         <p>We will say nothing about the unintelligibleness of nearly the whole of the above, but simply enter our protest to
            the deductions of the author that the old English mansion,
            the rural gothic cottage and the Italian villa, express the every day language of American life. They do no such thing.
            They are as foreign to our language as the dialects of Boccaccio and Chaucer. They can never be made to express
            our feelings—first, because they are foreign, and secondly, because they are old.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ As an example of the violation of the unity of style, we might re.
            fer to a number of country chapels, or churches, within our knowledge, where a Grecian portico and Gothic or pointed windows occur
            in the same composition !”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ A solecism in taste which we have several times witnessed with
            pain in this country, and which we will therefore caution our readers
            against, is the introduction of green blinds or Venetian shatters, upon
            a building in the pointed or English cottage style.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>These solecisms in taste are the only redeeming points
            about these styles. They are evidences that the minds of
            the people are not wholly prostrated by foreign example.
            Windows of any kind, Gothic windows not peculiarly so,
            are sufficiently incongrous in a Grecian temple, but it is better
            to commit a solecism in taste than sit in the dark, and if
            nothing short of green Venetian blinds can render an English
            cottage endurable in our scorching summers, it would be better to pain an architect by their adoption than to be roasted
            or parboiled by leaving them off for the sake of avoiding a
            solecism. The solecism would be more easily borne than
            the solstice. If Baptists and Presbyterians will persist in
            worshipping in tabernacles copied after the temple of Jupiter Panhellenius, let them not be wholly pagans by excluding the blessed light of day from their chapels for congruity’s sake.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>One of the most remarkable specimens of rural architecture which we have heard of in our country, is an example
            given by Mr. Downing in his “Landscape Gardening” of
            the seat of a reverend gentleman in Westchester county, called
            “ Pelham Priory.” It has two towers with battlements, and
            to make the whole perfect in keeping, the flag of St. George
            is flaunting from the summit of one of them. “ The interior is fitted up and constructed throughout with the same
            feeling (want of it), with harmonious wainscoting, quaint
            carving, massive chimney pieces, and old furniture and armor."
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Perhaps the greatest amount of architectural nonsense to
            be found in the world may be seen in a circle of five miles,
            taking Boston common for a centre. The same circle will
            also include some of the finest examples of country houses in
            the Union, but they are nearly all half a century old. One of
            the best among them is occupied by the poet Longfellow,
            who with praiseworthy taste preserves the fine old mansion
            of which he is the owner, in its original integrity. It was
            once the residence of Washington. The Gothic and Grecian
            villas, scattered about like castles on a chess board, give the
            country the appearance of a large toy shop.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Prince Maximilian remarks, that when he landed in Boston
            he looked about in vain for some specimens of American
            plants, particularly the species that were cultivated in
            Europe, but he could find only foreign trees; it was with
            difficulty that he discovered some stems of the Catalpa. If
            he had looked for an American house he would have experienced much greater difficulty in finding one. They appear
            to have gone resolutely to work with the intention of copying every example out of Loudon’s encyclopedia, and when
            they have exhausted bis specimens and the ten examples in
            Mr. Downing’s book, they will probably begin at the beginning of some French or German work and exhaust that
            Mr. Downing’s works contain much to recommend them
            to the favorable notice of his countrymen; although their
            chief fault, in our estimation, is a want of indigenous feeling,
            they possess the charm of novelty which will recompense
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>for much greater faults in the eye of the majority of readers. His work on landscape gardening must long continue
            a text book in the United States ; it contains a great amount
            of valuable information, and many sound precepts on the
            art of improving the appearance of the country ; while his
            smaller work, on cottage residences, will be found a valuable guide in the construction of a dwelling house, whether in
            town or country. The engravings by which they are illustrated are among the best specimens of art that we have
            produced in this department.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The cost of these books is nothing, compared with the
            value of their contents, and being the only works of the
            kind which have been produced in the country, they should
            be found on every book table, especially in country houses,
            where they could not fail to create a taste for landscape decorations, which is much needed in our rural districts. In
            the city they will create a taste for the country, and if they
            have no other good effect, they will at least serve to occupy
            an idle hour, and while they amuse the mind, will be sure
            to leave some good impression on it.
         </p>
         <p>Original Poetry.
            
         </p>
         <p>[We might guess who is the fair author of the following lines,
            which have been sent us in a MS. evidently disguised—but we are
            not satisfied with guessing, and would give the world to know. We
            think the “ Rivulet’s Dream” an exceedingly graceful and imaginative poem, and our readers will agree with us. Kate Carol will do
            us the justice to note that we have preferred her “ sober second
            thought” in the concluding line.—Eds. B. J.]
         </p>
         <p>THE RIVULET’S DREAM.
            FROM THE GERMAN OF — SOMEBODY.
            A careless rill was dreaming,
            One fragrant summer night ;
            It dreamed a star lay gleaming
            With heavenly looks of light,
            Soft cradled on its own pure breast,
            That rose and fell, and rocked to rest,
            With lulling wave, its radiant guest,
            In silent beauty beaming;
            And like a lute’s low sighing,
            The rill sang to the star,
            “ Why earnest thou, fondly flying,
            From those blue hills afar ?
            All calm and cold without thy ray,
            I slept the long dark night away—
            Ah! child of heaven! forever stay !”
            No sweet voice rose replying.
            “ Oh, glorious truant ! listen !
            Wilt fold thy shining wings,
            That softly glance and glisten
            The while the wavelet sings ?
            Wilt dwell with me ? I’ll give thee flowers,—
            Our way shall be through balmy bowers,
            And song and dance shall charm the hours:—
            My star-love ! dost thou listen 1
            "No gorgeous garden-blossom,
            In regal grace and bloom,
            May pour upon my bosom
            Its exquisite perfume ;
            But I may wreathe, with wild flowers rare,
            That softly breathe, thy golden hair,—
            The violet's tear shall tremble there.
            A fair though fragile blossom
            Alas .’ when morning slowly
            Stole o’er the distant hill,
            From that sweet dream, so holy,
            It woke—the sorrowing rill!
            No “ child of heaven” lay smiling there,—
            ’Twas but a vision bright and rare,
            That blessed, as passed the star in air,
            The rivulet lone and lowly.
            KATE CAROL.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page216"></div>
            MR. HUDSON, THE NEW LECTURER ON SHAKSPEARE.
            
         </p>
         <p>We present our readers with a sketch of this popular lecturer, as he appears in the
            desk, while delivering his unique remarks on the Shakspearian age. We have already awarded to Mr. Hudson the claim of a Genius. His peculiarities
            are very striking, and his manner provincial
            in the extremest degree. He might have served Mr. Halliburton as a model for Sam Slick,
            and if he should ever repeat his lectures in England,
            we have no doubt that he would be taken for the original of that happy creation. He
            is a yankee of the yankees, and would, as such, create
            a sensation in London. It is just the place for him to make his fortune in, and if
            he is the real yankee that we take him for, he will certainly
            repeat his lectures in that city. We cut from an exchange paper a brief account of
            his career, from which it will be seen that he is the maker
            of his own fortunes. It is said, or rather he says it himself, that he delivered eleven
            lectures in Cincinnati, and seven in Boston, before he got
            a full audience. He has succeeded wherever he has made an attempt to gain an audience,
            and we have no doubt that success will still follow
            him. He is one of those who compel it. 
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>"In youth Mr. Hudson was sent to learn the blacksmith’s trade, at which he labored
            till the age of eighteen. The individual with whom
            he passed these important years of his life entirely neglected his education and afforded
            him scarcely the means of comfort. Under such circumstances, the young apprentice was transferred from the shop of the blacksmith to
            that of a coachmaker, to which occupation he applied
            himself diligently four years more—three years as apprentice and one as a journeyman.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Up to this time, the advantages which he enjoyed for improving ids intellectual
            capacities were very slight, and by no means satisfactory
            to one who had even an ordinary degree of mental gifts. He had for some time felt
            the want of an education, and at length resolved to obtain
            it; preparing himself for a collegiate career, he entered the University in Middlebury,
            Vt., adjoining his native town, and graduated there
            in 1840.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ After his graduation, Mr. H. went to the South to engage as a teacher. He spent
            one year in Kentucky and subsequently two years in
            Huntsville, Alabama; and while occupied in this little retired town, he wrote for
            his own gratification, and for the purpose of occupying an
            ever restless mind, his lectures on Shakspeare. At first they were read before a few
            person, in Huntsville, some of whom were discriminating
            enough to appreciate their beauties, and induce Mr. II. to try his fortunes as a bona
            fide lecturer. Thinking to compass his desire of discharging his college debts sooner by this course than by continuing as a teacher, he went
            to Mobile during the winter of 1833—4, and delivered his
            Shakspearian discourses before an audience sufficiently large to defray his expenses.
            He now felt encouraged to visit a larger city ; and he accordingly went to Cincinnati, where he gave two courses with much the same success
            as at the South.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ He was now urged by some gentlemen of Boston, whom he met in Cincinnati, to make
            a visit to the ' Athens of America.’ He followed their
            advice, and his success has surpassed even his most sanguine expectation, while it
            has afforded him the means, to a considerable extent, of liquidating his pecuniary engagements.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ At the commencement of his college life, Mr. Hudson says, he finally resolved 'to
            make just as much of himself as possible;’ and his subsequent course shows that thus far he has not lost sight of his determination. He
            is now preparing for one of the learned professions, and intends only to continue his lectures until he shall have procured the means of defraying
            his old arrears, and of prosecuting his future studies.”
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page217"></div>
            "SO LET IT BE.”
            TO------.
            Perhaps you think it right and just,
            Since you are bound by nearer ties,
            To greet me with that careless tone,
            With those serene and silent eyes.
            So let it be ! I only know,
            If I were in your place to-night,
            I would not grieve your spirit so,
            For all God’s worlds of life and light!
            I could not turn, as you have done,
            From every memory of the past;
            I could not fling, from soul and brow,
            The shade that Feeling should have cast.
            Oh ! think how it must deepen all
            The pangs of wild remorse and pride,
            To feel, that you can coldly see
            The grief, I vainly strive to hide !
            The happy star, who fills her urn
            With glory from the God of Day,
            Can never miss the smile he lends
            The wild-flower withering fast away;
            
         </p>
         <p>The fair, fond girl, who at your side,
            Within your soul’s dear light, doth live,
            Could hardly have the heart to chide
            The ray that Friendship well might give.
         </p>
         <p>But if you deem it right and just,
            Blessed as you are in your glad lot,
            To greet me with that heartless tone,
            So let it be ! I blame you not!
            VIOLET VANE.
            BERENICE.
            Dicebant mihi sodales si sepulchrum amicae visitarem, curas meas ali-
            quantulum fore levatas.—Ebn Zaiat.
            
         </p>
         <p>Misery is manifold. The wretchedness of earth is multiform. Overreaching the wide horizon as the rainbow, its
            hues are as various as the hues of that arch,—as distinct too,
            yet as intimately blended. Overreaching the wide horizon
            as the rainbow ! How is it that from beauty I have derived
            a type of unloveliness ?—from the covenant of peace a simile of sorrow? But as, in ethics, evil is a consequence of
            good, so, in fact, out of joy is sorrow born. Either the
            memory of past bliss is the anguish of to-day, or the agonies
            which are have their origin in the ecstasies which might have
         </p>
         <p>been.
            
         </p>
         <p>My baptismal name is Egæus ; that of my family I will
            not mention. Yet there are no towers in the land more
            time-honored than my gloomy, gray, hereditary halls. Our
            line has been called a race of visionaries; and in many striking particulars—in the character of the family mansion—in
            the frescos of the chief saloon—in the tapestries of the dormitories—in the chiselling of some butresses in the armory
            —but more especially in the gallery of antique paintings in
            the fashion of the library chamber—and, lastly, in the very
            peculiar nature of the library’s contents, there is more than
            sufficient evidence to warrant the belief.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The recollection of my earliest years are connected with
            that chamber, and with its volumes—of which latter I will
            say no more. Here died my mother. Herein was I bom.
            But it is mere idleness to say that I had not lived before-that the soul has no previous existence. You deny it ? let
            us not argue the matter. Convinced myself, I seek not to
            convince. There is, however, a remembrance of aerial
            forms—of spiritual and meaning eyes—of sounds, musical
            yet sad—a remembrance which will not be excluded ; a
            memory like a shadow, vague, variable, indefinite, unsteady ;
            and like a shadow, too, in the impossibility of my getting
            rid of it while the sunlight of my reason shall exist.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In that chamber was I born. Thus awaking from the
            long night of what seemed, but was not, nonentity, at once
            into the very regions of fairy-land—into a palace of imagination—into the wild dominions of monastic thought and erudi-
         </p>
         <p>tion--it is not singular that I gazed around me with a star-
            
         </p>
         <p>tled and ardent eye—that I loitered away my boyhood in
            books, and dissipated my youth in reverie ; but it is singular
            that as years rolled away, and the noon of manhood found me
            still in the mansion of my fathers—it is wonderful what stagnation there fell upon the springs of my life—wonderful how
            total an inversion took place in the character of my commonest thought. The realities of the world affected me as
            visions, and as visions only, while the wild ideas of the land
            of dreams became, in turn,—not the material of my everyday existence—but in very deed that existence utterly and
            solely in itself.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>**********
            Berenice and I were cousins, and we grew up together in
            my paternal halls. Yet differently we grew—I ill of health
            and buried in gloom—she agile, graceful, and overflowing
            with energy—hers the ramble on the hill-side—mine the
            studies of the cloister—I living within my own heart, and addicted body and soul to the most intense and painful meditation--she roaming carelessly through life with no thought of
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>the shadows in her path, or the silent flight of the raven-winged hours. Berenice !—I call upon her name—Berenice !—and
            from the gray ruins of memory a thousand tumultuous recollections are startled at the sound ! Ah ! vividly is her image
            before me now, as in the early days of her light-heartedness
            and joy ! Oh ! gorgeous yet fantastic beauty ! Oh ! sylph
            amid the shrubberies of Arnheim !—Oh ! Naiad among its
            fountains !—and then—then all is mystery and terror, and a
            tale which should not be told. Disease—a fatal disease—
            fell like the simoom upon her frame, and, even while I gazed
            upon her, the spirit of change swept over her, pervading
            her mind, her habits, and her character, and, in a manner
            the most subtle and terrible, disturbing even the identity of
            her person ! Alas! the destroyer came and went, and the
            victim—where was she ? I knew her not—or knew her no
            longer as Berenice.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Among the numerous train of maladies superinduced by
            that fatal and primary one which effected a revolution of so
            horrible a kind in the moral and physical being of my cousin,
            may be mentioned as the most distressing and obstinate in
            its nature, a species of epilepsy not unfrequently terminating
            in trance itself—trance very nearly resembling positive dissolution, and from which her manner of recovery was, in most
            instances, startlingly abrupt. In the mean time my own disease--for I have been told that I should call it by no other
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>appellation—my own disease, then, grew rapidly upon me,
            and assumed finally a monomaniac character of a novel and
            extraordinary form—hourly and momently gaining vigor—
            and at length obtaining over me the most incomprehensible
            ascendancy. This monomania, if I must so term it, consisted
            in a morbid irritability of those properties of the mind in
            metaphysical science termed the attentive. It is more than
            probable that I am not understood ; but I fear, indeed, that it
            is in no manner possible to convey to the mind of the merely
            general reader, an adequate idea of that nervous intensity of
            interest with which, in my case, the powers of meditation
            (not to speak technically) busied and buried themselves, in
            the contemplation of even the most ordinary objects of the
         </p>
         <p>universe.	
            To muse for long unwearied hours with my attention
            
         </p>
         <p>riveted to some frivolous device on the margin, or in the
            typography of a book; to become absorbed for the better part
            of a summer’s day in a quaint shadow falling aslant upon the
            tapestry, or upon the floor; to lose myself for an entire night
            in watching the steady flame of a lamp, or the embers of a
            fire; to dream away whole days over the perfume of a flower; to repeat monotonously some common word, until the
            sound by dint of frequent repetition, ceased to convey any
            idea whatever to the mind; to lose all sense of motion or
            physical existence, by means of absolute bodily quiescence
            long and obstinately persevered in ;--such were a few of the
            most common and least pernicious vagaries induced by a
            condition of the mental faculties, not, indeed, altogether unparalleled, but certainly bidding defiance to anything like
         </p>
         <p>analysis or explanation
            
         </p>
         <p>     Yet let me not be misapprehended.—The undue, earnest,
            and morbid attention thus excited by objects in their own
            nature frivolous, must not be confounded in character with
            that ruminating propensity common to all mankind, and
            more especially indulged in by persons of ardent imagination.
            It was not even, as might be at first supposed, an extreme
            condition, or exaggeration of such propensity, but primarily
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page218"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>and essentially distinct and different. In the one instance,
            the dreamer, or enthusiast, being interested by an object usually not frivolous, imperceptibly loses sight of this object in
            a wilderness of deductions and suggestions issuing therefrom,
            until, at the conclusion of a day dream often replete with
            luxury, he finds the incitamentum or first cause of his musings entirely vanished and forgotten. In my case the primary object was invariably frivolous, although assuming,
            through the medium of my distempered vision, a refracted
            and unreal importance. Few deductions, if any, were made;
            and those few pertinaciously returning in upon the original
            object as a centre. The meditations were never pleasurable;
            and, at the termination of the reverie, the first cause, so far
            from being out of sight, had attained that supernaturally exaggerated interest which was the prevailing feature of the
            disease. In a word, the powers of mind more particularly
            exercised were, with me, as I have said before, the attentive, and are, with the day-dreamer, the speculative.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>My books, at this epoch, if they did not actually serve to
            irritate the disorder, partook, it will be perceived, largely, in
            their imaginative and inconsequential nature, of the characteristic qualities of the disorder itself. I well remember,
            among others, the treatise of the noble Italian Cœlius Secundus Curio “ de Amplitudine Beati Regni Dei:" St. Austin’
            great work, the “ City of God;" and Tertullian “ de Carne
            Christi," in which the paradoxical sentence “ Mortuus est
            Dei filius ; credibile est quia ineptum est: et sepultus resurrexit; certum est quia impossible est" occupied my undivided
            time, for many weeks of laborious and fruitless investigation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Thus it will appear that, shaken from its balance only by
            trivial things, my reason bore resemblance to that ocean-crag
            spoken of by Ptolemy Hephestion, which steadily resisting
            the attacks of human violence, and the fiercer fury of the
            waters and the winds, trembled only to the touch of the flower called Asphodel. And although, to a careless thinker, it
            might appear a matter beyond doubt, that the alteration produced by her unhappy malady, in the moral condition of Berenice, would afford me many objects for the exercise of
            that intense and abnormal meditation whose nature I have
            been at some trouble in explaining, yet such was not in any
            degree the case. In the lucid intervals of my infirmity, her
            calamity, indeed, gave me pain, and, taking deeply to heart
            that total wreck of her fair and gentle life, I did not fail to
            ponder frequently and bitterly upon the wonder-working
            means by which so strange a revolution had been so suddenly brought to pass. But these reflections partook not of the
            idiosyncrasy of my disease, and where such as would have
            occurred, under similar circumstances, to the ordinary mass
            of mankind. True to its own character, my disorder revelled in the less important but more startling changes wrought
            in the physical frame of Berenice—in the singular and most
            appalling distortion of her personal identity.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>During the brightest days of her unparalleled beauty,
            most surely I had never loved her. In the strange anomaly
            of my existence, feelings with me, had never been of the
            heart, and my passions always were of the mind. Through
            the gray of the early morning—among the trellissed shadows
            of the forest at noon day—and in the silence of my library
            at night, she had flitted by my eyes, and I had seen her—
            not as the living and breathing Berenice, but as the Berenice
            of a dream—not as a being of the earth, earthy, but as the
            abstraction of such a being—not as a thing to admire, but to
            analyze—not as an object of love, but as the theme of the most
            abstruse although desultory speculation. And now—now I
            shuddered in her presence, and grew pale at her approach:
            yet bitterly lamenting her fallen and desolate condition, I
            called to mind that she had loved me long, and, in an evil
            moment, I spoke to her of marriage.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>And at length the period of our nuptials was approaching,
            when, upon an afternoon in the winter of the year,—one of
            those unseasonably warm, calm, and misty days which are
            the nurse of the beautiful Halcyon,*—I sat, (and sat, as I
            thought, alone,) in the inner apartment of the library. But
            uplifting my eyes I saw that Berenice stood before me.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Was it my own excited imagination—or the misty influence of the atmosphere—or the uncertain twilight of the
            chamber—or the gray draperies which fell around her figure
            —that caused in it so vacillating and indistinct an outline ?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>* For as Jove, during the winter season, gives twice seven days of
            warmth, men have called this clement and temperate time the nurse
            of the beautiful Halcyon.—Simonides.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I could not tell. She spoke no word, and I—not for worlds
            could I have uttered a syllable. An icy chill ran through
            my frame ; a sense of insufferable anxiety oppressed me ; a
            consuming curiosity pervaded my soul; and sinking backupon the chair, I remained for some time breathless and motionless, with my eyes riveted upon her person. Alas! its
            emaciation was excessive, and not one vestige of the former
            being, lurked in any single line of the contour. My burning
            glances at length fell upon the face.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The forehead was high, and very pale, and singularly
            placid; and the once jetty hair fell partially over it, and
            overshadowed the hollow temples with innumerable ringlets
            now of a vivid yellow, and jarring discordantly, in their fantastic character, with the reigning melancholy of the countenance. The eyes were lifeless, and lustreless, and seemingly pupil-less, and I shrank involuntarily from their glassy
            stare to the contemplation of the thin and shrunken lips.
            They parted ; and in a smile of peculiar meaning, the teeth
            of the changed Berenice disclosed themselves slowly to my
            view. Would to God that I had never beheld them, or that,
            having done so, I had died !
         </p>
         <p>********
            
         </p>
         <p>The shutting of a door disturbed me, and, looking up, I
            found that my cousin had departed from the chamber. But
            from the disordered chamber of my brain, had not, alas! departed, and would not be driven away, the white and ghastly spectrum of the teeth. Not a speck on their surface—
            not a shade on their enamel—not an indenture in their edges
            —but what that brief period of her smile had sufficed to
            brand in upon my memory. I saw them now even more unequivocally than I beheld them then. The teeth !—the
            teeth!—they were here, and there, and every where, and
            visibly and palpably before me; long,narrow, and excessively white, with the pale lips writhing about them, as in the
            very moment of their first terrible development. Then came
            the full fury of my monomania, and I struggled in vain against
            its strange and irresistible influence. In the multiplied objects of the external world I had no thoughts but for the
            teeth. For these I longed with a phrenzied desire. All
            other matters and all different interests became absorbed in
            their single contemplation. Thev—they alone were present
            to the mental eye, and they, in their sole individuality, became the essence of my mental life. I held them in every
            light. I turned them in every altitude. I surveyed their
            characteristics. I dwelt upon their peculiarities. I pondered upon their conformation. I roused upon the alteration in
            their nature. I shuddered as I assigned to them in imagination a sensitive and sentient power, and even when unassisted by the lips, a capability of moral expression. Of Mad’selle Salle it has been well said, “ que tous ses pas etaient des
            sentiments," and of Berenice I more seriously believed que
            tous ses dents elaientides idées. Des idées!—ah here was
            the idiotic thought that destroyed me! Des idées!— ah
            therefore it was that I coveted them so madly ! I felt that
            their possession could alone ever restore me to peace, in giving me back to reason.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>And the evening closed in upon me thus—and then the
            darkness came, and tarried, and went—and the day again
            dawned—and the mists of a second night were now gathering around—and still I sat motionless in that solitary room,
            and still I sat buried in meditation, and still the phantasma
            of the teeth maintained its terrible ascendancy as, with the
            most vivid and hideous distinctness, it floated about amid the
            changing lights and shadows of the chamber. At length
            there broke in upon my dreams a cry as of horror and dismay ; and thereunto, after a pause, succeeded the sound of
            troubled voices, intermingled with many low moanings of
            sorrow, or of pain. I arose from my seat, and, throwing
            open one of the doors of the library, saw standing out in the
            antechamber a servant maiden, all in tears, who told me that
            Berenice was—no more. She had been seized with epilepsy
            in the early morning, and now, at the closing in of the night,
            the grave was ready for its tenant, and all the preparations
            for the burial were completed.
         </p>
         <p>********
            
         </p>
         <p>I found myself sitting in the library, and again sitting
            there alone. It seemed that I had newly awakened from a
            confused and exciting dream. I knew that it was now midnight, and I was well aware that since the setting of the sun
            Berenice had been interred. But of that dreary period which
            intervened I had no positive—at least no definite comprehen-
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page219"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>sion. Yet its memory was replete with horror—horror more
            horrible from being vague, and terror more terrible from ambiguity. It was a fearful page in the record of my existence,
            written all over with dim, and hideous, and unintelligible
            recollections. I strived to decypher them, but in vain; while
            ever and anon, like the spirit of a departed sound, the shrill
            and piercing shriek of a female voice seemed to be ringing
            in my ears. I had done a deed—what was it ? I asked myself the question aloud, and the whispering echoes of the
            chamber answered me, “ what was it ?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>On the table beside me burned a lamp, and near it lay a
            little box. It was of no remarkable character, and I had
            seen it frequently before, for it was the property of the family
            physician ; but how came it there, upon my table, and why did
            1 shudder in regarding it ? These things were in no manner
            to be accounted for, and my eyes at length dropped to the
            open pages of a hook, and to a sentence underscored therein.
            The words were the singular but simple ones of the poet
            Ebn Zaiat. “ Dicebant mihi sodales si sepulchrum amicae
            visitarem, curas meas aliquantulum fore levatas." Why then,
            as I perused them, did the hairs of my head erect themselves
            on end, and the blood of my body become congealed within
            my veins ?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There came a light tap at the library door, and pale as the
            tenant of a tomb, a menial entered upon tiptoe. His looks
            were wild with terror, and he spoke to me in a voice tremulous, husky, and very low. What said he ?—some broken
            sentences I heard. He told of a wild cry disturbing the silence of the night—of the gathering together of the household—of a search in the direction of the sound ;—and then
            his tones grew thrillingly distinct as he whispered me of a
            violated grave—of a disfigured body enshrouded, yet still
            breathing, still palpitating, still alive !
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>He pointed to my garments ;—they were muddy and clotted with gore. I spoke not, and he took me gently by the
            hand ;—it was indented with the impress of human nails.
            He directed my attention to some object against the wall;—
            I looked at it for some minutes;—it was a spade. With a
            shriek I bounded to the table, and grasped the box that lay
            upon it. But I could not force it open ; and in my tremor it
            slipped from my hands, and fell heavily, and burst into
            pieces ; and from it, with a rattling sound, there rolled out
            some instruments of dental surgery, intermingled with thirtytwo small, white and ivory-looking substances that were
            scattered to and fro about the floor.
         </p>
         <p>EDGAR A. POE.
            
         </p>
         <p>Prospects of the Drama.—Mrs. Mowatt's Comedy.—So
            deeply have we felt interested in the question of Fashion’s
            success or failure, that we have been to see it every night
            since its first production; making careful note of its merits
            and defects as they were more and more distinctly developed in the gradually perfected representation of the play.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We are enabled, however, to say but little either in contradiction or in amplification of our last week’s remarks —
            which were based it will be remembered, upon the original
            MS. of the fair authoress, and upon the slightly modified
            performance of the first night. In what we then said we
            made all reasonable allowances for inadvertences at the
            outset—lapses of memory in the actors—embarrassments in
            scene-shifting—in a word for general hesitation and want of
            finish. The comedy now, however, must be understood as
            having all its capabilities fairly brought out, and the result
            of the perfect work is before us.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In one respect, perhaps, we have done Mrs. Mowatt unintentional injustice. We are not quite sure, upon reflection,
            that her entire thesis is not an original one. We can call to
            mind no drama, just now, in which the design can be properly stated as the satirizing of fashion as fashion. Fashionable follies, indeed, as a class of folly in general, have been
            frequently made the subject of dramatic ridicule—but the
            distinction is obvious—although certainly too nice a one to
            be of any practical avail to the authoress of the new comedy.
            Abstractly we may admit some pretension to originality
            of plan—but, in the representation, this shadow of originality
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>vanishes. We cannot, if we would, separate the dramatis
            personae from the moral they illustrate ; and the characters
            overpower the moral.	We see before us only personages
         </p>
         <p>with whom we have been familiar time out of mind:_______when
            
         </p>
         <p>we look at Mrs. Tiffany, for example, and hear her speak,
            we think of Mrs. Malaprop in spite of ourselves, and in vain
            endeavour to think of anything else. The whole conduct
            and language of the comedy, too, have about them the unmistakeable flavor of the green-room. We doubt if a single
            point either in the one or the other, is not a household thing
            with every play-goer. Not a joke is any less old than the
            hills—but this conventionality is more markedly noticeable
            in the sentiments, so called. When, for instance, Gertrude
            in quitting the stage, is made to say, “if she fail in a certain
            scheme she will be the first woman who was ever at a loss
            for a stratagem,” we are affected with a really painful sense
            of the antique. Such things are only to be ranked with the
            stage “ properties,” and are inexpressibly wearisome and distasteful to every one who hears them. And that they are
            sure to elicit what appears to be applause, demonstrates exactly nothing at all. People at these points put their hands
            together, and strike their canes against the floor for the reason that they feel these actions to be required of them as a
            matter of course, and that it would be ill-breeding not to
            comply with the requisition. All the talk put into the mouth
            of Mr. Truman, too, about “when honesty shall be found
            among lawyers, patriotism among statesmen,” etc. etc. must
            be included in the same category. The error of the dramatist lies in not estimating at its true value the absolutely certain “ approbation” of the audience in such cases—an approbation which is as pure a conventionality as are the “ sentiments” themselves. In general it may be boldly asserted
            that the clapping of hands and the rattling of canes are no
            tokens of the success of any play—such success as the dramatist should desire:—let him watch the countenances of
            his audience, and remodel his points by these. Better still—
            let him “ look into his own heart and write”—again better
            still (if he have the capacity) let him work out his purposes
            a priori from the infallible principles of a Natural Art.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We are delighted to find, in the reception of Mrs. Mowatt’s comedy, the clearest indications of a revival of the
            American drama—that is to say of an earnest disposition to
            see it revived. That the drama, in general, can go down,
            is the most untenable of all untenable ideas. Dramatic art
            is, or should be, a concentralization of all that which is entitled to the appellation of Art. When sculpture shall fail,
            and painting shall fail, and poetry, and music;—when men
            shall no longer take pleasure in eloquence, and in grace of
            motion, and in the beauty of woman, and in truthful representations of character, and in the consciousness of sympathy
            in their enjoyment of each and all, then and not till then,
            may we look for that to sink into insignificance, which, and
            which alone, affords opportunity for the conglomeration of
            these infinite and imperishable sources of delight.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There is not the least danger, then, that the drama shall
            fail. By the spirit of imitation evolved from its own nature
            and to a certain extent an inevitable consequence of it, it has
            been kept absolutely stationary for a hundred years, while its
            sister arts have rapidly flitted by and left it out of sight.
            Each progressive step of every other art seems to drive back
            the drama to the exact extent of that step-just as, physically the objects by the way-side seem to be receding from
            the traveller in a coach. And the practical effect, in both
            cases is equivalent :-but yet, in fact, the drama has not receded: on the contrary it has very slightly advanced in one or
            two of the plays of Sir Edward Lytton Bulwer. The appa-
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page220"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>rent recession or degradation, however, will, in the end,
            work out its own glorious recompense. The extent—the
            excess of the seeming declension will put the right intellects
            upon the serious analysis of its causes. The first noticeable
            result of this analysis will be a sudden indisposition on the
            part of all thinking men to commit themselves any farther
            in the attempt to keep up the present mad—road because
            false—enthusiasm about “ Shakspeare and the musical glasses.” Quite willing, of course, to give this indisputably great
            man the fullest credit for what he has done—we shall begin
            to ask our own understandings why it is that there is so
            very—very much which he has utterly failed to accomplish.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>When we arrive at this epoch, we are safe. The next
            step may be the electrification of all mankind by the representation of a play that may be neither tragedy, comedy,
            farce, opera, pantomime, melodrama, or spectacle, as we
            now comprehend these terms, but which may retain some
            portion of the idiosyncratic excellences of each, while it introduces a new class of excellence as yet unnamed because
            as yet undreamed-of in the world. As an absolutely necessary condition of its existence this play may usher in a thorough remodification of the theatrical physique.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This step being fairly taken, the drama will be at once side
            by side with the more definitive and less comprehensive arts
            which have outstripped it by a century :—and now not merely
            will it outstrip them in turn, but devour them altogether.
            The drama will be all in all.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We cannot conclude these random observations without
            again recurring to the effective manner in which “ Fashion”
            has been brought forward at the Park. Whatever the management and an excellent company could do for the comedy,
            has been done. Many obvious improvements have been adopted since the first representation, and a very becoming deference has been manifested, on the part of the fair authoress
            and of Mr. Simpson, to every thing wearing the aspect of
            public opinion—in especial to every reasonable hint from the
            press. We arc proud, indeed, to find that many even of our
            own ill-considered suggestions, have received an attention
            which was scarcely their due.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In “Fashion” nearly all the Park company have won new
            laurels. Mr. Chippendale did wonders. Mr. Crisp was, perhaps, a little too gentlemanly in the Count—he has subdued
            the part, we think, a trifle too much:—there is a true grace
            of manner of which he finds it difficult to divest himself, and
            which occasionally interferes with his conceptions. Miss
            Ellis did for Gertrude all that any mortal had a right to expect. Millinette could scarcely have been better represented.
            Mrs. Knight as Prudence is exceedingly comic. Mr. and Mrs.
            Barry do invariably well—and of Mr. Fisher we forgot say
            in our last paper that he was one of the strongest points of
            the play. As for Miss Horne—it is but rank heresy to imagine that there could be any difference of opinion respecting
            her. She sets at naught all criticism in winning all hearts.
            There is about her lovely countenance a radiant earnestness
            of expression which is sure to play a Circean trick with the
            judgment of every person who beholds it.
         </p>
         <p>THE MAGAZINES.
            
         </p>
         <p>Graham’s Magazine.—The April number of “ Graham” has in its
            Table of Contents some very well known names—those of Mrs. Osgood, for example, Mrs. Sigourney, Mrs. Embury, Mrs. Seba Smith,
            “ Fanny Forrester,” Grund, Landor,Robert Motris, and several others.
            Mrs. Osgood contributes the best poem she has yet written—a more
            exquisitely graceful thing (Grace is Mrs. Osgood’s queendom in which
            she reigns triumphant) we have rarely if ever seen. Mr. Robert Morris, also, has a sweet poem of great pathos, called “ The Toilers.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The best prose papers, we think, are those of Grund and Landor—although, in general, the contributions are either good in themselves, or
            meritorious in their adaptation to the tone and purpose of the Magazine. With a less objectionable form, “ Graham’s Magazine” would
            have long ago taken a station with the most elevated and influential
            journals.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The most interesting feature in this number, to merely literary people, is the Critical Biography of General Morris, whose worst fault is
            that he has a habit of making too many and too devoted friends, who
            now and then do him injury by permitting their personal feelings to
            appear above the current of their critical opinion. We really believe
            that but for this fault in the General he would have attained even a
            higher rank in the literary world than he actually possesses. The
            dogged determination to praise him at all hazards will, for example,
            in this very Biography induce very many persons to perpetrate injustice not against the biographer (whom we should not care to see
            abused) but against the poet himself. Moreover the nature of that
            merit which is peculiarly General Morris’ own, has a tendency to increase the evil effect on which we comment—for this merit is that of
            rich and vigorous simplicity—a quality of all others in the world the
            least likely to be estimated at its full value. The world are too apt
            to think the critic guilty of exaggeration in praising with enthusiasm
            that which (however effective) appears to be easy of execution ;—and
            simplicity has always this air. Yet of one thousand persons who
            should attempt to compose anything in the manner of the following
            truly admirable stanzas, nine hundred and ninety-nine would fail miserably in the undertaking.
         </p>
         <p>THE STAR OF LOVE.
            The star of love now shines above,
            
         </p>
         <p>Cool zephyrs crisp the sea ;
            Among the leaves the wind-harp weaves
            Its serenade for thee.
         </p>
         <p>The star, the breeze, the wave, the trees,
            Their minstrelsy unite,
            But all are drear till thou appear
            To decorate the night.
            The tight of noon streams from the moon,
            Though with a milder ray ;
            O’er hill and grove, like woman’s love,
            It cheers us on the way.
            Thus all that’s bright, the moon, the night,
            The heavens, the earth, the sea,
            Exert their powers to bless the hours
            We dedicate to thee.
            
         </p>
         <p>We regard this little song—“ Where Hudson’s Wave”—“ Woodman spare that Tree”—and “ Near the Lake where droops the Willow”, as undeniably four of the truest and sweetest poems (independently of their idiosyncratic merit as songs) ever published in America, and we are delighted to know that both the intellect and the popular sentiment of the country sustain us in the opinion.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The picture of the General is wretched in every respect except as a
            mechanical engraving. As a drawing it is unworthy of a school-boy
            —who ever saw feet such as these ?—and the willow is of a species
            unknown to Gods, men, and columns. As a composition it is detestable—stiff and ill arranged. As a portrait it is a falsehood—conveying
            not even the most remote idea of the man. This face is impassive—
            with no expression beyond the absence of all—that of the General is
            beaming with sensibility.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The other engravings of the number are admirable indeed—the
            “ View of Tallulah Falls” is especially so, and has seldom been excelled.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Lady’s Book.—There is an indication of durability about the
            Lady's Book which is not to be mistaken—an air of quietude—of simplicity—and therefore of strength. Mr. Godey was the pioneer in
            this species of literature, and his work has the vigor which is always
            inseparable from originality of any kind. We do not mean to say, and
            we do not suppose that Mr. Godey means to assert, that the “ Lady’s
            Book” belongs to a high order of literature, but of its kind it is as
            nearly perfect as can well be. It addresses itself principally to ladies,
            and addresses them as ladies wish to be addressed. The secret of its
            wonderful, because long-continued success, is tact.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The April number is not unusually good, but is a fair specimen of
            the general conduct of the Magazine. Miss Leslie continues the
            “ Bloxams and Mayfields;" Mrs. Hale has “ The Gold Pen”—a poem;
            Mrs. Embury contributes “Intimate Friends;” Mrs. Mowatt (we
            think) furnishes “ The Mercenary Marriage,” and also " A Sketch of
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page221"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>Joseph Buonaparte”—both very excellent magazine articles. The
            “ Intercepted Letter” by Mrs. Seba Smith, is a well written plate illustration. Miss Gould has a brief poem of much force and originality
            of expression—and there is not a bad paper in the number: which we
            fancy is saying a very great deal. The most valuable contribution is
            from Grand, who writes from Antwerp an amusing letter chiefly of
            theatrical gossip.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There are three engravings, inclusive of a colored fashion-plate. The
            best of them is the first—The Intercepted Letter, done by Dick, from a
            drawing by Miss Corbould. We have had an opportunity of seeing some
            eighteen or twenty proof impressions from plates prepared by Mr.
            Godey for his forth-coming numbers, and can assure our readers (our
            fair ones especially,) that many of these engravings are truly excellent
            —fully equal to any in our best annuals. This is what all have a
            right to expect—good pictures, or none.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Monthly Rose.—A periodical sustained by the present and
            former members of the Albany Female Academy. Albany, S. H. Pease
            and W. C. Little. We have received the April number of this magazine. It is a tastefully arranged and well printed journal of no little
            literary merit.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Ladies’ Garland, and Cabinet of the Daughters or Temperance.—This is a weekly Journal, whose purpose is explained in
            the title. The first number, as yet, is the only one issued, and it promises well. The publishers are Messrs. Piercy &amp; Reed, New York.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Knickerbocker for April contains several good articles, two
            or three very good ones, and one very good one. We will let the
            readers of the magazine find them out for themselves. We do not
            remember that we ever looked at the editor’s table without finding
            something to laugh at; and very rarely any thing to pish at. Mr. C,
            should not sneer at our “ Operative,” but if he can gainsay the technical objections which were pointed out against the mouldings in the
            interior of Trinity Church, he is heartily welcome. The height of the
            steeple has very little bearing on the imperfect drawings and decorations. If the strictures of our “ Operative” had not been “ highly tech,
            nical,” they would have been highly nonsensical. That the steeple is
            highly beautiful, no one will deny, but it may contain blemishes notwithstanding, which an unprofessional eye may not be able to distinguish.	____________
         </p>
         <p>MAGNIFICENT BOOKS.
            
         </p>
         <p>Two or three copies of the “Travels in the Interior of
            North America, by Maximilian Prince of Wied,” have been received
            by our foreign-book-sellers. It is one of the most superbly illustrated
            volumes of modern times. The letter-press is copiously illustrated
            by fine wood cuts, but the real illustrations consist of a portfolio of
            eighty-one colored plates, of imperial folio size. The engravings are
            executed in line, and colored, from pictures by M. Bodmer, an accomplished artist who travelled in company with the Prince. This great
            work was published simultaneously in England, France and Germany.
            The English plates are said to be superior in coloring to the others,
            and are sold at a less price.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Prince Maximilian landed in Boston in July, 1832, and after spending
            few days in that city he proceeded west, stopping a short time in
            New York and Philadelphia, and making a prolonged visit to the
            German-Moravian settlement at Bethlehem in Pennsylvania, where
            M. Bodmer began to exercise his pencil. The greater part of the
            plates are representations of Indian life; they have all the truthfulness
            of the sketches by Mr. Catlin, but in a style of art greatly superior to
            his drawings. Many of the landscapes are beautiful pictures, which
            have the appearance of original water-color paintings. The subscription price of the work in Paris was 850 frances; but a great many copies must have been sold to defray the cost of publication even at
            that price.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The travels of the Prince would doubtless be much belter known,
            had they been published in a less magnificent manner. It must be
            gratifying to an author to sec his book elegantly illustrated, but it
            would be better for his reputation that it should be published without
            pictures, than to have them of so high a character as to overshadow
            his book altogether. Those who are able to purchase works like this
            of Prince Maximilian’s are the kind of people who do the least to give
            currency to an author’s name. One of the plates gives a full-length
            portrait of the Prince, whose appearance corresponds very much with
            the idea which we conceived of him from reading his travels. He is,
            apparently, a good-natured gentleman of about forty-five years, with
            an honest Dutch face, light hair, broad shoulders, and five feet in sta-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>ture. He wears a shooting jacket, has a gun in his hand, a cap on
            his head, and gold-mounted spectacles on his nose. Surrounded by
            wild-looking Indians, as he is represented, the Prince has a remarkably tame but good-fellow look.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>His stay in New York was too brief to allow him to make many
            comments upon our city: but he did not fail to notice that "it has
            one remarkably fine street called Broadway, which has an uninterrupted line of shops but little inferior to those of London or Paris.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Bartlett &amp; Welford have a copy or two of Catlin’s Indian
            Portfolio, consisting of 25 colored lithographed plates, in the highest
            style of art. As portraits they are, perhaps, more valuable than the
            drawings of Mr. Bodmer which accompany the travels of Prince Maximilian, but they cannot be ranked together as artistic productions.
            One of the most touching and apparently most truthful of the sketches, although from the nature of the subject it must be a purely imaginative painting, is the representation of a wounded buffalo attacked
            by a herd of white wolves. The time is not very distant when these
            illustrated works will possess a deeper interest than they do at present—when they will be almost the only vestiges left of the original
            inhabitants of our soil. An English magazine, in noticing Mr. Catlin’s Portfolio, expresses a fear that mankind will reward him with
            little more than empty praise for his labors. But we trust that he
            will receive from his own countrymen something more than empty
            praise, though as yet he has had from them but a small quantity of
            even that easily bestowed commodity.
         </p>
         <p>THE CONCERT ROOM.
            
         </p>
         <p>Signor Rapetti’s Concert.—This gentleman’s annual concert
            came off at Palmo’s theatre on Saturday evening last. Signora Pico,
            Madame Otto, Signor Antognini, Sanquirico and De Begnis sang,
            Md’lle Desjardines danced, and the Beneficiare played.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It would be useless to go through the whole programme, as we
            have noticed most of the pieces before, this season. Pico and Sanquirico sang the duette from Elisor d’Amore most admirably. De
            Begnis sang better than we ever heard him. His style was unexceptionable, and he was most justly and warmly applauded.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have again the unpleasant duty of condemning the performance of Madame Otto. The piece chosen by her in the second act,
            was Zerlina’s song from Fra Diavolo, while preparing to retire to rest.
            The scene was duly arranged, and Madame Otto in costume, introduced the song by a few words. All the action of the scene was gone
            through, and it ended by the lady falling upon her knees and singing
            the prayer to the virgin, at which point the curtain fell. But long before this there was a general move throughout the house—ladies bonneting and shawling and hurrying from their places, so absurd was
            the whole affair. The song is certainly beautiful and effective, taken
            in connection with the incident of the scene, but given alone it is trifling and ineffective in the extreme. Added to which Madame Otto’s
            peculiar style of singing and awkward action were by no means calculated to increase its importance. There was no applause at the conelusion although much mirth was evinced by the audience at this very
            novel exhibition.
         </p>
         <p>The house was very thinly attended.
            MR. COLEMAN’S PATENT DISPUTED.
            
         </p>
         <p>There has been so much fuss made about the Æolian Attachment,
            said to be invented by Mr. Coleman, that we are sure the public will
            feel an interest in all that relates to it. We have received many com.
            munications respecting this invention, in which we are informed that
            there are several instruments in this city, in Philadelphia, and in
            Baltimore, which have had attachments of the same description for
            many years. We are waiting replies to some questions, before stating
            the facts to the public ; aud we beg all those who are acquainted with
            the merits of the question to assist us with their knowledge.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the mean time we publish the following statement from the Savannah Republican of March 15. It will be perceived that a Mr.
            Coburn claims priority of invention, and that his Euphonon is a far
            more perfect instrument than the Æolian Attachment. This question
            is one of deep interest to those who have invested money in purchasing the patent right. We of course gave no credence to the exaggerated and ridiculous reports relative to the immense sums obtained
            by Mr. Coleman for his right, both here and in Europe. They are in
            every way, we believe, newspaper puffs, put forth with the sole object of deception. The mark has, however, been overshot, and the
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page222"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>people are now scarcely inclined to credit even the simple truth. We
            were told many months since that Mr. Coleman was to be paid a certain proportion upon every instrument sold, and under such an arrangement we doubt very much if he has received the amount in
            cents which he is said to have received in dollars.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We shall resume this subject as soon as we are prepared to do so,
            and shall for the present leave the Savannah Republican to open the
            case.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ As early as 1829, Mr. Moses Coburn, a professor of music, a gentleman of much mechanical ingenuity, and a resident of Savannah,
            invented an instrument on the precise principle of Coleman’s Æolian
            Attachment, which he called the Euphonon. During that and the following years, he constructed several instruments on the same principle, though differing in form, size and elegance of finish. One of
            these instruments is now in this city. We have examined it minutely,
            and are fully of the opinion that while the general principle is the
            same as Coleman's, the tone is decidedly superior. Indeed we feel
            assured that it supplies every defect (and there are not a few) in Colman’s invention. Mr. Coburn’s instrument is strictly Æolian—Coleman’s is not.—Mr. Coburn’s, even when filled with air to its utmost
            tension, gives all the softness and swell of the real Æolian sound—in
            this Coleman’s instrument entirely fails, for when subjected to the
            full force it has only the harsh and monotonous tones of the organ.
            Early in the month of November, 1829, Mr. Coburn exhibited his invention to crowded audiences in Savannah, of which fuel many persons now living can testify. In the Savannah Georgian, of November
            4th 1829, we find a flattering notice of the exhibition. That paper,
            after speaking in terms ot praise of the instrument, says: “ With the
            principle of the invention we do not profess to be acquainted. The
            sound, however, is produced by the action of wind through a double
            bellows worked by the alternate motion of the feet; the notes being
            produced by keys struck or pressed by the fingers, as in the piano.”
                 "So much for Mr. Coburn’s invention of the Æolian attachment,
            which is the basis of Coleman’s instrument. We come now to its
            application to the piano forte. This was also made by our fellow citizen in 1832, with complete success, and in such a manner that each
            could be played separately or both together. By a peculiarity in
            the construction and management of the bellows, the most delicate
            expression could be given to the notes. The crescendo, diminuendo,
            sforzando, and every variety of effect, from the softest breathing
            notes of the Æolian harp to the full swell of the diapason, could be
            given at will, while the instrument combined many other advantages
            over Coleman’s, which we do not deem advisable to detail at present. The works of this instrument are still in the possession of Mr.
            Coburn to attest the truth of this statement, which can also be substantiated by many living witnesses.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>"Mr. C. did not, for reasons with which the public has no concern,
            apply at the time for a patent. Indeed be is a most unassuming gentleman, who was probably not fully aware of the magnitude of his
            invention, or its identity with Coleman’s, until recently meeting with
            a gentleman who had seen both instruments, and who significantly
            remarked, that Coleman was making a fortune out of his (Mr. Coburn’s) old invention of 1832 !! This led to an investigation, which
            has already gone far to prove the identity of the inventions in more
            tenses than one. Had application been made in 1832, the skill and genius of our fellow citizen, might have been rewarded as have been
            those of Coleman since. However, the time has not yet passed, and
            we are happy to know that this invention and the proofs relative
            thereto, will be submitted to the Commissioner of Patents before the
            expiration of the two years, which are necessary to elapse before the
            original inventor is debarred the advantages gained by a previous patentee. We do not wish to see Mr. Coleman’s patent annulled unless
            it be proved that he is a Copyist; but we do wish to see Mr. Coburn placed on a perfect equality with him ; because we feel assured
            that there is no comparison between the inventions in detail, though
            they are identical in principle.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>" We are happy to know that Mr. Coburn has nearly completed a
            specimen of his invention, and applied it to one of Chickering’s fine
            pianos, with which it is his intention to leave for Washington in a few
            days, to lay the whole matter before the proper authorities. We
            heartily wish him that success which his modesty and his merit so
            richly deserve.”
         </p>
         <p>IMPORTANT ADDITION TO THE PIANO-FORTE.
            MR. walker’s harmonic attachment.
            
         </p>
         <p>The theory of Harmonics is as old as the hills, therefore no merit
            is claimed upon the score of originality. The beautiful effects developed in the production of harmonies have also been well known for
            thousands of years, consequently no claim is made to discovery. Accident will frequently lead to the discovery of an important action in
            nature, but talent, ingenuity, and perseverance are required in a high
            degree to apply such action to the familiar uses of our every day life.
            Mr. Walker, in applying his machinery to the piano forte, has undoubtedly been a follower of other men's thoughts. The idea of producing harmonic tones upon that instrument is by no means of recent
            date, and very many practical men have tried it, but not one of them
            has been fortunate enough to succeed sufficiently well to become impressed with the importance of the subject.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Walker has succeeded, and his success has had the effect of
            calling forth claimants to the invention—men who have tried and
            failed, now wish to claim the honor of the thought. The manifest ab-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>absurdity of this is self-evident. All charges of piracy should be treated with the contempt they merit, unless they contain statements of
            facts, developing the principle of construction and the method of application of the thing said to be pirated ; then if the identities are satisfactorily proved, they must of course be defended upon the principle
            of Outis—that there is no such thing as plagiarism. Mr. Loud of
            Philadelphia comes out boldly and lays claim to Mr. Walker’s invention. But before we can place implicit reliance upon his assertions, he
            must bring forth proofs to support his case ; let him prove identities
            But even if he can do this, we fear that he will reap no further reward
            than the honor of the first thought, for the law can hardly be expected
            to protect the rights of one who has himself voluntarily resigned them ;
            for Mr. Loud in his letter, distinctly states, that he ‘tried the experiment himself in 1833—that it was successful, but that it was found to
            be of no value—for, although, in the hands of a fine extempore player
            it might be made use of, yet to the ordinary performer it was entirely
            useless.” This, to say the least, is candid in the extreme, and proves
            all that Mr. Walker desires; their inventions must, indeed, have been
            entirely dissimilar, for while the one is declared by the inventor to be
            entirely useless, the other is acknowledged on all hands to be a great
            acquisition to the piano, and capable of being used effectually by a performer of very moderate power—while in the hands of a master it becomes a means of positive fascination. We have but little acquaintance with either party, but in order to do equal justice, we will gladly
            publish such statements as shall set the matter fairly before the
            public.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Of Mr. Walker's Harmonic Attachment we shall speak more fully
            in our next number. That it will give many beautiful effects to, and
            add largely to the capabilities of the instrument, we assure our readers, and advise them to give their earliest attention to the subject.
         </p>
         <p>STODART &amp; DUNHAM'S PIANO-FORTE MANUUFACTORY.
            
         </p>
         <p>We resume this subject from last week. We then conducted our
            readers over the lumber yard to the veneer room and to the drying room.
            Before proceeding farther, we may as well correct an error in our
            statement of last week, which arose from our unassisted guessing at
            the value of an article of which we know but little, save in its polished
            state. The value of the stock of veneers in the factory of Messrs.
            Stodart A Dunham, instead of being some thousand and odd dollars,
            is estimated at nearly four times that amount.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Case Room. After the wood has been thoroughly seasoned and
            dried, it is sent to the Case Room. It will of course be understood,
            that every department of this interesting manufacture is going on simultaneously, but we prefer tracing it in its regular progress from the
            beginning to the finishing. The mere shell without the bottom is
            formed of heavy und well-seasoned material. The exquisite and minute workmanship required to form the round corners, is worthy of
            particular attention. It is then veneered and glued on to the bottom,
            and to insure its perfect adhesion, as soon as it is glued it is surrounded by screws of immense power, and thus held in many vices until
            it is thoroughly dry and set. The bottom is several inches in thickness, and formed of three pieces. In order to render it somewhat sonorous, it is made hollow. The upper and lower parts are each formed
            of three pieces laid at angles with the case, to prevent yielding, and
            the interior is formed of cross-bars laid at intervals crosswise, in a line
            with the vibration of the strings. These undergo the same operation
            of screwing, to insure unyielding firmness. The blocks are then placed
            in the interior, such as the angle block, the lower back block, the braces, the rest-pin block, &amp;c., &amp;c., all of which go through the operation of a powerful screwing. Even these unseen portions of the instruments are finished up with the most surprising care.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Probably the cabinet work of this factory has never been excelled
            in this country. The veneers are laid on with such a nicety that it is
            impossible to tell where the one begins or the other ends. After all the
            blocks, which constitute the strength of the instrument, have been laid
            in the interior with mathematical precision in regard to the equal resistance of every part, it is certain that no pull could be brought to
            bear upon it of sufficient power to cause the frame to start the breadth
            of even a hair. The case is then sent up stairs into the
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Varnishing Room. Here the veneers receive their first coat of varnish, and the colors of the wood begin to show. Coat after coat is
            then laid on, until the wood is so saturated that the varnish rises above
            the level. The wood, after each separate coat, is either dried in
            the drying room, or if the wood required to be darkened, In the full
            power of the sun. When the wood has been dried al ter the last coat,
            an instrument is used with which the varnish is scraped off to a level
            with the wood. It is then capable of receiving the highest degree of
            polish, which is imparted solely by the friction of the palm of the
            hand. The labor of this operation, as may be imagined, is immense.
         </p>
         <p>(To be Continued.)
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page22"></div>
            MISCELLANY.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Governor’s room in the City-Hall, has recently been
            painted and newly carpeted, and it will soon be decorated with two
            new portraits, a full length of Governor Bouck, and a half-length of
            Mayor Harper. We have not heard the name of the artist who is to
            paint the Governor, but we trust that some New York artist will be selected by the city authorities, that we may be saved from a repetition
            of the disgraceful manœvering which was practised in the affair of Governor Seward’s portrait. It has been the custom for the city to refer the
            choice of an artist to the Governor himself, when he has been requested
            to sit, or stand for his portrait. But Governor Seward, from some inscrutable motives, declined making a selection, and referred the matter back to the Common Council. The city authorities refused to
            appoint an artist, and again requested the Governor to select one.
            The Governor was still unwilling, and appointed a committee of
            five of his political friends in this city, to whom he entrusted
            the privilege of appointing a painter to do his portrait. A new
            difficulty sprung up with the committee, for instead of the five gentlemen not being able to make a selection, each one had his favorite artist. They took a room at the Astor House, the New York Hotel
            not being in existence at that time, and sent circulars to the artists of
            their acquaintance, requesting them to send specimens of their work
            to the committee-room. This was very much in the manner of the
            pedant who exhibited a brick as a specimen of his house. How many
            specimen-bricks were sent to the committee we have never heard, but
            they were unable to agree upon an artist, and at last they concluded
            to employ five, each member of the committee making his own selection. Each artist so nominated, was to paint a portrait of the Governor,
            and the choice of one, to be handed down to posterity, was to be decided by some sort of hocus-pocus, the particulars of which we have
            forgotten. Only two of the artists named, Inman and Harding, consented to paint the Governor on such conditions. When the portraits
            were done, the same difficulties of choice existed that had so bothered
            the committee before; they paid both artists for their work, and tossed up a copper to decide which one should be placed in the City Hall.
            Whether the copper fell “ head’s up or tail’s up,” we are not precisely
            informed, but the choice fell upon Inman’s picture, and we have now
            the full-length portrait of a country-attorney-looking-personage, standing in a highly-satisfiedwith-himself position, with a glove in his hand,
            as though he were just starting for a village tea-party, to be passed
            down, or up, to future generations as a likeness of one of the Govern
            ors of the Empire State for two terms. We fear that our descendants
            will have but an indifferent opinion of their ancestors, when they
            come to see the representations of the best specimens of humanity
            which we could find among us for our governors, as represented on
            the canvasses which are labelled " Seward” and “ Van Buren,” in the
            City Hall. Fortunately, however, the substantial humanly looking
            form of Governor Marcy comes between these dignitaries, to rescue
            our age from an imputation of petitism.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The only person to blame in the matter of Governor Seward’s portrait, was the governor himself. He should have designated an artist
            among the painters of New York, to paint his portrait. If he had no
            preference, he should have taken the names of four or five of the most
            eminent, and drawn one of them by lot. But to avoid such difficulties
            in getting an artist to paint our future governors, we trust that the
            Corporation will establish a good precedent by selecting an artist
            themselves. We can see no possible objection to their doing so.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A New Name for the Nation.—The committee appointed
            by the New York Historical Society, consisting of David Dudley Field,
            Henry R. Schoolcraft, and Charles Fenno Hoffman, "upon the subject of the irrelevant appellation at present used for the country,”
            made their report on Tuesday evening last, in which they recommend,
            with many sound arguments, that “ Allgania” be adopted by the
            nation as its distinctive name hereafter. The subject is of greater
            importance than our people generally think it to be, and we hope
            that the report of the committee will meet with the consideration
            which the subject and the gentlemen making it are entitled to.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The London papers are paying compliments to the " Hon,
            John Harper, Mayor of New York,” who sent "a large deal case” to
            the Lord Mayor of London, ‘‘containing an arm-chair made in that
            city by order of its literary inhabitants to be presented to Miss Jane
            Porter, the English Authoress.” Doubtless the “ Hon. John Harper"
            and the “ literary inhabitants” of New York, will be sufficiently rewarded for the cost of the " Arm-Chair” by seeing themselves noticed in this distinguished manner in a London paper.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. I. T. Hart, (of Lexington, Ky.) who won so much
            deputation by his bust of General Jackson, has nearly completed one of
            Mr. Clay, which the friends of the latter pronounce of eery great excellence. Mr. Hart, in mechanical skill, is the equal of the late Mr.
            Clevinger, and perhaps surpasses him in his sense of the ideal.
         </p>
         <p>F RILEY &amp; CO., No. 297 Broadway, (between
            
         </p>
         <p> Reade and Duane street-*,) New York, Publishers ot Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition to their
            own catalogue, (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep on hand
            the publications of all the principal Music houses. They are erecting a large
            Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes of a superior quality,
            will be constantly kept on hand.
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES,
            THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their
            
         </p>
         <p> numerous friends, and to the public, would, at the same time, call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, in
            elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of the
            business, have been enabled to add several important improvements to the
            action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, upon examination, equal to any in the market.
         </p>
         <p>STODART &amp;: DUNHAM.
            361 Broadway.
            Manufactory 13th St., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
            N. B.—A good second-hand Piano Forte for sale.
            PIANO FORTES.—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
            Street, N. Y.
            
         </p>
         <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as iron frames,
            &amp;c., with a compass of 6 1/2 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of
            23 years experience in the business.
         </p>
         <p>JAMES PIRSSON,
            PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER,
            88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.
            A large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
            TERMS MODERATE.
            SINGING AT SIGHT.
            MR. WARNER, translator of Weber’s theoretical
            
         </p>
         <p>work, &amp;c., continues his course of Vocal Instruction at his rooms, 411
            Broad-Way. Mr. Warner’s new Illustrating Apparatus will also furnish
            very great facilities for a ready and full understanding of the subject preparatory to the study of Instrumental Music.
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
            THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, late Practical partner of
            
         </p>
         <p>the old established firm of 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the larest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most superior
            quality ; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone
            Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Tories Tuned and Repaired. Piano
            Fortes aways on hire.
         </p>
         <p>BERTINI'S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
            
         </p>
         <p> work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method
            the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies, are
            given in such progressive order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
            carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
            otherwise, are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
            has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,
            and it is only by the study of such methods as Bellini's that pupils w ill be en
            abled to READ music with facility, and at the same time become good musi-
         </p>
         <p>cians.
            
         </p>
         <p> This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ; the rudments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each lesson
            is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest reccommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of Bertini’s Method
            over all others yet published in this country, most of them having used the
            foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
            names in the principal cities.
         </p>
         <p>Boston.
            Messrs. G. J. Webb.
            J. G Maedar.
            H. T. Hach.
            
            E. L. White.
            David Paine.
            A. Kurek.
            T. B. Moses.
            New York.
            Messrs. H. C. Timm.
            W. Alpers.
            U. C. Hill.
            F. H. Brown.
            Philadelphia.
            B. C. Cross.
            Joseph Duggan.
            Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            
         </p>
         <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
            American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Wash
            ington street, Boston.
         </p>
         <p>
            MITCHELL’S OLYMPIC THEATRE.
            PERFORMANCES EVERY EVENING.  DOORS
            open at Seven; Curtain rises at half-past Seven.
            Dress Circle, 50 Cents. Upper Boxes, 25 cents. Pit, 12 1-2 cents. Private
            Boxes. $3. Box Office open every day.
            JOHN DOUGLAS,
            BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            
         </p>
         <p>NO. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every description of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
            with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, on terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
         </p>
         <p>January 16, 1845
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page224"></div>
            JUST PUBLISHED,
            NUMBER THREE OF MARTIN’S EDITION
            OF
            THE HOLY BIBLE,
            Illustrated with Steel Engravings,
            AND ACCOMPANIED BY NOTES AND DEVOTIONAL REFLECTIONS BY THE REV.
            ALEXANDER FLETCHER.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE immense circulation already attained compels the publishers to arrange the supply
            to their agencies
            upon as permanent a footing as possible. The three numbers now published will enable
            persons to decide on the merits of the work, and
            those desiring to subscribe will facilitate the publication by handing the names to
            our agents as early as practicable. The Engravings in
            this edition being all on steel, and the whole work proportionately superior to any
            other, the publishers are anxious to avoid the possibility of
            injuring the copies by anything like steam-hurry, particularly as they possess every
            means and facilities for publishing the numbers with all
            reasonable expedition.
         </p>
         <p>R. MARTIN &amp; CO. 26 John St.
            EVERY BODY’S BOOK.
            A PLAIN SYSTEM OF ELOCUTION: OR, LOGI-
            
         </p>
         <p> cal and Musical Reading and Declamation, with Exercises in Prose and
            Verse, distinctly marked for the guidance of the Ear and Voice of the Pupil:
            to which is added, AN APPENDIX, containing a copious Practice in Oratorical, Poetical, and Dramatic Reading and Recitation: the whole forming a
            Complete Speaker, well adapted to private pupils, classes, and the use of
            schools; by G. Vandenhoff, Professor of Elocution in the City of New
            York. Second Edition.	Published by C. SHEPARD,
         </p>
         <p>191 Broadway, opposite John st.
            From the Rev. R. T. Hoddart, (Classical Academy, Houston street.)
            
         </p>
         <p>It affords me much pleasure to add my testimony to the value, importance,
            and advantage of Mr. George Vandenhoff’s Work on Elocution. He has
            aptly styled it “ a plain System such it truly is to those who will pursue
            the instruction given, step by step; and cannot fail of producing a beneficial
            and much wished for result in one of the departments of education so sadly
            neglected—correct reading—devoid of vulgarities, and errors in articulation
            and pronunciation. I hope the book will have a wide circulation, in order
            that the good which it is capable of effecting may be thus more extensively
            diffused, and a better system of instruction be afforded to the rising generation, in that which constitutes a most agreeable accomplishment in every
            gentleman’s education, namely, “ Logical and Musical Declamation
         </p>
         <p>(Signed)	R. Townsend Hoddart.
            New York, March 14, 1845.
            From Mrs. Lawrence, (Academy, Stuyvesant Place.)
            
         </p>
         <p>I have great pleasure in stating, that Mr. G. Vandenhoff’s work on Elocution has been used with so much success in my school, that I can safely recommend it to all, who may desire improvement in that elegant branch of
            education; as the most simple, clear and concise treatise on the subject; and
            well adapted to the comprehension of any mind.
         </p>
         <p>(signed)	Julia Lawrence.
            March 8th, 1845.
            From Jacob Le Roy, Esq., (Lafayette Place.)
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Vandenhoff’s Treatise on Elocution has been used by a Class of Ladies at my house, and has been found in every way adapted to produce its
            intended effect.	(Signed)	Jacob Le Roy.
         </p>
         <p>24th March, 1845.
            KEIGHTLEY’S HISTORICAL WORKS.
            THE HISTORY OF GREECE.—By Thomas Keight-
            ley, with notes and additions by G. Toulman Smith, in one volume.
            THE HISTORY OF ROME-By the same author, with notes and addi-
            tions in the same manner, in one volume.
            THE HISTORY OF THE ROMAN EMPIRE—Being a continuation of:
            the History of Rome. By the same author. In one volume.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE HISTORY OF ENGLAND-Fxom the Invasion of Julius Cæsar to
            the close of the reign of George IV. By the same author, with notes
            and additions as above. In two volumes. Published by
         </p>
         <p>TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John St.
            THE
            SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
            Published Monthly at Richmond, Va. ; price Five Dollars per Year.
            THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835,
            has a large subscription list among the elite of the Southern Aristocracy,
            and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the "Broadway Jour-
            nal," 153 Broadway.
            DISEASES OF THE TEETH.
            Washington, D. C., May, 1844.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
            and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
            The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
            professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
            Dental Surgery and an accomplished and skillful operator, we moat
            cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
            the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
            durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
         </p>
         <p>Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo. Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
            Joshua Herrick, Me.	John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
            James Irvin, Pa.	J. Thompson, Miss
            Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.
            DISBROW'S RIDING SCHOOL,
            NO. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette
            Places. New York.
            Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Even-
            ing, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.
            TERMS:
            Lecture Let sons.
            16 Lessons......................$16	00
            10 “ ........................10 00
            4	“	 5 	00
            Single Lessons...................2 	00
            Road “	 2	 50
            Exercise Riding.
            1 Month.......................$12	 00
            20 Rides........................10	 00
            10 “ .........................6 00
            Single Rides....................0 	75
            N. B.—Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let.
            Evening Class.
            12 Lessons................$9 00  20 Rides. ..............$10 00
            Single “ ..................1 00  Single Ride.........• ... 0 75
            RULES:
            1.	All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.
            2.	One hour allowed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.
            3.	One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.
            4.	Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 3 P. M.
            5.	Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.
            6.	No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladies.
            A card of address is requested previous to commencing.
            N. B. Gentlemen keeping their horses at this establishment, will have the
            privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
            The first Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for the
            best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
            NO. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
            
         </p>
         <p>tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
            in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms Reduced to TWO DOLLARS
            AND A HALF.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
            course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
            Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
         </p>
         <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen
            and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
            Price Five Dollars.
            
         </p>
         <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27. 1844.
            Goldsmith’s Gems or Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
            much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
            Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
            volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
            of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
         </p>
         <p>From the New- York Express.
            
         </p>
         <p>Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship.—We have seen the original, as
            executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
            wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
            to be “ more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
         </p>
         <p>PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY
            AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
            
         </p>
         <p>Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
            the Medal, four first Premiums, and two “Highest Houors,” at the
            Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
            the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
            at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
            the score of economy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American In
            struments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polish
            ing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders receive
            promptly attended to.
         </p>
         <p>John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      
   </div>
</div>