<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450503</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1.     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, MAY 3, 1845.     NO. 18.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum. 
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>C.F. Briggs, Edgar A. Poe, H.C. Watson, Editors.
         
         <br></br>Published at 153 Broadway,
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">House furniture.</div>
         <div class="biblPage">273</div>
         
         <div class="head">HOUSE FURNITURE.</div>
         
         <p>In the internal decoration, if not in the external architecture of their residences, the English are supreme. The Italians have but little sentiment beyond marbles and colors.
            In France meliora probant, deteriora sequuntur--the people
            are too much a race of gad-abouts to maintain those household proprieties of which, indeed, they have a delicate appreciation, or at least the elements of a proper sense. The
            Chinese and most of the eastern races have a warm but inappropriate fancy. The Scotch are poor decorists. The
            Dutch have, perhaps, an indeterminate idea that a curtain is
            not a cabbage. In Spain they are all curtains a nation of
            hangmen. The Russians do not furnish. The Hottentots
            and Kickapoos are very well in their way. The Yankees
            alone are preposterous.
         </p>
         
         <p>How this happens it is not difficult to see. We have no
            aristocracy of blood, and having therefore as a natural, and
            indeed as an inevitable thing, fashioned for ourselves an aristocracy of dollars, the display of wealth has here to take
            the place and perform the office of the heraldic display in
            monarchical countries. By a transition readily understood,
            and which might have been as readily foreseen, we have
            been brought to merge in simple show our notions of taste itself.
         </p>
         
         <p>To speak less abstractly. In England, for example, no
            mere parade of costly appurtenances would be so likely as
            with us, to create an impression of the beautiful in respect
            to the appurtenances themselves--or of taste as regards the
            proprietor:--this for the reason, first, that wealth is not, in
            England, the loftiest object of ambition as constituting a nobility; and secondly, that there the true nobility of blood,
            confining itself within the strict limits of legitimate taste,
            rather avoids than affects that mere costliness in which a
            parvenu rivalry may at any time be successfully attempted.
            The people will imitate the nobles, and the result is a thorough diffusion of the proper feeling. But in America the
            coins current being the sole arms of the aristocracy, their
            display may be said, in general, to be the sole means of aristocratic distinction; and the populace, looking always upward for models, are insensibly led to confound the two entirely separate ideas of magnificence and beauty. In short,
            the cost of an article of furniture has at length come to be,
            with us, nearly the sole test of its merit in a decorative
            Point of view--and this test, once established, has led the
            way to many analogous errors, readily traceable to the one
            primitive folly.
         </p>
         
         <p>There could be nothing more directly offensive to the eye
            of an artist than the interior of what is termed in the United
            States--that is to say in Appallachia--a well furnished
            apartment. Its most usual defect is a want of keeping. We
            speak of the keeping of a room as we would of the keeping
            of a picture--for both the picture and the room are amenable to those undeviating principles which regulate a varieties of art, and very nearly the same laws by which we de-
            cide on the higher merits of a painting, suffice for decision
            on the adjustment of a chamber.
         </p>
         
         <p>A want of keeping is observable sometimes in the character of the several pieces of furniture, but generally in their
            colors or modes of adaptation to use. Very often the eye
            is offended by their inartistical arrangement. Straight lines
            are too prevalent--too uninterruptedly continued--or clumsily interrupted at right angles. If curved lines occur, they
            are repeated into unpleasant uniformity. By undue precision
            the appearance of many a fine apartment is utterly spoiled.
         </p>
         
         <p>Curtains are rarely well disposed, or well chosen, in respect to other decorations. With formal furniture curtains
            are out of place; and an extensive volume of drapery of any
            kind is, under any circumstances, irreconcilable with good
            taste: the proper quantum, as well as the proper adjustment, depending upon the character of the general effect.
         </p>
         
         <p>Carpets are better understood of late than of ancient days,
            but we still very frequently err in their patterns and colors.
            The soul of the apartment is the carpet. From it are deduced not only the hues but the forms of all objects incumbent. A judge at common law may be an ordinary man; a
            good judge of a carpet must be a genius. Yet we have heard
            discoursing of carpets, with the air "d'un mouton qui r ve,"
            fellows who should not and who could not be entrusted with
            the management of their own moustaches. Every one knows
            that a large floor may have a covering of large figures, and
            that a small one must have a covering of small--yet this is
            not all the knowledge in the world. As regards texture the
            Saxony is alone admissible. Brussels is the preter-pluperfect tense of fashion, and Turkey is taste in its dying agonies. Touching pattern--a carpet should not be bedizzened
            out like a Riccaree Indian--all red chalk, yellow ochre, and
            cock's feathers. In brief--distinct grounds, and vivid circular or cycloid figures, of no meaning, are here Median laws.
            The abomination of flowers, or representations of well-known
            objects of any kind, should not be endured within the limits
            of Christendom. Indeed, whether on carpets, or curtains,
            or tapestry, or ottoman-coverings, all upholstery of this nature should be rigidly Arabesque. As for those antique floorcloths still occasionally seen in the dwellings of the rabble
            --cloths of huge, sprawling, and radiating devices, stripeinterspersed, and glorious with all hues, among which no
            ground is intelligible,--these are but the wicked invention
            of a race of time-servers and money-lovers--children of Baal
            and worshippers of Mammon--Benthams, who to spare
            thought, and economize fancy, first cruelly invented the Kaleidoscope, and then established joint-stock companies to twirl
            it by steam.
         </p>
         
         <p>Glare is a leading error in the philosophy of American
            household decoration--an error easily recognized as deduced
            from the perversion of taste just specified. We are violently enamoured of gas and of glass. The former is totally inadmissible within doors. Its harsh and unsteady light offends No one having both brains and eyes will use it. A
            mild, or what artists term a cool light, with its consequent
            warm shadows, will do wonders for even an ill-furnished
            apartment. Never was a more lovely thought than that of
            the astral lamp. We mean, of course, the astral lamp proper-- the lamp of Argand, with its original plain ground
            glass shade, and its tempered and uniform moonlight rays.
            The cut glass shade is a weak invention of the enemy. The
            eagerness with which we have adopted it, partly on account
            of its flashiness, but principally on account of its greater cost,
            is a good commentary on the proposition with which we began. It is not too much to say that the deliberate employer of a cut glass shade, is either radically deficient in taste,
            or blindly subservient to the caprices of fashion. The light
            proceeding from one of these gaudy abominations is unequal,
            broken, and painful. It alone is sufficient to mar a world of
            good effect in the furniture subjected to its influence. Female loveliness, in especial, is more than one half disenchanted beneath its evil eye.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the matter of glass, generally, we proceed upon false
            principles. Its leading feature is glitter--and in that one
            word how much of all that is detestable do we express!
            Flickering, unquiet lights are sometimes pleasing--to children and idiots always so--but in the embellishment of a
            room they should be scrupulously avoided. In truth, even
            strong steady lights are inadmissible. The huge and unmeaning glass chandeliers, prism-cut, gas-lighted, and without shade, which dangle in our most fashionable drawingrooms, may be cited as the quintessence of all that is false
            in taste or preposterous in folly.
         </p>
         
         <p>The rage for glitter--because its idea has become, as we
            before observed, confounded with that of magnificence in the
            abstract--has led us, also, to the exaggerated employment
            of mirrors. We line our dwellings with great British plates,
            and then imagine we have done a fine thing. Now the
            slightest thought will be sufficient to convince any one who
            has an eye at all, of the ill effect of numerous looking-glasses, and especially of large ones. Regarded apart from its
            reflection, the mirror presents a continuous, flat, colorless,
            unrelieved surface--a thing always and obviously unpleasant.
            Considered as a reflector, it is potent in producing a monstrous and odious uniformity:--and the evil is here aggravated, not in merely direct proportion with the augmentation of
            its sources, but in a ratio constantly increasing. In fact, a
            room with four or five mirrors arranged at random, is, for all
            purposes of artistic show, a room of no shape at all. If we
            add to this evil, the attendant glitter upon glitter, we have a
            perfect farrago of discordant and displeasing effects. The
            veriest bumpkin, on entering an apartment so bedizzened,
            would be instantly aware of something wrong, although he
            might be altogether unable to assign a cause for his dissatisfaction. But let the same person be led into a room tastefully furnished, and he would be startled into an exclamation
            of pleasure and surprise.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is an evil growing out of our republican institutions,
            that here a man of large purse has usually a very little soul
            which he keeps in it. The corruption of taste is a portion
            or a pendant of the dollar-manufacture. As we grow rich
            our ideas grow rusty. It is, therefore, not among our aristocracy that we must look (if at all, in Appallachia) for the spirituality of a British boudoir. But we have seen apartments
            in the tenure of Americans of modern means--which, in negative merit at least, might vie with any of the or-molu'd
            cabinets of our friends across the water. Even now, there is
            present to our mind's eye a small and not ostentatious chamber with whose decorations no fault can be found. The proprietor lies asleep on a sofa--the weather is cool--the time
            is near midnight--we will make a sketch of the room during
            his slumber.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is oblong--some thirty feet in length and twenty-five in
            breadth--a shape affording the best (ordinary) opportunities
            for the adjustment of furniture. It has but one door--by no
            means a wide one--which is at one end of the parallelogram,
            and but two windows, which are at the other. These latter
            are large, reaching down to the floor--have deep recesses,
            and open on an Italian veranda. Their panes are of a crimson-tinted glass, set in rose-wood framings, more massive
            than usual. They are curtained within the recess, by a thick
            silver tissue adapted to the shape of the window, and hanging loosely in small volumes. Without the recess are curtains of an exceedingly rich crimson silk, fringed with a deep
            network of gold, and lined with the silver tissue, which is
            the material of the exterior blind. There are no cornices;
            but the folds of the whole fabric (which are sharp rather
            than massive, and have an airy appearance) issue from beneath a broad entablature of rich gilt work, which encircles
            the room at the junction of the ceiling and walls. The drapery is thrown open also, or closed, by means of a thick rope
            of gold loosely enveloping it, and resolving itself readily into
            a knot;--no pins or other such devices are apparent. The
            colors of the curtains and their fringe--the tints of crimson
            and gold--appear everywhere in profusion, and determine
            the character of the room. The carpet, of Saxony material,
            is quite half an inch thick, and is of the same crimson ground,
            relieved simply by the appearance of a gold cord (like that
            festooning the curtains) slightly relieved above the surface of
            the ground, and thrown upon it in such a manner as to form
            a succession of short irregular curves--one occasionally overlaying the other. The walls are papered with a glossy paper
            of a silver grey tint, spotted with small Arabesque devices
            of a fainter hue of the prevalent crimson. Many paintings
            relieve the expanse of the paper. These are chiefly landscapes of an imaginative cast--such as the fairy grottoes of
            Stanfield, or the lake of the Dismal Swamp, of Chapman.
            There are, nevertheless, three or four female heads, of an
            ethereal beauty--portraits in the manner of Sully. The tone
            of each picture is warm, but dark. There are no "brilliant
            effects." Repose speaks in all. Not one is of small size.
            Diminutive paintings give that spotty look to a room, which
            is the blemish of so many a fine work of Art overtouched.
            The frames are broad but not deep, and richly carved, without being dulled or fillagreed. They have the whole lustre
            of burnished gold. They lie flat on the walls, and do not
            hang of! with cords. The designs themselves are often seen
            to better advantage in this latter position, but the general
            appearance of the chamber is injured. But one mirror, and
            this not a very large one, is visible. In shape it is nearly
            circular--and it is hung so that a reflection of the person can
            be obtained from it in none of the ordinary sitting-places of
            the room. Two large low sofas of rose-wood and crimson
            silk, gold-flowered, form the only seats with the exception
            of two light conversation chairs, also of rose-wood. There
            is a piano-forte (rose-wood also,) without cover, and thrown
            open. An octagonal table, formed altogether of the richest
            gold-threaded marble, is placed near one of the sofas. This
            is also without cover--the drapery of the curtains has been
            thought sufficient. Four large and gorgeous Sevres vases,
            in which bloom a profusion of sweet and vivid flowers, occupy the slightly rounded angles of the room. A tall candelabrum, bearing a small antique lamp with highly perfumed
            oil, is standing near the head of my sleeping friend. Some
            light and graceful hanging shelves, with golden edges and
            crimson silk cords with gold tassels, sustain two or three
            hundred magnificently bound books. Beyond these things,
            there is no furniture, if we except an Argand lamp, with a
            plain crimson-tinted ground-glass shade, which depends from
            the lofty vaulted ceiling by a single slender gold chain, and
            throws a tranquil but magical radiance over all.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Twentieth Annual Exhibition of the Academy of National Design</div>
         <div class="biblPage">275</div>
         
         <div class="head">TWENTIETH ANNUAL EXHIBITION OF THE ACADEMY
            OF NATIONAL DESIGN. 
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">LANDSCAPES.</div>
         
         <p>No. 5. View of the Roman Forum.--Chev. Pacetti. A
            little dingy canvass, with columns and arches, and other architectural shapes, feebly represented on its surface. On
            turning to the list of exhibitors, we learn that the Chev. Pacetti resides in Rome, which is all the information that we
            have been able to glean in respect to either the Chev. or his
            soiled canvass: but we have a great curiosity to learn three
            things: first, why the Chev. Pacetti's Roman Forum was
            brought away from Rome; second, why the same was hung
            up in the exhibition of the National Academy, and third,
            what the meaning of Chev. is as applied to a spoiler of canvass on a small scale. If any thing can cure our artists of
            their absurd practice of making pilgrimages to Rome, it must
            be the contemplation of such things as this of the Chev. Pacetti's, and the filthy daub by Rossiter that hangs near it,
            which were both painted in the atmosphere of the eternal
            city. Or if these things should not thoroughly wean an honest
            mind from all yearnings after Italy, surely the comparison
            of the works produced by the young artists who have never
            left their native soil, with those by Huntington and Freeman in the present exhibition which have been sent home
            from Rome, must have the effect to do so. We do not find
            the name of the Chev. Pacetti among the honorary members
            of the Academy, but it will of course be put there before
            long.
         </p>
         
         <p> No 16. Landscape--by J. F. Cropsey, A. Here is a very
            genuine American picture, pervaded wtth great purity of
            feeling and technical knowledge. The artist has been tied
            down to the exact features of a particular scene, which he
            has transferred to his canvass very successfully. The scene
            is a view of the Saugerties White Lead Works on Esopus
            Creek in this State. The time is early spring, when the tender foliage of the trees gives to nature her sweetest aspect.
            But it is also the most difficult aspect for the painter to represent, for every thiDg is tremulous with new life, and the
            earth is covered with smiles like the face of an infant.
            There are in this picture all the elements of a grand landscape, ledges of rocks, a fall of water, beautiful trees, and a
            clear sky; but yet a grand landscape has not been formed
            by their combination, mainly because the artist has aimed to
            give all the details of a particular locality rather than a
            point of interest, imbued with a touch of truth and feeling.
            The rocks are painted with sufficient knowledge for a geologist to give them a name, and the trees have a character of
            their own in form and color, but their beauty is spoiled by
            too much distinctness in the foliage. The shadows are clear
            and cool, and the sky is of a quality that we can look into
            rather than upon; but the water resembles some substance
            that we have never seen--liquified sandstone, or something
            like it. The foam upon it is whiling, not the graceful substance out of which the goddess of love and beauty bounded
            into life and action. Of all natural things which the artist
            strives to pul upon his canvass, water is the most perplexing
            and intractable; it rarely finds its level in the imagination of
            the painter, but seems to run from him, and he is generally
            too indolent to run alter it. There is water enough in the
            present exhibition, if it possessed the quality of a liquid, to
            drown the world, yet Sisyphus might walk through the rooms
            of the Academy without being reminded of his thirst, unless
            
            he caught sight of the water-bucket and tin cup in Mr. Edmonds' picture of the Truant School Boy. These are suggestive of water, but the sea scene by Mr. Cole, the rivers of
            Mr. Durand, the lake by Mr. Inman, and the Niagara Falls
            by Mr. Havell, to leave the stagnant pool by Mr. Shegogue
            out of the catalogue, do not, all combined, contain as much
            moisture as Dives prayed for--one drop. Mr. Havell is obtrusively ambitious of painting water, for he has made an
            attempt upon Niagara Falls and the North river, and yet he
             has not given evidence of ability to depict a drop of dew. Of
            all other painters in the world a New-Yorker is the least
            excusable for libelling water; with a noble river on each side
            of the city, a bay of unsurpassed magnificence before him,
            and fountains dashing their spray in his face as he walks
            through the street, he must become acquainted with the
            qualities and appearances of the liquid element. Yet, with
            all these advantages, we see our artists continually painting
            lakes of polished steel, and oceans of sheep's wool. The
            reason is that they paint pictures in confined rooms, and borrow their waves and water-falls from engravings. But unless
            an artist is willing to look nature in the face, and strive honestly to copy her features, he has no right to make an attempt at representing her, for he will be certain to caricature
            her. If a young painter be ambitious of fame, and should
            think to gain it by making pictures of water, let him, instead
            of making a pilgrimage to Rome, take up his residence on
            Staten Island, and cross the bay every day in the year, rain
            or shine, calm or storm, hot or cold. Let him take his seat
            upon the taffrail of the boat, and never think about a shelter
            or an umbrella, or coughs or colds, or rheumatic pains, but
            watch the ever-varying form and color of the water, until
            his frame shall become invigorated with health, his nerves
            braced by the pure air, and his soul thoroughly imbued and
            saturated with living palpable ideas of the glorious beauty
            of the sea: its motion, moisture, transparency, and ever
            changing but ever beautiful forms. Let him each day note
            down his thoughts, and if at the end of the year he can represent upon his canvass one wave with the light palpitating
            through its translucent form, or flashing in its dancing spray,
            he will have laid the corner stone of an immortality and a
            life of honor. But even though he should not be able to do
            this to the degree that will satisfy his own aspirations, he
            will have spent a year of delight that will freshen his afterlife, and have gained an amount of knowledge, that will, at
            least, impart to his productions a degree of grace and beauty
            which, otherwise, they could never have possessed. The bay
            of New York is the happiest spot in the whole world to form
            a painter, because it has all the qualities that water can possess; it has the rapid current of a river, the breadth, depth,
            and motion of the sea, and the placidity and quiet of a lake.
            Its surface, too, is covered at all times, with all the different
            forms of boats that float--the canal boats from the interior,
            the pleasure yacht, the skiff, river craft, galliots, war vessels,
            steamers and merchant ships. There is not another port in
            the United States where the same variety of navigation may
            be found. But beyond all these advantages for the painter
            are the shores which bind this matchless bay; the wooded
            hills, the palisades, the low beach, the ledges of rocks, the
            fairy islands, with their demon-like fortifications, the city
            rising from the sea, the promontories, light-houses, castlecrowned heights and rocky precipices. Yet our artists give
            us none of these glories on their canvasses. Mr. Cole has
            gone down to Frenchman's bay, four or five hundred miles
            off towards the North Pole, and has come back and painted
            a pea-green sea with ledges of red rocks; Huntington has
            gone to Tuscany, and sent home a landscape with prismatic
            hills and a rivulet of soap-suds; Inman went to Cumberland,
            
            
            and sent here a back and purple and pea-green lake, with
            hills and trees of the same complexion: but our magnificent
            bay has not been able to furnish either of these New-Yorkers
            an idea for his canvass. We would not have them paint dioramic views of the bay as some painters attempt to do, and
            so fail of doing any thing, but let them take one ray of light,
            one wave, one hill, one cloud, one sun-set, one of our twilights, one of our ships or sloops, or barges, or steamboats-objects as full of poetry and romantic interest as any that can
            be found in Venice or Naples, and transfer it to their canvass,
            that there may be something on the walls of the Academy
            to appeal to the understandings and touch the hearts of those
            who crowd to look upon them. The great defect of every
            one of our landscape painters is an ambition to do everything
            upon one canvass. But in nature the eye will make for itself
            a point of interest, for it can comprehend but one thing at a
            time. Therefore the artist should never attempt to make
            two pictures on one canvass, for the eye cannot accommodate itself to both, and in glancing from one to the other,
            the interest of both will be destroyed. When we walk into
            the fields, or climb a mountain, or go out to sea, the eye and
            mind immediately seek out a particular object for contemplation, and all except the object selected immediately becomes
            a confused blank. If we look at a rock near by, we cannot
            see the distant hills; if we look at a flower at our feet, we
            cannot see the tree above our heads; if we gaze at the
            purple hills in the distance, we lose the green ones near by.
            A painter, therefore, should select his point of interest, and
            invest it with all the life and truth that his powers will allow, and only try to avoid giving the same degree of finish to
            any other part of his picture; then the spectator will have a
            key to his thoughts, and be spared the perplexity of trying to
            discern what he desired to accomplish. The pictures by Cole
            and Durand, in the present exhibition, contain within themselves dozens of other pictures, and the eye wanders from
            object to object, from sight to shadow, from men here to cattle yonder, seeking in vain after repose and a point to pause
            and hold communion with the artist. The Landscape, 39,
            by Durand, is wearying both to the eye and the mind, because you keep travelling over it for a place to rest upon and
            begin to drink its beauty. Here is an old man sitting in the
            cool shadow of the trees--you, are content to sit and rest
            also, and as you look upon him, sympathise with his feelings--but you cannot rest; a group of young men playing at
            ball are twitching away your eyes and distracting your
            thoughts; you pass to them, but beyond is a glimpse of
            bewitching sun-shine stealing through the trees which you
            must enjoy, and you leave the cricketers for the sun-shine,
            and that for the people at the farm-house door, and them for
            the man with the load of hay, and him for the clump of
            chesnut trees, and them for the objects in the foreground. The
            mind is wearied and dissatisfied; the heart is not touched--
            you feel pettish and--without knowing what to find fault
            with, for the picture is really made up of most admirable
            materials--condemn it in your heart while you pronounce it
            with your tongue a magnificent work.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is hardly a landscape in the rooms in which you
            can discover with certainty the intent of the painter, beyond
            the very obvious one of catching the eye of a gaping crowd.
            There are a few which seem to have been painted with a
            sentiment of Nature in the artist's mind, and these make the
            most forcible appeal to the heart of the spectator. No. 37,
            a study from Nature, by Cropsey, is a very truthful picture;
            the rocks are the best of any in the exhibition; the shadows
            are clear and distinct; the light pure and bright, and the little bit of water is limpid and cool, although it is smooth as a
            mirror. The picture does not stand out from the canvass, as
            we hear amateurs absurdly say, sometimes, when they mistake the gross faults of a painting for its beauties, but it takes
            you into the canvass as you stand and look at it, and if you
            saw it by itself, would doubtless make you forget that you
            were looking at a picture at all. The pictures in a promiscuous collection are seen lo very great disadvantage; the eye
            and the mind are distracted by the varieties of style, of objects
            and of color. Artists paint to attract admirers, and modest
            nature is trampled upon like violets in a garden of sun-flowers. No. 177, an October landscape, by J. R. Bleecker, is a
            charming little bit of tender feeling; an artist whose love of
            the true and beautiful leads him to scorn the flaunting gewgaws by which vulgar minds seek to gain applause, and
            contents himself to copy nature as he finds her, will run the
            risk of being thrust into a bye-place as this little painting has
            
            been. But he should work on and bide his time--his day
            will dawn by-and-bye. There is a most charming little
            painting by Mr. Casilear, in the rooms of the Art-Union in
            Broadway, which should have been sent to the exhibition.
            It is a perfectly painted oak tree, with a couple of horses
            resting in its shadow; it is very simple, very highly finished,
            and full of genuine love of nature and high artistic expression. It is worth an acre of the stumps of trees, and mahogany looking rocks which occupy so large a part of the walls
            of the National Academy.
         </p>
         
         <p>113, 168, 236. Three Landscapes, by R. A. Powers--are
            from the pencil of an artist of whom we have never heard
            before; but we feel confident from the merit which each
            contains, that we shall hear from him again to better advantage.
         </p>
         
         <p>153, 160, 306, by W. W, Wotherspoon--are the most promising pictures in the exhibition. They are very strongly
            marked by a decided manner; but the artist was born a landscape painter, and his manner must be rather a choice than
            a necessity. He must look a little closer into Nature, and
            free himself of his present manner, before it becomes a decided habit. The best part of his picture is the drawing;
            the color is monotonous and untrue.
         </p>
         
         <p>117. View on Long Island--J. H. Cafferty. A quiet, unobtrusive piece of nature. We have seen the tree before--
            but we are never loth to meet such an acquaintance a second
            time.
         </p>
         
         <p>321, 324, Landscapes--by F. E. Church, of Catskill, a pupil of Mr. Cole's. These little pictures give evidence of genius in the painter. They are somewhat crude, but they
            contain touching little effects, which many works of greater
            pretensions lack. The red clouds in the sunset, 321, are
            painted with beautiful effect.
         </p>
         
         <p>30. Sunset--by C. P. Cranch. There are many good things
            in this picture, and many weak parts. The sky is given with
            good effect, and the shadows are cool and transparent; but
            the picture is too large for the subject. Mr. Cranch has four
            more landscapes in the exhibition, which all possess some
            good touches, but he would do well to exhibit more sparsely
            until he has had more practice and become more familiar
            with nature.
         </p>
         
         <p>88. View across Frenchman's Bay from Mount Desert
            Island, after a squall--T. Cole. This is the only marine
            picture that we have seen by Mr. Cole. The water is well
            drawn, but not well colored, and the rocks are of a kind that
            no geologist would find a name for; the whole coast of
            Maine is lined with rocks nearly black in color, and tinged
            with a greenish hue, as all marine rcoks are. These in Mr.
            Coles's picture are red. An artist should be something of a
            geologist to paint rocky scenes correctly, as he should be a
            botanist to paint flowers, and an anatomist to paint the human form. The picture is a good deal too large. So wide a
            surface for so meagre a subject must be filled up chiefly with
            common places; a few inches of canvass will serve to convey
            as vivid an idea of the sea, if properly covered, as a yard;
            as much breadth of effect can be given in the palm of your
            hand, as on a canvass twenty feet wide; why, then, should
            artists waste their materials in painting enormous pictures,
            whose sizes alone will prevent their being purchased. No.
            97, by the same artist, is too large for any ordinary room,
            and the sublime idea of the subject is lost in its expansion.
            We have been told that this great picture was painted in
            four days, which is time enough, but if it had been painted
            within the space of four inches, it would have been infinitely
            more impressive. 178--a sunset, is one of Mr. Cole's weakest pictures; it is evidently a composition, and it appears to
            worse advantage for being put in an oval frame. Mr. Cole
            still reigns supreme in landscape, as we doubt not he will
            long continue to do. But he does not always paint with the
            same power. His two pictures in the rooms of the Art-Union
            are much finer than either of those in the exhibition; they
            are among the very best American landscapes ever painted.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 125, 133, 140, 226. Landscapes--by John F. Kencett,
            now in England. These pictures of English scenery contain much that is pleasing and true to nature. They are
            evidently studies; but they are too highly elaborated. The
            strange effect of light in No. 140, a view near Richmond,
            appears like an attempt to imitate some of the startling effects of Turner. It may be true, but all truths are not proper for circulation.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 71. Land Storm--T. Doughty, H. A most excellent
            picture.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">My Village Home</div>
         <div class="biblPage">275</div>
         <div class="head">MY VILLAGE HOME.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>In dreams sweet thoughts of thee will come,
            
            <br></br>I see thee yet once more,
            
            <br></br>My own, my happy Village-Home,
            
            <br></br>As lovely as of yore.
            
            <br></br>I see the snow-white cottage stand
            
            <br></br>Amid its leafy bowers,
            
            <br></br>Surrounded by a fairy land,
            
            <br></br>A Paradise of flowers.
            
            <br></br>I see the shade the willow throws,
            
            <br></br>The stately poplar trees,
            
            <br></br>The woodbine and the blushing rose
            
            <br></br>Whose fragrance fills the breeze.
            
            <br></br>I wander by the river-side,
            
            <br></br>A young child free from care,
            
            <br></br>And mark the meadow spreading wide,
            
            <br></br>The cattle browsing there.
            
            <br></br>Beneath a gently-sloping hill
            
            <br></br>I see the streamlet steal,
            
            <br></br>Whose waters seek the village mill,
            
            <br></br>And turn its busy wheel.
            
            <br></br>Afar, my wandering eyes behold
            
            <br></br>The lowly house of prayer,
            
            <br></br>Where oft the faithful of the fold
            
            <br></br>In reverence meek repair.
            
            <br></br>And one spot dearer still than all
            
            <br></br>My heart can ne'er forget,
            
            <br></br>The forest-walk, the waterfall,
            
            <br></br>Where oft in youth I met
            
            <br></br>A fair young girl, whose lustrous eyes
            
            <br></br>No longer smile or weep, 
            
            <br></br>For in the church-yard lone she lies,
            
            <br></br>In deep and dreamless sleep.
            
            <br></br>There is no old familiar place
            
            <br></br>Beloved in boyish years,
            
            <br></br>That I cannot distinctly trace
            
            <br></br>Athwart my falling tears.
            
            <br></br>And even in my dream I grieve
            
            <br></br>That I could wish to roam,
            
            <br></br>And marvel I could ever leave
            
            <br></br>My happy Village Home.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Philadelphia, April 16.	</div>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">MARY G. WELLS</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Living Artists of Europe: No. 2</div>
         <div class="biblPage">277</div>
         <div class="head">LIVING ARTISTS OF EUROPE.No. 2.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">HORACE VERNET.</div>
         
         <p>Three generations of the family of Vernet have rendered
            the name famous in the annals of the French school. They
            were originally from Avignon, in which city was born Joseph Vernet, the grandfather of the subject of this notice, and
            the first of the three celebrated men, each of whom, in his
            time, has so identified himself with the progress of Art. The
            father of Joseph Vernet was a landscape painter, by whom it
            is said there exist in the department of Vaucluse creditable
            examples of talent. Marine painting was the department of
            Art in which Joseph Vernet excelled, and in this he surpassed all the French artists of his time. His son, Carl Vernet,
            acquired an extensive reputation from his historical pictures
            and battle pieces; this last is the father of the yet more famous Vernet of our own epoch.
         </p>
         
         <p>Jean Emile Horace Vernet was born in Paris on the 30th
            of June, 1789, in the Louvre, in which palace both his father and grandfather occupied apartments. Born at a period
            when education was little cared for in France, he was abandoned almost entirely to the guidance of his own natural intonations, which, in default of that kind of instruction,
            adapted for children of his age, turned his undivided attention to Art. He exhibited, therefore, very early, a capacity
            for drawing--crayons and pencils were his first toys, and his
            practice with these he soon began to aid with a knowledge
            of anatomy and perspective. His first instructions in drawing he received from his father, and he afterwards worked
            some time in the atelier of M. Vincent, a painter of some
            celebrity under the Consulate.
         </p>
         
         <p>The first money received by Horace Vernet, in the exercise of his profession, was while he was yet in childhood:
            in boyhood he was an independent member of the Art. At
            the age of eleven years he made a drawing of a tulip for
            Madame de Perigord, for which she paid him twenty-four
            sous; and at the age of thirteen he had commissions insomuch as to be in a condition to support himself. One of his
            earliest efforts was the vignette which, according to the taste
            of the times, headed the card of invitation to the imperial
            hunting parties, which was of such merit that an engraver
            of considerable reputation--Duplessis Bertaut--did not hesitate to pronounce it worthy of his own burin.
         </p>
         
         <p>Commissions began to flow in upon the young Vernet--
            drawings at six francs, and pictures at twenty. He worked
            principally for the Journal des Modes, for which he became
            the acknowledged draughtsman; and it was, perhaps, from
            his experience in this department of Art, that he acquired
            that power in caricature with which he even now amuses
            his intimate friends; and often at their own cost.
         </p>
         
         <p>Carle Vernet, who had gained the travelling pension,
            wished his son should win the same distinction; but Horace
            failed in competition for this honor, as he had already done
            upon every occasion hitherto of his disputing the academic
            palm. The taste for classic history and mythology prevailed
            at this time in its full force in France, and Horace Vernet
            was among the first of the French artists who saw that the
            Greeks and Romans had already had their day, and to understand that he was one of those who were assisting at a
            grand crisis in Art, in conjunction with a grand crisis in history, and that the particular period would claim for itself
            those great men who should signalize themselves amid the
            turmoil of their times. Moved by a natural inclination for a
            military life, and having served some time in the ranks of
            the French army, he was an enthusiastic admirer of Napoleon; it is not, therefore, surprising that he should have early
            devoted himself to the celebration of the achievements of the
            French armies and their adored chief; and, although his
            power is universal, it is yet in this kind of composition in
            which we find it most emphatically pronounced.
         </p>
         
         <p>In order to check a strong inclination for a military career,
            he was induced by his father to marry at an early age; thus
            at twenty he took upon himself the cares of a household, for
            which, as his family was rich only in reputation, his exertions were now taxed to provide; hence, to those habits of
            industry, seconded by his marvellous facility of execution, he
            is indebted for the reputation of being the most prolific artist
            that ever existed, having, up to the present time, made more
            than 1200 drawings, nearly 1000 portraits, all of important
            persons, and at least 300 pictures, many of which are large
            and complex compositions.
         </p>
         
         <p>In 1814 he was enrolled in the Legion of Honor for the
            active part which he had taken in the defence of Paris; and
            in 1925 he was promoted to the grade of officer by Charles
            X.; and in 1842 he was appointed commander of the order,
            by the present king of the French, a distinction at which he,
            of all the French School of Art, has alone arrived. In 1826
            he was elected a member of the Institute, where, in the
            class of Fine Arts, he took his place by the side of his father,
            who long before him had been similarly placed in the old
            Academy of Painting.
         </p>
         
         <p>In August, 1828, Horace Vernet was appointed Director
            of the French Academy at Rome, an office which he filled
            until the first of January, 1839. During his residence at
            Rome M. Vernet sent as a present to Charles X. an admirable portrait of Pope Pius VIII., which is ranked among the
            best productions of its author, and now occupies a place in
            the Museum at Versailles. The king, being charmed with
            this act of graceful homage, caused the secretary of the embassy to Rome to be charged to ascertain what return on the
            part of the king would be most grateful and flattering to the
            artist; and to learn particularly whether the title of baron
            would be agreeable to him. The office of discovering his
            feelings in this latter respect fell to the lot of one of his particular friends, to whom he replied--"The name of Vernet
            for a painter seems to me sufficiently good without any honorary title; the name has shot forth from the crowd, and,
            in my opinion, the title of baron would again obscure it; but
            if his Majesty (as you assure me he is) be disposed to accord
            me that which would afford me the greatest pleasure, say
            that I pray his Majesty to grant the distinction of the Legion
            of Honour to M. Dumont, a sculptor, and one of our pensionnaires, who has just executed a group of the highest merit."
         </p>
         
         <p>Vernet was not made a baron, nor did Dumont upon that
            occasion receive the cross, although he has since acquired
            that honor, and even been also enrolled a member of the Institute.
         </p>
         
         <p>When the revolution of 1830 broke out, the whole of the
            French legation at Rome retired to Naples, where the ambassador had already been for some time, and thus the Director of the Academy was left at Rome alone, the only
            French functionary that remained there, in which position of
            affairs M. Veruet was nominated the diplomatic representative of France at the Holy See--a signal distinction for an
            artist--with full powers to treat directly with the Papal Government, and amid circumstances of great difficulty. He
            acquitted himself, however, with such firmness and judgment as to gain the entire and unqualified approbation of the
            French government; the expression of which was conveyed
            to him in a letter written by M. Guizot, then Minister of the
            Interior.
         </p>
         
         <p>The manner in which this great artist relaxes from his
            professional labors is by travel; and during these periods of
            diversion he has visited many distant countries, as Egypt,
            Syria, and Algeria, as well as having travelled through all
            the European states, and having been presented to almost all
            the sovereigns who have lived in his time. He possesses an
            assemblage of endowments with which few men have been
            gifted, or at least, being so, have turned to such account.
            His conversation is light, most agreeable, and full of anecdote, and, under apparent inattention, be conceals a deep and
            penetrating observation. His memory is singularly retentive of facts, forms, and localities, insomuch that he can describe with exactitude, and after a lapse of years, a place
            which he may have seen but once; and so entirely has he
            reduced this wonderful force of memory to professional purposes, that he can paint the portrait of a person with whom
            he may have passed an hour in conversation. His reading is
            confined almost to the Bible; it was the Scriptures that first
            inspired him with the desire of visiting the East; and with
            respect to his travels in the Holy Land, after close and elaborate research, and observation, he declares his conviction,
            that the habits and costumes of the Arabs of the present day,
            are, with little change, the same as they were in the days
            of the patriarchs. As regards the long catalogue of his
            works, this is to be explained by reference to his teeming
            imagination and happy adaptation of subject-matter, rapidity
            of execution, earnestness of purpose, and uninterrupted good
            health. Albeit his works are so numerous, and of character so diverse, he cannot anywhere be charged with imitation--it is sufficiently evident in all that the inspiration is from actual nature, or has its source in his own
            vivid imagery--and this is the more apparent that in his
            works there is no self-repetition. Observation and study
            of nature are considered by him two grand principles of excellence. As Professor of the School of Fine Arts, his instructions are considered by the students more serviceable
            than those of any of the other eleven professors. It is not
            the classes alone of this admirable institution that profit by
            the instructions of M. Vernet; nor is it merely to his own
            countrymen that they are confined; for he receives in his own
            atelier, with the utmost kindness and amenity, students of
            all nations, to whom he offers freely his valuable counsel
            and best advice. With respect to the measure and the reward of his labors, of these he never thinks in comparison;
            for the picture which he intends as a work of love, or a simple gift, he elaborates as highly as that for which he receives
            a princely reward.
         </p>
         
         <p>Like all men of superior genius, M. Vernet has his ardent
            admirers and determined detractors; but the test of time and
            the public voice are of infinitely more weight than such a
            complexity of praise and censure. Thirty years of success,
            and an ever-increasing popularity, have placed Horace Vernet in the highest rank of the profession of Art--a position
            awarded to him first by the mass of his countrymen, and
            acknowledged by the rest of Europe.
         </p>
         
         <p>The works of no artist are more extensively known, or
            more eminently popular than those of M. Vernet, because
            in the commonest human incidents he sees pictures: and
            gives, accordingly, a version of them which comes at once
            home to the heart. Horace Vernet has been the first to break
            decidedly away from the dull classic formality of the French
            School, and to exhibit to its members the real fingering of
            the chords of the social affections.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Sleeper</div>
         <div class="biblPage">278</div>
         <div class="head">THE SLEEPER.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>At midnight, in the month of June,
            
            <br></br>I stand beneath the mystic moon.
            
            <br></br>An opiate vapor, dewy, dim,
            
            <br></br>Exhales from out her golden rim,
            
            <br></br>And, softly dripping, drop by drop,
            
            <br></br>Upon the quiet mountain top,
            
            <br></br>Steals drowsily and musically
            
            <br></br>Into the universal valley.
            
            <br></br>The rosemary nods upon the grave;
            
            <br></br>The lily lolls upon the wave;
            
            <br></br>Wrapping the fog about its breast,
            
            <br></br>The ruin moulders into rest;
            
            <br></br>Looking like Lethe, see! the lake
            
            <br></br>A conscious slumber seems to take,
            
            <br></br>And would not, for the world, awake.
            
            <br></br>All Beauty sleeps!--and lo! where lies
            
            <br></br>(Her casement open to the skies)
            
            <br></br>Irene, with her Destinies!
            
            <br></br>Oh, lady bright! can it be right--
            
            <br></br>This window open to the night?
            
            <br></br>The wanton airs, from the tree-top,
            
            <br></br>Laughingly through the lattice drop--
            
            <br></br>The bodiless airs, a wizard rout,
            
            <br></br>Flit through thy chamber in and out,
            
            <br></br>And wave the curtain canopy
            
            <br></br>So fitfully--so fearfully--
            
            <br></br>Above the closed and fringed lid
            
            <br></br>'Neath which thy slumb'ring soul lies hid,
            
            <br></br>That, o'er the floor and down the wall,
            
            <br></br>Like ghosts the shadows rise and fall!
            
            <br></br>Oh, lady dear, hast thou no fear?
            
            <br></br>Why and what art thou dreaming here?
            
            <br></br>Sure thou art come o'er far-off seas,
            
            <br></br>A wonder to these garden trees!
            
            <br></br>Strange is thy pallor! strange thy dress!
            
            <br></br>Strange, above all, thy length of tress,
            
            <br></br>And this all solemn silentness!
            
            <br></br>The lady sleeps! Oh, may her sleep,
            
            <br></br>Which is enduring, so be deep
            
            <br></br>Heaven have her in its sacred keep!
            
            <br></br>This chamber changed for one more holy,
            
            <br></br>This bed for one more melancholy,
            
            <br></br>I pray to God that she may lie
            
            <br></br>Forever with unopen'd eye,
            
            <br></br>While the dim sheeted ghosts go by!
            
            <br></br>My love, she sleeps! Oh, may her sleep,
            
            <br></br>As it is lasting, so be deep!
            
            <br></br>Soft may the worms about her creep!
            
            <br></br>Far in the forest, dim and old,
            
            <br></br>For her may some toll vault unfold--
            
            <br></br>Some vault that oft hath flung its black
            
            <br></br>And winged pannels fluttering back,
            
            <br></br>Triumphant, o'er the crested palls
            
            <br></br>Of her grand family funerals--
            
            <br></br>Some sepulchre, remote, alone,
            
            <br></br>Against whose portal she hath thrown,
            
            <br></br>In childhood, many an idle stone--
            
            <br></br>Some tomb from out whose sounding door
            
            <br></br>She ne'er shall force an echo more,
            
            <br></br>Thrilling to think, poor child of sin!
            
            <br></br>It was the dead who groaned within.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Grateful Clerk</div>
         <div class="biblPage">279</div>
         <div class="head">THE GRATEFUL CLERK,</div>
         
         <div class="ab">A TALE  FOUNDED ON FACTS.</div>
         
         <p>Mr. Hubs was head salesman in the wholesale jobbing
            store of Hinks and Whipple; he was looked upon as one of
            the best judges of satinets in Cedar street, as he well might
            be, for he was a judge of nothing else. He knew nothing of
            men, manners, metaphysics, or muslins: nothing of politics,
            pictures, poetry, or poplins; of sects, sciences, or satins. He
            knew nothing of literature, linens, or love. No, he knew
            nothing about love, although he thought that he did, for a
            young lady in Division street, whose mother kept a fancy
            store, by some witchery induced Mr. Hubs to offer himself;
            he did so because he thought that he was in love: but anybody who had ever been in that condition, could tell at a
            glance that John Hubs was a stranger to the passion. His
            forehead was too narrow, and the back part of his head was
            all shrunk away, or rather it had never been filled out.
            There was no more love in him than in a winter squash.
            It was his misfortune that he could not love. Poor Hubs!
            I could sooner spare a tear for such a fellow-being, than for
            the loss of an estate like Astor's. To live in a world which
            has nothing in it but love worth living for, and to be denied
            that!
         </p>
         
         <p>Notwithstanding that Hubs had a faint impression that he
            was in love, it is by no means certain that he would have
            married for that reason alone. His employers had made an
            addition of two hundred dollars per annum to his salary, and
            he thought that a wife would be very convenient tohelp him
            spend it. He could not spend his salary before it was raised, how then could he do so with so great an addition to it?
         </p>
         
         <p>By some accident his employers heard that their salesman
            was going to get married on a certain day, for Hubs could
            not brace up his nerves to announce the fact himself. He
            was fearful that they might not approve of so rash an undertaking, and he had not the courage to act contrary to their
            wishes. The night before the great day that was to see
            Hubs a married man, he called Mr. Hinks, the senior partner, aside, with the intention of asking leave of absence for a
            week; for the lady's friends had planned out a wedding
            tour to the Springs, for Hubs and his bride. But Mr. Hinks,
            being fond of a joke when it was not played off at his own
            expense, and suspecting the nature of his salesman's communication, did not give him time to open his mouth, but informed him that he must go into New Jersey the next morning by daybreak, to look after a delinquent customer. The
            terrified client looked as horror-struck at this announcement
            as he well could, and before he could gather together his astonished senses, stammered out that he could not go.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Can't go, sir!" exclaimed Mr. Hinks in a voice that was
            widely at variance with the expression of his face, as Hubs
            might have seen if he had looked at him. "But you must
            go, Mr. Hubs. Can't go! Bless my buttons, Mr. Hubs, I
            never heard such an expression before."
         </p>
         
         <p>"I'm engaged to --to --" stammered Hubs.</p>
         
         <p>"Engaged to what, sir?" said Mr. Hinks fiercely, "engaged to what, sir? I had an idea that you were engaged to
            the firm of Hinks and Whipple, sir. Have we not raised
            your salary two hundred dollars, Mr. Hubs?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"You have," replied Hubs, "I have not forgotten it, and
            I never can; but I have got a little engagement on my hands
            which I cannot well put off, and I should be glad to have a
            week's liberty, if it be possible."
         </p>
         
         <p>"It is impossible, quite impossible," replied the inveterate
            jobber, with great seriousness, "times are hard and business
            must not be neglected."
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs was beginning to look most uncomfortably pale, and
            Mr. Hinks was afraid to carry ibe joke further.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Well, Mr. Hubs, since you must go," said his employer,
            "I will despatch Mr. Putty, the book-keeper, into New Jersey,
            and here is a trifle to pay for your wedding suit." Whereupon he handed Hubs a check for a hundred dollars and then
            broke loose into a most unjobber-like explosion of mirth, in
            which he was joined by Mr. Whipple and all the junior
            clerks who had been watching all the proceedings and dying
            for their employer to give them the cue, that they might
            laugh at poor Hubs, who was so overcome that he was forced to walk off to some dark nook where he could give utterance to a heart full of feelings, which had been gathering
            like water in a mill-dam after a sudden thaw.
         </p>
         
         <p>It would have been a difficult matter to decide whether
            Hubs or his employer went home with the lighter heart that
            night. There can be no doubt that, generally speaking, the
            giver of a gift is a happier person than the receiver; and if
            men would but bear this fact in mind there can be as little
            doubt, that gifts would become more common than they are.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs made his appearance the next morning in Division
            street, in a white satin stock and a Marseilles vest: the marriage passed off without an accident, the tour was accomplished, and time's wheels rolled round as smoothly and as
            swiftly as though nothing remarkable had happened. In the
            first wild tumult of his feelings, Hubs made a silent vow
            that his first-born should be called, in honor of his employer,
            Hinks. But, two years had already flown by and he had
            not, for a very sufficient reason, performed his vow. His
            grateful feelings, however, had not diminished in the slightest degree, and he wished for nothing so ardently as for an
            opportunity to manifest them. It is true that Hubs had at
            times wished that his employer had been in earnest about
            sending him into New Jersey to look after a delinquent customer, or that something else had happened to prevent his
            marriage. Not that the matrimonial state was not all that
            he anticipated, but it proved to be a vast deal more; but
            that was no fault of his employers.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs occupied a little frame house in the outskirts of the
            city, with a little dusty garden attached to it, containing a
            woful looking lilac bush and two very dirty poplars. He
            had selected this spot because he was growing dyspeptic
            and his physician had recommended a country residence;
            and had it not been for a tannery and glue factory in his immediate neighborhood it would have been quite delightful.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Hinks had a remarkable excrescence on his right cheek,
            generally of an ashy color, but every autumn it assumed a
            very peculiar yellowish hue. People said that he was
            marked with a cantelupe. However that may be, it is certain that he was extravagantly fond of that kind of fruit, and
            while they lasted he hardly ate of anything but muskmelons.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs was well acquainted with his employer's appetite,
            and he determined to raise some of the finest cantelupes in
            his little garden that the world had ever seen, and present
            them to him. It was a happy thought, and so completely
            took possession of his brain that he could think of nothing else.
            Even satinets became a weariness to him, It was before
            the frost was out of the ground that the idea occurred to him,
            and he could hardly wait for the sun to soften the soil so that
            he could begin to plant. But while he was waiting for the
            season to roll round, he read through half a dozen numbers of the Farmer's Almanac in search of agricultural
            knowledge. It had never occurred to him before that cantelupes required any particular mode of culture. He thought,
            if he ever thought on the subject at all, that they grew
            spontaneously. He knew that they were always to be found
            in the market at a certain season of the year, but how they
            got there was a matter entirely beyond the circle of his
            thoughts. It was a thing of course, and that was all he
            knew about it. But his new course of study opened to him
            a world of pleasures. Every fact that he found out proved
            a new delight. Once he looked upon an acquaintance with
            the different qualities of satinets as the highest kind of knowledge but he now found turnips and cauliflowers a source
            of amusement and profit. The whole vegetable world was
            suddenly invested with most marvellous properties that excited the utmost astonishment in his mind. He looked upon a
            potato with feelings bordering on veneration when he learned that that humble vegetable was compounded of starch,
            water, albumen, sugar, poison fatty matter, parenchyma,
            malic acid and salts; and the knowledge that a simple little
            green weed, as soon as it thrusts its innocent head above the
            earth begins to imbibe carbonic acid and oxide of ammonia
            from the surrounding atmosphere, and that it produces hydrogen, fixes azote and abstracts electricity, made him regard
            the grass beneath his feet with affection. He had no idea
            that there was such instinct in plants. The trees in the Park,
            the flowers in street windows, the vegetables in the market,
            and the fruits on street stalls, all attracted his attention, not
            as things of traffic or of nourishment, but as organized existences obeying the laws of their own being, and showing
            forth the glory and goodness of their Maker as plainly, and
            as abundantly as his own species. He wondered at his former darkness, and he began to perceive what an abundance
            of lovable things there are in the world.
         </p>
         
         <p>O what a blessing is knowledge! thought Mr. Hubs.
            How it enhances our delights, lessens our griefs, gives a rel-
            
            ish to labor, makes even poverty cheerful, and takes from
            death itself more than half its terrors.
         </p>            
         
         <p>His acquisitions of knowledge were very small indeed, and
            confined entirely to the manufacture of satinets and the culture of cantelupes, and yet such was the liberal effect of science on his mind that he could have clasped the whole world
            to his heart if his wife had been out of it. His little insight
            into the mysteries of vegetable germination had given him
            a vague feeling of awe for his mother earth, although it was
            mainly as the great parent of cantelupes that he reverenced
            her, and he looked with growing impatience for the time to
            arrive when he should be permitted to scratch her back with
            his iron rake, and root up the weeds from her face as a pious child would pull the intrusive hairs from the chin of his
            grandmother.
         </p>
         
         <p>He had exhausted his almanacs, hut his thirst for knowledge had increased in proportion to his acquisitions, as a
            miser grows covetous as he grows rich, and he now supplied
            himself with a paper of seeds and Bridgman's darling little
            Gardener's Assistant at the same time, and took them home
            with the feelings of a philosopher. His wife scolded him
            smartly for his extravagance, but he bore all her womanly
            reproaches with the equanimity of a Socrates, and only replied to her long lecture, "wait and see.'' That the reader
            may know to what extent Hubs carried his philosophy, we
            will give a short extract from one of his help-mate's exerci tations.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Goodness me? What is that, a book? A nasty book!
            Well, now we shall starve! Mother always said so. I
            never new a man worth anything who was always lazying
            away his time over books. Well, I see what my fate will
            be. I shall have to go home to my mother's. I won't work
            to support a loafer, not I. You had better have given me
            that money to buy a breast pin. I told you yesterday I
            wanted a brooch to put my brother's hair in. You silly
            thing, what good will a book do you? O, yes, I seem to see
            you.	Aint you going to set up for a literary character. O
            my!	I should n't wonder. You told me yesterday you
            could'nt afford to go to the theatre, and there you have went
            and thrown away your money for a good-for-nothing book.
            But I'll go to the theatre if I live, and to the museum too, and
            I'll treat myself and my sister to ice creams and soda water
            at Thompson's. See if I don't. I never done such an extravagant thing as to buy a book, nor my mother before me.
            I have got that to be thankful for. Goodness me, no! I
            come from good respectable folks, who knew no more about
            books than the pope of Rome. But don't leave your book in
            my reach, mister; if you do, into the fire it goes, I can promise you."
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Hubs's two years of matrimonial trials had given him
            somewhat of an insight into the peculiarities of the female
            character, and he well knew the consequences of attempting
            to convince his wife that she had taken hold of the wrong
            of the question; so he merely answered, "wait and see,"
            and resolved to profit by her caution, and keep his precious
            little treatise under lock and key.
         </p>
         
         <p>His grounds only measured twenty five feet by forty, and
            as one portion of them was used as a grass plat for bleaching
            clothes, and a large slice was taken up by a gravel walk, it
            will readily be perceived that his garden could not be very
            extensive. But it was large enough for his desires, and he
            looked upon his little enclosure with the feelings of a landholder. It is doubtful whether the rich Mr. Wadsworth,
            who owns half the Genessee flats, ever felt as grand as Mr.
            Hubs did when he first stuck his shovel into the ground to
            commence the cultivation of cantelupes.
         </p>
         
         <p>Ambition always will overleap its mark. Hubs planted
            his cantelupe seed at least a fortnight too soon, and they all 
            rotted in the ground. After waiting an unreasonable time
            to see the young vines show their little heads above ground
            he was obliged to rake open the hills and plant afresh. Every morning he got up with the sun, and sometimes before,
            to watch his seeds, and see if they had burst from their dark
            hiding places; and as the dews were copious and the sun
            warm, he soon had the delight of seeing their delicate leaves,
            like outspread hands, throw aside the earthy particles which
            covered them, and salute the uprising sun with a grateful
            smile, like a new born infant gazing into the face of its parent. Surely never before did a tiller of the soil experience
            such delightful sensations as those which agitated the breast
            of Mr. Hubs on this occasion. He could not help running back
            to the bedside of his sleeping wife to beg that she would
            come down and look at his cantelupes. But his "last best
            gift" did not relish his intrusion at such an unseasonable
            hour, and she turned upon him with a How of expressions
            that our respect for her sex will not permit us to repeat. He
            left her to sleep on, and when he took his seat in the omnibus to go to his daily occupation of selling satinets, he felt
            like a new man. He tried to appear as humble as he could,
            but he experienced an uncomfortable feeling of superiority
            in spite of himself, which he had never felt before. All day
            his thoughts were wandering away to his cantelupes. He
            was impatient to get back to them. A long-winded customer front Vermont detained him forever, as it appeared to
            him, just as he was about to leave the store, and it was almost dark when he reached home. Before he would sit
            down to his supper, he rushed out to look at his young troop
            of vegetable earlings. But, alas! for human anticipations!
            The cantelupes had disappeared; vanished from mortal sight
            as though they had never been. The had been cruelly, barbarously cut off in the morning of their existence. He could
            have wept over their loss, bnt tears would avail them nothing. Their fate was shrouded in deep mystery. Nobody
            knew how it was done. Mrs. Hubs was profoundly ignorant
            of the matter, and Bridget was willing to take her Bible oath
            that she knew no more about the "young millions" than the
            child unborn. Mr. Hubs, of course, could not compel people to confess what they did not know, and he went to his bed
            in a state of miserable ignorance about the premature disappearance of his darling vegetables. But he had a horrible
            suspicion, which kept him awake half the night, that he was
            the victim of a wicked conspiracy between the wife of his bosom and her servant-maid.
         </p>
         
         <p>He was not to be daunted, however, for he had been educated in a school which knows no such word as despair.
            By dawn the next morning he was planting fresh seeds, having put them to soak in warm lye over night. But Hubs
            was doomed once more to disappointment; he had not been
            seated five minutes in the omnibus when a scoundrel cock,
            belonging to a sporting neighbor, walked deliberately into
            the hall door, which had been left open by Bridget, and
            strutted pompously into the garden, where, without the
            slightest hesitation, he scratched up every individual seed,
            and when he had stowed them away in his remorseless maw
            gave three loud exulting "cock-a-doodle-doos," and flew
            over the fence into his master's premises. It was the coolest performance that was ever seen, and when the unhappy
            clerk was told of it, his wrath was too big for words. He
            doubled his fists, stamped his feet, aud looked about him for
            some object upon which to wreak his vengeance; but there
            was nothing appropriate at hand, so after a moment's reflection he put more seeds in soak, and when he had eaten his
            supper retired to bed, that he might rise with the dawn.
         </p>
         
         <p>In due time, and it was a very short time too, for the sun
            was unseasonably hot, he had the happiness to see the little
            leaves once more popping up bright and joyous from the
            earth. He had watched them, and watered them an entire
            week, sprinkling snuff upon them to kill the bugs, and nipping off the first indications of a runner bud, to strengthen the
            vines and give richness to the fruit, when his wife's brother
            returned from a long voyage to the Pacific. He was one of
            the best-natured and most restless creatures in the world;
            like the sea, he would not be quiet a moment, and after he
            had kissed his sister and joked her about her husband, he
            rolled out into the garden and, to make himself useful, took
            up Hubs's hoe and began, to use his own phrase, "to work
            a traverse among the weeds."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Goodness me!" exclaimed his sister, "what have you
            done! You have went and hoed up all of Mr. Hubs's cantelupes. My, what will he say when he comes home!"
         </p>
         
         <p>When Hubs did come home he was soon informed of the
            full extent of his misfortune, but he could not open his
            mouth. It was his wife's brother who had done the deed,
            and wives' brothers are always privileged characters. He
            knew moreover, that there was no malice in the act. He
            had the stomach to do anything that was monstrous, if it
            would bring back his vines, but as no desperate deed could
            restore them he had the prudence to eat his supper in a quiet manner, although his mind was in a most unquiet state.
            The young sailor expressed a world of regret for the mischief he had done, and to console his brother-in-law, told
            him that he had got some first rate melon seeds in the till of
            his chest, which he had brought from round Cape Horn; and
            the next morning bright and early, he brought them up to
            Hubs, who was greatly astonished at the sight of them.
            They were as big as a dozen of those that he planted before.
            The young sailor took a fresh quid of tobacco, and told him
            that he would be more astonished at the fruit. Then they
            both went to work and made fresh hills, and felt once more
            happy at the prospect of beiag able to present his employer
            with some of his favorite fruit. In a week the new seeds
            showed themselves. Never before were such promising
            vines seen. They were so stout, and they grew so rapidly
            that Hubs was in a continual ecstasy of wonder; but when
            he looked out of his chamber window one morning and saw
            a large yellow blossom on one of the vines his admiration
            was boundless. He ran down to examine it, and was half
            disposed to be angry when he found that it was nothing but
            a male blossom. The vine which bore it grew very rapidly
            in the direction of the garden fence, and Hubs watched it
            with great anxiety to see whether it would run its head
            against the obstruction like a foolish blind creature; and his
            delight was immense when he perceived that it only approached within a safe distance, and then turned off to the
            right without rubbing a leaf against the palings. "You are
            a fine fellow," said Hubs, speaking to the vine, as though it
            had been furnished with a pair of ears like his own, "You
            are a fine fellow; yes you are, and I will demolish that rascal of a caterpillar that is eating one of your big leaves. The
            villain."
         </p>
         
         <p>The rains fell, the sun shone bright and warm upon it;
            the gentle summer winds rustled among its great summer
            blossoms and fan like leaves; the dews pearled it in the
            morning and the bees hovered about it all the day long, and
            still the vine grew, trailing its long rope-like body all over
            the garden, to the infinite wonder of all who looked upon it.
            At last a little knob of pale green showed itself in the extreme end of the vine, and gave promise of fruit. It was
            bailed with rapture by Mr. Hubs, and even his wife condescended to cast a favorable eye upon it, out of regard to her
            brother, as she said, but in reality because she was fond of
            melons herself, and because she had secretly resolved to invite all Division street to partake of it as soon as it should
            be ripe.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs was constantly in a high fever through fear that
            somebody would tread upon the vine, and he cautioned Bridget, on pain of instant dismissal, to be cautious how she
            planted her big feet near it. The young melon promised to
            be a monster, it grew in the space of three days to the size
            of an apple dumpling, and Hubs put some dry leaves under
            it to keep it from decaying; although a slate would have
            been better, as he might have found out by reading Bosc.
            But his researches had not yet extended so far. Neither had
            he stumbled upon Jolyclerc or Linn us. More was the pity,
            as the reader will discover.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs regarded the promising appearance of his cantelupe
            with some such feelings as a fond mother looks upon her
            precocious child, and sees in its premature wisdom a sign of
            premature decay. He dared not hope that so remarkable a
            melon would be permitted to arrive at perfection. It was
            too much to think of. And his forebodings were not without cause, for the phenomenon had not been in existence a
            fortnight when a hungry sow with a litter of pigs broke into
            the enclosure and devoured the precocious vegetable before a
            soul could come to its rescue.
         </p>
         
         <p>As the readers of romantic histories are often called upon
            to exercise their imaginations when the descriptive powers
            of the author fail him, they are respectfully requested to do
            so now, for no pen could begin to describe the anguish of
            mind which Mr. Hubs experienced when he was made acquainted with the disaster which had befallen him. He
            knew of no suitable manner of manifesting his feelings on
            the occasion; it was a grief without a precedent; so he
            strolled into his garden in a bitter frame of mind, and began
            to kick pettishly at the vines and blossoms which now looked hateful to him. Soon he kicked over one of the great
            broad leaves, and underneath it he discovered another melon
            larger and fairer than the one that was lost. He clapped
            his hands with delight, and could hardly restrain himself
            from falling on his knees and saluting the precious object.
         </p>
         
         <p>Every precaution was now taken to keep out hogs and
            boys and every kind of vermin. The new melon was watched over with a degree of solicitude passing belief, and it grew
            to a size far surpassing any melon that had been seen or
            read of. Hubs knew that professor Alpin bad seen melons
            in Egypt so large that three of them were a load for a camel
            but they were water-melons, and this was a cantelupe.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs watered the roots of the vine with weak pickle, after the Honfleur fashion, to give richness to the fruit; and he
            covered the joints with earth in place of pinching off its runner buds, to increase its size; for he had already learned
            enough about culture to make him reject the theory of the
            pinchers, and he argued (whether truly or not, we must leave
            others to decide,) that any mutilation of a plant must of necessity injure its organization. Who would think of chopping off his son's legs, said Hubs, with the expectation of increasing the length of his son's arms thereby?
         </p>
         
         <p>By the end of September, the melon had increased to such
            a size that Hubs could hardly lift it off the ground. It had
            begun to assume a rich buff color, nearly as bright as a ripe
            Havana orange, but it did not emit that rich delightful fragrance that ripe cantelupes usually do. But Hubs was fearful that it would decay, or that some accident might befall
            it if it were kept longer, and he determined to invite his employer to partake of it while he was sure of it. In truth, his
            determination was fixed from certain movements on the part
            of his wife having led him to believe that she meditated
            treating her Division street friends to a taste of it.
         </p>
         
         <p>A good opportunity having soon occurred, he asked Mr.
            Hinks to do him the favor to go home with him and partake
            of a remarkably fine cantelupe, which he had raised in his
            own garden. The mark on Mr. Hinks's cheek turned yellow
            as Hubs spoke.
         </p>
         
         <p>"By all means," replied Mr. Hinks, "but is it really a fine
            one, though, Hubs?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"Very," replied Hubs, who did not care to let out the
            whole truth, for he wished to enjoy his employer's surprise.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Then I will go to-night," said Mr. Hinks. "But, have
            you got no more than one, Hubs? you know that I am a coon
            at cantelupes."
         </p>
         
         <p>"I know it, sir," replied Hubs, "but it is a caution. Big
            enough to feed the corporation."
         </p>
         
         <p>"First rate, I dare say," said Mr. Hinks, and he winked
            his right eye knowingly, and smacked his lips, and the mark
            on his cheek glowed with a bright yellowish tinge.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs exulted inwardly, although he said nothing more in
            praise of his melon; he was burning with impatience to see
            the effect that the great reality would have upon his employer.
         </p>
         
         <p>As soon as business hours were over they got into an omnibus, a very happy pair of individuals, and in proper time
            were landed in front of Mr. Hubs's residence. Hubs would
            not allow Mr. Hinks to remain a moment in the house, but
            hurried him out into the garden to show him the miraculous
            cantelupe, lest he should doubt that it grew there.
         </p>
         
         <p>"There it is, sir," exclaimed Hubs, pointing to the mon-
            ster, "isn't it a whaler?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"Where? where?" said Mr. Hinks, gazing about.</p>
         
         <p>"Here, sir, here," replied Hubs as he patted the huge veg-
            etable.
         </p>
         
         <p>"That!" ejaculated Mr. Hinks, with a very red face.</p>
         
         <p>"Just try and lift it, sir," said Hubs, exultingly.</p>
         
         <p>"Hubs," said Mr. Hinks seriously, while the mark on his
            face changed from a yellowish hue to an ashy paleness,
            "you impertinent rascal, are you making sport of me?"
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubs was paralyzed at the manner of his employer, and
            could not speak a word.
         </p>
         
         <p>"I'll have satisfaction for this, sir," said Mr. Hinks, growing more and more indignant. "You invite me to your
            house to eat a Valparaiso pumpkin, do you, sir?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"A Valparaiso pumpkin, sir!" gasped the terrified Hubs,
            and the truth at once flashed upon his mind. "It was all
            owing to my wife's brother. O, dear! and I shall have no
            cantelupe after all!"
         </p> 
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Harry Franco.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">Alnwick Castle</div>
            <div class="biblPage">281</div>
            <p>Alnwick Castle, with other Poems. By Fitz-Greene Halleck. New
               York, Harper &amp; Brothers. 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>The system of criticism which obtains among us, and which
               tries the productions of one American mind by those of another, instead of comparing them with some immutable standard, or with the best examples in the same kind with which
               other countries have supplied us, has done great injury to the
               
            </p>
            <p>cause of true Art in our Republic. It was our misfortune to
               be in too great a hurry to have a literature of our own. We
               had built up an army and navy: we must build up a literature. It was further unanimously resolved that we had a
               national literature; and a score or two of terrified Tompkinses, who might otherwise have remained life-long the co
               tented anchorites of the poet's corner in a village newspaper,
               were suddenly snatched up and set to bear the pitiless storm
               of foreign fun and criticism on the bald lop of our American
               Parnassus. Henceforth every new work was measured by
               the 
               <span class="person" id="tompkins">Tompkins</span> yardstick; and the "precision and elegance,"
               "the refined dignity," "the exuberant humor" of 
               <span class="person" id="tompkins">Tompkins</span>
               became proverbial. Under these favorable circumstances,
               the gentlemen thus ostracised from among their fellow citizens for their country's fame, plucked up courage, and by
               dint of well-directed energy succeeded in founding what we
               may call the 
               <span class="person" id="tompkins">Tompkins</span> dynasty of American literature. A
               court dress of a certain innocuous drab-color was established,
               and any author who was detected without this 
               <span class="person" id="tompkins">Tompkins</span>
               uniform was forthwith arrested and thrown into a review, or
               set in the pillory of the newspapers. The heresy of originality was everywhere industriously hunted out and crushed;
               and independence of judgment in criticism was declared to
               be immoral, or, what was far worse, anti-Tompkinsian. If
               man, woman, or child, was unwilling to receive the opinion
               of a Tompkins, how great an insensibility did it display to
               the numerous privileges we enjoy!
            </p>
            
            <p>The truth is that we shall never have a literature until we
               become thoroughly persuaded that we have not yet done all
               that is needful to that end, and that it requires at least as
               much previous study and preparation to criticise a work of
               art as a steam engine. We must get over our cant of always
               speaking of certain of our authors and artists as if they filled
               up the majestic round of that circle which even 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>
               did not touch at all points. We must no longer endeavor to
               measure anything really great by the rushlight criticism of
               the Tompkinses, but must look on it in the broad frank sunshine of honest desire after Truth. We must get rid also of
               this unhealthy hankering after a National Literature. The
               best and most enduring literature is that which has no nationality except of the heart,--that which is the same under
               all languages and under all skies. A poet's inspiration has
               no more intimate connection with the country in which he
               chances to be bom, than with the village or the garret in
               which he may dwell. While yet a sojourner among our
               mists and shadows, he is made citizen of a higher country,
               whose language is an interpreter throughout the universe,
               and which has no words mean enough to express our paltry
               nationalities, nor indeed any thoughts but such as are primitive and universal.
            </p>
            
            <p>The office of poet, then, is the highest to which any man.
               in these latter times, may aspire. The poet has taken the
               place of the prophet, and, without laying any claim to immediate inspiration, he yet, by force of seeing the heart of those
               mysteries whose shell only is visible to others, instructs and
               prophesies with an authority felt if not acknowledged. If
               his words inculcate no truth directly, yet, by their innate
               harmony with universal laws, and by the sweet domestic
               privilege with which they enter the heart without knocking,
               they clarify the conscience, and inspire us with an eagerness
               after truth, as would a lender or majestic landscape in outward nature. Let no man then take up the lyre hastily or
               irreverently, still less let him make its chords answerable
               for a gross and vulgar music.
            </p>
            
            <p>In America we have been accustomed to confer the title
               of poet as if it were of no more value or import than a trum-
               pery "Honorable" or "Excellency." We have something
               like a thousand individuals in the country to whom the critics
               of the newspapers and magazines concede the name. But
               there are half a dozen who form a kind of inner circle, who
               already, though in the prime of life, enjoy all the advantages
               of a posthumous fame, and whose portraits smile with an
               embarrassed air opposite all the title-pages of selections from
               American poets. It is to these that our critics periodically
               challenge England to produce a parallel. It is these who are
               led out and exhibited when the intelligent foreigner inquires
               after our poets--honest, matter-of-fact-looking men, as the
               poets of a business people ought to be.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span> has had the ill fortune to be one of these frontispiecial exemplars. We call it ill fortune, for it is as unhappy a thing for a man to receive more as to receive less
               than his deserts. But in speaking of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span> we shall
               treat him as if he were a young author now for the first time
               making his appearance before the world. What his reputation has been is nothing to us: what it ought to be is the only question. To have been always considered and treated as
               one of Fame's joint-heirs, and then to find that Fame has cut
               one off with a shilling, is worse than to have known the truth
               from the beginning.
            </p>
            
            <p>If the volume before us, then, were the work of a young
               author, (and we should remember that in this case the real
               age of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">H.</span> renders all faults less inexcusable,) is there
               anything in it that would lead us to prophesy great things of
               his future career? To this question we must frankly and
               readily answer, no. There is none of that exuberance here,
               that seeming waste of energy, which characterises the springtide of a great poet's heart, of whose innumerable blossoms
               few will ever become anything more useful than an ornament and token of immortal plenty. Here is none of that felicitous sympathy of ear and eye which gives every word and
               image and harmonic invention of his as good a right to be in
               the world, as any blossom or bird or sigh of the wind can
               have. Here is none of that fine reverence which overhangs
               his heart like the broad free sky, now bare, simple, sustaining, now sprinkled thick with starry hopes and aspirations,
               and always the bestower of dignity, courage, and the calm
               majesty of entire humbleness. Here is none of that enthusiasm for his art which makes success but an argument for
               less self-glory, and which turns a whole unbelieving world's
               scorn into a stepping-stone to a higher peak of inspiration.
            </p>
            
            <p>The world is indebted to the volume before us for no new
               thought, for the opening of no new vista into the enchanted
               forest of imagination, for no new combination of the wondrous melody of words. There is none of that inspiration
               here, none of that magnetic sympathy of genius which could
               solve for the young poet the enigma of his soul, and waken
               the slumbering energies of heart and brain and will, till the
               grand images and harmonics of the master fade away, and
               he beholds only the great void future like a silent organ
               waiting but for the appointed touch to breathe divinest music and ravish the reluctant world with love and pity. But
               even in some of the yet coarser elements of a true poet, Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span> is deficient. To the simpler and more vivacious
               kinds of metre, which depend rather on a certain gross and
               physical excitement of the musical sense, his ear is competent; but he seems to lack comprehension of these whose
               meaning is more interior, and whose charm is due to remoter
               and less tangible sympathies. What ingenuity, for example,
               could make anything like rhythm of such incorrigible, corduroy joltings as these:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Even of Campbell's pen bath pictured: he.--
               
               <br></br>"To be o'erpraised even by her worshipper--Poesy"?
            </div>
            
            
            <p>Love has been so reverenced by true poets, and woman so
               worthily praised, that a poet's treatment of either of these
               hallowed subjects might almost be taken as a test of his power. Andromache and she
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"Whose face did launch a thousand ships"
               </div>
               give bloom and fragrance to the Iliad. Beatrice hangs like
               a quiet star over the sulphureous pit of 
               <span class="person" id="dalighieri">Dante</span>'s Hell, glides
               with a calming sereneness through his Purgatory, and is the
               heavenliest part of his Paradise. How unequalled are Shakspeare's pictures of women! Playful, whimsical, coquettish,
               sarcastic, yet never merely ornamental, and rounded off always with tender reverence and a pathos that gives them a
               noble dignity. And who will ever forget (to name no others)
               
               <span class="person" id="wwordsworth">Wordsworth</span>'s "Phantom of Delight" and 
               <span class="person" id="stcoleridge">Coleridge</span>'s "Genevieve"? Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span>, with all the experience of fifty years
               in his head and heart, is content to put forth the following
               verses as containing his theory of love, but at the same time,
               to prevent any ill effect upon the mind of a susceptible public, he neutralises his nonsense by an equal amount of incomprehensibility. In the first two stanzas the poet's mind
               takes a horticultural turn, and beholds love in the original
               and novel shape of a tree:
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"When the tree of Love is budding first,
                  
                  <br></br>Ere yet its leaves are green,
                  
                  <br></br>Ere yet, by shower ami sunbeam nursed,
                  
                  <br></br>No infant life has been,
                  
                  <br></br>The wild bee's slightest touch might wring
                  
                  <br></br>The buds from off the tree"--
               </div>
               Love, it will be seen, makes but an indifferent kind of tree
               and puts forth buds of most singular, though convenient fragility.
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"But when its open leaves have found
                  
                  <br></br>A home in the free air,
                  
                  <br></br>Pluck them--and there remains a wound
                  
                  <br></br>That ever rankles there."
               </div>
               Where? why?
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"The blight of hope and happiness
                  
                  <br></br>Is felt when fond ones part.
                  
                  <br></br>And the bitter tear that follows is
                  
                  <br></br>The life-blood of the heart."
               </div>
               A statement with regard to arterial circulation that would
               make 
               <span class="person" id="hervey">Hervey</span> open his eyes.--But "the tree of Love" is cut
               down in the next stanza to make a fire of.
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"When the flame of Love is kindled first,
                  
                  <br></br>'Tis the fire-fly's light at even--
                  
                  <br></br>.  .  .  .  
                  
                  <br></br>A breath can bid it bum no more."
               </div>
               Flatly contradicted by the experience of every unbreeched
               philosopher who has exercised his lungs in endeavoring to
               blow a fire-fly into a flame. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghallecke">H.</span> seems to think the success of such an experiment possible.
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"But when that flame has blazed into
                  
                  <br></br>A being and a power,
                  
                  <br></br>And smiled in scorn upon the dew
                  
                  <br></br>That fell in its first warm hour."
               </div>
               We were rather puzzled at first to think with what particular muscles a "flame" would "smile", but we had neglected
               to observe that it had "blazed into a being." Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jpespy">Espy</span>'s
               theory of rain is hinted at in the third verse, we suppose, or
               else what has the dew to do with it? We should like also
               to know which "hour" of a flame is not "warm." We must
               not be surprised to find that a flame which has already been
               a tree and has accomplished the difficult disdain of a "smile
               in scorn", should become two things at once in the next
               stanza.
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br> "'Tis the flame that curls round the martyr's head,"--
               </div>
               Our sympathies, then, for 
               <span class="person" id="hlatimer">Latimer</span>, and 
               <span class="person" id="jhuss">Huss</span>, and the rest,
               have been strangely misplaced.
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"Whose task is to destroy,
                  
                  <br></br>'Tis the lamps on the altars of the dead,
                  
                  <br></br>Whose light but darkens joy."
               </div>
               The next stanza is wholly incomprehensible:
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"Then crush even in their hour of birth,
                  
                  <br></br>The infant buds of love,
                  
                  <br></br>And tread his glowing fire to earth,
                  
                  <br></br>'Ere 'tis dark in clouds above;
                  
                  <br></br>Cherish no more a cypress tree
                  
                  <br></br>To shade thy future years,
                  
                  <br></br>Nor nurse a heart-flame that may be
                  
                  <br></br>Quenched only with thy tears."
               </div>
               In the next line a girl's Leghorn hat is said to be
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>.... Of the bright gold tint
                  
                  <br></br>The setting sunbeams give to Autumn clouds,
                  
                  <br></br>The riband that encircled it as blue
                  
                  <br></br>As spots of sky upon a moonless night
                  
                  <br></br>When stars are keeping revelry in heaven."
               </div>
               We shall expect to hear shortly of Jupiter being put into
               some celestial watch-house, or Mars relating his "experience" in a Temperance meeting.
            </p>            
            
            <p>The same young woman's waist, the poet tells us, might
               be "spanned with your thumb and finger", and
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"Her foot was loveliest of remembered things"!
                  
                  <br></br>.  .  .  .  .  .  
                  
                  <br></br>"But 'twas that foot that broke the spell--alas!
                  
                  <br></br>Its stocking had a deep, deep tinge of blue--
                  
                  <br></br>I turned away in sadness and passed on."
               </div>
               It is possible that Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span> may have the hardihood to
               defend this on the ground of its being humorous. And we
               suppose that the next poem is humorous also. If it be, we
               are sincerely glad, for it is surely nothing else. We shall
               not take the trouble to prove that humorous poetry, even
               where the humor is genuine, is the lowest kind of poetry, if,
               indeed, it can be rightly called so at all. In Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span>'s
               verses the "humor" comes in very incongruously, and gives
               all our expectations a neck-breaking jolt.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is a great deal of traditional morality and of entirely
               false sentiment in Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">H.</span>'s verses. For example, "Alnwick Castle" he says
               
               <div class="lg">
                  <br></br>"The Moslem tramples on the Greek,
                  
                  <br></br>And on the Cross and altar stone,
                  
                  <br></br>And Christendom looks tamely on,
                  
                  <br></br>.  .  .  .  
                  
                  <br></br>And not a sabre blow is given
                  
                  <br></br>For Greece and fame, for faith and heaven,
                  
                  <br></br>By Europe's craven chivalry."
               </div>
               When "faith and heaven" require to be defended by "sabre
               blows" and bloodshed, they must have sadly degenerated
               from what they were in Christ's time.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the same poem Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">H.</span> laments that the day of romance
               has gone by, a statement which he sustains by telling us
               that the Highlanders of Scotland wear pantaloons, and that
               
               <div class="lg"> 
                  <br></br>"Lord Stafford mines for coal and salt,
                  
                  <br></br>The Duke of Norfolk deals in malt,
                  
                  <br></br>The Douglas in red herrings"--
               </div>
               four facts which all the shopkeepers in New York will consider extremely ludicrous, as a matter of course, without
               thinking for a moment that all these peers are much more
               creditably employed than any of their ruffian ancestors ever
               were. Moreover, there is more that is truly poetical in the
               operations connected with mining, the raising of malt, and
               the herring fishery, than in all the "chivalry" that ever went
               about breaking the heads of peaceable neighbours and the
               hearts of their wives and children. The man who thinks
               that the age of romance has gone by to-day, would have
               thought the same in Spenser's time. Poetry is as rife in the
               world as ever, but the secret of it lies in the heart and eye
               and ear of the poet, not in any combination of circumstances.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Critical Notices</div>
         <div class="head">CRITICAL NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Prisoners of Perote</div>
            <div class="biblPage">284</div>
            
            <p>The Prisoners of Perote ; containing a Journal kept by the Author, who was
               captured by the Mexicans, at Mier, December 25, 1842, and released from
               Perote May 16, 1844. By 
               <span class="person" id="wpsnapp">William Preston Snapp</span>. New York: Burgess,
               Stringer &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a book at all points entertaining, and now and then imbued
               with a vivid and terrible interest. We quote some instances of Mexican vagrancy and audacity:--if these things were not known to be
               fact, we should speak of them as capital romance:
            </p>
            
            <p>"Among the numerous wretches who, as professional beggars,
               swarm the streets of this city, or in the filthy guise of blackened leperos, haunt the pav  by day, and prowl for plunder at night, are out.
               casts and cut-throats, whom previous convictions have deadened to
               all sense of shame, and habitual vice and indolence trained to every
               deed of violence. In the portals of the churches, beneath the walls
               of the convents, in the markets, or their lairs in the suburbs, they
               crouch to watch tor their unsuspecting prey, and wo to that unarmed
               pedestrian, who, in reply to their Por el amor de Dios, reveals a purse
               to tempt their ferocious cupidity.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Banded in fraternities, that reach from the pulque shops to the
               palace, their organization has been known to reveal itself through every grade of rank, from the roofless footpad to those nearest in authority to the president. An instance of audacity is authentically related
               to have occurred some years ago, which not unaptly illustrates the
               lawless spirit of these plunderers. The mules of a conducta were
               ranged in two tiles in the square of the Adouana (or custom-house),
               and, surrounded by a strong squadron of cavalry, waited to be
               loaded with the bags of specie, containing fifteen hundred dollars each,
               and piled up in the square to be sent off. A large crowd was as usual
               assembled to look on, when a gang of mounted thieves charged through
               the streets leading to the square, and riding down idlers and troops,
               seized each a bag of the treasure, and bore it off in triumph.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The energy of the present government has done much to reduce
               the frequency and insolence of these outrages about the capital, yet
               they continue to prevail in all their won led atrocity elsewhere through
               the republic. Not a league of their only national highway from the
               city to Vera Cruz, but is the scene of some robbery within the year,
               the public coach being repeatedly pillaged within hail of the cities
               that lie on the route.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The following notorious instance of a participation in these enormities by persons of rank, is familiar to all persons of inquiry who
               have recently been in Mexico.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The Swiss consul, (M. Mairet,) a merchant and man of fortune,
               lived in the western suburbs of the city, and was suspected to have a
               considerable sum of money about his house. His dwelling was more
               than ordinarily secure, being built in the strongest manner, with grated windows, and several ferocious dogs were kept chained in the court
               and on the terrace.
            </p>
            
            <p>"A man in the habit of a priest, accompanied by two others, appeared at his gate one day, and announced to the servant, who answered
               their summons, that they desired to purchase some merchandise of
               the consul, in which he was known to deal. Upon being admitted,
               two of them seized the servant, bound him to a pillar, and gagged
               him, whilst the third relocked the gate. All three then passed into
               the house, where they found Mairet alone, and after stabbing and
               gashing him repeatedly, finally compelled him to disclose the place
               where his treasure was secreted. This, to the amount of some
               ten thousand dollars, with various articles of valuable plate, they
               brought off; the consul only surviving his wounds long enough to relate the particulars of the affair, with such descriptions of the assassins, as it was thought would lead to their apprehension. A noisy
               search and pursuit was kept up by the police, until a miserable creature was arrested, tried, and garroted, upon the ground of some declarations said to have fallen from him whilst grossly intoxicated. No
               money or article of the plunder being found in his possession, nor
               any corroborative circumstance accompanying his insane confession
               the foreigners denounced the execution as a cowardly subterfuge of
               the government to atone for its corruption and remissness by a double
               murder.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Some time elapsed, when two daring robberies were again perpetrated in rapid succession upon wealthy monasteries of the city.
               These were entered and pillaged of more than thirty thousand dollars,
               and the church being roused and combined in the pursuit with the civil authorities, finally traced them home to the door of Colonel Janes,
               an officer of standing, and acting aid-de-camp of Santa Anna. This
               worthy colonel, having access to the passport office, was more than
               suspected of having planned several previous robberies of the public
               coach, availing himself of the information thus acquired to direct his
               accomplices where the booty was such as to indemnify an attack.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The trial of himself and his associates for the pillage of the monnasteries lasted nearly three years, every effort being made during
               this time by Santa Anna and other officials, to screen him from conviction. Their attempts, however, proving abortive, and sentence of
               death being finally awarded against him, it fell to the lot of the dictator, who had, in the meanwhile, risen to the presidency, to ratify the
               verdict, and order his execution. This he declined to do upon one
               pretext and another, granting the condemned respite after respite,
               until popular indignation became exasperated to the highest pitch.
               Dreading the fury bis equivocal course had excited in the public mind,
               and alarmed by threats of a revolutionary character, Santa Anna retired from the city, and left the task of consummating the vengeance of
               the law to General Bravo.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Janes was finally executed, and, before suffering, confessed his numerous crimes. Amongst these was the murder of Mairet, in which,
               as in all, he plead the connivance of Santa Anna, and other accomplices. He died, invoking the most direful curses upon their heads, for
               abandoning him and concurring in his death."
            </p>
            
            <p>In justice to Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="bmayer">Brantz Mayer</span>, the author of "Mexico as it Was
               and Is," we must say that the "New York Mirror" has lately pointed out some very remarkable plagiarisms from Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="bmayer">M.</span>'s book, perpetrated by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="wpsnapp">Snapp</span>.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">Remarks on an Address delivered before the New England Society</div>
            <div class="biblPage">284</div>
            
            <p>Remarks on an Address delivered before the New England Society of the City of
               New York, December 23, 1844, by 
               <span class="person" id="gpmarsh">George P. Marsh</span>. Boston: C. Stimpson.
            </p>
            
            <p>The manner of writing and punctuating the title-page of this pamphlet, is every thing. The remarks are certainly not by 
               <span class="person" id="gpmarsh">George P. Marsh</span>.
               They are by some person anonymous, and are levelled against Mr. M
               --a point which it is just as well to understand. The treatise is pungently written, but we disagree with it throughout in its estimate of
               Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="gpmarsh">Marsh</span>'s eloquence. The floridity which is objectionable in a
               written book, is not unfrequently a merit in an oration. In this case
               we can easily conceive not only that Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="gpmarsh">Marsh</span>'s oratory was enthusiastically received, but that it was skilfully planned for the purpose
               of ensuring an enthusiastic reception.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">Table-Talk</div>
            <div class="biblPage">284</div>
            
            <p>Table-Talk. By 
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">William Hazlitt</span>. Part 1. No. 6 of Wiley and Putnam's Li-
               brary of Choice Reading, pp. 200. Price 37 1-2 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a reprint of the two volumes published in Paris by Galignani,
               under the author's own supervision, the essays having been selected
               from the four volumes published by himself in London. The second
               part will comprise the essays which the author would probably have
               included in another series which he intended to publish in Paris. It
               would be hardly a remove from sheer impertinence to recommend the
               essays of 
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> to ordinary readers; he has been more universally
               read in this country than any other English essayist, if we except Macaulay. His egotism, though as obtrusive as 
               <span class="person" id="wcobbett">Cobbett</span>'s, is one of the
               charms of his style, for it is only the egotism of a dunce that is often
               sive. The two first essays in this volume, on the pleasure of painting,
               we would recommend to the consideration of all young artists who
               have not been abroad. The author had made very satisfactory progress in the art when he went to the Louvre while it contained the
               fruits of Napoleon's conquests in Italy, and he abandoned his easel.
               He saw a variety of excellence that he felt himself unable ever to
               equal, and he gave up painting in despair. Yet he had, unquestionably, the genius of a painter, and his writings on art are among the
               most valuable of his productions. His principles may be safely trusted, but his criticisms on pictures must be taken with many grains of
               allowance for his enthusiasm. He could see charms in a picture which
               no one else could discover, and as bis criticisms were generally based
               upon recollections, he sometimes attributed qualities and features to a
               work which on inspection it was found to lack. The essay in this collection on a picture by Nicolas Poussin would lead a novice to expect
               qualities in a landscape which no work of art can ever possess. The
               critic attributes to the work itself the sublime ideas which it suggested
               to his mind, but which the painter himself probably never knew
               But the essay in the collection from which most practical good maybe gained is that on the ignorance of the learned. It is just the thing
               to take the starch out of a pedant and a book-worm, and we would
               recommend it to the sensible ignorant for their consolation.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">American Facts</div>
            <div class="biblPage">284</div>
            
            <p>American Facts. Notes and Statistics relative to the government, resources,
               engagements, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c. of the United States of America. By 
               <span class="person" id="gpputnam">George
                  Palmer Putnam
               </span>, member of the New York Historical Society; Hon. Mem.
               of the Connecticut Hist. Soc., Hon. Secretary of the American Art-Union;
               Author of an introduction to history, &amp;c. With portraits and a map.
               London and New York. Wiley and Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>A handsome volume of nearly three hundred pages, containing a large
               amount of statistics, well calculated to enlighten English readers in
               respect to this country. We cannot understand the motive of the
               author in affixing to a work of this kind such a ponderous joke
               as the absurd review of British poets which appeared in the
               North American Review a year ago. It cannot surely help the sale
               of the book in London, and it will hardly have the effect of soothing
               any of the harsh feelings which may be still entertained by English
               writers towards American authors, or the American people at large.
               It is attaching too much importance to the paltry jealousy or ill nature of an anonymous scribbler to make his niaseries the subject of national recriminations. The portraits are chiefly valuable as being impressions from plates produced by the nearly discovered process of
               multiplying prints.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">Count Ludwig</div>
            <div class="biblPage">284</div>
            
            <p>Count Ludwig, and other romances. By 
               <span class="person" id="cdickens">Charles Dickens</span>, with stories by
               
               <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Jerrold</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="tmoore">Moore</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="whainsworth">Ainsworth</span>, and 
               <span class="person" id="acunningham">Allan Cunningham</span>. Now first collected
               into a single vol. H. G. Daggers, 30 Ann st. Price 25 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>Count Ludwig is one of the most remarkable of its author's productions, as containing not the slightest evidence of his peculiar and brilliant genius. The changes of an author's style forms a curious chapter
               in the history of literature, and the study of Count Ludwig in contrast
               with the other writings of 
               <span class="person" id="cdickens">Boz</span>, is an interesting subject for the
               critic.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Apochryphal New Testament</div>
            <div class="biblPage">285</div>
            
            <p>The Apochryphal New Testament, containing all the Gospels, Epistles, and
               other pieces, not included in the New Testament, by its compilers. Translated and now first collected into one volume. New York. Published by
               H.	G. Daggers, 30 Ann st.
            </p>
            
            <p>The importance of this publication to all Bible students may be inferred from the following passage in the translator's preface to the
               second English edition.
            </p>
            
            <p>"By some persons of the multitude commonly known by the name
               of Christians, and who profess to suppose they do God service by calling themselves so, the editor has been assailed with a malignity and
               fury that would have graced the age of Elizabeth and Mary."
            </p>
            
            <p>The volume is handsomely printed on good paper in a shape uniform
               with the ordinary editions of the genuine New Testament.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">History of Germany</div>
            <div class="biblPage">285</div>
            
            <p>History of Germany, from the earliest period to the present time. By 
               <span class="person" id="hftkohlrausch">Frederick Kohlrausch</span> translated from the last German edition, by 
               <span class="person" id="jdhaas">James D.
                  Haas
               </span>. Appleton and Co., 200 Broadway. Part 2d, 25 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>The present number of this admirable history reaches to the middle
               of the fourteenth century. The work will be complete in three more
               numbers, and will form a most valuable and much needed addition to
               historical libraries.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Specimens of Ancient Oracular and Fighting Eolipiles</div>
            <div class="biblPage">285</div>
            
            <p>Specimens of Ancient Oracular and Fighting Eolipiles: with remarks on Dragons and other fire breathing monsters of mythology and the middle ages,
               being a supplement to his treatise on hydraulics and mechanics; by Thomas 
               <span class="person" id="tewbank">Ewbank</span>. New York. Published by the Author. 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>This supplement to the large work on Hydraulics, by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="tewbank">Ewbank</span>,
               will render that treatise the most learned and perfect one on that
               branch of science in existence. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="tewbank">Ewbank</span> is a double enthusiast,
               for he seems to have given as much thought and research to the moral demons and dragons of antiquity as to those of metal, wood and
               stone.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p16">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Magazines</div>
         <div class="biblPage">285</div>
         <div class="head">THE MAGAZINES.</div>
         
         <p>The Aristidean.--The April, or second number of the Aristidean,
            is a decided improvement on the first. Some of the papers are exceedingly good--precisely what Magazine papers should be--vigorous,
            terse, and independent. "Travels in Texas" is very interesting.
            "Richard Parker's Widow" is also admirable; and "Hans Spiegen"
            is quite in the Blackwood vein. There is a long review or rather running commentary upon 
            <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>'s poems. It is, perhaps, a little
            coarse, but we are not disposed to call it unjust; although there are
            in it some opinions which, by implication, are attributed to ourselves
            individually, and with which we cannot altogether coincide. "Shood
            Swing is queer, and the "Notes about Men of Note" are amusing. Of
            the political papers we shall not speak. There is not much verse in
            the number, but some of it is admirable. "The Necessity of Strangling" is worthy of Hood, and "The Hanging of Polly Bodine" is
            perhaps a better thing in the same way. To show how high an opinion we entertain of the lines with the wretched title of "A HeartBurst," we will take the liberty of purloining them in full. They are,
            we think, the composition of the editor, Mr. English, and it is many a
            long day since we have seen anything so truly beautiful--in its peculiar mode of beauty:
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Fill me no cup of Xeres' wine to her my heart holds dear;
            
            <br></br>If you insist to pledge with me, then drop a silent tear.
            
            <br></br>For she I love is far away, and months must pass before
            
            <br></br>Her heart shall leap to hear again my foot-tramp at the door.
            
            <br></br>And thus apart, my weary heart, torn both with hopes and fears,
            
            <br></br>Gives to my spirit wretchedness, and to my eyelids tears.
            
            <br></br>You laugh and quaff your Xeres' wine around the festive board,
            
            <br></br>And jest with names of those you love, which secret you should hoard;
            
            <br></br>And I conceal how much I feel, for words could not express
            
            <br></br>The sorrow weeping in my heart, the abject wretchedness,
            
            <br></br>Illumined by a single hope--God grant it not in vain!--
            
            <br></br>That foes may cease to part our hearts, and we may meet again.
         </div>
         
         <p>In mechanical execution--that is to say, in its general external and
            internal arrangement, the "Aristidean" is infinitely before any American magazine:--although the cover, perhaps, might be improved.
            In regard to its morale, the rock on which it seems most in danger of
            splitting is coarseness of vituperation. But if we are to choose between this and namby-pambyism, give us by all means not the latter.
            We sincerely wish the editor all the success which his vigorous abilities deserve.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Review</div>
         <div class="head">MUSICAL REVIEW.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">Melodies</div>
            <div class="biblPage">285</div>
            <p>Melodies, by J. T. S. Sullivan, adapted to Airs, selected from the German
               Italian and French Composers. Published by George W. Appleton, 148
               Chesnut street, Philadelphia.
            </p>
            
            <p>Such is the title of a typed, or rather stereotyped work of some
               pretension. How it will support this pretension we shall see anon.
               We have heard of poems of every description being adapted to melodies, but we must candidly confess that we never before heard of Melodies being adapted to Airs. 
               <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span> and 
               <span class="person" id="tmoore">Moore</span> wrote words to Hebrew and Irish Melodies, and the joint production (words and music)
               was known as the Hebrew Melodies or the Irish Melodies. We think
               that it would be advisable to alter the title to one more comprehensive.
            </p>
            
            <p>The composers from whose works the airs are selected, are F.
               Schubert, Bellini, F. Wollank, and G. Doering, besides two airs, composers' names not known. We think the selection very poor; they are,
               in fact, the veriest musical trifles that have come under our notice for
               a considerable period. From such an inexhaustible stock of good materials, it is really a matter for wonder, that six such unimportant
               melodies or airs should have been chosen. It must have cost considerable trouble to pick them out. The music of Germany and France is
               particularly rich in songs, romances, and chorusses, and the amount
               of the beautiful in them is truly great. It would be a valuable gift to
               the musical world, if an extensive and judicious selection were made
               from these gems, and we believe Mr. Sullivan to be eminently calculated to adapt the poetry to them. We can find nothing to condemn
               in the present poetical portion of the work before us. It is carefully
               executed, the accentuation is well preserved, and the sentiments justly conceived. We are pleased to be able to compliment Mr. Sullivan
               upon his taste.
            </p>            
            
            <p>Where Art Thou, words by Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="norton">Norton</span>, are by no means adapted to
               the air Oft in the Stilly Night, there being one or two feet more in every
               line of her poem than there are in 
               <span class="person" id="tmoore">Moore</span>'s. To adapt them, therefore,
               would require additional notes, to commence on the third beat, instead
               of the first of the bar, which would materially alter the character of
               the music. Why this poem is placed in this collection, (unless to fill
               up a space) especially as the music is not given, we are at a loss to
               understand. We like the idea of the work much, and it is probable
               that the selections may improve. We wish the undertaking every
               success, and hope to be able to give a more flattering account of the
               next number.
            </p>
            
            <p>Clydesdale Farewell, a Scottish ballad, written and composed by
               
               <span class="person" id="jlawson">James Lawson</span>. This ballad is written and composed by an amateur.
               Music owes a considerable debt of gratitude to musical amateurs, for
               the interest they take in the art, and for the many admirable contributions they have given to the world. The names of Lord Onslow,
               the Earl of Mornington, Beale, Rogers, and very many others, will be
               remembered by musicians with pleasure. We have, to be sure, very
               frequently to be lenient to the effect, for the sake of the cause.
            </p>
            
            <p>The ballad before us is simple and pretty. The composer has aimed at an imitation of the Scottish character, and if the imitation be
               not very close, it is at least near enough to fix the idea. The arrangement is very easy, and the vocal part ranges within the compass of
               very little more than an octave. It will doubtless find many admirers
               and numerous purchasers.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">Bertini's Piano Forte Method</div>
            <div class="biblPage">285</div>
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">BERTINI</span>'S PIANO FORTE METHOD. Published by W. H. Okes, and for sale by
               E. H. Wade, 197 Washington st. Boston.
            </p>
            
            <p>Our remarks upon this celebrated Instruction Book, have called forth
               many enquiries from various quarters, and as it is impossible for us to
               answer them individually, we take this opportunity to answer them
               en masse.
            </p>
            
            <p>What we have before said upon the excellences of this work, we find
               fully confirmed upon closer examination, and we have the testimony
               of many eminent men to the fact of its admirable adaptation to the use
               of students, and of its inevitable effect in producing brilliant and certain players, undeviating timeists, and in imparting a thorough theoretical knowledge of the necessary principles of music, and a sterling
               and classical method of performance.
            </p>
            
            <p>We ourselves, have daily evidence of the benefit conferred upon pupils by the adoption of 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s method; not alone in the mechanical
               but in the mental portion of the art, which is, after all, of the highest
               importance to the beginner, for unless the mind perceives and comprehends what the hands have to execute, the progress must be slow and
               unsatisfactory in the extreme. The most intelligent master, without
               the assistance of some such work as this, and there is no work extant so perfect, must find an almost unconquerable difficulty in making
               clear to the perception of the pupil the minute divisions of time, and
               
               other particulars, which, though trifling in themselves, yet serve to
               make up an amount of mystery, to a youthful mind, hard to unravel.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of course these mysteries have been unravelled; each master having some particular plan or method to elucidate the system. But how
               much labor may be saved the master; how much mental puzzling and
               memory-staving may be spared the pupil, when a work is used which
               will lighten the toil of both. We have had many years' experience in
               the instruction of young people, and have groaned in spirit for ourselves, and have mourned no less for those, who, lacking in quick appreciation, have toiled and struggled on through what must have appeared to them an endless sea of difficulty, and can, therefore, fully
               appreciate to the fullest extent all the advantages offered by the
               Method of Bertini.
            </p>
            
            <p>We promised in our notice of this work, to advise our young friends
               upon certain important and admirable portions of the Method for particular practice. We are unable to do so in this notice, from want of
               space. But we will do so, by and bye, as we do not think that too
               much attention can be drawn to an elementary work of such undoubted merit.
            </p>
            
            <p>To those of our professional friends who have not already examined
               it, we earnestly recommend an early and faithful perusal of the work,
               for we feel convinced, that its general use will do more to correct the
               imperfect and superficial system of musical education now but too
               prevailing, than all that can be written or urged by the united power
               of the press.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">Piano-Fortes</div>
            <div class="biblPage">286</div>
            <p>Piano-Fortes.--We recommend our musical friends to call at the
               store of Mr. T. H. Chambers, 385 Broadway, and try a seven octave
               instrument, which is now on exhibition there. It is really a most
               lovely instrument. It is clear, brilliant and powerful in tone, and at
               the same time sweet and melodious. The touch is light, free and
               springy, and the form is elegant and unique. He has many fine pianos
               in his store, but we desire to call particular attention to this one, as
               we think that it is one of the finest he has ever turned out.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Items</div>
         <div class="head">ITEMS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">Park Theatre</div>
            <div class="biblPage">286</div>
            <p>Park Theatre.--Mr. Anderson has just closed an engagement at
               this establishment, which has proved beyond a doubt, the most profitable and the most honorable, both to the manager and the actor, to
               be found on record for many years. Mr. Anderson has won for himself
               the universal praise of the press, and he is the acknowledged and
               prime favorite of the public. He has won his laurels justly, and may
               he wear them long.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">Olympic Theatre</div>
            <div class="biblPage">286</div>
            <p>Olympic Theatre.--This popular place of amusement, finished on
               Wednesday last, a season of the most unparalleled success. Mr. Mitchell is undoubtedly the wisest and the most far-seeing of managers.
               His success cannot be attributed to individual excellence, but rather to
               the perfect ensemble. He deals not with stars, but he gathers around
               him a first-rate working team which he fashions to his hand, adapting
               them to the wants and the tastes of the public. Every novelty abroad
               --adapted to his company and his audience, finds its way to his theatre in advance of all competitors. He is indefatigable in catering to
               the amusement of the public, and hence his unwavering success.
               Mr. Mitchell departs upon a professional tour next week. He will
               visit Boston first we believe.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">Concert for the Benefit of Mr. W. Alpers</div>
            <div class="biblPage">286</div>
            <p>Concert for the Benefit of Mr. W. Alpers.--It is proposed, we
               understand, to give a grand concert in a short time, for the benefit of
               Mr. Alpers, who has been laboring for a considerable period under severe sickness. We are sure that every member of the profession will
               volunteer their services with hearty good will upon the occasion, for
               Mr. Alpers is esteemed and respected upon every hand. We know
               him to be one of the most worthy members of the profession--talented, learned, accomplished, and willing to assist all who are in need of
               his assistance.
            </p>
            
            <p>We earnestly appeal to the public and the profession, to come forward and give substantial evidence of their appreciation of his merits,
               upon this deeply interesting and truly sad occasion.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mary Taylor</div>
            <div class="biblPage">286</div>
            <p>Mary Taylor, it is said, will proceed to Boston, after the closing of
               the Olympic, which will lake place this week, and returns to fulfill an
               engagement at Niblo's, which will open early in June.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mr. George Loder</div>
            <div class="biblPage">286</div>
            <p>Mr. George Loder has become the organist of Grace Church, and is
               succeeded in the Market St. church by Mr. Bristow, who is succeeded
               by Mr. Harrison in St. Patrick's Cathedral. Instability is the order of
               the day.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         <div class="biblTitle">National Nomenclature</div>
         <div class="biblPage">286</div>
         <div class="head">NATIONAL NOMENCLATURE.</div>
         
         <p>Although we have approved the recommendation of the Committee of the Historical Society, in regard to changing the national name,
            yet we must acknowledge that we have had but little faith that the
            people would be influenced by the recommendation. Names of countries must be of spontaneous generation, but when one is given by
            law it may be as well not to disturb it. As our nation extends its
            boundaries, the States must grow more provincial, and from necessity
            the people will be called after their provinces rather than the continent which they inhabit. We shall learn to call each other, and shall
            be distinguished abroad as Vermonters, Virginians or Texans. But
            there is a difficulty in the awkward names of some of the Slates--as
            Massachusetts, Ohio, New Hampshire, &amp;c. Necessity, however, who
            is always ready with an invention, when one is needed, will never fail
            to supply a nick-name without the help of any other society than society at large. The following list of national nick-names, which we
            cut from an exchange paper, shows how little we need apprehend a
            dearth of distinctive titles by which we may be known.
         </p>
         
         <p>The inhabitants of
            Maine, are called	Foxes.
            New Hampshire,	Granite boys.
            Massachusetts,	Bay Staters.
            Vermont,	Green Mountain Boys.
            Rhode-Island,	Gun Flints.
            Connecticut,	Wooden Nutmegs.
            New York,	Knickerbockers.
            New Jersey,	Clam-catchers.
            Pennsylvania,	Leatherheads.
            Delaware,	Musk-rats.
            Maryland,	Craw-thumpers.
            Virginia,	Beagles.
            North Carolina,	Tar-boilers.
            South Carolina,	Weasels.
            Georgia,	Buzzards.
            Louisiana,	Cre-owls.
            Alabama,	Lizards.
            Kentucky,	Corn-crackers.
            Tennessee,	Cotton-manies.
            Ohio,	Buck-eyes.
            Indiana,	Hoosiers.
            Illinois,	Suckers.
            Missouri,	Pewks.
            Mississippi,	Tadpoles.
            Arkansas,	Gophers.
            Michigan,	Wolverines.
            Florida.	Fly-up-the-Creeks.
            Wisconsin,	Badgers.
            Iowa,	Hawkeyes.
            N. W. Territory,	Prairie Dogs.
            Oregon,	Hard Cases.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p26">
         <div class="biblTitle">Popular Lectures</div>
         <div class="biblPage">286</div>
         
         <p>Popular Lectures.--We looked into some forty or fifty exchange
            papers one day last week, and found in every one of them, from city
            and country, Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Caudle</span>'s lectures from Punch. This led us first to
            read them and then to reflect on the cause of their popularity. They
            are evidently a hit. Yet they possess no particular interest, no story,
            no plot, no wit, no puns, nothing thrilling or exciting, but only a few
            little touches of nature which have found admission into every heart
            at which they have knocked. We will venture to assert that no lady
            will see anything to admire or laugh at in Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Caudle</span>'s lectures.
            But they are immensely popular among husbands, who have all heard
            something like them, and out of pure spile to their Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Caudles</span>, all
            who have newspapers under their control, publish the lectures to let
            the world into secrets that they dare not directly divulge. 
            <span class="person" id="lblanchard">Laman
               Blanchard
            </span> has been named as the author of these popular lectures,
            but that is an error: they are by another hand. Let him be who he
            may, he relates his own experiences; there is more truth in Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Cau</span>dle's curtain lectures than in any course of scientific lectures that we
            are acquainted with. Dr. 
            <span class="person" id="dlardner">Lardner</span>'s were not half so popular because
            they were not half so true.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p27">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Way They Do Things in England</div>
         <div class="biblPage">286</div>
         
         <p>The Way they do things in England.--The Committee of the
            Royal Corporation of the Literary Fund, at its meeting on Wednesday
            the 19th ult. unanimously voted 100l. towards the fund now raising for
            the benefit of the family of the late 
            <span class="person" id="lblanchard">Laman Blanchard</span>.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p28">
         <div class="biblTitle">Mr. Howitt</div>
         <div class="biblPage">286</div>
         
         <p>We learn that Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="whowitt">Howitt</span> is engaged on a work which has occupied
            more or less of his attention for some years, viz. "Visits to the Birthplaces and Resorts of the most eminent English Poets." It will include not only visits to many of the most interesting spots in England,
            Ireland, and Scotland, but also in Switzerland, Italy, &amp;c.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p29">
         <div class="biblTitle">Notice</div>
         <div class="biblPage">286</div>
         <p>Notice.-- The Office of the Broadway Journal has been
            removed from 153 Broadway to 135 Nassau Street, Clinton
            Hall Buildings.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">287</div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DESIGNING AND ENGRAVING
               ON WOOD.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">SAMUEL E. BROWN, 70 Nassau Street, Corner of
               
               <br></br>John, New York.
               
               <br></br>Portraits, Views of Buildings, Scenery. Original Designs, &amp;c. &amp;c.
               furnished
               
               <br></br>at this establishment.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">MR. AND MRS. KIRKLAND'S</div>
            
            <div class="head">SCHOOL FOR YOUNG LADIES,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">
               <br></br>No. 255 Greene Street,
               
               <br></br>One door above Waverly Place, New York.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS School differs essentially from most others in
               this city, in one particular: the number admitted is so limited that each
               scholar receives the personal attention and instruction of the principals.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Kirkland resided some years in Europe for the express purpose of
               qualifying himself as an instructor.
            </p>
            
            <p>The French language is taught by an approved master, a native of France;
               and every facility is afforded for practice, both in the school and in the
               family.
            </p>
            
            <p>The plan of instruction embraces three divisions. The Initiatory Course includes Grammar, Geography, American History, Writing and Arithmetic,
               with Composition. Reading aloud, Spelling and Definition, form part of the
               daily exercises of the whole school.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Second continues the above-named studies, with the addition of An-
               cient and Modern History and the French Language.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the higher or ?sthetic course all the usual branches of a thorough En-
               glish course of education are included, with French, German, Latin and
               Greek, according to the wish of the parent and the capacity of the scholar.
            </p>
            
            <p>Pupils in this course pay particular attention to Poetry, to the art of Composition, and to the Philosophy of History. Moral Philosophy is taught
               from
               
               <span class="person" id="jdymond">Dymond</span>, as abridged and prepared for schools by Mrs. Kirkland. Lectures
               on various subjects are delivered by Mr. and Mrs. Kirkland, and others; and
               the general course of study is advanced and rendered interesting by copious
               illustrations from French and English Literature.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS.
               
               <br></br>Primary Course, - - - $12 50 Per Quarter
               
               <br></br>Second " (including French, &amp;c.) 18 00 "
               
               <br></br>Third, or highest course, - - 15 00 "
               
               <br></br>Music--Piano Forte,  -   -   -   15 00 "
               
               <br></br>  "   Singing,  -   -   -   15 00 "
               
               <br></br>Drawing,  -   -   -   10 00 "
               
               <br></br>Dancing,  -   -   -   12 00 "
               
               <br></br>For Board, (payable Quarterly in advance,) $175 per Annum.
               
               <br></br>Board during vacation, at the same rate.
               
               <br></br>The young ladies are required to bring towels, spoons, fork and napkin
               
               <br></br>ring--every article fully marked,
               
               <br></br>Washing $7 50 per Quarter.
               
               <br></br>No Extras--whether for fuel, use of instruments, or any thing not here
               
               <br></br>specified.
               
               <br></br>Pupils received at any time, and charged in proportion only.
               
               <br></br>References to parents and guardians given if desired.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE UNITED STATES MAGAZINE AND DE-
               MOCRATIC REVIEW, for May, 1845.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">CONTENTS.
               
               <br></br>1. The Mexican Question.
               
               <br></br>2. New Orleans as I found it.
               
               <br></br>3. English Letter Writers. By 
               <span class="person" id="wajones">W. A. Jones</span>.
               
               <br></br>4. Bedreddin's Tarts, or the Consequences of an Indigestion.
               
               <br></br>5. On Writing for the Magazines.
               
               <br></br>6. Brallaghan, or the Deipnosophists.
               
               <br></br>7. Legends of the Lakes. No. 1. By Rev. 
               <span class="person" id="rhoyt">Ralph Hoyt</span>.
               
               <br></br>8. Education. By 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Henry Norman Hudson</span>.
               
               <br></br>9. The Journal of an American Cruiser. By an officer of the U.S. Navy.
               
               <br></br>10. Alleghan; or Alleghania America.
               
               <br></br>11. Connet. By 
               <span class="person" id="httuckerman">N. H. T. Tuckerman</span>.
               
               <br></br>12. The Young American. By 
               <span class="person" id="aheverett">Alex. H. Everett</span>.
               
               <br></br>I3. The Friends. From the German of 
               <span class="person" id="ltieck">Ludwig Tieack</span>.
               
               <br></br>14. Monthly Financial and Commercial Article.
               
               <br></br>15. New Books of the Month.
               
               <br></br>16. Literary Bulletin.
               
               <br></br>17. Miscellany.--The Antigone at Palmo's; Mr. Anderson in Beaumont
               
               <br></br>and Fletcher; the Drama and Mr. Murdoch.
               
               <br></br>18. New York Historical Society.
               
               <br></br>Note to the Article on Alleghan.
               
               <br></br>HENRY G. LANGLEY, 8 Astor House.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE B HM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">(NEW INVENTION.)
               
               <br></br>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the Conservatorie at
               
               <br></br>Paris, and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
            </div>
            
            <p>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the "B hm
               FLUTE," 110 FULTON ST. N.Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of
               the cities the above Important Invention, which has been so enthusiastically
               received and generally used by the most distinguished European Artists, feels
               happy in being able to place before them the following testimonial to its
               merits, signed by two or the moat distinguished of our resident Artists.
               We hereby certify to the the excellence of B hm Flute as manufactured
               by Mr. J.D. Larrabee; to the beauty of its tone, the perfection of its tune,
               and the simplicity of its fingering, which readers a brilliant execution
               comparatively easy.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">PHILIP ERNST (who has already introduced it
               
               <br></br>successfully among his pupils.
               
               <br></br>JOHN A. KYLE, Principal Flute of the Philhar-
               
               <br></br>monic Society and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the B hm
               Flute,
               
               <br></br>41 Forsyth street, New York.
               
               <br></br>Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory, 110
               
               <br></br>Fulton st. and judge for themselves.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">JOHN DOUGLAS,
               BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 68 ANN STREET.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">--A. H. GALE &amp; CO.'S WARE-
               
               <br></br>Rooms, No. 239 Broadway--Manufactory Third Avenue, corner of 13th
               
               <br></br>street.
            </div>
            
            <p>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assortment of
               Rosewood and Mahogany Piano-Fortes, with from six to seven octaves, embracing ever variety of patterns, made in their well known substantial manner, under their immediate and personal superintendence, by skillful
               and
               experienced mechanics, from the best seasoned materials.
            </p>
            
            <p>These instruments embrace many important improvements, which will recommend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of
               perfection, with
               the best French grand action, warranted in every respect by the manufacturer.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to
               Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the larest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most
               superior
               quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone.
               Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano
               Fortes aways on hire.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their
               numerous friends and to the public, would, atthe same time, call attentton to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just
               finished, in
               elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.
               The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of the
               business, have been enabled to and several important improvements to the
               action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNHAM.
               
               <br></br>361 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>Manufactory 13th St., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
               
               <br></br>N. B.--A good second-hand Piano Forte for sale.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">--V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as iron frames,
               &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the
               result of
               23 years experience in the business.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">F. RILEY &amp; CO.,</div>
            <p> No. 297 Broadway, (between
               Reade and Duane streets,) New York, Publishers of Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition
               to their
               own catalogue, (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep on hand
               he publications of all the principal Music houses. Thev are erecting a large
               Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes of a superior quality
               will be constantly kept on hand.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO - FORTES.</div>
            <p>--JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, Corner
               of
               Cottage-place and Bleecker Street, which he will sell at prices unusually low.
               J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twenty
               years, and for a large portion of that time manufacturer for two of the largest Music Stores in this city, feels warranted in saying that his
               instruments
               will bear a favorable chmparison with those of the best makers in this country or Eurepe, and that they contain all the real improvements of the
               day.
               Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and Repaired.
               New York, April 23d. 1845.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,
               PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.
               
               <br></br>a large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
               
               <br></br>TERMS MODERATE.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">BERTINI'S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
               work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method
               the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prom-
               inent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies,
               are
               given in such PROGRESSIVE order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
               carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
               otherwise, are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
               has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,
               and it is only by the study of such methods as 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s that pupils, will be en
               abled to READ music with facility, and at the same time become good musi
               cians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the rud-
               ments of music being given and illustrated at the same time and each lesson
               is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest reccommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">BERTINI</span>'s
               METHOD
               over all others yet published in this country, most of them having used the
               foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
               names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">BOSTON 
               
               <br></br>Messrs. G.J. Webb 
               
               <br></br>J.G. Maedar. 
               
               <br></br>H.T. Hach. 
               
               <br></br>E.L. White. 
               
               <br></br>David Paine. 
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek. 
               
               <br></br>T.B. Moses. 
               
               <br></br>NEW YORK.
               
               <br></br>Messrs. H.C. Timm.
               
               <br></br>W. Alpers.
               
               <br></br>U.C. Hill.
               
               <br></br>F.H. Brown.
               
               <br></br>PHILADELPHIA
               
               <br></br>B.C. Cross.
               
               <br></br>Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>ALBANY--O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professor, and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work
               American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">SHEPARD</div>
            
            <p>IS SELLING BOOKS AND STATIONARY AS
               cheap as ever.
               He has added a large assortment of Books bought at very low prices at
               the late trade sale.
               
               <span class="person" id="bgniebuhr">Niebuhr</span>'s Rome, just published at $5, he will sell far below that price.
               Encyclopedia Americana, in 13 vols., he will sell low enough.
               He has also added a beautiful assortment of Gold Pencils--some of which
               he will sell as low as $1,87 1-2 cents, warranted.
               Another lot of that beautiful Letter Paper at $1,50 per ream--well worth
               $2,25.
               Please call and see if you cannot buy to suit you at
               SHEPARD'S, 191 Broadway,
               opposite John street.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">NOW READY,
               No. VI. of
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'S
               LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING,
            </div>
            
            <p>TABLE-TALK--Opinions on Books, Men, and
               Things, by 
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">William Hazlitt</span>. Part 1, price 37 1-2 cents.
               CONTENTS.
               Publisher's Advertisement.
               1. On the Pleasure of Painting.
               2. The same subject.
               3. On the Past and Future.
               4. On People with one Idea.
               5. On the Ignorance of the Learned.
               6. On Will-Making.
               7. On a Landscape of Nicholas Poussin.
               8. On Going a Journey.
               9. Why Distant Objects please.
               10. On Corporate Bodies.
               11. On the Knowledge of Character.
               12. On the Fear of Death.
               13. On Application to Study.
               14. On the Old Age of Artists.
               15. On Egotism.
               16. On the Regal Character.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. VII.
               
               <br></br>HEADLONG HALL AND NIGHTMARE ABBEY. 37 1-2
               
               <br></br>cents.
               
               <br></br>NO. VIII.
               
               <br></br>THE FRENCH IN ALGIERS. 1. The Soldier of the Foreign
               
               <br></br>Legion. 2. The Prisoners of Abd-el-Kader. From German and French
               
               <br></br>sources, by 
               <span class="person" id="ldgordon">Lady Duff Gordon</span>, translator of the Amber Witch. 37 1-2 cents.
               
               <br></br>IN PRESS,
               
               <br></br>EVENINGS WITH THE OLD STORY TELLERS. Ancient
               
               <br></br>Moral Tales from the Gesta Romanorum.
               
               <br></br>IMAGINARY CONVERSATIONS, by 
               <span class="person" id="wslandor">Walter Savage Landor</span>.
               
               <br></br>
               <span class="person" id="jhlhunt">LEIGH</span> HUNT'S INDICATOR.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
               The first Premium awarded fire years by the American Institute for the
               best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">GOLDSMITH</span>'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">GOLDSMITH</span>'S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed 10 all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms Reduced to TWO DOLLARS
               AND A HALF.
               Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
               Class Hours--9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen
               and from 11 to 1 o'clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
               For sale "
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">Goldsmith</span>'s Gems or Penmanship," elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISBROW'S RIDING SCHOOL,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette
               
               <br></br>Places. New York.
               
               <br></br>Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Even-
               
               <br></br>ing, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS:
               
               <br></br>Lecture Lessons.
               
               <br></br>16 Lessons. . . . . . . . . . $15	00	
               
               <br></br>10	 "	   . . . . . . . . . . 10	00
               
               <br></br>4	 "	     . . . . . . . . . . 5	00
               
               <br></br>Single Lessons . . . . . . . .2 00
               
               <br></br>Road   "	       . . . . . . . 2 50
               
               <br></br>Exercise Riding.
               
               <br></br>1	Month. . . . . . . . . .$12 00
               
               <br></br>20	Rides. . . . . . . . . . 10 00
               
               <br></br>10	 "	   . . . . . . . . . .  6 00
               
               <br></br>Single Rides. . . . . . . . .0 75
               
               <br></br>N. B.--Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let.
               
               <br></br>Evening Class.
               
               <br></br>12 Lessons................$9 00 | 20 Rides.............$10 00
               
               <br></br>Single "................. 1 00 | Single Ride........... 0 75
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">RULES:
               
               <br></br>1.	All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.
               
               <br></br>2.	One hour allow ed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.
               
               <br></br>3.	One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.
               
               <br></br>4.	Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 3 P. M.
               
               <br></br>5.	Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.
               
               <br></br>6.	No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladies.
               
               <br></br>A card of address is requested previous to commencing.
               
               <br></br>N. B. Gentlemen keeping their horses at this establishment, will have the
               
               <br></br>privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            </div>
         </div> 
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE
               SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published Monthly at Richmond, Va.; price Five Dollars per Year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835,
               has a large subscription list among the  lite of the Southern Aristocracy,
               and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
               Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the "Broadway Jour-
               nal," 153 Broadway.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">IMPORTANT WORKS FOR PUBLIC LIBRARIES,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">FOR SALE BY
               
               <br></br>BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, NEW YORK.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE TRANSACTIONS OF THE ROYAL SOCI-
               
               <br></br>ETY OF LONDON, or Philosophical Transactions, from the
               
               <br></br>commencement, in 1665 to 1800. By Drs. 
               <span class="person" id="chutton">Hutton</span> and 
               <span class="person" id="tshaw">Shaw</span>;
               
               <br></br>in 18 vols. 4 to., and from 1600 to 1835, in 36 vols., together
               
               <br></br>54 vols. royal, 4 to. uniformly bound in half calf. $250 00
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE ARCHAEOLEGIA; or Miscellaneous Tracts, relating to
               
               <br></br>Antiquity, by the Society of Antiquaries of Sweden, complete
               
               <br></br>from the beginning in 1770 to 1843, in 30 vols. uniformly
               
               <br></br>bound in half russia. 225 00
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE DELPHIN EDITION OF THE LATIN CLASSICS; by
               
               <br></br>Valpy, with various notes, the best edition, (published at  150
               
               <br></br>sterling) in 142 vols. 8 vo. boards. 200 00
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">PINKERTONS' COLLECTIONS OF VOYAGES AND TRAV-
               
               <br></br>ELS in various parts of the world, 17 large vols., 4 to. half
               
               <br></br>bound in calf. 70 00
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">
               <span class="person" id="pbayle">BAYLE</span>'S GREAT HISTORICAL AND CRITICAL DICTION-
               
               <br></br>ARY; by 
               <span class="person" id="pdesmaizeaux">Des Maizeaux</span>, best edition, 5 vols. folio, bound in
               
               <br></br>calf. 30 00
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">ANDERSONS'BRITISH POETS; from Chaucer lo Warton; 14
               
               <br></br>vols. royal 8 vo. bound in calf extra. 40 00
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">COLONEL 
               <span class="person" id="rwhvyse">VYSE</span>'S ACCOUNT OF OPERATIONS CARRIED
               
               <br></br>ON IN EXPLORING THE PYRAMIDS OF EGYPT; with
               
               <br></br>numerous plates; 3 vols. 4 to. 14 00
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="ab">REPUBLICATION OF THE FOREIGN MAGAZINES.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">LONDON, EDINBURGH, FOREIGN, and WEST-
               
               <br></br>MINSTER QUARTERLY REVIEWS, and BLACKWOOD'S MAGA-
               
               <br></br>ZINE.
            </div>
            
            <p>The above Periodicals are reprinted in New-York, immediately on their
               arrival by the British steamers, in a beautiful clear type, on line white paper
               and are faithful copies of the originals--Blackwood's Magazine being an exact fac-simile of the Edinburgh Edition.
            </p>
            
            <p>The wide spread fame of these splendid Periodicals renders it needless to
               say much to their praise. As literary organs, they stand far in advance of
               any works of a similar stamp now published, while their political complexion
               is marked by a dignity, candor, ana forbearance not often found in works of
               a party character.
            </p>
            
            <p>They embrace the views of the three great parties in England, Whig, Tory,
               and Radical. "Blackwood" and the "London Quarterly" are Tory; the
               "Edinburgh Review" Whig; and the "Westminster" Radical. The "Foreign Quarterly" is purely literary, being devoted principally to
               criticisms on
               foreign Continental Works.
            </p>
            
            <p>The prices of the Re-Prints are less than one third of those of the foreign
               copies; and while they are equally well got up, they afford all that advantage to the American over the English reader.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS.--Payment to be made in Advance.
               
               <br></br>For the four Quarterly Reviews, $8.00 per annum,
               
               <br></br>For any three   "    "    7.00  "
               
               <br></br>For any two     "    "    5.00  "
               
               <br></br>For any one     "    "    3.00  "
               
               <br></br>For Blackwood, Monthly,   3.00  "
               
               <br></br>For 4 Reviews &amp; Blackwood,  10.00 "
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">CLUBBING.</div>
            
            <p>Four copies of any or all the above works will be sent to one address, on
               payment of the regular subscription for three--the fourth copy being gratis.
               Remittances and communications (post-paid or franked) should be made to
               LEONARD SCOTT &amp; CO., Pub's, 113 Fulton st., N.Y.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
               The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow's
               professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo.
               
               <br></br>Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
               
               <br></br>Joshua Herrick, Me.
               
               <br></br>John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               
               <br></br>James Irvin, Pa.
               
               <br></br>J. Thompson, Miss.
               
               <br></br>Dr. A. G. Bigelow's Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York. 
            </div>
            
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p30">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">288</div>
         <div class="ab">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL,
            
            <br></br>Redding &amp; Co., .   .   .   .    Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance,   .   .   .   Philadelphia, Pa.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. HUNTINGTON, .   .   . 		Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>George Jones,    .   .   .   .   Albany, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Thomas H. Pease,  .   .   .   New Haven, Ct.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.</div>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>