<div>
   <div class="issueId">18451115</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL
            VOL. 2.	EDGAR A. POE,	NO. 19.
            editor and proprietor.
            NEW-YORK, SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 15, 1845.
            Sonnet.
            ON SEEING THE IVORY STATUS OF CHRIST.
            The enthusiast brooding in his cell apart
            O’er the sad image of the Crucified,
            The drooping head, closed lips and pierced side,
            A holy vision fills his raptured heart;
            With heavenly power inspired, his unskilled arm
            Shapes the rude block to this transcendant form.
            Oh Son of God! thus, ever thus, would I
            Dwell on the loveliness enshrined in Thee,
            The lofty faith, the sweet humility,
            The boundless love, the love that could not die.
            And as the sculptor with thy glory warm
            Gives to this chiselled ivory thy fair form,
            So would my spirit in thy Thought divine
            Grow to a semblance, fair as this of Thine.
            ANNE C. LYNCH.
            A New Mode of Collecting a Library.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Knickerbocker Magazine has received a severe rebuke from the city press, during the last week, for some
            peculiarities in its general conduct, and especially for the
            spirit and letter of an article in the last number, upon
            Mr. Mathews. The inquiry has arisen in many quarters,
            what has Mr. Mathews done to subject himself to this
            extraordinary annoyance and detraction? Of what literary or social offences has he been guilty, that he should
            be pilloried in the small print and pelted with the pleasant missives of the “ Editor's Table ?” Better dine with
            Duke Humphrey than sit down to the scraps and cheeseparings of such a table. “What is this?” says an old
            gentleman, a merchant, a subscriber to the Knickerbocker
            Magazine. “ John, get me a copy of Big Abel. I must
            look into it; always my practice. There’s that fellow,
            Pipkins, comes to my store, passes the best hour of the
            day in abusing Jenkins, drones over cotton, sighs at real
            estate, shudders at stocks. Memorandum: Make it a
            rule, when he is gone out to give Jenkins unlimited credit, buy up cotton, hold on to real estate, and invest in
            Wall Street. So much advice is never gratuitous ; goes
            by contraries. Always make it a rule to buy the books
            upon which the most malice is expended. Malice is too
            valuable a quality to throw away upon mere emptiness.
            Never knew it to fail. In consequence have got one of
            the best libraries in town. Vastly indebted to the Knickerbocker in this respect. Remember reading once in the
            small type, something to the effect that Coleridge was a
            bore—stole all his ideas, and didn’t understand himself
            after all. Became the purchaser of a copy of Coleridge’s
            Works. Submitted to six months intellectual discipline,
            and passed the wisest hours of my life. Very great difference between Coleridge and Clark. Impossible to
            measure the ocean with a thimble. In the same way
            saw John Neal called " crazy Neal.” Had never paid
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>much attention to American Literature. Was induced
            to look for his works. Found them out of print. Very
            extraordinary circumstance, for a trashy author. Got a
            copy of “ Seventy-Six” at last. Read it, holding my
            breath all the while. Full of life, passion, and patriotism, with an intense earnestness. Same thing with
            Simms. The small type called him a “naughty man.”
            Found him, on investigation, a frank, manly Southron;
            carving his own way to fame, brushing off the musquitos with a sturdy right arm as he went An extremely
            “naughty man,” in the way of demolishing shabbiness;
            but probably with some virtues of his own, or the Harpers
            would not have published for him, or his chivalric countrymen sent him to the Legislature :—added his forty volumes to the shelf. A lecturer came here, by the name of
            Hudson. Was tired and exhausted with lectures of all
            sorts—had made up my mind never to attend another lecture in my life. One day, the small type began to spirt
            and spatter. The Angel was evidently troubling the waters. Took tickets for the course of lectures for wife and
            family, and attended with them all through. That Hudson had a muzzle which closed upon a truth like a bull dog
            upon a bone. What compressed force and sinewy intellect ! A tremendous fellow at crushing a falsehood.—
            The bones and cartilage of Error crunched in his “ bear’s
            paw.” Trembled once for the “ small type.” “Ah ! John,
            you have come. What kept you so long?” “Please,
            sir, the first edition was exhausted, and had to scramble
            about among the retailers for a copy.” “ Strange again;
            very like 'crazy Neal.’ Can the public read the small
            type? Doubtful. Read us a passage.” John reads the
            vindication of a suspected criminal:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Another officer came in from a bye-way. That was a wicked
            devil he had in charge—make up your mind that. A murderer?
            Why, no. A wronger of orphans in their pale and tender youth?
            Not that either. A cutter to the quick of honest fame? I can’t
            say that. Suspected—that’s all. A wicked devil, you see. His
            coat shows that, by its thin, shivering way of sitting about the
            shoulders. His spindle limbs that just keep him up; his face
            covered with no memory of a sufficient meal, even a long way off.
            Suspected? Who better or more than he? Of all the men that
            run or wa1k or ride within the city bounds, he is the guiltiest-suspected wretch. Thrust him in a cell: the ground must be damp:
            on bread and water ; where rats, if any are to be had thereabout,
            may have free resort to him ; and in a few days—a very few days—
            Suspicion, at a touch almost, will become a fearful certainty. He
            will be dead! Lawgivers and magistrates—you know—he will
            be dead !
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Something honest and feelingly spoken in that.—
            Take another dip.” Reads the Indian’s reflections during
            the night of that day which was devoted to the “ City at
            its Crimes.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>And now to-bed ; up-stairs, with candles, one to lead and one to
            follow, they wait on Lankey and Big Abel. Tidy chambers, and in
            half a minute Big Abel sound asleep. But still the rain kept pattering down, and stirred poor Lankey's Indian heart with strange
            effect. In this humor, as he laid awake, he heard in a far-off street
         </p>
         <p>284	THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            
         </p>
         <p>the dolefully of some late-tarrying man,—“Oysters' —on a wet
            drizzly summer’s night the melancholies! sound — delivered to him
            as though it was sung in a far-off world.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Then, as Lankey thought of turbulent rivers, swelled by this
            heavy fall of rain, and the roar of the angry Bay stretching far out
            to sea, there sprung upon the air, from down the dreary hollow they
            had rambled through that day, a quick, sharp cry for life; a woman’s voice; a fearful cry for dead midnight ! Lankey was
            troubled. He could not sleep ; and going to the window, he bent
            himself upon his hands, and looked abroad. While yet his eyes
            glowed strangely upon the dark, there came gliding along a woman’s
            shape, with hair streaming back with the light that was abroad
            from lamps about, and eyes glistening-wet with sadness or joy too
            great to keep its fountain in the heart. Ah, what a cry shot up just
            then against the sky  She spread her hands. There was no one
            near to see her, save Lankey, none besides, nor far away ; all the
            wide city’s eyes were shut; and she possessed the night alone, with
            sorrow, for another night, within her breast. For ever so! The
            keenest hurts, the deadliest wrongs life lays on human souls, have
            none, save God and  the poor heart, to know of them!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Following this dim figure through the perilous night along the
            winding way, the Little Manhattan called to mind how once an
            ancient path that led into the hills ran there before it, and how in
            sadness deep as this the dusky maiden took her way, so long ago,
            up towards the calm blue heaven, and sought to soothe her spirit
            with the silence of the woods, the sight of stars, and whispering of
            the winds of night.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>When he sought sleep again, he had a troubled dream in which,
            by some strange magic in his thoughts, the city passed back out
            of all its squares and streets and stony flats into his fresh, fair,
            lovely island-youth ; of hill, stream, valley, wood. Ah, how he
            pined to have them by the hand, kinsmen, as he saw them now,
            silent in the lodge, or swift at chase, or shining from the ruddy
            fight! But morning came, and took them all away
         </p>
         <p>Ah, sad and gentle. A true vein in that ! Once more
            the scene changes to the Battery.
            
         </p>
         <p>And how bore the old Battery this far-and-wide repose? Settled in the midst of it like a smooth-backed duck in the water ! He
            held his breath and listened for the Bay to speak, and the ships, and
            the islands. The great trees ; not a whisper from them ! The
            grass ; not the rustling of a blade! And up and down the paths
            there moved stout old gentlemen, and thin young gentlemen with
            canes under their arms, and masters, and ’prentices, and shopkeepers and shop-boys, throngs of them ; and, the very Spirit of the
            whole thing, there went along, close to the railing, as near the water as he could, an old sea-dog of a grizzled captain, who snuffed
            hes alt air and caught a flavor of the oakum and the tar that lingers round about, and seemed to hush within himself the thousand
            storms he knew of, off Bahamas and the Capes, and down the hot
            Gulf Stream. There was a packet captain for you! Not a word
            of the sea, nor of fine company on ship-board, nor wrecks, nor
            great northwesterners, nor strange appearances far from the shore,
            nor spouting whales, cutting voyages, men overboard. But all
            about a little plot of ground, he mentioned, in Westchester : a few
            acres only: the soil was good, the plough went always twenty inches
            in the mould ; sufficient for a horse and cow. So much for land.
            The house (this was his vision of a house) red-roofed, one-storied,
            with a dainty balcony before (for smokers in long summer afternoons) ; a grassy green ; some sea-thought there, no doubt! and
            then, roving there, as easy and as kind and soft in glossy beauty
            for the eye to dwell on as the summer’s day itself, a smooth, snug,
            cobby horse. Not far off, a gig ; at rest now ; but out upon the
            road once with that cobby horse, they'll play the mischief all the
            country round ! And, as for drivers, where’s to match the grizzled
            seaman with his cunning hand ! Climbing far away the winding
            roads ; there arc such roads there ; they get, a truth to tell, a look
            out to the sea. Ah, there it is again, old sea-dog; all the salt is in
            you still, and keeps fresh that stormy heart, though beating in the
            very bloom of silent fields !
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Lay that book on the centre table where my friends
            may see it, and now read that passage in the small type
            of the Knickerbocker. John reads:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ A bald inventory of everything that strikes the eye of the writer,
            (who you cannot help thinking, has ‘a screw loose’ somewhere in
            his mental machinery). To us the book seems about as 'deep' as
            a thimble. It requires no thought from those who road it, for the
            simple reason that it made no such demand upon the author who
            wrote it. We cannot help giving it as our settled conviction, after
            a careful perusal, that 'Big Abel’ is a dreadful failure', that in
            short 'to compare it with a bottle of small beer, would be greatly to
            belie that fluid.’ ”
         </p>
         <p>“So Dogberry ‘could not help giving it as his settled
            conviction-’ with due reiteration that he was an—!
            
         </p>
         <p>John, you may go to-morrow and 'stop’ the Knickerbocker;
            but stay, I’ll lose my guide to the authors of the country.
            You may read me the critical passages first and take it
            away afterwards.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Old Gentleman was a logical man in his way.
            We have given up our space to his conversation though
            we have much else to say, “ if not toothsome yet wholesome,” according to an old writer, which we reserve for
            our leisure and convenience.
         </p>
         <p>THE AMERICAN PIONEER.
            How bravely moves the warrior, in panoply arrayed,
            As marching on to battle, he draws his shining blade!
            His enemies he scatters, like chaff before we wind,
            And drives Despair Before him, while Ruin stalks behind,
            And gains, perchance a province, to ruthless pillage given,
            And from the wretched curses that will drive his soul from heaven!
            But never rose a warrior among the sons of men—
            Not Cœur de Leon when he marched against the Saracen,
            
         </p>
         <p>More brave than Peace has nurtured, and Freedom’s host sent forth,
            With neither sword nor trappings, to the conquest of the earth.
            Behold the young American, how cheerily he moves,
         </p>
         <p>And proudly as a Paladin protecting those he loves—
            His sinewy hands shall wrestle with Nature for her spoil,
            The giant trees shall feel his axe, his plough subdue the soil,
            
         </p>
         <p>And now he eyes his waggon, with its snow-white curtain veil’d,
            And his steeds that like Bucephalus their master never fail’d,—
            But pride is merged in gladness, and his heart is beating high,
            When through the snowy curtains, like stars in June’s soft sky,
         </p>
         <p>The laughing eyes of childhood peer upon his way of toil.
            And she, his gentle wife looks forth, to cheer him with her smile.
            She smiles, that gentle woman, and yet a sigh will come,
            When rises on her reverie the cherished scenes of home,
            
         </p>
         <p>—The clear and calm Connecticut, the schoolhouse in the glade,
            The Church upon the village green, the old elm’s chequered shade;
            The seat beneath the hawthorn, when summer days were long,
         </p>
         <p>The seat beside the hearth-stone, when autumn winds were strong,
            The friends—but here she pauses and forces back the tear—
            Her husband is beside her, and, shall she grieve or fear
            Her husband is beside her, their children at her knee,
            They go with blessings dowered to gain the triumph of the Free;
            A sovereignty unchallenged by earthly king or lord—
            A home of peace and plenty, brave Labor's just reward:—
            The Starry Banner o’er them, what foe will dare molest?
            And in God’s forest Temple how sweet the Sabbath Rest!—
            And so, in faith, in hope, and love, those pioneeers move on,
            As though an Angel led the way toward the setting sun.
            Sarah J. Hale.
            Fancies
            
         </p>
         <p>The Past—the Present—the Future. The shadowy
            phantom that broodeth over the by-gone—the stern spirit of the things that be—the dread spectre of the tocome.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Lo! where roll the waters of Oblivion adown that
            vale dimmed by the pail of sumless ages. Onward they
            sweep ; on—forever on—and no pauses, nor back-turnings
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>be theirs. Terrible they sweep—for in their depths existence is annihilated. Noiseless they sweep; for, high upon
            e livid wave, his stony finger planted on his compressed
            p, triumphant floats grim Silence. And ever, as, outgushing from the unfathomable bosom of Eternity, they
            have flowed forth on their awful way, stilled have been
            the voices of submerged cities and states all glorious, and
            only not omnipotent. Stilled have been the tones of cavernous India, and proud Assyria, and sepulchral Egypt,
            and hallowed Greece, and mighty Rome—aye, Rome,
            within whose Coliseum even yet shall ye see, by the midnight watch, the ghost of the gladiator dim flitting across
            the vacant area, or the mailed spirit of the stern centurion lone stalking within that towering Palladium of his
            world. A hundred—a thousand—all nations ! Gaze into
            that tide, and ye shall see no sight. List by that blackened shore, and ye shall hear no sound. As well might
            ye there linger for the sweetest dream-murmurs of the infant as for the thunder-shouts of congregated myriads. Yes,
            there be kings and their people—lords and their serfs—
            heroes and cravens—patriots and recreants—glorious intelligences, that have lightened over a wondering world,
            and those in whose breasts the foul emissaries of Hell
            once revelled. There be joys, and sorrows, and hopes
            whose stars have gone down, and memories whose wand
            of power hath been dashed to pieces, and high ambition
            quenched—materiality and immateriality—all lost, everlastingly lost! And where, too, are so many of our own
            old joys and griefs and hopes ? Often, oh ! often an ineffable ecstasy, wildly moving across the heart’s strings
            like the gathering breath of the west across the chords
            f the unfingered wind-harp, hath beaten its unmeasured
            music in the throbbing pulse ; and often hath the soul
            been shaded by the dark flapping wing of agony. But
            they are gone—the glory of exultation and the gloom of
            anguish ; transient as the Day-god’s effulgence, or as the
            shattered cloud that dims it, when the storm-shroud is
            fitfully passing from before the face of Heaven. They
            have all gone down in that rolling tide. Awe for the
            mighty Past!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Present—bridge from the Past to the Future, ever
            frail, ever changing. Entity, nonenity. Link in the infinite chain ! At the dawn of creation, when Chaos was
            transfused into forms of perfect beauty, and primeval
            Night first rolled away before the fiat of the Almighty,
            wide over the earth shone God’s high power and goodness, in characters of living splendor, and were sublimely
            hymned through infinity of space, in the undying paeans
            of the stars of Heaven ! And yet as wondrously are they
            graven upon the front of Nature, yet as marvellously
            pealed by those far-rolling orbs of fire. Still, in mystic
            regularity, revolves the rapid year ; still comes the holy
            sunshine still the storm ; still comes the glorious dayspring, noun and eve, and night in her deep halls unrolls
            her starry robe. And yet do the Fates unravel and weave
            and cut the threads of human life. There be births,
            there be deaths ; there be ripenings and strengthenings
            and uprisings in proud integrity—and wastings and sinkings and a down-sending of earth to earth, and a rotting,
            and crawling of the gorged grave-worm—and then, when
            ye dig, ye find but cold, damp mould. And oh ! in the
            march of time, how little changed is man ! We are ; and
            around us, in countless breasts, are glowing the self-same
            emotions that glowed in those of old. Joys are elating, sorrows subduing, hopes shedding their evanescent
            smiles; ambition is pluming her insubstantial wings, remorse is corroding, revenge is at his fearful labors. And
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>kingdoms are rising, and kingdoms are tottering, and
            kingdoms are falling; and monarchs and slaves—the
            great and the lowly—the good and the evil—the demigod and the moonling—were not, and are ; are, and shall
            not be. And as of that strange and deep-sounding anthem of life that goeth incessantly up, one strain riseth,
            its usherer-in, slow floating back, dieth away forever and
            forever. We are, and lor that we are, joy for the Present !
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Future—twin sister of the Past—as dark, as dread,
            and oh! how vacant ! Through its undiscovered ways
            are yet to travel what multitudes of Earth’s own children, what myriads of vet uncreated things! How is its
            silence to be broken by the shrill cry of youth, the deep
            tone of manhood, the bitter murmurings of age; the voice
            of rejoicing, the moan of anguish; the hum of the
            peaceful traffickers, the giant roar of contending nations,
            the crash of falling monarchies! There shall intermingle, and rise to that thunder-pavillioned throne of eternity, the vaunt of the blood-reeking conqueror, and the
            cracking of the strings of the poor human heart. There
            shall go up the meek prayer of helplessness and innocence, and the high blasphemy of the strong boaster. As
            it hath been, so it shall be. Still shall scythed Saturn,
            (oh solemn and truthful myth!) devour his progeny, the
            bright and golden hours, who ever, as they die. shall bequeath their awful burthen to their young sisters. Still,
            over old earth—her womb one vast charnel house—shall
            spread the gorgeous vale, shall rise the cloud-heaving
            mount, shall stretch the sombre forest, shall heave the
            tide of ocean, shall rush the swelling river, shall dance
            the sparkling brooklet. And who may tell how long?
            aye, who how long the earth shall roll, the sun shall
            blaze, and yet how long shall peal those paeans of the
            circling hosts? Mystery for the Future! Joy for the
            Present ; and Awe for the mighty Past.
         </p>
         <p>R. S. Rowley.
            The Autumnal Leaf
            
         </p>
         <p>Thou faded leaf! it seems to be
            But as of yesterday
            When thou didst flourish on the tree
            In all the pride of May.
         </p>
         <p>Then ’twas the merry hour of spring—
            Of Nature’s fairest blossoming.
            
         </p>
         <p>On field, on flower, on spray
            It promised fair; how changed the scene
            To what is now, from what hath been!
         </p>
         <p>So fares it with lire’s early Spring ;
            Hope gilds each coming day,
            And sweetly does the Syren sing
            Her fond delusive la,
            
         </p>
         <p>Then the young fervent heart beats high
            Whilst passion kindles in the eye
            With bright unceasing play
            Fair are thy tints, thou genial Hour,
         </p>
         <p>Yet transient as the autumn flower.
            Thou faded leaf! how like to thee
            Is beauty in her morning pride,
            When life is but a summer sea
            And hope illumes its placid tide:
            Alas! for beauty’s autumn hour,
            Alas! for beauty’s blighted flower!
            When hope and bliss have died,
            Her pallid brow, her cheek of grief
            Have thy sad hue, thou faded leaf
            
            Autumnal leaf! there is a stern
            And warning tone in thy decay:
            Like thee must man to death return
            With his trail tenement of clay.
            Thy warning is of death and doom
            Of genius blighted in its bloom,
            Of joy’s o’erclouded ray;
            Life, rapture, hope,|ye are as brief
            And fleeting as the Autumn leaf.
            O. H. Mildeberger.
            Critical Notices.
            The Artist, the Merchant, and the Statesman. By C.
            Edwards Lester. Vol. 1. New-York: Paine &amp; Bur-
            gess, 62 John-street.
            
         </p>
         <p>This book opens with a commentary on the chief portion of its contents, in a likeness of Mr. Powers. The
            Sculptor, whose name has recently grown into a worldwide one, by the success of his Greek Slave, has a square,
            firm head, un-ideal in its outline, but indicating quick observation, and great depth of purpose ; deficient in proportion and geniality in the lower features, with a broad
            brow, and an eye rather steady than kindling in its glance.
            The countenance is a criticism on the autobiography of
            Mr. Powers, of which the book mainly consists. His
            discourse in these conversations with Mr. Lester, in
            which the autobiography is disclosed, is plain, sensible,
            in a judicious spirit of praise and censure, showing the
            practised and the practical eye, at times glancing off,
            Yankee-like, sharply to the main chance; independent,
            as is, or should be characteristic of an American, of old
            usage and authority, and leaving altogether on the reader’s mind an opinion honorable to the sense and intellect
            of the artist.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The language of the Conversations is generally clear
            and simple, and such as a sculptor, used to a clear,
            round outline, might be expected to employ. Throughout
            there are dropped, from time to time, hints and suggestions likely to be of decided service to art, and to art, particularly, in the United States. The zeal of Mr. Powers
            for the embellishment of the country by fountain-pieces,
            statues and monuments, agrees with our own long-entertained sentiments entirely ; and in his utter repudiation
            of the mongrel in monumental architecture, like the proposed Washington Memorial, with its subsidiary library,
            reading-room, &amp;c., we heartily concur. The most sustained speculation in the Conversations, is that upon a
            proper monument of Washington; and, although we
            doubt whether at all points the ground is properly laid
            out by the artist, we give it at length :
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A very laudable effort is now making, not by the Government,
            which ought to have done it long ago, but by some generous individuals in America, to erect a monument to Washington; and I
            hope it will be a monument. But a Public Edifice they propose to
            call a monument, which would have answered their purpose just
            as well, might have been had without the trouble and expense of
            building one. I should be sorry to see so great a name as Washington’s associated in a monument with Institutions, Libraries,
            Rooms for Art, Debating Societies, &amp;c.; all dignified by the name
            of a monument to our great Hero and Father. Almost as soon
            would I think of changing money in a church, or profaning the
            altars of God with traffic, as to convert Washington’s monument
            into such a business-like place.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Monuments to the dead should never be made the habitations of
            the living; they should be resorted to, to teach us how to live and
            how to die, and an eternal Sabbath should be kept around their
            graves. Let some imposing but solemn structure be raised over
            the dust of Washington—single in its purpose and single in its
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>form. Let it be made of the most durable and massive materials;
            and let it rise as high as a grateful nation can carry it—without
            spires, or turrets, or windows, or any other littleness to disturb the
            grandeur and solemnity of its design. Let it, in a word be in harmony with the character of the man.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The most appropriate monument is that which, as far as the nature of such a thing can do, illustrates this character. It should
            be something analogous. If a man of taste and literary pursuits,
            his tomb should be embellished with ornaments, and all its proportions should present a classic appearance; if a military hero,
            his monument should be in keeping with the spirit of loftiness, and
            breathe the soul of daring and glory, so that his character might
            be clearly known without reading the inscription. And such is
            the richness and fertility of the genius of the fine arts, as understood by great artists, their language is even more expressive in
            the hands of the master, than any other language in the world.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But a monument to such a man as Washington, who is not considered as a scholar, nor even so much as a military hero, or
            statesman, as one of those exalted characters that stand far above
            all other men, embracing all that is noble known to humanity, and
            even something we may almost regard as divine; one who never
            lived before, nor is likely ever to live again;—his monument
            should be as distinct from all others, as he was from all other men.
            A classic monument would not do for him, nor a military monument, nor any other peculiar style; for none of them can reach
            him. No little thing should be introduced in it; no petty parts or
            decorations; it should be distinct and unbroken, and rise in solemn
            grandeur, a simple mass of vast bulk and height, so that it might
            be seen across a plain fifty miles off, surmounted by his statue of
            such colossal proportions, it might be recognized, if possible, even
            at that distance as the statue of Washington. And this would not
            be so difficult as might appear; for such were his form and general proportions, so different from all other men, and so expressive
            of himself, that the most feeble attempt at his likeness never fails
            to be recognized. His person was as distinct from other men as
            was his character.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But of what form should be this monument, to express the durability of his fame, and at the same lime embody and illustrate that
            solemnity of character so peculiarly his own? Before answering
            this question, we should look for guidance, and enquire what human structures have stood the longest, and will probably descend
            farthest into coming ages. And at the same time what are the
            most expressive, and excite the greatest wonder over successive
            races of men.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Are they solemn temples or sumptuous palaces, or lofty towers,
            or massive obelisks, or solid columns, or colossal statutes? The
            learned have spent ages in disputing about the site of Babylon,
            with her gorgeous temples, and Thebes, with her hundred brazen
            gates. The ruins even of Roman structures, reared less than two
            thousand years ago, have long been preserved with sacred veneration ; and the temples of Greece are mournful heaps. But the
            Pyramids of Egypt still lift their awful forms over the desert, and
            have watched the rise and the fall of a long succession of Empires.
            Human knowledge gropes back through dim ages to find the era
            of their beginning, and still time strives in vain to overwhelm
            them. The obelisks lie scattered around the deserts, or have been
            carried away by distant travellers; and the Memnon lies prostrate
            in the dust.. The great cities that once Mood upon the banks of
            the Nile, are levelled with the ocean of sand around them; and
            almost every vestige of the work of man has passed away in the
            flowing tide of ages. But the Pyramids still stand, and still rear
            themselves as vast as ever; stupendous beacons to the traveller
            from distant countries; piercing the clouds, where they catch the
            first blush of morning that flames on their summits, as fair as in
            the morning of Creation; defying the barbarous hand of the spoiler
            and the sweeping desolation of ages.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Why were they made? This question we may answer with
            certainty—they were raised for monuments. They contained the
            ashes of the dead, and a platform was left on their tops, we have
            good reason to infer, to receive colossal statues or figures in illustration of the dead beneath them. This would seem to be certain,
            for the science which built them never would have left them incomplete without an object.
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>And where is there anything in the universe human like them
            but the character of Washington, and what monument could we
            raise so appropriate to the Father of his Country?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Washington’s fame we well know can never die—it would outlive the Pyramids, without a monument and without a line or
            eulogy. But a long line of generations is to follow us ; and when
            they come upon the stage for their brief hour in the sweep of ages,
            each one to ask that distant Republic whose history will then have
            grown dim, what monument of gratitude she left to her Glorious
            Deliverer, let them turn to some pyramidal structure surmounted
            by a vast statue of Washington, of everlasting bronze:
         </p>
         <p>" Like some tall cliff that lids its awful form,
            Swells from the vale and midway leaves the storm :
            Though round its base the rolling clouds are spread,
            Eternal sunshine settles on its head.”
            
         </p>
         <p>As connected with another eminent American, of another day and an entirely different cast of character, the
            artist’s interview with General Jackson is worthy of particular mention.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The general arrangement and spirit of the book are extremely creditable to Mr. Lester, although there are certain defects and blemishes which we regret to find marring the volume. One of these is the inharmonious and
            inartistical union, in the same volume, of two subjects
            with so little to connect them, (although they are brought
            together in the general title of the work,) as an autobiography of Hiram Powers, the Sculptor, and a Treatise
            on the Consular System. Of this the editor is acquitted
            by the modest requirement of the Sculptor, that he should
            not be left to stand alone, in his autobiogaphical disclosures, in a book by himself. To the style of the work,
            in Mr. Lester’s portion of it, we might take some exception, in an extreme colloquialism which, although
            not offensive in the eagerness of a first reading, will
            injure it as a permanent record. There are great spirit
            and naturalness in Mr. Lester’s use of this style ; and we
            prefer it infinitely to the stilted assumption of a scholastic
            manner. We would have been glad to have found somewhere in the volume, or in Mr. Powers’ discourse, a recognition of his young contemporary, Crawford, who,
            though of an entirely different school and faith from Powers, has labored too long and too truly, to be out of mind
            when the talk is of American Sculptors, who have honored their country in their labors. It is possible that Mr.
            Lester intends to supply this, and other omissions, in his
            second volume, which is to include, we are told, sketches
            of various American artists. On the whole, we are
            pleased with this work, in the part we have given our
            attention to, (of the other portion of it we may speak
            at length hereafter) and believe it will be of service in
            its province.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Powers we have been in the habit of regarding
            as one of the few representative Americans, ranking in
            art with Webster, Jackson, Forrest, and other strongminded and sturdy-working men in other departments.
            He has in him the true indigenous sinew and straightforwardness of the place—the freedom from petty ligatures of schools, and fashions, and tastes, with which
            old-world people are apt to be oppressed. He has had a
            long and hard fight with fortune, such as every original
            and un-conventional man may lay his account in sustaining ; and he has come out of it, as every such man
            will, with a bright renown and an honor untouched
            through all its trials. We, for one, do not regret the
            learning of short-hand by Mr. Lester, as that seems to
            have enabled him to give us these excellent and judicious
            Conversations, and we shall look for his concluding volume of the Artist, Merchant and Statesman, with a good
            hope of profitable entertainment.
         </p>
         <p>In paper, typography, and general appearance, the vol-
            ume is neatly presented by the spirited publishers.
            Specimens of English Dramatic Poets, who lived about
            the time of Shakspeare. With Notes: By Charles
            Lamb. In two Volumes. Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library
            of Choice Reading, Nos. XXIX—XXX.
            
         </p>
         <p>If the Cheap Era in Literature had began with the first
            settlement of America, the improved Power Press been
            set in motion, throwing off its thousand sheets per hour,
            and steamboats and railroads been ready to blaze its issues
            through the country,—and it had happened that these
            Specimens had been the first work to engage their services,
            the whole face of its Literature would, according to all
            ordinary modes of calculation, have been changed, and
            would now present the aspect of a Jupiter rather than
            an Adonis. As it is, we set out in our career at the period
            of the predominance of the French school, and the school of
            Pope ; and it is only within a very recent period, that we
            have given any indications of a desire to escape from it.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have tinkled in the minor key, jingling our ten
            feet and keeping close to our regular measures, with the
            painful pertinacity of the droning minstrel of the streets.
            So deeply has the infection struck that, although England
            (our model and guide in these matters heretofore) has more
            than once in that time been swept by manlier lyres and
            braver singers, we have gone on in the old tune, assuaging
            and mollifying, even in our copies of these better spirits,
            strength and manhood and manly earnestness down to a
            poor, piping treble. The restoration and triumph of the
            Old Masters of English verse, in their own country, has
            been no triumph nor restoration to us. We have gone on
            in the old way in spite of new editions of Ben Jonson,
            and Beaumont and Fletcher, Webster, Decker, Massinger,
            and all the others of that hardy brood. Once in a long
            while a voice has been raised in a comer, in behalf of this
            noble peerage of elder poets—but without any obvious
            change in the popular sentiment. Now however the
            change has fairly come ! The country after undergoing the
            weariness of droning poetasters for half a century and
            more, has at length discovered that there is a kind of
            Literature more in harmony with its circumstances, and
            much truer to the breadth and grandeur of its national
            developements. The publication of these Specimens, is
            but the effervessence, of a spirit, long, quietly and patiently
            at work, under the surface. And their reception will be
            full of good omens to the future literary history of the
            country.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have conveyed our general opinion of this work
            in what we have already said: a word or two as to
            its peculiar merits. No where in the whole compass of
            its Literature, are the resources of the English tongue in
            power, in sweetness, terror, pathos, in description and dialogue, so well displayed. These two volumes are by the
         </p>
         <p>best hearts of England of their day and generation.—
            
         </p>
         <p>They speak the sorrow and the belief, the joy and the
            agitation of their times, like men. They dip their pens
            in the very life-blood of humanity, and write so as to stir
            the life-blood. Their fear is real fear, their joy is real
            joy, their grief, grief indeed, and no make believe. They
            therefore speak to all men of all times. These genuine
            words of theirs cutting their way through all of war,
            and darkness and discordant history that stands between,
            reach the present day, and with a vital fire come home to
            our hearts, as they did to the hearts of their contemporaries.
            See with what fire, and eagerness and inspired annimation
            they address themselves to the loves and griefs and
            passions of men and women !
         </p>
         <p>
            The forest deer being struck,
            Runs to an herb that closeth up the wounds;
            But when the imperial lion’s flesh is gor’d,
            He rends and tears it with his wrathful paw,
            And highly scorning that the lowly earth
            Should drink his blood, mounts up to th’ air.
            Sometimes like Women or unwedded Maids,
            Shadowing more beauty in their airy brows
            Than have the white breasts of the Queen of Love
            Now comes my Lover tripping like the Roe,
            And brings my longings tangled in her hair.
            To joy her love I’ll build a kingly bower,
            Seated in hearing of a hundred streams.
            
         </p>
         <p>Then, as in Arden I have seen an oak
            Long shook With tempests, and his lolly top
            Bent to his root, which being at length made loose
            (Even groaning with his weight) he ’gan to nod
            This way and that, as loth his curled brows
            (Which he had oft wrapt in the sky with storm)
         </p>
         <p>Should stoop; and yet, his radical fibres burst,
            Storm-like he fell, and hid the fear-cold earth;
            
         </p>
         <p>So fell stout Barrisor, that had stood the shocks
            Of ten set battles in your highness’ war
            Gainst the sole soldier of the world Navarre.
         </p>
         <p>Ferd. Is she dead?
            Bos. She is what you would have her.
            Fix your eye here.
            Ferd Constantly.
            Bos. Do you not weep?
            Other sins only speak; murder shrieks out.
            The element of water moistens the earth,
            But blood flies upward and bedews the heavens.
            Ferd. Cover her face; mine eyes dazzle; she died so young.
            Bos. I think not so: her infelicity
            Seem’d to have years too many.
            Ferd. She and I were twins;
            And should I die this instant, I had lived
            Her time to a minute.
            
         </p>
         <p>The whole brood of modern bards bend before them,
            like the slender woodland before the majestic breath of
            God. To Charles Lamb, who by wise and delicious painstaking makes us masters and friends of these noble spirits, thanks indeed. What he says, descriptively, of his
            plan in introducing them is well put.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The kind of extracts which I have sought after have been, not so
            much passages of wit, though the old plays are rich in such,
            as scenes of passion, sometimes of the deepest quality, interesting
            situations, serious descriptions, that which is more nearly allied to
            poetry than to wit, and to tragic rather than comic poetry
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>And what be says, here and throughout these choice
            volnmes in explanation or praise of his authors, is in admirable harmony with their own noble verse. One or
            two of these masterly notes will satisfy the reader into
            whose hands he entrusts himself.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>*To move a horror skilfully, to touch a soul to the quick, to lay
            upon fear as much as it can bear, to wean and weary a life till it is
            ready to drop, and then step in with mortal instruments to take its
            last forfeit: this only a Webster can do. Writers of an interior
            genius may “upon horror's head horrors accumulate," but they
            cannot do this. They mistake quantity for quality; they "terrify
            babes with painted devils,” but they know not how a soul is capable of being moved; their terrors want dignity, their affrightments
            are without decorum.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This tragedy, Marlowe’s Edward II , is in a very different style
            from “ mighty Tamburlaine.” The reluctant pangs of abdicating
            Royalty in Edward furnished hints which Shakespeare scarce improved in his Richard the Second; and the death-scene of Mar-
         </p>
         <p>lowe’s king moves pity and terror beyond any scene, ancient, or
            modern, with which I am acquainted.
            
         </p>
         <p>Marlowe is said to have been tainted with atheistical positions,
            to have denied God and the Trinity. To such a genius the history
            of Faustus mast have been delectable food: to wander in fields
            where curiosity is forbidden to go, to approach the dark gulf near
            enough to look in, to be busied in speculations which are the rottenest part of the core of the fruit that fell from the tree of knowledge.
            Barabas the Jew, and Faustus the conjuror, are offsprings of a
            mind which at least delighted to dally with interdicted subjects.
            They both talk a language which a believer would have been tender of putting into the month of a character though but in fiction.
            But the holiest minds have sometimes not thought it blameable to
            counterfeit impiety in the person of another, to bring Vice in upon
            the stage speaking her own dialect, and, themselves being armed
            with an Unction of self-confident impunity, have not scrupled to
            handle and touch that familiarly which would be death to others.
            Milton, in the presence of Satan, has started speculations hardier
            than any which the feeble armory of the atheist ever furnished:
            anil the precise, strait-laced Richardson has strengthened Vice,
            from the mouth of Lovelace, with entangling sophistries and abstruse pleas against her adversary Virtue; which Sedley, Villiers,
            and Rochester wanted depth of libertinism sufficient to have invented.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This scene in the Merry Devil of Edmonton has much of Shakspeare's manner in the sweetness and goodnaturedness of it. It
            seems written to make the reader happy. Few of our dramatists
            or novelists have attended enough to this. They torture and
            wound us abundantly. They are economists only in delight.
            Nothing can be finer, more gentlemanlike, and noble, than the conversation and compliments of these young men. How delicious is
            Raymond Mounchensey's forgetting, in his tears, that Jerningham
            has a “ Saint in Essex;” and how sweetly his friend reminds him!
            —I wish it could be ascertained that Michael Drayton was the author of this piece; it would add a worthy appendage to the renowm
            of that Panegyrist of my native Earth; who has gone over tier soil
            (in his Polyolbion) with the fidelity of a herald, and the painful
            love ot a son; who has not left a rivulet (so narrow that it may be
            slept over) without honorable mention; and has animated Hills
            and Streams with life and passion above the dreams of old mythology.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>After all, Love’s Sectaries are a “ reason unto themselves.” We
            have gone retrograde in the noble Heresy since the days when Sidney proselyted our nation to this mixed health and disease; the
            kindliest symptom yet the most alarming crisis in the ticklish state
            of youth; the nourisher and the destroyed of hopeful wits; the
            mother of twin-birds, wisdom and folly, valor and weakness; the
            servitude above freedom; the gentle mind's religion; the liberal
            superstition.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>No one will doubt, who reads Marston’s Satires, that the author
            in some part of liis life must have been something mote than a theorist in vice. Have we never heard an old preacher in the pulpit
            display such ati insight into the mystery of ungodliness, as
            made us wonder with reason how a good man came by it?
            When Cervantes with such proficiency of loudness dwells upon the
            Don’s library, who sees not that he has been a great leader of books
            of Knight-Errantry? perhaps was at some lime of his life in danger of tailing into those very extravagances which he ridicules so
            happily in his Hero?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The blank uniformity to which all professional distinctions in apparel have been long hastening, is one instance of the Decay of
            Symbols among us, which, whether it has contributed or not to make
            us a more intellectual, has certainly made us a less imaginative
            people. Shakapeare knew the force of signs;—“a malignant and
            turban'd Turk.” “This meal-cap Miller," says the Author of
            God's Revenge against Murder, to express his indignation at an attrocious outrage committed by the miller Pierot upon the person of
            the fair Marieta.
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>The insipid levelling morality to which the modern stage is tied
            down would not admit of such terrible passions as these scenes
            are tilled with. A puritanical obtuseness of sentiment, a stupid infantile goodness, is creeping among us, instead of the vigorous passions, and virtues clad in flesh and blood, with which the old dramatists present us. These noble and liberal casuists could discern
            in the differences, the quarrels, the animosities of man, a beauty
            and truth of moral feeling, no less than in the iterately inculcated duties of forgiveness and atonement. With us all is hypocritical meekness. A reconciliation scene (let the occasion be never so
            absurd or unnatural) is always sure of applause. Our audiences
            come to the theatre to be complimented on their goodness. They
            compare notes with the amiable characters in the play, and find a
            wonderful similarity of disposition between them.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Of all the English Play-writers, Chapman perhaps approaches
            nearest to Shakspeare in the descriptive and didactic, in passages
            which are less purely dramatic. Dramatic imitation was not his
            talent. He could not go out of himself, as Shakspeare could shift
            at pleasure, to inform and animate other existences, but in himself
            he had an eye to perceive and a soul to embrace all other forms.
            He would have made a great epic poet, if, indeed, he has not abundantly shown himself to be one; for his Homer is not so properly
            a Translation as the Stories of Achilles and Ulysses re-written.
            The earnestness and passion which he has put into every part of
            these poems would be incredible to a reader of mere modern translations. His almost Greek zeal for the honor of his heroes is only
            paralleled by that fierce spirit of Hebrew bigotry, with which Milton, as if personating one of the Zealots of the old law, clothed himself when he sat down to paint the acts of Sampson against the uncircumcised.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We repine, we confess, at the taking down of this book
            from our shelf, (it has been the dear companion of many
            joyful years,) and leading it out into the market place.
            But as we hope for many sharers, through it, in our old
            and long-time enthusiasm for the Elders—we submit that
            our fell-grief be made common, and that all mankind be
            let in to ‘joy in our joy, and sadden in our sadness.’
            Farewell, old Friends!—The million spread their hands to take you.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Foreign Library. No. 1. Vol. 11.
            Memoirs of Benvenuto Cellini. Written by Himself.
            Translated by Thomas Roscoe, Esq..
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We made but scant mention last week of this interesting work ; but we may supply the omission of words of
            our own by the following well written remarks from the
            Evening Post:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A better book than the autobiography of Benvenuto Cellini
            could hardly have been chosen for the first number of the Foreign
            Library. The old adage “ ce n’ est que le premier pas qui coute!"  must
            have been in the minds of the publishers in the selection. It is a very
            happy one, and if it is to be taken as an indication of the works
            which are to follow, augurs well for their success.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the original, this book is a classic. Its reputation among
            Italian critics is very great, and by scholars, all the world over, it
            has always been regarded as giving Cellini high rank as an author. To American readers it is comparatively unknown. The
            present translation has never before been published in this country ; it is extremely felicitous and spirited; one forgets entirely
            that he is not leading the author's own words in his own tongue,
            so admirably are the difficulties of translation overcome. The
            notes and observations of the Italian editor are included in this
            edition, and form an instructive and interesting addition to the
            text.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Benvenuto Cellini was born at Florence, in the year 1500.—
            There and at Rome he spent the greater part of his life. He died
            in 1570. His eminence as an artist, or rather, artisan in gold, silver and precious stones, and his exploits in the service of the
            state, and in the course of his personal adventures, made him
            famous in Italy and throughout Europe. The shop in which he
            worked is pointed out on one of the bridges at Florence, and spe-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>cimens of his handicraft are carefully preserved as heir-looms in
            ancient families, and exhibited as curiosities of note in the cabinets of virtuosi, and in royal museums.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>At the age of fifty-eight he wrote his autobiography. Thus the
            narrative embraces the first half of the sixteenth century, a brilliant
            and eventful era. During the time, the fine arts reached the culminating point in Italy, under the patronage of the Medici, in the
            works of Michael Angelo, Raffael, and Titian.—These great masters, and others of almost equal eminence, were contemporaries
            and intimates of Cellini, and figure in his pages. Besides these,
            the circle of his acquaintance and friendship included many of the
            first men of his times; he was the favorite and confidant of two
            popes, of a king, and of cardinals and dukes royal without number. The pictures he gives of the habits and manners, the ways of
            thinking, speaking and acting of the men with whom he came in
            contact, especially the more illustrious, are vivid and life-like, and
            doubtless more correct from the fact of their being incidental and
            unstudied, and no part of the author’s main design.—The great object of Cellini's book is his own glorification. He is his own hero.
            He reaches the very acme of egotism. Not even his “Holiness”
            himself can stand on the same level—it is "ego et pontifex meus”
            throughout, and the same disrespect of persons marks his intercourse with the whole tribe of dignitaries. Never was genius more
            conscious of itself and its divine prerogatives; never was a man
            predestined to immortality with a fuller acquiescence on his own
            part. This spirit pervades the book, and is hall the secret of its
            excellence. It is an egotism that forces our admiration. One cannot help sympathising with the complete self-satisfaction of the author. A man so perfectly at ease with himself is invulnerable to
            censure, he disarms prejudice and forestals criticism by asserting
            the infallibility of his own judgment. He is always in the right—
            his opinion invariably correct; his taste never at fault; his quarrel
            never unjust. He maintains himself in all sons of controversies
            with a firmness which would pass current anywhere for obstinacy ;
            suffers daily contradiction from “fools,” “simpletons" and “ blockheads,” unmoved; receives as matters of course the flatteries of
            princes; and executes summary vengeance on his foes, as though
            he were the appointed arbiter of fate. All this, while it would be
            disgusting in most autobiographies, gives to this one of its highest
            charms. It is impossible to find fault with Cellini for his egotism;
            one might as well quarrel with Swift for his humor.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>So with regard to his exaggerations. Some of his stories are
            exceedingly marvellous, and far more creditable to his imagination
            than his veracity. As an artist he was famous for giving rare
            tints to diamonds and other precious stones—his facility as an author in imparting a happy gloss of the fanciful to a rough narrative of facts is no less admirable. The Preface attributes most of
            his exaggeration to his “ confined education, his susceptible nerves,
            his superlative credulity and superstition, and his wild imagination.” To this fair apology it may be added, that a “strict adherence to truth,'' and a rigid “ abstinence from fiction,” was by no
            means the characteristic of the writers of his time, especially where
            their own exploits formed the subject matter of their narrations.—
            Cellini’s book is a running commentary on the era in which he
            lived—it reflects with wonderful accuracy and minuteness the very
            form and spirit of the age; but it partakes of it itself. The incredibility of his stories, his sublime indifference to dates and circumstances, his neglect of historic order or precision, while they unfit
            the book to be what it does not pretend to be, a work of historical
            accuracy, make it more faithful to the lime in which it was written. We are almost driven to make as anomalous an assertion as
            this, that if the book had been more reliable it would have been
            less authentic.
         </p>
         <p>New Books received, to be noticed more fully in our
            next:
            
         </p>
         <p>The London Medical Student, (second series,) by Punch,
            with Illustrations, by Leech. Philadelphia: Carey &amp;
            Hart.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Observations in the East, chiefly in Egypt, Palestine,Syria, and Asia Minor. By John P. Durbin, D. D. Late
            President of Dickinson College, Author of “Observa-
         </p>
         <p>
            tions in Europe,” &amp;c. In two volumes. New-York:
            Harper &amp; Brothers.
            The Democratic Review, for November.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Adventures of Gilbert Gurney. By Theodore Hook,
            Author of “ Merton," “ Sayings and Doings," “ Jack
            Bragg," &amp;c. &amp;c. Philadelphia: Carey &amp; Hart.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Appleton's Literary Miscellany, No. V. The Life of
            Frederick Schiller, by Thomas Carlyle. New-York:
            D. Appleton &amp; Co.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Prairiedom ; Rambles and Scrambles in Texas, or NewEstremadura. By A Southron. New-York: Paine &amp;
            Burgess.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Historical Essays and Narratives of the Merovingian Era, or Scenes of the Sixteenth Century, with an
            Autobiographical Preface, by M. Augustin Thierry.
            Philadelphia : Carey &amp; Hart.
         </p>
         <p>Martin's Illustrated Family Bible, No. XI. New-York:
            R. Martin &amp; Co., 26 John-street.
            The Wandering Jew, No, III. Superbly Illustrated.—
            Harper &amp; Brothers. New-York.
            
         </p>
         <p>New-York Illustrated Magazine of Literature and Art.
            Edited by Lawrence Labree. New-York: Robinson &amp;
            Co.
         </p>
         <p>Harper's Illuminated Pictorial Bible, No. XLII.
            Republication of the London Quarterly Review, for Sep-
            tember. New-York: Leonard Scott &amp; Co.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Shilling Library. Published Every Saturday.—
            New-York: Homans &amp; Ellis. No. 1.—The Mother's
            Mrdical Adviser. No. 2.—Cotton from the Pod to the
            Factory.
         </p>
         <p>The Missionary Memorial. New-York: Walker &amp; Co.
            Von Raumer's America. New-York: J. &amp; H. G. Langley.
            Song.
            I.
            Farewell! 'Twere vain to bid thee wear
            Mine image in thy breast,—
            Thou at another shrine wilt breathe
            The vows that made me blest.
            Yet I know when thou art lonely,
            When a cloud lies on thy heart,
            O'er thy memory, like a sunbeam,
            Some thought of me will dart.
            II.
            And when low words of melody
            Shall chain thy raptured ear —
            When beauty’s cheek beneath thy glance
            Its quick, pure blush shall wear —
            Though I languish all forsaken,
            Yet I know those tones, in thee,
            And that kindling brow will waken
            Some memory of me.
            III.
            And when soft fingers clasp thy hand,
            When fond arms thee entwine;
            When thou seest thyself reflected
            In brighter eyes than mine,
            Oh, then from out the Past my face,
            Though prized no more it be,
            Will beam upon thy memory,
            As once it beamed on thee. Mary E. Hewitt.
            The Drama.
            
         </p>
         <p>By a certain fluttering in the Press, we can discern as
            clearly as by the spreading of its wings, that the bird
            would take under them the warmth of the rising sun, that
            a new spirit is abroad in the Drama. The advent of this
            better feeling we predicted long since. Among its earliest indications was the reception of the new comedy
            Fashion’ (to which we cannot altogether give our critical approval, but which, as from the hand of a well-liked
            woman, was a fortunate pioneer,) and of its authoress as
            a performer on the same boards where her play had been
            successfully produced. To these, are to be added, the
            interest excited in Mr. Hudson’s admirable Lectures, appealing to the higher standards ; the general attention
            called to the peculiar reception of Mr. Forrest, and Miss
            Cushman, an American actor and actress in England.
            Accumulating in the same direction we have another
            comedy, from the pen of Mr. Epes Sargent, the offer of a
            handsome (but inadequate) sum for a new play of American Life and Manners, by Mr. Manager Burton; a small
            offer for a shorter piece of a similar complexion, by Marble, the Comedian—and, to crown all, the appearance of
            an American actor upon the stage, in the person of
            Mr. Murdoch, who at a bound has passed his English rivals
            who were making a handsome figure in the country, or are
            on their way to do so, and satisfied the American Public
            once for all, that if they will be at the pains to look at
            home when they arc in want of actors, they may possibly
            find them. That a great change has come over the American Dramatic world within a very recent period—would
            be manifest at once, if we should ask what chance of
            success Mr. Murdoch might have entertained as an American Actor, if he had presented himself a couple of years
            ago! We believe that the universal answer would be
            that in spite of his great acknowledged talents, he must
            have come near failing altogether, or at least that he would
            have sorely felt the want of that popular and journalistic
            support which has, lately, been so liberally accorded to
            him. As we were among the first to stake our faith on
            this young American performer, we feel bound to accompany him in the future stages of his success. In Philadelphia where he played the week ending on the 8th November, he has had a great reception ; his first house at
            the Walnut St. Theatre, being according to the correspondent of the N. Y. Spirit of the Times, the largest audience ever within its walls. The press and the people
            have appeared with greater unanimity and enthusiasm,
            if possible, in his behalf than even in New York. We
            give the account of two or three of the most judicious and
            sagacious of our Philadelphia contemporaries.
         </p>
         <p>From Neal's Saturday Gazette.
            
         </p>
         <p>Quite a sensation has been created during the week, at the Walnut street Theatre, by the return to the stage of our townsman and
            long-established favorite, Mr. Murdoch, who after years of retirement and careful study, once more presents himself as a candidate,
            not, as heretofore, for a second place, but for a station in the front
            rank of theatrical merit; and it was a source of much pleasure to
            observe how cheerily the call to such an ordeal, on the part of an
            American actor, was responded to by the public, who, knowing
            that no crude attempt was to be offered to their consideration, and
            that all necessary preliminary training had been encountered, came
            in crowds to form opinion and to record their judgment. At once
            grappling with the utmost difficulty, Mr. Murdoch first presented
            himself as Hamlet; and a more arduous selection could not
            have been made, both as regards the part itself and the prestige of
            many “ illustrious predecessors,” several of whom have so identified
            themselves with Hamlet, that it is cot easy to have an idea of the
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>character which is not incorporated, as it were, with them. But
            Mr. Murdoch’s personation was triumphantly received—rarely, if
            ever, have we heard such bursts of enthusiastic applause within the
            walls of a theatre, as greeted him throughout, and as followed the
            fall of the curtain. So has it been also, on every night of his appearance, the house being crowded by brilliant audiences on each
            occasion; and the experiment may, therefore, be regarded as one of
            the most successful on record.
         </p>
         <p>And this from the Saturday Courier :
            
         </p>
         <p>The success of this gentleman, since his return to the stage, has
            been most gratifying to his friends, and a source, we doubt not, of
            great felicitation to himself. From our too settled servility hitherto
            to foreign dictation in theatrical affairs, it was to be feared that native genius, however eminent, would not excite sufficient interest to
            insure a fair hearing. But in the case of Mr. Murdoch, that fear
            has been entirely dissippated, especially in this, his native city.,
            where his houses have been thus far crowded from pit to dome, with
            most intelligent and attentive audiences. To say that Mr. Murdoch who was ever a favorite, has greatly improved since he has
            left the stage, would be but a faint expression, in regard to one who
            has grasped with a nervous arm, an unfaltering foot, an indomitable resolution, the very highest range of his profession. His readings, points, and bearings evince the close and hearty study he has
            accorded to their perfection, and his audiences appear keenly alive
            to their many beauties.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Murdoch has performed, during the present week,
            another brilliant and triumphant engagement in this same
            city. In our notices of the Theatre, we shall always have
            an eye to its reform and elevation. We are, in this respect, on the eve of a great dramatic Revolution.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Miss Cushman, the Actress.—We notice that some of the
            American papers say Miss Cushman has not been doing well at
            the English provincial theatres. There are few, if any, of our own
            celebrated actresses who have pocketed so many English sovereigns
            as our fair American friend, who has so lately left her home and
            country to seek fame and fortune in a foreign land.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Miss Cushman has just completed an engagement of twelve
            nights at Manchester, for which she received 2000 dollars. Her
            engagements at Bristol, Bath, Sheffield, and other places, have been
            excellent and most profitable.—English paper.
         </p>
         <p>Musical Department.
            
         </p>
         <p>Another leaf has again been added to Leopold De Meyer’s wreath of laurels, and another two or three thousand
            dollars haye wandered into the pockets of the artist, on
            the occasion of his first Concert, last Friday evening.—
            The Tabernacle was crammed; but this was no more
            than we expected.
         </p>
         <p>The performance consisted of
            
         </p>
         <p>1. Duett from Don Giovanni, Mozart, by Madame Adler and Signor Ph. Mater. It was rather indifferently
            performed, and the introduction Mr. Perabeau played,
            was altogether out of place ; for, though he behaved like
            a madman, he could not make the audience believe that he
            was a great performer on the Piano. The piece itself
            would have been of more effect in the middle of the performance.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>2.	Russian Airs, Second Set, composed and performed
            by L. De Meyer. If we never knew what Piano-forte music is, or can be, we might have learned it that evening.
            The most beautiful harmonies, the most delicate passages, the most brilliant arpeggios, each one by itself, and
            all combined—this was what the artist offered to an enraptured audience. He was encored, but declined playing, fearing, perhaps, to be too much fatigued at the end
            of the performance, to do justice to himself.
         </p>
         <p>3.	Casta Diva, from Norma, Bellini, by Madame Ad-
            ler. Perhaps Pico’s Casta Diva, which incessantly
            
         </p>
         <p>haunted our ears that evening, prevented our appreciating
            Madame Adler’s singing. We shall, therefore, wait for
            another opportunity to speak of her style and voice.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>4. Carnival de Venice arranged and performed by Leopold De Meyer, was rapturously encored, and Mr. De
            Meyer kindly repeated it, with a different introduction.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>5.	Aria from Lucia di Lammermoor, Donizetti, by
            Signor Ph. Mayer. A little hoarseness which prevailed
            in the beginning, wore off soon, and Mr. Mayer acquitted
            himself exceedingly well.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>6.	Overture to William Tell, arranged and performed
            by L. De Meyer. We have in vain ransacked the dictionaries of Webster, Walker, and others—no words could
            be found to express the effect produced by this composition. We will leave it, therefore, to our readers to imagine to themselves something so beautiful as to be indescribable, and they will have something like Mr. De Meyer’s performance of Rossini’s Overture.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>7.	Recitative and Grand Aria, from Massaniello, by
            Madame Adler. Much better sung than the former pieces of this lady. It would have gained her at once the
            good-will of the audience, if the brilliant roulades and
            coleratures at the end had not spoiled all the effect.—
            More scale singing we would recommend to this lady.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>8.	Grand March, Marocaine, by Leopold De Meyer.
            That the house did not break down under the thunder of
            applause is the only thing we wonder at, and we would
            advise all artists, who think of producing such a sensation as Mr. De Meyer, to secure the Tabernacle, if they
            will not risk the lives of their audience. After being encored, Mr. De Meyer gave us a fantasie on Yankee Doodle, improvised or not, we cannot say ; but it is so short,
            was the last word of thousands, as they left the Tabernacle, highly delighted with the evening’s entertainment.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Huber, the Violoncellist, the Composer, the Pianist—lor all
            of these is he, although the violoncello is the instrument of his
            heart, and his choice shows the earnestness of his musical feeling
            and the purity of his taste,—is attracting more and more the attention of the musical connoisseurs and the public. It is only from
            his unaffected simplicity and freedom from all display, that he has
            not created as great an excitement among the public generally.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Upon this, the most expressive of all instruments, his power is
            very great The most touching, the most passionate strains, notes
            of flute-like delicacy and arpeggio passages, whose full tone fills
            the saloon like the swell of an organ, come from his magic bow
            with the same facility.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>His compositions are replete with passages of great feeling and
            power, and though in a style peculiar to himself, have much of
            that passionate earnestness and abandon which is found in the
            compositions of Schubert.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>To the above remarks, from the Evening Gazette, we
            only add, that he is a Piano manufacturer at the same
            time. We have tried an instrument of his make, and in
            many points find it superior to those of Erard. It is a
            great deal lower in price. We understand the chief object of Mr. H. is to establish a manufactory of grand
            pianos in this city.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>U. C. Hill's Festival Concert.—Between three and
            four thousand people made the walls of the Tabernacle
            resound with their bravos and encores during the evening.
            It was a Festival Concert in the true meaning of the
            word. Chorists and Solists all tried their utmost; the
            orchestra was never better than on this occasion. Besides Leopold De Meyer, who drew down thunders of
            applause, no one astonished the audience more than Mr.
            Boucher. For the last four years he had not played in public,and here he comes out with a beautiful composition of
            his own, the performance of which would have given
            credit to a Servais, Franchomme, or Knoop.
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>We hope Mr. Boucher will no longer withhold from
            the public his talent and genius. Nothing serves more
            to make the violincello popular than such playing.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Miss Northall sang the Duett of Eliza el Claudio in
            good style; in fact, better than on former occasions. This
            young lady is destined, if she keeps on, to adorn all our
            public concerts and musical festivals. Mr. Meyer supported her well.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Madame Otto, has, it seems, improved in voice and
            style during her late absence from this country. In questo
            semplice could not have been sung better. Her higher
            notes are clear as silver bells.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Messrs. Kyle and Aupick did their part well, and only
            want of space prevents our going more into detail. We
            hope we shall have another opportunity to speak of the
            merits of these two eminent musicians.
         </p>
         <p>Now, Mr. Hill, the sooner you get up another Festival
            Concert, the better for the public and yourself.
            Miss Bramson gives a Concert to-night (Tuesday even-
            ing) at Niblo’s, which we shall notice in our next.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Wollenhaupt, a young pianist, lately arrived
            from Leipzig, makes quite a sensation amongst musicians.
            He is a pupil of the Leipzig Conservatoire.
         </p>
         <p>Ole Bull plays again on Thursday evening in Phila-
            delphia.
            Lucia di Lammermoor will be brought out next week
            at the Park, with Miss Delcy as Prima Donna.
            
         </p>
         <p>L. De Meyer has announced his second Concert for
            Friday next. He will be assisted by Miss Northall, Madame Lazare and Mr. P. Mayer.
         </p>
         <p>Editorial Miscellany.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Churchman and Dr. Cheever.—The Churchman
            is no friend to Dr. Cheever, his theology and his opinions, and from our own reflections, we can easily understand how a difference may arise in the premises. But
            we can see nothing in the case to justify the spirit of an
            article, in the last number of that organ, on the “Wanderings of a Pilgrim.” In the first place the price is printed
            wrong, apparently with design, for the sake of a joke long
            since discarded by penny-a-liners. Price 3s. 6d. In the
            first place this is not the price of the book, which is legibly printed on the cover thirty-seven and a half cents.
            Supposing it were forty-four cents—what joke can there
            be in British shillings and pence that there is not in American currency ? Yet such is the fact to the theological
            critic (not the editor) of the Churchman. The reading
            of that man must have been miserably confined even
            among the book shelves of his own creed. The spirits
            of Old Latimer and of South and of Fuller and of Corbet and of Sterne and of Swift, should rise up and thrust
            such a witling as that from even the outer court of the
            sanctuary ! He is a disgrace to a church renowned
            for wit and humor and the soul of the gentleman.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>What follows is of a piece for candor—a passage being isolated and battered with dirty adjectives till we
            confound the innocent words with the shabbiness thrown
            upon it. With a foul mouth you may thus mar the whiteness of the Parian marble. If a dirty fellow will brush
            against a gentleman, the gentleman will be mistaken for
            a dirty fellow, and in this way vulgar and malevolent
            critics vilify pure authors.
         </p>
         <p>Just censure is one thing, and this wholesale abuse is
            another. It is very possible that a practised knight of
            
         </p>
         <p>the quill might prick Dr. Cheever gracefully, and the
            public might be gratified at the spectacle, for the public
            loves to see an author tickled; but the public requires
            this spiriting to be done “gently”, and has no affection
            for the weapons of fish-women or scavengers, clerical or
            otherwise.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Upcott, the great collector of Autographs, recently died at his residence near London. His house
            has been often visited by American tourists to whom he
            was uniformly courteous, showing them the unique treasures of his house, literally lined with books, and being
            led by them too often to anticipate the sale of a portion
            of his collections in this country. When we saw him
            some years since, he was daily expecting letters from
            the United States respecting such a purchase for some
            twenty thousand dollars! He was anxious that his collections should be unbroken. He would choose a particular topic, and cm up books and magazines and newspapers till he had exhausted the subject. He had such
            a collection of cuttings from newspapers contemporary with the American Revolution and relating to that
            struggle, which Mr. Brodhead purchased and presented
            to the New-York Historical Society, It is probable that
            his books and antographs will be sold at auction.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Picture of New-York.—We have seen some exceedingly beautiful wood cuts, forming a part of a pictorial
            description of New-York city. Among the designs
            furnished are views of ten Episcopal, two Unitari-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>an, three Presbyterian, and several other Churches; the
            Deaf and Dumb Asylum, Society Library, Bloomingdale
            Asylum, Blind Asylum, &amp;c., together with several Brooklyn buildings, viz: First Unitarian Church, Church of
            the Pilgrims, the Long Island Tunnel.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This volume, we are informed, will comprise about
            200 pages, including forty illustrations by the best wood
            engravers of New-York, and will be published by Messrs.
            Homans &amp; Ellis early next month. Our city has long
            wanted a pictorial guide book for the use of strangers
            and citizens ; and the specimens before us lead us to think
            that justice will be done to some of our noble institutions,
            especially those of a charitable order.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Messrs. Humans A Ellis have also in hand, preparing
            by a resident clergyman, a brief account of all the
            Churches in Brooklyn and New-York, with numerous illustrations.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is to be hoped that every facility will be afforded by
            clergymen to the publishers to enable them to furnish a
            work whose details may be relied upon. One fact is al-
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>ready elicited by the enquiries instituted, viz: that there
            are forty-two churches erected in the city of Brooklyn,
            and forty-five congregations, three of whom worship in
            temporary rooms. This is probably a larger number of
            Churches than are contained in any city with a similar
            number of inhabitants, say 60,000.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The drawing we now give is of St. Thomas’ Church,
            in Broadway, at the corner of Houston. It is one of the
            most beautiful structures of which our city may boast. Its
            dimensions are 62 feet in width, 113 feet in depth ; built
            of dark stone, in the Gothic order, with two towers, each
            80 feet high.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Biographical, Ancestrical and Romantic Items from
            late European Journals.—The daily papers give but a
            brief abstract of the foreign intelligence on the arrival of
            the Steamers, chiefly confined to a few dry political facts,
            the price current, with a stray anecdote or two of a dwarf
            or a calf with two heads. It is singular how uniformly
            a few passages of the latter description come up, on such
            occasions, in the papers. A man snatches at an ‘extra’
            in great haste and, ten to one, his eye first alights upon
            some such important item as the delivery of five children
            at a birth in one of the Orkney Islands. The finest portions, the gems of the literary, scientific and artistical
            world, are scantily given, if not altogether neglected. We
            have thought the endeavor to supply this defect might
            meet with favor, from our readers, and have gleaned the
            following paragraphs, none of which are likely to be met
            with in the newspapers of the day. If the plan meets
            with favor we shall continue it. For our own part, we
            think we are supplying a deficiency, and that our columns
            could not be better employed.
         </p>
         <p>Item i. A new work by Ariosto !
            
         </p>
         <p>From Florence, we heard of a discovery ot great interest which
            has just been made by Signor Zampieri conservator of the Grand
            Ducal Library. Amongst the manuscripts in that establishment he
            has found one containing the greater part of an epic poem by
            Ariosto, of which hitherto the existence was unknown—and whose
            title is Rinaldo l' Ardito ('Rinaldo the Bold’). The work has been
            originally composed of 244 octave verses, divided into twelve cantos; of which the first, the beginning of the second, and the sixth
            are wanting in the manuscript in question. The Grand Duke has
            ordered its publication, at the government expense; and directed
            that a copy shall be sent to each of the great libraries of Europe, in
            the hope that a search will br made in those various institutions for
            the absent portions of the poem.
         </p>
         <p>Item ii. News of Tycho Brahe.
            
         </p>
         <p>From Copenhagen, too, we have accounts of a discovery of interest—which we report as we find it, though we think it probable
            there is some mistake in the terms. They state that professor
            Heiberg, who is occupied in collecting materials for a History of
            the Lite and Labors of the Illustrious Swedish Astronomer Tycho
            Brahe,—which he purposes publishing in the course of next year,;
            wherein will fall the 300th anniversary of the birth of the great
            savant—lately caused searches and excavations to be made amongst
            the ruins of the Chateau and Observatory of Tycho, in the little,
            Swedish Isle of Hvcen, situate in the Sound, which was the properly of the latter. These researches have, it is said, produced some
            curious results. A number of the tools used by the philosopher for
            the construction of his astronomical instruments have been found,
            —many of the completed instruments themselves, and some in an
            unfinished state—and several manuscripts in the Latin language,
            bearing the signature of Tycho Brahe, and containing astronomical observations, reflections on the events of his day, and occasional poetry.
         </p>
         <p>Item III. A Jewel-Fountain in South America,
            
         </p>
         <p>Last week, says the London Athenæum, we gave our readers
            some account—Irom a report sent by the French Consul to his
            government,—of a diamond mine which has been discovered in
            the Province of Bahia , and we have since found some details in
            a Brazilian paper,—which we are tempted to quote, for the singular effect produced by a narrative of facts that can only be given
            in language recalling the marvels of Oriental fiction. “ Some
            years ago," says the journal in question, “ veins of gold were accidentally discovered in the Assuara; and a crowd of contrabandists
            soon flocked to that desert portion of Bahia—situate not far from
            the southern banks of San Francisco—in search of fortune. The
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>gold, however, was but the harbinger of more marvellous wealth
            ere long to be found. The labors of the miner extended on every
            side; and diamond-strata were soon discovered, of richness incalculable. In every stream and on every hill of these districts, and
            of the vast plain of Sincara, treasures inestimable, in gold and precious stones, presented themselves spontaneously to the hand of man.
            Attracted by the rumour, multitudes of emigrants from the town
            and province of Bahia, from Minas, and even from Rio Janerio,
            crowded thither to quench the universal thirst at this jewel-fountain. It is scarcely three years since the first ounce of gold was
            found in this region—then a desert; and it contains already a population exceeding forty thousand souls. It would be difficult, says
            this journal, to credit all that is told of the product of these new
            mines, if the letters and reports of trust-worthy eye-witnesses did
            not confirm the wildest of them. One letter says, “ Gold is common and abundant in every brook, and throughout the entire district ; but no man regards it—all are gathering diamonds.” “ Our
            readers may form an idea,” the paper adds, “ of the importance of
            these treasures, when they know that a single packet-ship exported
            lately, from Bahia to Europe, diamonds to the amount of 1,000
            contos des reis (upwards of 106,000._) although the larger portion
            of these precious stones are carried first to Rio Janerio,—where,
            because of a greater abundance of capital and better acquaintance
            with the sort of traffic, they fetch higher prices.”
         </p>
         <p>Item iv. Two anecdotes for Bibliomaniacs—Gold and
            Fame.
            
         </p>
         <p>A Precious Volume.—A curious circumstance occurred last
            week at the sale of the books of the late Dean of Lincoln.—
            Amongst the persons attracted was Mr. John Deighton, the bookseller, of Cambridge: he was looking over the lots shortly before
            the auction commenced, when on taking up a copy of Doane’s
            'Death, Judgment, Heaven, and Hell,’ he thought the volume felt
            very’ ponderous; and on examining it, he discovered that in the
            book-binder’s "fly-leaf,” at the beginning, several coins were sewed. He called the attention of the auctioneer to the circumstance;
            and it was ascertained that a manuscript letter was fastened to the
            leaf, and that seven guineas and two half-guineas of the reign of
            Charles II. were strongly sewed within, like so many buttons. The
            coins were quite bright and fresh ; and though many of the books
            in the library were sadly damaged by damp and neglect, this volume and its contents had escaped injury for the lapse of 160 years.
         </p>
         <p>The letter had no signature, but from its style seemed to be the
            writing of a father to his son at one of the universities. The lot,
            made interesting by this circumstance, was withdrawn from the
            auction.—Stanford Mercury.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Gazette des Tribunaux furnishes an anecdote from one of the
            bye-ways of Parisian life, which is worth reporting in the Athenæum rather for its touching character than lor any direct relation
            which it has to literature. Some days since, a widow, keeping a
            well-known book-stall near the Pont St. Michel, was addressed by
             an old man, to whom his load of wretchedness seemed a heavier
            burthen than even that of his years. From beneath an old tattered
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p> garment the stooping man drew forth a thick volume, torn and
            stained by long use; and offering it to the book-dealer, said:—
            “Intrinsically this is worth a mere nothing: it had a value to
            me, however; but I have not the courage to let myself die of
            my hunger,—so give me for it what you will.” The volume
            in question was the “ History of Astronomy amongst all Nations,”
            by Bailly; and, in its worn-cut condition, was dear at 50
            centimes;—but, the female merchant, pitying its owner’s destitution, gave him a franc; and the latter immediately entering a
            baker's shop, brought out a portion of a loaf, and sat down to eat it
            solitary by the river’s side. M. G—, a canon of Notre Dame and
            hunter of the book-stalls in this neighborhood, had been a witness
            of the scene; and taking up the book when the old man was gone,
            he found on the reverse of the title-page the following lines, firmly
            traced, but whose ink had assumed the color of rust"—"My young
            friend, I am condemned to die;—at this hour to-morrow I shall be
            no more. I leave you friendless in the world—in a time of dreadful trouble; and that is one of my bitterest griefs. I had promised
            to be a father to you;—God wills that my promise shall not be performed. Take this volume as the pledge of my earnest love—
            and keep it in memory of me.—Bailly.” Deeply affected by this
            one record of such varied miseries, at the opposite extremes of fifty
            years, the canon flung two francs to the merchant lor her bargain,
            —and hastened with it to the old man, of whom he had net
            for a moment lost sight. From the latter, he learned that
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>he was the natural son of a person of high rank; had been,
            Waller his father’s death, the pupil and almost the adopted
            child of Bailly; and that, on the eve of his death, the illustrious martyr sent to him this copy of the work which, in 1784, had
            opened to himself the doors of the Academy. This unfortunate
            pupil of an unfortunate master, after having been long engaged
            in the business of public instruction, had been attacked by illness,
            which compelled him to resign his functions; and had since been
            gradually sinking into the slate of destitution, under whose gnawing promptings he had turned the last gift of his benefactor and
            friend into bread. The canon took the old man to his home; and
            has since labored successfully to procure his admission into the
            hospital of Laronchefoucauld—where the remainder of his days
            are sure, at least, of temporal comforts.
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>Miss Elizabeth Hamilton, and not Mrs. Grant, as
            stated in a former number, is the author of “ The Cottagers of Glenburnie.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A Pension to Tennyson.—It is stated in the ‘ Cambridge Independent,’ says the London Examiner, that Alfred Tennyson, the Poet, has received a pension of £200
            per annum from her Majesty, at the recommendation of
            Sir Robert Peel.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Lord Byron’s Statue, by Thorwaldsen, of the admission of which to Westminster Abbey so much has been
            written, has reached its destination at Trinity, Cambridge,
            where it will be put up in the College Library.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Contributors to Punch move together in a body.
            They recently appeared, designers and all, with Dickens,
            in the amateur performance of Ben Jonson’s “Every
            Man in his Humor.” They are now to be present, or
            rather have been, Mark Lemon, Gilbert á Becket, Douglas Jerrold, with Charles Dickens, at the Manchester
            Athenaeum Soiree, held on the evening of the 23d of October.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Vatican Library.—The Pope has thrown the
            library of printed books in the Vatican open to the public, and ordered the preparation of a catalogue.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>New Poem by Southey.—Messrs. Longmans announce
            “ Oliver Newman, A New-England Tale," an unfinished
            poem from the literary remains of Southey.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Bryant is expected to return to the United States
            from his European tour, some time this month. He will
            bring with him the fruits of a ripe observation, gathered
            among the finest scenes of Europe, and under circumstances perhaps never surpassed by any traveller. His reception has been right honorable to the man.
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Forrest’s stay in Europe will probably be pro-
            tracted to another season.
            
         </p>
         <p>Professor Kingsley has already sent some three thou
            sand volumes from Amsterdam, Leyden and Paris, to the
            new Library of Yale College.
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Simms' new novel, “Count Julian,’’ will be ready
            in about a week.
            
         </p>
         <p>London Editions of the Reviews at American Prices.
            —We would call particular attention to the fact that
            Messrs. Wiley &amp; Putnam will hereafter furnish London
            copies of the Edinburgh Review, the Quarterly, Foreign
            Quarterly and Westminster, at three dollars and a half
            per annum, if mailed in London. Also, Blackwood and
            Frazer at five dollars per annum. This will secure the
            original copies and at the earliest moment, as they will
            be delivered through the post-office, at the reduced rates
            of postage, simultaneously with the letters, on the arrival
            of the steamers.
         </p>
         <p>WILEY &amp; PUTNAM
            "PROPOSE to supply, if there is sufficient patronage,
            the original London editions of the following Periodicals at
            the prices annexed, to be mailed in London.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Periodicals will be put in strong wrappers with printed address, and can be sent to any part of the United States; so that they
            may be received as soon as the letters per Boston Steamers.
         </p>
         <p>All persons wishing to subscribe will please address Wiley &amp;
            Putnam before the first of December next.
            Subscriptions must be paid in all cases in advance.
            
         </p>
         <p>Edinburgh Review, $3 50
            Foreign Quarterly Review, 3 50
            Westminster Review, 3 50
            Forbes’ Medical Review, 4 00
            Frazer’s Magazine,	5	 00
         </p>
         <p>dec 13 3t
            Quarterly Review,	$3 	50
            North British Review,	3 	50
            For. &amp;. Colonial Review,	3	 50
            Blackwood's Magazine,	5	 00
            Presbyterian Review,	3	 50
            ELEGANT NEW WORK.
            C. SHEPARD, BOOKSELLER, 191 BROADWAY.
            
         </p>
         <p>CHAUNT OF LIFE—and other Poems, by Rev. R. Hoyt, a
            Clergyman of the Episcopal Church, New York. Parts 1 &amp; 2.
            This work is beautifully printed on fine paper, embellished, and
            handsomely bound. Price 37 1/2 cents.
         </p>
         <p>The following are extracts from a few of the notices it has re-
            ceived from the Press:—
            
         </p>
         <p>“There is a natural vigor in this poem (World for Sale) which
            is wrung from the life,—a wild music from the very heartstrings.”
            —Morning News.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ This is a scene (snow) that every one will recognize as lifelike and truthful,—no artist could paint it better.”—Hud. Riv.
            Chronicle.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ We have seen many quartos, not taken either from the lowest
            rank of dullness, with far less that is acceptable in them.”—Dem.
            Review.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ We commend this volume to the lover of true poetry, and can
            say, in all sincerity, if Mr. Hoyt, in his following numbers, sustains the character of this, there is no doubt of his success."—N.
         </p>
         <p>Y. Evening Mirror.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ It is printed in a very neat and even elegant style, worthy of
            the grace, delicacy and beauty of the poems.”—N. Y. Courier and
            Enquirer.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ He writes with grace, taste and genius, and many of his productions possess merit of the highest order. Some of his best
            pieces will be incorporated in a new edition of the Poets and
            Poetry of America.”—Phil. Nat. Gazette.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“We give a stanza from the principal poem in the volume,
            commending this delicious little brochure as one of the best New
            Year’s presents that could be selected.”—N. Y. Express.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ The Chaunt is one of the finest modern poems that we have
            read this many a day, and abounds in highly wrought and beautiful
            passages. The author, Rev. Ralph Hoyt, is destined to a high
            rank in the American temple ol poetry, and we heartily thank
            him for providing us such a rare poetic feast as he has given us
            in this volume.”—N. Y. Rambler.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Full of delicate description, perfect truth and beauty of sentiment; and style pure and limpid as the chrystal stream, all enveloped in a charming atmosphere of grace and piety and purest imagination. It is a gem and a noble offering,’’— Churchman.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Part II. contains the second canto of a very fine poem,—the
            Chaunt of Life; From the first stanza we quote three remarkably
            beautiful lines. The fourth and fifth stanzas are very noble.—
            The poem Old has so many rare and peculiar excellences, that
            we shall venture to copy it in full.”—Broadway Journal.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ The Chaunt of Life is like the opening of some glorious ma
            jestic strain of music, through which the mournful spirit of the
            past gives lone and unutterable earnestness to the aspirations of
            the present and the hopes of the future. Such strains as those ot
            our author will be heard. They sink at once into the heart and
            abide there.”—Prot. Churchman.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ We have not seen a volume in a year that we have been more
            taken with than this. It is a pleasure to meet an author who can,
            like Mr. Hoyt, make his theories attractive and bis method striking without setting up lor a misanthrope, or invoking the aid of
            the infernals.—Phil. Sat. Eve. Post.
         </p>
         <p>CHEAP MUSIC.
            HOMANS &amp; ELLIS have published the first No. of
            	THE MUSICAL WORLD,
            
         </p>
         <p>A Semi-monthly Magazine, containing sixteen pages of beautifully printed Music, and a Journal of Musical Biography, Criticism, and News.</p>
         <p>Edited by Henry C. Watson.—Contents of No. 1.
            
         </p>
         <p>I'll be there,—words by Fitzball—music by Herbert Rodwell.
            Let no thought of care oppress thee,—words by Charles Jeffreys—
            music by Bellini.
         </p>
         <p>Far away in my own bright land,—	“	“ Bellini.
            O cast that shadow from thy brow,— a beautiful ballad.
            The sunny hours of childhood,—words by J. L. Carpenter—music
            by J. Hanoway, R. A.
            The melodies of many lands,—words by Charles Jeffreys—music
            by C. W. Glover.
            Price 25 Cents.
            The second number ol the Musical World will be published on
            the 15th inst.
            In Press—Grand Galop, by Leopold De Meyer, with a portrait
            and critical biography, will be ready early next week.
            JOHN ANDERSON &amp;. CO.
            importers and dealers in
            
         </p>
         <p>CHOICE SEGARS, and Manufacturers of Premium
            Tobacco and Snuffs—2 Wall, and 13 and 15 Duane streets,
            New-York.	nov 8—3m
         </p>
         <p>
            NEW WORKS,
            TO BE PUBLISHED BY
            MESSRS. WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 BROADWAY,
            IN THE MONTH OF NOVEMBER.
            I.
            Western Clearings, by Mrs. C. M. Kirkland, author of “ A New
            Home,” &amp;c. 1 vol. 16mo. 50 cents.
            II.
            The Raven and other Poems, by Edgar A. Poe, 1 vol. 16mo. 31 cts.
            III.
            Views and Reviews in American History, Literature, and Fiction,
            by W. Gilmore Simms. 1 vol. 16mo.
            IV.
            Life of the Great Condi, by Lord Mahon, 2 vols. 16mo. 37 1/2
            cents each.
            V.
            Charles Lamb's Specimens of English Dramatic Poets, 2 vols.
            16mo. 50 cents each.
            VI.
            The Rhine, by Victor Hugo.
            VII.
            Father Ripa’s Residence in China, 1 vol. 16mo. 37 1/2 cts.
            VIII.
            The Fall of the Jesuits, 1 vol. l6mo. 37 1/2 cts.
            IX.
            Lectures on the English Poets, by Wm. Hazlitt. 1 vol, 16mo.
            PAINE &amp; BURGESS,
            62 John Street,
            WILL PUBLISH IN A FEW DAYS,
            
         </p>
         <p>THE ARTIST, MERCHANT, AND STATESMAN,
            Part I. This work is made up of the choicest and most original material on Fine Arts, Commerce, and Political Economy,
            by C. Edwards Lester.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>PRAIRIEDOM ; Rambles and Scrambles in Texas or
            New Estremadura, by a Southron. 1 vol. l2mo. with a map. “ It
            is light and vivacious—filled with incident—easy and flowing in
            style, and brilliant in imagery.”—Evening Mirror.
         </p>
         <p>THEY ARE PREPARING FOR PUBLICATION,
            Songs and Ballads by Gen. G. P. Morris, 32mo. gilt.
            
         </p>
         <p>Rambles by Land and Water, or Notes of Travel in Cuba and
            Mexico, including a canoe voyage up the river, Panuco, and Researches among the Antiquaries of Taumelipas, by B. M. Norma,
            1 vol. 12mo. illustrated.
         </p>
         <p>The Greece of the Greeks, by G. A. Perdicarts, U. S. Consul at
            Athens, 2 vols. 12mo. illustrated.
            Trippings in Authorland, by Fanny Forrester.
            Montezuma, the Last of the Aztecs, an Historical Romance, on
            the Conquest of Mexico, by Edward Maturin, 2 vols. 12mo.
            “This is an original American work.”
            The Prince, by Machiavelli, 1 vol. 12mo.
            Man in the Republic, by C. Mathews, 1 vol. 32mo. gilt.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Old Continental; or the Prince of Liberty—an historical
            romance, by the author of the 'Dutchman’s Fireside,’ 2 vols. 12mo.
            —now ready—
         </p>
         <p>The Medici Series of Italian Prose.
            The Autobiography of Alfieri, l vol. 12mo. Price 50 cents.
            The Secret Thoughts and Actions of Genius, blended with the
            wildest adventures and strongest caprices.
            The Citizen of a Republic; what arc his rights and duties, by
            Ansaldo Ceba, 1 vol. 12mo. Price 50 cents.
            “ A book of condensed and rare thoughts, like diamonds finely
            polished and richly set.”
            The Challenge of Barletta, a romance of the Times of the Me-
            dici, l vol. 12mo.		
            “ A gem gathered from the jewelled mine of Italian romance."
            The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli, 2 vols. 12mo.
            “ The charmed records of the classic city of the Arno, by the
            master spirit of his age.”			nov 8
            General furnishing Hardware, Cutlery, Tools, &amp;c.
            OSBORN &amp; LITTLE,
            Importers and General Dealers in English, German and
            American
            HARDWARE, CUTLERY, &amp;.C.,
            No. 33 FULTON STREET,
            BETWEEN PEARL AND WATER STREETS,
            [Where the business has been carried on for Eighty Years past,]
            Charles Osborn	NEW YORK.
            Charles S. Little
            
         </p>
         <p>Hardware, Cutlery, Nails, Locks, Latches, Butts, Screws, Anvils, Vices, Saws, Files, Shovels ami Spades, Hollow Ware, Corn
            and Coffee Mills, Rivets, Pumps, Curriers’ Hones, Crucibles,
            Black Lead, Pots, &amp;c. &amp;c. Also Genuire Haarlem Oil. American Coopers and Carpenters Edge Tools, of Albertson's Conger's
            Barton's, Horton’s, Gifford’s, and other makers. Also, Cooper’s
            Truss Hoops.	nov8—3m
         </p>
         <p>KNOX’S HATS.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE FALL STYLE OF GENTLEMEN’S HATS are now
            ready for the season, 1845, which for lightness and superiority
            of color cannot be surpassed, which is a very important part of the
            hat, retaining the color till it is worn out. Any article sold in this
            establishment is never misrepresented but sold for what it is. Also the fall style of boy’s and children’s Caps, of various patterns.
            Gentlemen can have their hats made to order in any shape or style
            they wish. A full assortment of ladies’ Muffs, of all kinds.
         </p>
         <p>C. KNOX, No. 110 Fulton st,
            Nov. 8—3m	between William and Nassau sis.
            GURNEY’S
            PREMIUM DAGUERRIAN GALLERY,
            189 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.
            
         </p>
         <p>PITCURES taken at this Establishment are not excelled in this
            country—so say his numerous patrons. The public are invited to call and judge for themselves.	o2
         </p>
         <p>TO MEDICAL MEN.
            This day published, the London lancet
            
         </p>
         <p>for November, a Journal of British, Foreign, Medical and
            Chemical Science, Criticism and News—edited by Thomas Wakely, M. P. Surgeon, and Henry Bennett, M. D.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is the fifth number ot the second volume, containing, besides its usual quantity of valuable matter, the 2d Lecture of a series of Lectures on Organic Chemistry, by Justus Liebig.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Also, four additional Lectures on the Mechanism and Management ot Natural and Difficult Labors, by Edward W. Murphy,
            A.M. MD.
         </p>
         <p>Terms—$5 per annum, in advance; single numbers 50 cents,
            mailed to any part of the United States, by
            BURGESS, STRINGER &amp; CO.
            222 Broadway, cor. Ann st.
            P.S.—The postage to any distance on the Lancet is 6 1/4 cts.
            PENMANSHIP.
            
         </p>
         <p>RE-OPENING OF GOLDSMITH’S WRITING ACADEMY,
            289 Broadway—La Farge Buildings, corner of Reade street.
            Terms reduced to three dollars, and no extra charge.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the citizens of New
            York and Brooklyn, that his rooms are now open, during the day
            and evening, tor Pupils and Visitors. Mr. G’s. specimens of
            PENMANSHIP
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>have received the First Premium Five Years, from the American
            Institute, and he guarantees to all in TEN EASY AND INTERESTING EXERCISES, a free and elegant style of writing, that
            the pupils cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice. 
         </p>
         <p>For sale at the Academy GOLDSMITH’S GEMS OF PEN-
            MANSHIP.
            Ladies’ Class meets daily at 11 o’clock. Gentleman’s day and
            evening. See circular.	s18
            PARLOR ORGAN.
            A FINE toned Parlor Organ for sale or in exchange for a Pia-
            no-Forte. Apply to
            3w               EZRA COLLIER, 103 Fulton st.
            JAMES PIRSSON,
            
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER, 88, 90, and 92
            Walker street, near Elm. A large slock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms moderate. For Sale—A splendid
            Harp, nearly new—to be sold at a great bargain for cash.
         </p>
         <p>J. BALLARD,
            PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR, SINGING AND FLUTE.
            No. 135 SPRING-STREET.
            JOHN BURFORD,
            PORTRAIT AND LANDSCAPE PAINTER,
            27 Dey Street
            G. B. CLARKE,
            MERCHANT TAILOR, (from Brundage, Broadway)
            No 132 William Street, 3 doors from Fulton, N. Y.
            Dress Coat, from $12 to $20 00
            a nts,	“	2 50 to 8 00
            Vest,	“	1 50 to 4 50
            
         </p>
         <p>Making and Trimming
            Dress Coat, from $6 00 to 9 00
            Pants,	“	l 50 to 2 00
         </p>
         <p>Vests,	“	1 50 to 2 00
            N. B. Seasonable SACK COATS, VESTS, &amp;c. always on
            hand, from $1 50 upwards.	____ nov8—3m
            WEDDING, VISITING, &amp; PROFESSIONAL CARDS
            Engraved and Printed at VALENTINE'S, 1 Beekman-st.
            Lovejoy’s Hotel.___________________________
            CARD OF REMOVAL,
            
         </p>
         <p>MR. W. A. KING PROFESSOR OF MUSIC, AND
            Teacher of the Piano Forte and Organ, has removed to the
            First House above Twenty-fifth street, on the Railroad, (4th
            Avenue.)
         </p>
         <p>
            HARPER &amp; BROTHERS’ RECENT PUBLICATIONS,
            In one splendidly printed volume, with above 1000 engravings.
            Sheep Extra.—Price $3 75.
            ENCYCLOPӔDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY.
            
         </p>
         <p>The wide range of topics comprised in this valuable publication,
            commends it to the attention of an unusually extended class of readers:—to the family circle primarily, the architect, the horticulturist, the cabinet-maker, and others to whom the work addresses
            itself. It is undoubtedly by far the best work of reference ever presented for the use of families. Every housekeeper would find the
            work a real treasure.—Globe.
         </p>
         <p>II.
            PROFESSOR WHEWELL’S ELEMENTS OF MO-
            RALITY.
            Two volumes l2mo. extra muslin gilt, 81.-Forming the com-
            mencement of
            HARPER’S NEW MISCELLANY,
            
         </p>
         <p>A work of extraordinary merit. It is a thorough discussion of
            the fundamental principles of morals, by one of the profoundest
            thinkers of the age: and whether his conclusions are adopted or
            not, no reader can fail to perceive in any page, the traces of discrimination, thought, and a high moral aim. Its classic parity and
            precision of style is also a strong commendation of the work.—Observer.
         </p>
         <p>III.
            MORRELL’S AMERICAN SHEPHERD,
            
         </p>
         <p>Being a complete history of the sheep, with their breeds, management, diseases, &amp;c. Illustrated by numerous engravings, 1
            vol. 12mo., cloth binding, $1—paper covers 75 cents.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ The above named volume, which is issued under the immediate sanction of the New York State Agricultural Society, is a work
            of great practical importance, and contains a prodigious amount of
            instructive matter, suited to the farmer, the cattle fattener, the agriculturist and the wool-grower. Every one interested it. these departments of commerce would find the work invaluable.”—Evening
            Gazette.
         </p>
         <p>ILLUSTRATED WANDERING JEW.
            In numbers; price 25 cents each. Profusely embellished.
            
         </p>
         <p>"We think these illustrations evince more vigor, brilliancy, and
            effect, than almost any thing of the kind we have yet seen. As the
            Harpers publish this revised and elegant edition at such very trifling charge, we doubt not a prodigious demand will await it from
            the public ; and it richly merits the largest popularity.”—Evening
            Post.
         </p>
         <p>v.
            GEN. GREEN’S
            
         </p>
         <p>TEXAN EXPEDITION AGAINST MIER,
            Including the subsequent imprisonment of the author; his sufferings and final escape from the Castle of Perote; with reflections
            upon the present political and probable future relations of Texas,
            Mexico and the United States, &amp;c. Illustrated by thirteen line engravings. One volume, 8vo. $2.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This stirring narrative of the perilous and heroic exploits of a
            small band of patriotic Texans, who won not only laurels by their
            prowess, but liberty, is so rife with thrilling interest that it will win
         </p>
         <p>the attention of the public with the fascination of a romance._
            Com. Adv.
            VI.
            CURIOUS AND UNIQUE WORK.
            Now ready, in one beautiful octavo volume, with many Engra-
            vings on steel, price $2,
            NARRATIVE OF A MISSION TO BOKHARA.
            In the year 1843-45, to ascertain the fate of Col. Stoddart and
            Capt. Conolly.
            By the Rev. Joseph Wolff L.L.D.
            
         </p>
         <p>“This work has created a prodigious excitement throughout
            England: it is unique in its character, as a literary production. It
            seems to partake of the features of an autobiography ; the narrative
            being full of personal detail, description of the perilous adventure
            and imminent hazard of the author, in his expedition through the
            East. No man living, perhaps, has travelled so extensively as this
            celebrated individual, and few could have contributed a more intensely interesting narrative of his experience.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ It will thus be seen that this extraordinary and eccentric man
            is admirably qualified to present a transcript of Asiatic Characteristics,—supplying much that is novel and exceedingly curious
            about tribes and nations of which we know so little. To say that
            the work is an acceptable addition to the library of travel, is affirming far too little of so striking a production : it is a book that ought
            to he read and deliberately enjoyed by every intelligent person, for
            its quaintness, freshness, and superabounding interest. The work
            is elegantly primed as a library hook, and adorned by some dozen
            curious facsimiles of oriental drawings."— Courier and Enquirer.
         </p>
         <p>IMPORTANT WORKS,
            RECENTLY PUBLISHED BY
            J. &amp; H. G. LANGLEY, 8 ASTOR HOUSE.
            I.
            Von Raumer’s New Work.
            
         </p>
         <p>America and the American People: being the result of the author’s recent travels through the United States. Translated from
            the German of Frederick Von Raumer, by Professor Wm. W.
            Turner. 1 vol. 8 vo: 530 pp. Price $2.
         </p>
         <p>II.
            Eliza Cook’s Poetical Works.
            
         </p>
         <p>New Edition, containing all her recent productions. Edited by
            Rufus W. Griswold. 1 vol. 12 mo., illustrated with a Portrait and
            twelve exquisite English engravings. Copies in Morocco, super
            $3 50—Cloth Gilt, $2 50.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>"This is a beautiful volume, splendidly bound, and still more
            elegantly illustrated, and combining some of the choicest poems in
            the language. The “ Old Arm Chair,” is one of the most popular
            poems, and has touched the hearts of thousands who never knew
            even the name of the author. She writes for the heart, and her
            beautiful songs always reach it. The book forms one of the most
            elegant holiday presents yet offered."—Cour. &amp; Enq..
         </p>
         <p>III.
            Miss Barrett’s Poems.
            The Drama of Exile, and other Poems, by Elizabeth B. Barrett.
            2 vols. 12 mo., elegantly printed.—$2 00.
            
         </p>
         <p>"Miss Barrett is worth a dozen of Tennyson, and six of Motherwell—equal perhaps in orignial genius to Keats and Shelley.—
            There are beauties enough in one of her poems to have made a
            fame in Waller's time.”— Willis' Evening Mirror.
         </p>
         <p>IV.
            Gregg’s Santa Fe and the Prairies.
            
         </p>
         <p>Commerce of the Prairies, or the Journal of a Santa Fé Trader,
            the personal observation of a trader, made on eight several ex
            ditions across the Great Western Prairies, and during an aim
            uninterrupted residence of nine years in Northern Mexico.— Illustrated with numerous engravings. New Edition, revised by
            Author. By Josiah Gregg. 2 vols. 12 mo. $2 00.
         </p>
         <p>V.
            M. DE TOCQUEVILLE’S GREAT WORK.
            
         </p>
         <p>Democracy in America, by Alexis De Tocqueville. Third edition, in 2 vols. 8vo. Corrected and Enlarged, with an Original Index. Translated by Henry Reeve, Esq., with Introductory Prefaces, by the Hon. John C. Spencer. Price $4 00 in muslin or
            sheen.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>" This work is one of the most profound and philosophical ever
            written upon the character and institutions of our country.”—
            Boston Traveller.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>"As a Study of political science, this book stands unrivalled in
            our times; equally remarkable for lucidity of style, acuteness and
            delicacy of reasoning, and lor the moral and intellectual rigor with
            which it has been conceived and completed.”—London Times.
         </p>
         <p>VI.
            DE TOCQUEVILLE ABRIDGED.
            
         </p>
         <p>Designed for District School Libraries, Colleges, tic. In accordance with the recommendation of several superintendents of District Schools, the Publishers beg to announce that they have just
            issued a condensed edition of the above standard work, adapted expressly for the use of District Schools, Colleges &amp;c., to form 1 vol.
            12mo. Price $1 00.
         </p>
         <p>VII.
            The Life of General Francis Marion.
            By W Gilmore Simms, author of “ Guy Rivers,” &amp;c. &amp;c.
            Seventh edition, revised by the author, with numerous engravings,
            
         </p>
         <p>1 vol. l2mo.—81. “ Few characters have stood out more boldly
            on our Revolutionary Annals, or have supplied more interesting
            and exciting materials for the historian, than that of Gen. Marion ;
            and it is not saying too much to claim for the work before us no
            less the merit of accredited historical truth, than the most stirring
            and absorbing attributes of high-wrought fiction.”—Democratic
            Review.
         </p>
         <p>VIII.
            The Poetical Works of Praed.
            
         </p>
         <p>Lillian, and other Poems, Fanciful and Facetious. By William
            Mackworth Praed. First collected edition: Edited by R. W.
            Griswold, 1 vol. 12mo., muslin. $1 25.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>" Praed was the Poet of Society, 'a fellow of infinite humor,’
            and in scholarship and art, surpassed by none of the English poets
            of the age. Though many of his pieces have been almost universally read in this country, they have never yet been printed collectively, either here or in England.”—Democratic Review.
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
            THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to Du-
            
         </p>
         <p>bois and Stodart.) No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete
            assortment the latest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of
            the must superior quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for
            their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices.
            Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired, Piano Fortes always on hire
         </p>
         <p>
            J. F. BROWNE &amp; CO.
            MANUFACTURER Of THE
            IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION HARP,
            By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years with Erard.
            JF. BROWNE respectfully informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has established
            himself for the manufacture
            and importation of these very beautiful instruments, at
            281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET.
            His arrangements are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices,
            thereby saving purchasers the high duties
            imposed by Tariff on these Instruments.
            
         </p>
         <p>J. F. Browne would observe, these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
            with all the modern improvements of
            London and Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy of tone, fineness of touch, and perfectness
            of mechanism. Particular care is taken
            to fit them for the extremes of climate in this country, in which respect they will
            be found far superior to any of European manufacture, imported in the usual way.
         </p>
         <p>These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and professional talent in
            Europe; among the latter, he would mention
            N. C. Boscha, who invariably selects froth this establishment.
            J. F. Browne begs to offer the opinions of some of the first professional talent in
            this country.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. J. F. Browns, Sir:—Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making
            a professional use of your Harps, and of
            testing their qualities, it affords me pleasure to certify, that in point of tone,
            workmanship, and above all, a solidity that stands proof
            against the inconstancy of our trying climate, they have in all cases given me the
            most entire satisfaction.
         </p>
         <p>January, 1845	I am yours, CHARLES THIBAULT, No. 40 Beach St., N. Y.
            
         </p>
         <p>Dear Sir:—I write to express the delight I experienced in performing on one of your
            Harps at Sig. Casella’s Concert in this city.—
            The mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly superior to any harp I
            have heard for many years. I remember my old
            Master, Boscha, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no
            other. Yours, most truly, H. G. TRUST
            Philadelphia, March 4th, 1844.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir :—I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make
            I performed on at the St. George’s Society
            Concert, is, in brilliancy of tone, touch and elegance of workmanship, the finest
            I ever played on. This will apply to all your Harps.
            The grand six and a hall Gothic Double action, is a most splendid instrument Yours,
            with respect, ELIZABETH SLOMAN.
            New York, January 16th, 1845.	A pupil of N. C. Boscha.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—Having at your request closely scrutinized your double-action
            Harps, I find they possess the best qualities of the first makers in Europe combined. That in the ease of touch, by which the
            most brilliant tone is obtained, in perfection and
            ease of modulation, they arc superior to any I have used ; their elegance of exterior
            must gratify the most refined taste. Your new
            Grand Gothic six and a half octave, is the most splendid effort of art yet produced
            in the musical world ; it will give me great pleasure
            in recommending your Harps at every opportunity.	Yours Truly, HENRY HORN.
         </p>
         <p>January 12th, 1845	An eminent professor, and Member of the Royal Academy.
            
         </p>
         <p>These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
            show the estimate of persons every way capable of
            making a correct decision. J. F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the
            Society of Arts, Philadelphia, for his splendid
            improvements in this delightful Instrument.
         </p>
         <p>Harps from 300 to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.
            DENTISTRY.
            
         </p>
         <p>DOCT. H. E. SCHOONMAKER, Dental Surgeon, Office 446
            Houston St., two doors from Broadway—opposite St. Thomas’
            Church.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Doct. S's experience and skill in his profession, give him confidence in asserting that his operations are unsurpassed by any
            Dentist in this city. Dr. S.’s manner of inserting artificial teeth
            varies in many essential points from the usual mode ; and his success in pleasing all, he is happy to say, has brought him many
            difficult cases, which had been unsuccessfully treated by Dentists
            of established professional reputation, and whose prices for the
            same operation were double his own. The object in inserting
            artificial teeth is to supply the deficiency occasioned by the loss of
            natural teeth, both in regard to utility, comfort in wearing, and
            natural appearance. In all these points, Doct S.'s manner is preeminent. His mechanical tact and ingenuity have enabled him to
            surmount many obstacles, which have long, with the profession
            generally, impeded the path to success in every operation. He
            makes use of the best materials in all his operations—and in cases
            where the gum has fallen away by absorption, (which is always
            the case, more or less, when teeth have been extracted,) which
            causes a contraction of the lips and cheeks, the disfigurement of
            which cannot be fully obviated without adopting the artificial gums,
            which will supply the deficiency, and give to the mouth its usual
            redundancy—besides, their beauty and natural appearance, render detection impossible.
         </p>
         <p>Dr. S. would be happy to refer those who require it, to many of
            the best families in this City, in which he has practised.
            Ladies who desire it, can have their teeth examiner at their re-
            sidences, by sending their addresses above,	nov. 8—9t
            UNITED STATES HOTEL.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE PROPRIETOR OF THIS HOTEL, desires to return his
            thanks to his friends, and the travelling portion of the community generally, for the favors which they have bestowed upon him
            since he opened his Establishment, and to assure them that he will
            spare no exertions to render his House worthy of the patronage of
            which he has already received so liberal a share.
         </p>
         <p>H. JOHNSON. 
            Nov. 8th, 1845.	6m
            PIANO FORTES.
            
         </p>
         <p>CHEAP FOR CASH.—The Subscribers have on hand a
            handsome assortment, 6, 6 1/2, and 7 octave mahogany and rosewood Pianos, which they will warrant and sell low tor cash or approved paper.	GLENN, ROGERS &amp; CO.,
         </p>
         <p>___________Manufacturers, 152 Fulton street, east of Broadway.
            JUST PUBLISHED
            WILEY &amp; PUTNAM’S FORIEGN LIBRARY—No. I.
            
         </p>
         <p> The Auto-Biography of Benvenuuto Cellini—The complete
            and annotated edition of Roscoe, [in two parts.] 50 cents. In
            English cloth, by Bradley, 75 cents.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Cellini was one of the most extraordinary men in an extraordinary age; his life, written by himself, is more amusing than any
            novel I know.”—Horace Walpole.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The distinguished eminence of this artist, in the times of the
            “old masters”—the intimacy of Cellini with Michael Angelo, Titian, and all the great Italian sculptors and painters of the age;
            his connections with Francis I. of France, Emperor Charles V .,
            Popes Clement VII and Paul III, the Dukes Alessandro and Cosino of Florence, and with many of the princes, statesmen, commanders and dignified ecclesiastics of that turbulent age, which
            called forth all the energies of Europe, and compelled our author
            more than once to exchange the chisel lor the sword—these circumstances afforded him opportunities of making the most interesting observations, and perhaps no man was ever more capable
            of availing himself of such advantages.—Roscoe’s Preface.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“This is, perhaps, the most perfect piece of autoo-biography that
            ever was written, whether considered with reference to the candor
            and veracity of the author, the spirit of the incidents, or the creating vitality of the narrative. •	• We never, in the whole
         </p>
         <p>course of our life, read a book of a more engaging description.—
            Retrospective Review.
            
         </p>
         <p>Part II —Completing the work, will be ready in a few days —
            WILEY&amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway, New-York; and all the
            booksellers throughout the country.
         </p>
         <p>JOHN N. GENIN,
            fashionable hat and cap establishment,
            214 Broadway.
            
            CATALOGUE OF TEAS,
            ON, SALE AT THE TEA WAREHOUSE OF THE
            PEKIN TEA COMPANY,
            Importers of fine Green and Black Teas, No.15 Fulton-st.
            New York.
            
         </p>
         <p>[The Teas mentioned in this Catalogue are done up in quarter,
            half pound, and pound packages—the first, or inside wrapperis lead,
            the second wrapper is water proof paper, and the third or outside
            wrapper is of Chinese Rice paper. The Company sell none but
            good Teas, done up in this superior manner, all of them grown in
            the most luxurious districts in China. Country dealers can select
            as small a quantity of each kind as they like and have them packed
            in one chest. These Teas also come in five pound Chinese packages, called quattoons, a very convenient, fanciful and portable
            shape.]
         </p>
         <p>Green Teas:
            Young Hyson, sweet cargo,	50
            do.	do. do. do.	finer	62A
            do.	do.	finer cargo,	75
            do.	do.	extra fine,	87 1/2
            do. do. Silver Leaf,	1 00
            
         </p>
         <p>Silver Leaf—Seldom sold, even
            by large dealers, because of the
            very small profits made on its
            sale. This is a very superior
            tea.
         </p>
         <p>do.	do.	Golden Chop, Plantation
            
         </p>
         <p>or Garden growth, 1 50
            Golden Chop—This is the finest
            Green Tea cultivated in China.
            It is of the first pickings, and ex
            cels all other Green Teas for its
            delicacy of flavor, strength and
            aroma. Heretofore this tea has
            never reached this country, except in small lots, as presents to
            importers.
         </p>
         <p>Hyson,* very fine,	75
            do. Plantation growth,	1	00
            Gunpowder, good,	—
            do.	superior, (Rend “mon-
            strous fraud” below.) 1 00
            do.	small leaf, plantation
            growth,	1	25
            Imperial, good,	—
            do. brisk and fragrant,[read
            “ mnstrous	fraud”	be-
            low,]	1 	00
            do. curious leaf, very supe-
            rior,	1 	25
            Hyson Skin, good, fine flavor,	38
            do. do. extra fine,	62
            Black Teas.
            ouchong, good, full flavor,	38
            do. fine,	50
            do. very superior,	75
            Souchong, good,	38
            do. extra fine,	50
            Oolong, strong, flavor fine,	50
            
         </p>
         <p>Oolong—This tea is a great favorite, and gives universal satisfac
            tion.
         </p>
         <p>do. very fine,	62$
            do. in one pound and half
            pound cattys, extra fine, 75
            Ne Plus Ultra,	150
            
         </p>
         <p>NE Plus Ultra—This tea is as
            fragrant and sweet as a nosegay.
            It yields a perfume that is truly
            delightful. It is of garden growth,
            and superior to any thing of the
            kind ever sold in this country.
         </p>
         <p>English Breakfast Tea, very
            fine,	50
            
         </p>
         <p>do. do. do. in one
            pound and half pound cattys,	62 1/2
         </p>
         <p>Howqua’s Mixture, a strong and
            rich black tea, Pekoe flavor, 75
            Congo, good,	37 1/2
            do. very fine,	50
            Pekkoe Flowers, good,	87 1/2
            do. do. garden growth, 1 50
            
         </p>
         <p>*Caution. —Large quantities of Hyson Skin are retailed in
            this market as being a Hyson Tea. It is well worth while to compare the Hyson tea usually sold at 75 cents with the genuine article that the Company offer at the same price. The difference is so 
            perceptible on trial as to render any further comment unnecessary. 
            Monstrous Fraud.—Gunpowder and Imperial Teas cannot be
            retailed by small dealers, in this country, at 75 cents per pound,
            because they frequently cost that money in China, and no Importer
            in this city can sell good Gunpowder or Imperial Tea at a less
            price than 75 cents per pound by the hundred packages. T. F.
            Davies, Esq., in his interesting work on China, details the manner
            in which he saw the lowest grades of Black Teas manufactured
            and colored with Prussian Blue, so as to closely imitate Gunpowder and Imperial Teas, and adds, the Prussian Blue being a combination of Prussic Acid with Iron, is of course a dangerous poison. Let purchasers therefore beware of adulterated teas, and
            deal with those venders whose characters and resources raise them
         </p>
         <p>above suspicion. Beware of the Gunpowder and Imperial Teas
            retailed at 75 cents per pound, and compare them with the genuine
            article sold by the Pekin Tea Company. No one, it is presumed,
            wishes to drink poison. The Company have published a book,
            giving full details on this subject, which may be had at their 
            Warehouse, 75 Fulton street, free of charge.
            RECOMMENDATIONS.
            
         </p>
         <p>We drink Green Tea, and for many years have been paying one dollar per
            pound for it. But thanks to the Pekin Tea Company, we now get a better tea
            from them at 75 rents per pound. We drink one pound peer week, by which
            we are now saving thirteen dollars per year, and enjoying better tea in the
            bargain. Commend us to the Pekin Tea Company, say we.—Mirror.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Pekin Tea Company, 73 Fulton street, are performing a great and good
            work, and will, in a few years, beyond all doubt, drive all the poor teas which
            have deluged this country, and defrauded consumers of the article, out of the
            market. They import none but pure and fragrant teas, and retail them by the
            single pound at wholesale prices. Families are always sure of obtaining good
            teas at this great tea warehouse, in quantities to suit their convenience, and at
            the same price that the merchant pays who buys to sell again.—Daily True
            Sun. 
         </p>
         <p>You may be sure of obtaining at all limes, pure and highly flavored tens, by
            the single pound, at wholesale prices, of the Pekin Tea Company, 79 Fulton
            street.—They have probably the largest stock, and greatest variety of fine
            green and black teas, of any one establishment in the United States. They 
            are doing a large business, and a great benefit to consumers of tea. —Atlas.
            Heretofore it has been very difficult, indeed impossible, to always obtain
            green and black teas. But now you only have to visit the warerooms of 
            the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street, to obtain as delicious and fragrant
            teas as you could wish for.—Daily Sun.
            If any of our readers desire to have good tea, they can obtain it of the Pekin
            Tea Company, 75 Fulton street.—Mercury.
            A Word to Tea Drinkers.—The Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street.
            
            
         </p>
         <p>have imported into this market some five hundred thousand dollars worth of
            the finest grades of Green and Black Teas grown in the Celestial Empire, don
            up in all the various fancy packages that Chinese ingenuity can invent. It is
            a privilege to buy teas at this great establishment, and a luxury and comfort
            to drink them They sell good teas only, and retail them at wholesale prices .
            Country merchants who wish to always sell good teas can always obtain them
            at this place, on reasonable terms.—Emporium.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Tiie Pekin Tea Company—We very cheerfully call the attention of all
            lovers of pure and fragrant Teas, both in town and country, to the great Tea
            warehouse of this Company. Our long acquaintance with the proprietors enables us to bespeak for them the entire confidence of the public. We know
            that their Teas, both in quality and price, are all that is stated of them. Many
            a lover of the fragrant herb has been compelled to eschew the drinking of Tea
            in consequence of its injurious effects, until at length he has become hopeless
            of finding, among any of the imported varieties of Tea in our market a kind
            which had not such an effect. In this, however, such persons will be agreeably disappointed. The Pekin Tea Company have commenced the importation
            of choice varieties of Garden Teas, of most delicious flavor-cultivated and
            packed with great care, which have heretofore never been introduced into this
            country, except as presents to importers. Among these they have an Oolong,
            mild as zephyr, and fragrant as a rose, which we especially recommend to all
            nervous persons, its effect upon many of those who have tried it, has been
            to make them confirmed tea-drinkers. Ladies who have used it, say they
            never before drank such tea. But all tastes can here be suited, with the great
            advantage over other stores of getting a pure article at wholesale price, however small the quantity. The Company's Warehouse is at 75 Fulton street.—
            New World.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Tea.—The Pekin Tea Company, No. 75 Fulton street, unquestionably sell
            the best teas imported into this market. That they sell them cheaper than any
            other establishment, is a fact proven in a thousand instances since they have
            opened their store.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We would advise our friends to call at this place, and if they don’t wish to
            buy. at least to obtain a little pamphlet, kept on their counter, entitled “ Hints
            to Tea-Drinkers,” and therefrom learn a little useful information on the subject.
         </p>
         <p>The pamphlet is given gratis.—Anglo American.
            
         </p>
         <p>The finest specimens of green and black teas ever sold in this country, are
            imported by the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street. Those who want good
            teas at reasonable prices, can always get them there.—Tribune.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have tried the teas imported by the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street,
            and if we live will try them often. They are selling the most delicious teas
            we ever drank, and ret it them at wholesale prices.—Evening Post. oct8
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
            
         </p>
         <p>V. F. HARRISON, 23 CANAL STREET, N. Y.—In struments made with the most recent improvement, such as
            Iron Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are
            made from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most
            faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the business.
         </p>
         <p>N. B.—Wanted a second hand Parlor Organ.
            Piano Fortes hired by the month.
            ӔOLIAN ATTACHMENT.
            Hermann s. saroni, professor of music,
            116 Leonard street, New-York, teaches the Piano-Forte, with
            or without Coleman’s celebrated Attachment.
            PIANO FORTES.
            
         </p>
         <p>H. WORCESTER, No. 139 THIRD AVENUE, CORner of 14th Street, respectfully informs his friends and the
            public, that he has a good assortment of Piano-Fortes, in Rosewood and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons wishing
            to purchase will find it to their advantage to call and examine before purchasing elsewhere.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>To the Public.—Edgar A. Poe, Esq. having purchased my interest in “The Broadway Journal,” is now sole
            proprietor of the same. All persons indebted to the paper will please make settlement with him.
         </p>
         <p>John Bisco.
            New-York, Oct. 24, 1845.
            TIIE BROADWAY JOURNAL:
            Edgar A. Poe,	Editor and Proprietor.
            IS PUBLISHED EVERY SATURDAY.—OFFICE 135 NASSAU ST.
            TERMS THREE DOLLARS PER ANNUM—SINGLE NUMBERS SIX AND A QUARTER CTS.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal is, in its general character, a literary paper: occupying itself with original, and more especially with critical
            articles, in every department of Literature, properly so called—with
            a preference, nevertheless, for the Belles L ettres and the
            Fine Arts. There is no better medium in the country lor
            literary or artistical advertisements.
         </p>
         <p>AGENTS.
            Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass.
            
         </p>
         <p>R. G. H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct.
            M. Baullemet, Mobile, Ala.
            Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O.
         </p>
         <p>D. M. Dewey,Rochester, N. Y.
            J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.
            W. E. Russ II, Chenectady, N. Y.
            Levi Willard, Troy. N Y.
            G. Jones, Albany. N. Y.
            
         </p>
         <p>S. F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y.
            Shurtz &amp; Wide, Baltimore. Md
            Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.
         </p>
         <p>Thos. H. Pease, New-Haven, Ct.
            J. C. Morgan, New Orleans
            W. W. Kingsley, New-London, CT.
            G. N. Beesley, Utica, N. Y.
            H. B. Strang, Peekekill, N. Y..
            
         </p>
         <p>Halburton &amp; Dudley, Boston, Mass.
            S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass.
            Peter Cooke, Hartford, Ct.
         </p>
         <p>H. Esten, Providence, R.I.
            Safford &amp; Park, Norwich, Ct.
            John Tomlin, P. M. Jackson, Tenn.
            S. Hart, Sen , Charleston, S.C.
            Printed at the Office of the Farmer And Mechants.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      
   </div>
</div>