<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450524</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1.     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, MAY 24, 1845.	    NO. 2l.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.	
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau St. 
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Spending Money on Worthless Objects</div>
         <div class="biblPage">321</div>          
         
         <div class="head">SPENDING MONEY FOR WORTHLESS OBJECTS.</div>
         
         <p>If men would always insist on having the worth of their
            money, according to their own standard of value, there would
            no longer be such a word as poverty in common use. Paying
            more for a thing than it is worth is as injurious to the seller
            as to the buyer, for it stimulates unprofitable industry, and
            leads to the production of articles which develope neither
            our mental nor physical resources. Perhaps there is no
            stronger, or more indisputable evidence of this truth, than
            that afforded by the picture dealing of Italy. By some
            strange freak of the mind of cultivated Europe, which it is
            difficult to trace to its origin, a monstrously fictitious value
            has been, for the last hundred years, attached to old paintings, and above all others to old Italian paintings. Italy,
            which was once the exclusive home of art, has become, under the effects of this false taste, the most degraded of all
            the schools of art in the world; all her intellect and industry have been wasted upon the production of works to gratify
            the morbid tastes of picture fanciers, until she has long since
            abandoned all attempts at improvement and rests satisfied
            with furbishing up and imitating the productions of her infancy. Under a delusion like this everything like truth and
            honesty must of course be smothered, and in their place chicanery, deception, and lying flourish. A mind bent upon deception cannot give birth to anything like greatness in art,
            and it is by no means difficult to understand why the Italians, who once produced the most glorious examples in art,
            should now be fallen beneath every other nation in the world
            in their artistic efforts.
         </p>
         
         <p>The last number of the Foreign Quarterly Review contains a very learned and pleasant article on Pictures and Picture dealing, being a review of the Catalogue of the gallery
            of Cardinal Fesch, who appears to have been one of the most
            extensive picture buyers of his own or any other age.
         </p>
         
         <p>He began to form his museum in France, when the property cast
            loose by the Revolution, and the spoils of half Europe, were to be
            gathered with little trouble, and at moderate cost. Having afterwards, in common with the rest of his family, found that country no
            longer a licensed residence, ho naturally sought a home in the metropolis of his church, and on transporting his pictures to Rome, he
            stipulated for their removal, at pleasure, from the papal states, exempt from the usual restrictions or export duties. To the choice
            productions of the ultra-montane schools which the collection already
            possessed, the constant augmentations which it subsequently received added but few gems. And these from Italian pencils. The 
            cardinal had little more to wish for, eminent rank and ample wealth
            were his, and the picture-gallery he was intent on forming had attained a European reputation. But the desire of acquisition had
            become a chronic disease, ever gaining force in its inroads upon his
            means. Not long before he died he negotiated with one Roman
            picture-dealer to pay for some indifferent picture with his service of
            Sevres china, representing the battles of Napoleon, sets of which
            were made only for the emperor’s nearest relations. To another
            he gave a set of silver plate by a similar transaction, and at length
            death itself snatched away the octogenarian from some uncompleted
            bargains. But his craving for canvass was not to be satiated even
            by wholesale dealings, which at once added hundreds to his pictorial investments. There was an understanding in his household,
            that for every picture offered at his palace, however execrable in
            merit or condition, four pauls (about twenty-one pence) were to be
            at once given. To clean and patch up these, he gave permanent
            
            employment to several young restorers, and many were the guesses
            as to what became of the bargains, after emerging from their hands.
            During the residence of his nephew, Joseph Bonaparte, in America,
            it was a common belief that they were shipped to the new world,
            and there converted into cash. When, on the cardinal’s death,
            the mystery was revealed, endless repositories of pictures were discovered, the exact number of which has not been, and perhaps
            could not be, ascertained, but it is estimated at 16,000 or 18,000.
         </p>
         
         <p>We imagine that shipments of old paintings to this country rarely pay the cost of transportation and the charges of
            sale. It is by no means uncommon to see warranted Guidos
            and Corregios sell at less than a dollar, and pictures by the
            old Dutch masters hardly ever reach higher than half a dollar.
            So that a profitable speculation might have been made in this
            country in the life time of the Cardinal by purchasing a lot of
            undoubted originals and sending them to Rome, where they
            were sure of commanding four pauls, at least, a price that
            connot be safely reckoned on in our auction rooms.
         </p>
         
         <p>Italy since the revival of art, has been the great cradle or school of
            painters for Europe, and a vast proportion of the pictures required
            for religions or ornamental decoration, has emanated from her studios, galleries, or churches. From thence came the gems which
            Charles I. contrived to accumulate, notwithstanding the difficulties
            of an empty treasury, and a troubled reign. There did the stately
            Arundel, the earliest English virtuoso, resort. France and Spain,
            for three hundred years; England, Germany, and South America,
            during the last century, have been working the same mine. After
            the disastrous occupation of Italy by the French, in 1798, and the
            subsequent convulsions of that ill-fated land, the sword of France
            and the gold of England combined to cull from her temples and
            palaces all that was most choice in this branch of art. Since the
            peace the drain has been continued, and though fewer pieces are
            now sent out for devotional uses, a new demand of amateurship has
            arisen from Russia and the United States, nations till then unknown
            in the market, while England is annually glutted by traffickers in
            old canvass and cracked panels. Yet the competition of these rival
            purchasers may, with a little dexterity, be accommodated, as their
            principles of choice do not by any means clash. The Russian taste
            in pictures, as in equipages and jewellery, is regulated rather by a
            semibarbarous magnificence, than by refinement, and their expenditure is in proportion to their colossal fortunes. Provided a picture have the name of a great master, and a corresponding price,
            the wily Italian owner may almost calculate upon transferring it in
            the course of the season to some Russian prince, although the subject be forbidding, the treatment mean, the restorations ill-disguised,
            or even the authenticity questionable.
         </p>
         
         <p>We think that the reviewer underrates the taste of United
            States’ Amateurs by classing them with the Russians. It is
            true that some of our travellers bring home from Rome some
            of the poorest trash in Italy, for which they probably pay sufficiently high, but generally their prices do not reach much
            above the minimum of Cardinal Fesch. We saw in the
            warehouse of a French importer, a short time since, a lot of
            original paintings, landscapes and devotional pieces, in handsome gilt frames, which were offered at twenty dollars the
            pair at wholesale. This will not be considered surpri ingly
            cheap for a pair of undoubted originals by the old masters, if
            the following statement in the Review be correct, as it doubtless is, for the writer appears perfectly familiar with his subject.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of the class of pictures now largely exported to the United States,
            it may be sufficient to mention, that a commercial traveller in that
            line, who came to Rome in 1837, had a commission to buy up any
            painting of whatever subject, or whatever substance, and in what
            ever state, not exceeding the price of sixteen pence! Akin to this
            is a variety of British Colonial emigration, which may be new to
            our readers. Chancing to visit lately at the close of the season, the
            warerooms of an obscure London picture-dealer, we found them
            encumbered with the refuse of various auction rooms, which had
            evidently been bought up on this Yankee principle. Whilst gazing
            in astonishment at the rare conglomerate, we were informed that 
            they were a speculation for Botany Bay!
         </p>
         
         <p>There is abundant food for thought to our political economists in the following extract; but we differ altogether with
            the writer as respects the advantage which Italy has derived
            from the sale of pictures. The incalculable national wealth,
            should read incalculable national degradation and poverty.
            It is not that there is anything hurtful to the health, or morals, in painting pictures: the harm all arises from making
            pictures to be passed off for what they are not. The Algerines certainly added vast sums of money to their national
            coffers by their piracies, but it cannot be said that they enriched themselves by such gains.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is a consideration suggested by the incredible number of
            paintings produced in Italy during the last five centuries, which
            ought not to he lost upon our money-getting generation. The sums
            which during that long period have been and still are sent there, in
            payment of exported pictures, have afforded incalculable national
            wealth. Let not this be forgotten by penny-wise Legislatures, who
            would measure the beautiful by the scale of utility, and estimate 
            genius and its highest productions by the returns of the outlay on 
            their raw material. Let them remember that trifling sums now
            doled out for the improvement of public taste, and the encouragement of art, are surely and profitably invested; and that nothing but
            the inadequacy of their amount, can prevent them rapidly yielding
            an almost usurious interest.—Could our own school of painting be
            raised to the perfection attained by those of Italy in the sixteenth,
            and Flanders in the seventeenth centuries, what need were there to
            send abroad our annual thousands for the purchase of their works! 
            Or, were our designs as tasteful as the French, why should our
            neighbours export their fashions and fancy goods, to eclipse ours
            wherever civilisation has penetrated? These matters are now beginning to be understood among us; much still remains to be
            known, and far more to be done: but it is well to have at length
            entered upon the right path:—sero let it be serio.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is not easy to understand why a gentleman should wish
            to possess objects of high cost that can give him no pleasure;
            and yet we see that purchasers of paintings will pay enormous prices for works which they have no capacity to enjoy;
            an instance of this kind is related by the reviewer which
            shows a most remarkable combination of simplicity and ambition on the part of the purchaser, and of a brilliant imagination and utter want of honesty on the part of the seller.
         </p>
         
         <p>Among the cleverest of the Roman picture-dealers in Signor A., a
            most fair-spoken fellow and facetious withal, who, conscious of his
            own talent, is ever ready to adduce some instance of its happy exercise. ’Tis but a year or two since he made a wholesale transaction, which, in a short half-hour, transferred to a young Irish peer the
            accumulated rubbish of his magazine. At the lucky moment of the
            sailor’s visit, there arrived a liveried servant with an official looking
            missive, which A. apologised for opening, and after glancing at it,
            said, ‘ Very good, but I have no time now to look at your pictures;
            come again.’ The servant hesitated, and to the inquiries of the
            stranger, A. said it was only the particulars of a lot of pictures
            which had been sent to him for sale, the heritage of an old Bolognese family, but that he had never had leisure to open the boxes,
            which must stand over till he could attend to the matter. On his
            lordship pressing to have a sight of them, A. reluctantly opened the
            cases, protesting that it was of no use, as it would take much time
            to clean and arrange and value this collection, before which, of
            course, the pictures were not for sale. The list exhibited Guidos,
            Domenichinos, Caraccis, Carlo Dolces,—in short, just that class of
            names which impose upon an Anglican amateur,—and the dingy
            canvasses were freely acknowledged to be so completely obscured
            by dirt and old varnish that their merits were undistinguishable.
            The more the dealer seemed anxious to divert his customer to the
            brightly varnished ornaments of his own walls, the less willing was
            he to lose sight of this singular chance of procuring ‘ a genuine gallery ready made,’ and ere the parties separated, a transfer was made
            to the peer of a mass of trash which scarcely merited the outlay of
            cleaning, in exchange for a thousand louis-d’or.
         </p>
         
         <p>Another story is told which displays a much higher reach
            of imaginative power, and shows a degree of dramatic skill
            which ought to be turned to a more profitable account than
            playing tricks upon ignorant travellers.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>M. Kerschoff, a Russian amateur, was invited to accompany some
            Florentine gentlemen on a shooting party into the Maremme.
            Whilst they pursued their sport, he, disgusted by ill-success, returned to wait for them at a cottage where their horses were put
            up. Having got into conversation with its occupant, the latter inquired if his guest was fond of pictures, as he had something curious
            that might interest him. After a long story how his father had, on
            his death-bed, confided to him the secret, that a picture concealed
            in the house was of value sufficient to make the fortune of all his
            family, but that having been feloniously obtained, it would, if ever
            shown or sold in that neighbourhood, certainly bring him into
            trouble—the rustic produced a very pleasing Madonna and Child, in
            a very antique carved frame, which the Russian cordially admired,
            and being asked to guess the artist, named Raffaelle. ‘ That,’ said
            the peasant, ‘was, I do believe, the very one my father mentioned,
            but you can see if it was so, as he gave me this bit of paper, with
            the name written in it.’ On the dirty shred there was in fact
            scrawled ‘ Raffaelle Sanzi;' and its possessor went on to hint that,
            being anxious to realize what he knew to be most valuable property,
            and seeing no great chance of then disposing of it safely, he would
            accept from him, as a foreigner, a price far below its value. The
            negotiation thus opened, ended in the Russian offering 35,000 francs,
            or 1,400l., which after due hesitation was accepted. The prize
            was huddled into a clothes-bag, and its new master, without waiting to take leave of his friends, started for Florence, and thence
            hurried on to Rome, lest it should be stopped by the Tuscan government. There he boasted of his acquisition, and showed it to
            several connoisseurs, who sang its praises, until Signor Vallati, a
            skilful dealer, whose name will be presently again mentioned,
            quickly recognized the real artist. It was in fact a beautiful repetition, with slight variations, of Raffaelle’s famous ‘ Madonna del
            Gran-duca:’ it was painted by Micheli, who avows that he sold it
            for 150 crowns; and the shooting-party was a conspiracy by several
            well-born swindlers to take in their Russian friend! The latter returned to Florence to seek redress by a prosecution, which was
            compromised by their returning most of the price. Being curious
            to see or obtain the subject of so strange a tale, we subsequently
            inquired for the picture, but were told it might probably bo met
            with as an original, in some great German collection, having been
            there resold by the Russian, at a price almost equal to what he had
            himself originally paid!
         </p>
         
         <p>We have no room for further extracts from this interesting
            article, but enough has been quoted to show the purchasers
            of old pictures the risk which they run in buying a work by
            the old masters. It is next to an impossibility for an American to become possessed of a genuine fine picture by one of
            the old painters; and it will be better therefore for all those
            who are ambitious of decorating their houses with good
            works of art to give orders to our own artists, who can, in
            nine cases out of ten, produce better pictures at less prices
            than those which are now ostentatiously hung up in the parlors of many of our wealthy citizens as the works of the “old
            masters.” Many of the houses of our rich merchants are disfigured by the worst daubs that ever came from Italy or Belgium, while their upholstery and carpets are of the most delicate and beautiful workmanship. We are by no means disposed to dampen the ardor of any lover of art; but we have
            no doubt that an improper outlay of money for unworthy objects has a greater tendency to depress the interests of true art,
            than the most stringent parsimony can have. A Wall Street
            Broker who has recently become rich and liberal, last year
            purchased a landscape from one of our artists at a generous
            price, because he liked it. He confessed he was utterly ignorant of the technical merits of a picture, but he knew when
            he was pleased and he was willing to pay for the pleasure.
            If all purchasers of works of virtu, would be guided by the
            same principle in their selections, they would be always sure
            of getting the worth of their money, and merit would generally receive its reward.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Eleonora</div>
         <div class="biblPage">322</div>
         <div class="head">ELEONORA.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Sub conservatione formae specificae salva anims.
            
            <br></br>Raymond Lully.
         </div>
         
         <p>I am come of a race noted for vigor of fancy and ardor of
            passion. Men have called me mad; but the question is not
            yet settled, whether madness is or is not the loftiest intelligence—whether much that is glorious—whether all that is
            profound—does not spring from disease of thought—from
            
            moods of mind exalted at the expense of the general intellect.
            They who dream by day are cognizant of many things which
            escape those who dream only by night. In their grey visions
            they obtain glimpses of eternity, and thrill, in awaking, to
            find that they have been upon the verge of the great secret.
            In snatches, they learn something of the wisdom which is 
            of good, and more of the mere knowledge which is of evil.
            They penetrate, however rudderless or compassless, into the
            vast ocean of the “light ineffable” and again, like the adventurers of the Nubian geographer, “agressi sunt mare
            tenebrarum, quid in eo esset exploraturi.”
         </p>
         
         <p>We will say, then, that I am mad. I grant, at least, that
            there are two distinct conditions of my mental existence—
            the condition of a lucid reason, not to be disputed, and belonging to the memory of events forming the first epoch of
            my life—and a condition of shadow and doubt, appertaining 
            to the present, and to the recollection of what constitutes the 
            second great era of my being. Therefore, what I shall tell 
            of the earlier period, believe; and to what I may relate of
            the later time, give only such credit as may seem due; or
            doubt it altogether; or, if doubt it ye cannot, then play unto
            its riddle the Oedipus.
         </p>
         
         <p>She whom I loved in youth, and of whom I now pen
            calmly and distinctly these remembrances, was the sole
            daughter of the only sister of my mother long departed.
            Eleonora was the name of my cousin. We had always
            dwelled together, beneath a tropical sun, in the Valley of
            he Many-Colored Grass. No unguided footstep ever came 
            upon that vale; for it lay far away up among a range
            of giant hills that hung beetling around about it, shutting 
            out the sunlight from its sweetest recesses. No path was
            trodden in its vicinity; and, to reach our happy home, there
            was need of putting back, with force, the foliage of many 
            thousands of forest trees, and of crushing to death the glories 
            of many millions of fragrant flowers. Thus it was that we 
            lived all alone, knowing nothing of the world without the
            valley,—I, and my cousin, and her mother.
         </p>
         
         <p>From the dim regions beyond the mountains at the upper
            end of our encircled domain, there crept out a narrow and
            deep river, brighter than all save the eyes of Eleonora; and, 
            winding stealthily about in mazy courses, it passed away, at
            length, through a shadowy gorge, among hills still dimmer
            than those whence it had issued. We called it the “River of
            Silence for there seemed to be a hushing influence in its
            flow. No murmur arose from its bed, and so gently it wan- 
            dered along, that the pearly pebbles upon which we loved to
            gaze, far down within its bosom, stirred not at all, but lay
            in a motionless content, each in its own old station, shining
            on gloriously forever.
         </p>
         
         <p>The margin of the river, and of the many dazzling rivulets
            that glided, through devious ways, into its channel, as well
            as the spaces that extended from the margins away down
            into the depths of the streams until they reached the bed of
            pebbles at the bottom,—these spots, not less than the whole 
            surface of the valley, from the river to the mountains that
            girdled it in, were carpeted all by a soft green grass, thick,
            short, perfectly even, and vanilla-perfumed, but so besprinkled throughout with the yellow buttercup, the white
            daisy, the purple violet, and the ruby-red asphodel, that its
            exceeding beauty spoke to our hearts, in loud tones, of the
            love and of the glory of God.
         </p>
         
         <p>And, here and there, in groves about this grass, like wildernesses of dreams, sprang up fantastic trees, whose tall
            slender stems stood not upright, but slanted gracefully towards the light that peered at noon-day into the centre of
            the valley. Their bark was speckled with the vivid alternate splendor of ebony and silver, and was smoother than
            all save the cheeks of Eleonora; so that but for the brilliant
            green of the huge leaves that spread from their summits in
            long tremulous lines, dallying with the Zephyrs, one might
            have fancied them giant serpents of Syria doing homage to
            their Sovereign the Sun.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hand in hand about this valley, for fifteen years, roamed
            I with Eleonora before Love entered within our hearts. It
            was one evening at the close of the third lustrum of her life,
            and of the fourth of my own, that we sat, locked in each
            other’s embrace, beneath the serpent-like trees, and looked
            down within the waters of the River of Silence at our images
            therein. We spoke no words during the rest of that sweet
            day; and our words even upon the morrow were tremulous
            and few. We had drawn the God Eros from that wave,
            and now we felt that he had enkindled within us the fiery
            
            souls of our forefathers. The passions which had for centuries distinguished our race, came thronging with the fancies
            for which they had been equally noted, and together breathed
            a delirious bliss over the Valley of the Many-Colored Grass.
            A change fell upon all things. Strange brilliant flowers,
            star-shaped, burst out upon the trees where no flowers had
            been known before. The tints of the green carpet deepened;
            and when, one by one, the white daisies shrank away, there
            sprang up, in place of them, ten by ten of the ruby-red asphodel. And life arose in our paths; for the tall flamingo,
            hitherto unseen, with all gay glowing birds, flaunted his
            scarlet plumage before us. The golden and silver fish
            haunted the river, out of the bosom of which issued, little
            by little, a murmur that swelled, at length, into a lulling
            melody more divine than that of the harp of AEolus—sweeter
            than all save the voice of Eleonora. And now, too, a voluminous cloud, which we had long watched in the regions of
            Hesper, floated out thence, all gorgeous in crimson and gold,
            and settling in peace above us, sank, day by day, lower and
            lower, until its edges rested upon the tops of the mountains,
            turning all their dimness into magnificence, and shutting us
            up, as if forever, within a magic prison-house of grandeur
            and of glory.
         </p>
         
         <p>The loveliness of Eleonora was that of the Seraphim; but
            she was a maiden artless and innocent as the brief life she
            had led among the flowers. No guile disguised the fervor
            of love which animated her heart, and she examined with
            me its inmost recesses as we walked together in the Valley
            of the Many-Colored Grass, and discoursed of the mighty
            changes which had lately taken place therein.
         </p>
         
         <p>At length, having spoken one day, in tears, of the last sad
            change which must befall Humanity, she thenceforward
            dwelt only upon this one sorrowful theme, interweaving it
            into all our converse, as, in the songs of the bard of Schiraz,
            the same images are found occurring, again and again, in
            every impressive variation of phrase.
         </p>
         
         <p>She had seen that the finger of Death was upon her bosom—that, like the ephemeron, she had been made perfect in
            loveliness only to die; but the terrors of the grave, to her,
            lay solely in a consideration which she revealed to me, one
            evening at twilight, by the banks of the River of Silence.
            She grieved to think that, having entombed her in the Valley of the Many-Colored Grass, I would quit forever its happy
            recesses, transferring the love which now was so passionately her own to some maiden of the outer and every-day
            world. And, then and there, I threw myself hurriedly at the
            feet of Eleonora, and offered up a vow, to herself and to
            Heaven, that I would never bind myself in marriage to any
            daughter of Earth—that I would in no manner prove recreant
            to her dear memory, or to the memory of the devout affection with which she had blessed me. And I called the
            Mighty Ruler of the Universe to witness the pious solemnity
            of my vow. And the curse which I invoked of Him and of
            her, a saint in Helusion, should I prove traitorous to that
            promise, involved a penalty the exceeding great horror of
            which will not permit me to make record of it here. And
            the bright eyes of Eleonora grew brighter at my words; and
            she sighed as if a deadly burthen had been taken from her
            breast; and she trembled and very bitterly wept; but she
            made acceptance of the vow, (for what was she but a child?)
            and it made easy to her the bed of her death. And she said
            to me, not many days afterwards, tranquilly dying, that, because of what I had done for the comfort of her spirit, she
            would watch over me in that spirit when departed, and, if
            so it were permitted her, return to me visibly in the watches
            of the night; but, if this thing were, indeed, beyond the
            power of the souls in Paradise, that she would, at least, give
            me frequent indications of her presence; sighing upon me
            in the evening winds, or filling the air which I breathed
            with perfume from the censers of the angels. And, with
            these words upon her lips, she yielded up her innocent life,
            putting an end to the first epoch of my own.
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus far I have faithfully said. But as I pass the barrier
            in Time’s path formed by the death of my beloved, and proceed with the second era of my existence, I feel that a
            shadow gathers over my brain, and I mistrust the perfect
            sanity of the record. But let me on.—Years dragged themselves along heavily, and still I dwelled within the Valley
            of the Many-Colored Grass;—but a second change had come
            upon all things. The star-shaped flowers shrank into the
            stems of the trees, and appeared no more. The tints of the
            green carpet faded; and, one by one, the ruby-red asphodels
            
            withered away; and there sprang up, in place of them, ten
            by ten, dark eye-like violets that writhed uneasily and were
            ever encumbered with dew. And Life departed from our
            paths; for the tall flamingo flaunted no longer his scarlet
            plumage before us, but flew sadly from the vale into the
            hills, with all the gay glowing birds that had arrived in his
            company. And the golden and silver fish swam down
            through the gorge at the lower end of our domain and bedecked the sweet river never again. And the lulling melody
            that had been softer than the wind-harp of AEolus and more
            divine than all save the voice of Eleonora, it died little by
            little away, in murmurs growing lower and lower, until the
            stream returned, at length, utterly, into the solemnity of its
            original silence. And then, lastly the voluminous cloud
            uprose, and, abandoning the tops of the mountains to the
            dimness of old, fell back into the regions of Hesper, and took
            away all its manifold golden and gorgeous glories from the
            Valley of the Many-Colored Grass.
         </p>
         
         <p>Yet the promises of Eleonora were not forgotten; for I
            heard the sounds of the swinging of the censers of the angels; and streams of a holy perfume floated ever and ever
            about the valley; and at lone hours, when my heart beat
            heavily, the winds that bathed my brow came unto me laden
            with soft sighs; and indistinct murmurs filled often the night
            air; and once—oh, but once only! I was awakened from a
            slumber like the slumber of death by the pressing of spiritual
            lips upon my own.
         </p>
         
         <p>But the void within my heart refused, even thus, to be
            filled. I longed for the love which had before filled it to
            overflowing. At length the valley pained me through its
            memories of Eleonora, and I left it forever for the vanities
            and the turbulent triumphs of the world.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">*     *     *     *     *</div>
         
         <p>I found myself within a strange city, where all things
            might have served to blot from recollection the sweet dreams
            I had dreamed so long in the Valley of the Many-Colored
            Grass. The pomps and pageantries of a stately court, and
            the mad clangor of arms, and the radiant loveliness of woman, bewildered and intoxicated my brain. But as yet my
            soul had proved true to its vows, and the indications of the
            presence of Eleonora were still given me in the silent hours
            of the night. Suddenly, these manifestations they ceased;
            and the world grew dark before mine eyes; and I stood
            aghast at the burning thoughts which possessed—at the terrible temptations which beset me; for there came from some
            far, far distant and unknown land, into the gay court of the
            king I served, a maiden to whose beauty my whole recreant
            heart yielded at once—at whose footstool I bowed down without a struggle, in the most ardent, in the most abject worship of love. What indeed was my passion for the young
            girl of the valley in comparison with the fervor, and the delirium, and the spirit-lifting ecstasy of adoration with which
            I poured out my whole soul in tears at the feet of the ethereal Ermengarde?—Oh bright was the seraph Ermengarde!
            and in that knowledge I had room for none other.—Oh divine
            was the angel Ermengarde! and as I looked down into the
            depths of her memorial eyes I thought only of them—and of
            her.
         </p>
         
         <p>I wedded;—nor dreaded the curse I had invoked; and its
            bitterness was not visited upon me. And once—but once
            again in the silence of the night, there came through my
            lattice the soft sighs which had forsaken me; and they modelled themselves into familiar and sweet voice, saying:
         </p>
         
         <p>“Sleep in peace!—for the Spirit of Love reigneth and
            ruleth, and, in taking to thy passionate heart her who is
            Ermengarde, thou art absolved, for reasons which shall be
            made known to thee in Heaven, of thy vows unto Eleonora.”
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">A Peep Behind the Curtain</div>
         <div class="biblPage">324</div>
         <div class="head">A PEEP BEHIND THE CURTAIN.
            MAN IN LOVE.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">“There’s no killing like that which kills the heart.”</div>
         
         <p>The sad effect which disappointment in love has upon the
            female heart, has ever been a fruitful theme with the poet
            and novelist, but we are singularly in the dark as to the manner in which the lordly sex meet a similar calamity; and
            this is the more strange since there is not a man living over
            the age of twenty-five, who could not favor us with some
            choice revelations, if he only saw fit. The Sorrows of Werter have come down to us in all their naturalness and pathos, but German nature and human nature are two different
            things, and nobody at the present day thinks of opening his
            jugular vein for anything short of a pecuniary misfortune.
            How heros of romance and fancymen demean themselves
            under sorrows of the heart is nothing to the purpose; the
            question that concerns us is, how do veritable flesh and blood
            in the shape of lawyers, doctors, merchants, editors, feel,
            when, after making a solemn tender of their persons, they
            find they have their labor for their pains. Do they bless us
            or do they curse us? Do they seek relief in solitude or in
            smoking? The following letter will throw some light on
            the subject, and although its details seem almost too sacred
            for the public eye, yet as the parties have all passed off the
            stage, we can see no good reason for withholding it. It was
            found among the papers of a lady lately deceased, and makes
            no pretension to elegance of style, yet we envy not the feelings of that female who can peruse it without emotion, and
            who in view of the intense suffering the softer sex are capable of producing, is not fully convinced that it is a great charity to be a woman! Ineffably captivating and winning as we
            undoubtedly are, we should still remember that one loveliest
            attribute is mercy.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">______, May 10th, 1820.
            
            <br></br>My Dear Sister:
         </div>
         
         <p>A sad calamity has befallen our family. Our darling brother
            has been—refused. It took place this morning. We had long
            known that he was suffering from an attack of the tender passion,
            but in consequence of severe losses at play, and our father's obduracy, who refused to advance him a single stiver, it reached its crisis, before we were prepared for it. It was a hard thing for him,
            a man and a Howard, to acknowledge to another, and that other a
            woman, that he found himself insufficient for his own happiness:—
            but when he reflected that his ancestors had all done the same thing
            before him, and that it would not be considered as derogating from
            his dignity, he resolved to smother his pride and follow in their footsteps. His strongest feelings too were enlisted in the question, for
            he had ever present with him a gnawing sense of emptiness, so to
            speak, which extended to his pocket.
         </p>
         
         <p>The most tender affection had ever subsisted between us, and on
            this occasion he sought my confidence. Ho had composed his offer, and had again and again recited it to the comer cupboard, and
            affectionately kissed the key hole: but fearing when he should address it to a sentient being, he might lose his self-possession and
            break down in the middle, he asked of me the favor of rehearsal.
            You will blush for my weakness, but I acknowledge the bare tho't
            of such a scene completely unnerved me,—but when I reflected
            upon the state of his finances, and that success to him was as the
            very breath of his nostrils, I conquered my emotions, and acceded
            to his solicitations. Ah! my sister, what a sweetly interesting moment! and if my agitation was so great at this, how shall I ever endure the reality?
         </p>
         
         <p>I endeavored to enter into the spirit of the scene, and according
            to custom essayed some faint objections; but he obviated them in a
            moment, and indeed the effect was truly tremendous when he came
            down upon his knees and alluded to self-destruction.
         </p>
         
         <p>I pronounced it perfect, but still he was not satisfied. “There
            are other ways,” he said, that may be more effective, for “instance,
            I am more at home on horseback, and as I have it all cut and dried,
            and on the very tip of my tongue, perhaps it might get jerked off,
            as it were, without my knowing it.” But I had insuperable objections to this plan, for though I was aware that if refused, he
            might show his sense of injury by spurring on and leaving her, yet
            still there were advantages in being under cover not lightly to be
            relinquished. Had he been more conversant with our sex, he
            would have known there is no sight so moving to the female heart,
            as that of a real, live man prostrate before her. weeping, perspiring,
            and imploring! Yes, my sister, this is no fiction,—many a man surprised and overwhelmed by a refusal, has “bowed his pride” and
            cried all over his broadcloth. Forgive the inelegance of my expressions, but truth must not be sacrificed to euphony.
         </p>
         
         <p>“I will do so," be exclaimed with enthusiasm, “and will this
            moment seek her residence,” and it was a beautiful sight as he flung
            himself into the saddle, and riding rather with the steed than on
            him, rose and fell gently in his seat with the regularity and precision of the piston of a steam engine.
         </p>
         
         <p>Occupied with pleasing thoughts of the great beauty and wealth
            of our intended sister, I was unconscious of the lapse of time, till I
            was roused by the tramp of a flying steed. Can this be the look
            of successful love, thought I, as with convulsed brow and clenched
            fists he flung himself into the apartment? Oh! what a spectacle
            
            
            for a sister’s eye! He was red to the very roots of his hair, and
            language not the most courtly fell from his quivering lips. I approached him—I endeavored to throw myself into his arms. He
            repulsed me. He used opprobrious epithets. “All alike, all
            alike,” said he. I felt the cutting injustice of the expression, for
            never could I answer to my conscience to bo guilty of such cruelty.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our mother, ah! what a tie that is, sought her son. She hung
            over him and pressed into his hand a “trifle” which she had privately subtracted from our father’s vestments. Heaven grant he may
            not miss it. The sight of his mother’s tears and the unexpected
            “tin” completely unmanned him, and the crystal sluices gave
            way.
         </p>
         
         <p>Nor did she forget his mortal nature—a potent cordial soothed
            his exasperated feelings and he sunk into a powerful slumber. I
            have just left him: a continuous hum sounds from his chamber. It
            has been a day of intense excitement to us all, for we feared at one
            moment it would strike to his vitals. To me it seemed that he was
            severely handled, but our dear mother, who has an uncommon acquaintance with men and things, remarked that he was not more so
            than is usual with men of sensibility and true feeling, and particularly
            where the charms of the beloved one are not entirely of a personal
            nature—that their exercises are frequently of an extraordinary character—that love is the strongest feeling in the manly heart except
            the passion for tobacco. Oh! what a responsibility is ours!
            When we consider that a proposal of marriage involves, not merely
            the bestowal of a name or of an immense fist, but the expenditure
            of money, absolute money; it seems to me, that nothing but a previous engagement can justify a refusal.
         </p>
         
         <p>But to our brother. No other connexion promised equal advantages. Old Van Bokkelen’s estate is dreadfully encumbered, and
            neighbor Vanduzzen has gone on foolishly adding to his family till
            his property is not worth dividing.
         </p>
         
         <p>3 o’clock. Our brother is awake but complains of an internal
            sense of goneness. I have witnessed mortal anguish in many shapes
            —I have seen the loss of teeth, eye teeth, I have witnessed fearful
            contusions, but never have I beheld aught that penetrated to the
            very depths of my soul like the wailings of a re-fused man!
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">« Oh Love! what is it in this world of ours,
            
            <br></br>That makes it fatal to be loved?”
            
            <br></br>Yours,	S****.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">To -----</div>
         <div class="biblPage">325</div>
         <div class="head">TO -----.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>I would not lord it o’er thy heart,
            
            <br></br>Alas! I cannot rule my own,
            
            <br></br>Nor would I rob one loyal thought,
            
            <br></br>From him who there should reign alone;
            
            <br></br>We both have found a life-long love
            
            <br></br>Wherein our weary souls may rest,
            
            <br></br>Yet may we not, my gentle friend
            
            <br></br>Be each to each the second best?
            
            <br></br>A love which shall be passion-free,
            
            <br></br>Fondness as pure as it is sweet,
            
            <br></br>A bond where all the dearest ties
            
            <br></br>Of brother, friend and cousin meet,—
            
            <br></br>Such is the union I would frame,
            
            <br></br>That thus wo might he doubly blest,
            
            <br></br>With Love to rule our hearts supreme
            
            <br></br>And Friendship to be second best.
         </div>     
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">M.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Duke of Wellington's Despatches</div>
         <div class="biblPage">325</div>
         <p>The Duke of Wellington’s Despatches.—The Albion
            is a greater admirer of “F. M. the Duke,” so much so as to
            treasure up every scrap that falls from F. M. the Duke’s pen.
            In copying into its columns the last letter of “F. M. the
            Duke,’’ &amp;c. to the editor of the Morning Post, the Albion
            says:
         </p>
         
         <p>Colonel Gurwood rendered a great service to the country and to
            military history, by collecting and compiling his Grace’s public Despatches; and any other person, or persons, would confer an equal
            favor on all lovers of brevity, anti-circumlocution and coming to the
            point, if he or they would collect and lay before an admiring world,
            all the noble Duke’s short notes, terse answers, and pithy replies to a
            parcel of people who are constantly bothering themselves about him.
            We could supply a number of choice little bits ourselves to any patriotic collector who may feel disposed to enter the field on this service.
            All remember the recent reply to the London reporter, who wrote to
            the Duke for permission to enter his residence, and report to the public the sayings and doings of the Queen and Prince Albert, who had
            gone to pay his Grace a private visit:
         </p>
         
         <p>" The Duke of Wellington presents his compliments to Mr.—,
            and does not see what Strathfieldsaye House has to do with the pub-
            lic.”
         </p>
         
         <p>On another occasion, a person addressed himself to the Duke, sending copies of several letters and papers, all of which were enclosed in
            a case of tin. The Duke acknowledged the receipt of them as follows:
            “The Duke of Wellington presents his compliments to Mr.—,
            has received his letters and the tin case.”
         </p>
         
         <p>These brief despatches of his Grace, are a proof of the
            good that may be done by a little wholesome criticism. There
            was a time when the letters of “F. M. the Duke” were not
            such perfect specimens of style, as the readers of Cobbett’s
            papers will remember. The following is one of the Duke’s
             despatches from Paris, with Cobbet’s admiring comments,
            which we fear have been omitted by Colonel Gurwood in his
            edition of the great captain’s works. It is a letter to Lord
            Castlereagh, concerning the stolen pictures in the Louvre.
         </p>
         
         <p>Having, as far as relates to the Museums, taken a sufficient view of
            the “greatest Statesman” of the age, I now come to that of “the
            greatest Captain.” The writing that I am now about to notice relates
            to the same subject. The Captain was one of the Commanders at
            Paris, at the time above spoken of; and it is in that capacity that he
            writes. But, we ought to observe here, that he is not only a great
            Captain, but a great Ambassador also; that he was Ambassador at
            the Congress of Vienna just before the time we are speaking of; and
            that he was formerly Secretary of State for Ireland.
         </p>
         
         <p>The paper, from which I am about to make a quotation, is a “dispatch” from the “greatest Captain” to Lord Castlereagh, dated at
            Paris, 23d September, 1815, soon after the Museums had been rifled.
         </p>
         
         <p>I shall not take up much of your time with the performance of this
            gentleman; a short specimen will suffice; and that shall consist of the
            three first paragraphs of his “dispatch.”
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">"My Dear Lord,</div>
         
         <p>” There has been a good deal of discussion here lately respecting the
            measures which I have been under the necessity of adopting, in order to get
            for the King of the Netherlands his pictures &amp;c. from the Museums; and lest
            these reports should reach the Prince Regent, I wish to trouble you, for his
            Royal Highness’s information, with the following statement of what has
            passed.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Shortly after the arrival of the Sovereigns at Paris, the Minister of
            the King ot the Netherlands claimed the Pictures, &amp;c. belonging to his Sovereign, equally with those of other pouers; and, as far as I could learn, never
            could get any satisfactory reply from the French Government. After several
            conversations with me, he addressed your Lordship an official Note, which
            was laid before the Ministers of the Allied Sovereigns, assembled in conference; and the subject was taken into consideration repeatedly, with a view
            to discover a mode of doing justice to the Claiments of the specimens of
            the arts in the Museums, without injuring the feelings of the King of France.
            In the mean time, the Prussians had obtained from His Majesty not only all
            the really Prussian Pictures, but these belonging to the Prussian territories
            on the left of the Rhine, and the Pictures, &amp;c., belonging to all the allies
            of His Prussian Majesty; and the subject pressed for an early decision; and
            your Lordship wrote your Note of the 11th inst. in which it was fully discussed.	
         </p>
         
         <p>“The Ministers of the King of the Netherlands, still having no satisfactory answer from the French Government, appealed to me as the General in Chief of the army of the King of the Netherlands, to know whether
            I had any objection to employ His Majesty’s Troops to obtain possession of
            what was his undoubted property. I referred this application again to the
            Ministers ot the Allied Courts, and no objection having been stated. I considered it my duty to take the necessary measures to obtain what was his right.”
         </p>
         
         <p>The great characteristic of this writing (if writing it ought to be
            called) is the thorough-paced vulgarity of it. There is a meanness of
            manner as well as of expression, and, indeed, a suitableness to the subject, much too natural, in all its appearances, to have been the effect
            of art.
         </p>
         
         <p>The writer, though addressing a minister of State, and writing matter to be laid before a Sovereign, begins exactly in the manner of a
            quidnunc talking to another that he has just met in the street. “There
            has been a good deal of “discussion” (that is to say, talk) here;"
            that is to say, at Paris, Castlereagh being, at that time, in London.
            The phrase "to get for” is so very dignified, that it could have come
            only from a great man, and could have been inspired by nothing short
            of the consciousness of being “the Ally of all the nations of Europe,”
            as the writer calls himself in another part of this famous “dispatch”
         </p>
         
         <p>But, what are “these reports," of which the great Captain speaks
            in the latter part of this paragraph? He had spoken of no reports before. He had mentioned “discussion,” and a “good deal” of it; but
            had said not a word about reports; and these reports pop out upon us
            like “these six men in buckram,” in Fulstaff’s narrative to the Prince.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Captain’s “wishing to trouble” Lord Castlereagh, “for the
            Regent's information," closes this paragraph in a very suitable manner, and prepares the mind for the next, where the Regent would find
            trouble enough, if he were compelled to find out the English of it.
            The Dutch Minister “claimed the Pictures belonging to his sovereign,
            equally with those of other powers." What! did this Dutchman claim
            the whole; those belonging to the Dutch sovereign and those belonging
            to all the other powers besides! This, to be sure, would have been in
            the true Dutch style: but, this could hardly be the fact. If it were,
            no wonder that the Duke had learned, that the Minister “never could
            get any satisfactory reply for, it must have been a deal indeed that
            would have satisfied him.
         </p>
         
         <p>The phrase, “he addressed your Lordship an official Note” is in the
            counting-house style; and then to say to Lord Castlereagh, “your
            Lordship wrote your Note of the 11th of September,” was necessary, lest the latter should imagine that somebody else had written the
            
            
            Note! Nor are the four ands in this paragraph to be overlooked; for
            never was this poor conjunction so worked before, except, perhaps,
            in some narrative of a little girl to her mother.
         </p>
         
         <p>The narrative is, in the last quoted paragraph, continued with unrelaxed spirit. The Dutch Minister can still obtain no satisfactory
            answer; he asks the Duke whether he have any objection to use force,
            and asserts, at the same time, that the goods in question are his master's “undoubted property.” Upon this the Duke applies to the other
            ministers, and "no objection having been stated,” he considers it his
            duty to obtain “what was his right;” that is to say, the Dutch king’s
            right.
         </p>
         
         <p>Never was there surely a parcel of words before put together by any
            body is so clumsy a manner. In a subsequent part of the “dispatch,"
            we have this: “I added, that I had no instructions regarding the
            Museum, nor no grounds on which to form a judgment.” In another
            place we have t! the King of the Netherland's Pictures.” In another
            place we have “that the property should be returned to their rightful
            owners.”
         </p>
         
         <p>But, to bestow criticism on such a shocking abuse of letters is to
            disgrace it; and nothing can apologize for what I have done, but the
            existence of a general knowledge of the fact, that the miserable stuff
            that I have quoted, and on which I have been remarking, proceeded
            from the pen of a man, who has, on many occasions, had some of the
            most important of the nation’s affairs committed to his management.
            There is in the nonsense of Castlereagh a frivolity and a toppery that
            give it a sort of liveliness, and that now-and-then elicit a smile: but,
            in the productions of his correspondent there is nothing to relieve; all
            is vulgar, all clumsy, all dull, all torpid inanity.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         <div class="biblTitle">Sonnet</div>
         <div class="biblPage">326</div>
         <div class="head">S O N N E T .</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Fair eyed Sincerity forbids me write
            
            <br></br>' Dear Love,’ but smiles assenting on ‘ Dear Friend;'
            
            <br></br>(Since time has swept my passion into night;)
            
            <br></br>Nor dare I with this pure emotion blend
            
            <br></br>Aught sensuous, or of ideal rapture born:
            
            <br></br>For now am I in love with Cheerfulness;
            
            <br></br>And almost have forgot that mood forlorn,
            
            <br></br>Which bids the poor soul hug her own distress.
            
            <br></br>Now, evening bells ring in my evening peace,
            
            <br></br>And tranquil morn salutes me for a friend:
            
            <br></br>My wane of passion is my mind’s increase,
            
            <br></br>And every hour I rather live than spend.
            
            <br></br>Then, if you mourn, morn not for me that live
            
            <br></br>So rich in pity I can spare to give.
         </div>	
         <div class="byline">HORUS.</div>
      </div> 
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">Life of Goderly William Von Leibnitz</div>
            <div class="biblPage">326</div>
            <p>Life of Goderly William Von Leibnitz.—On the basis of the
               German work of Dr. J. E. Guhrauer. By John M. Mackie. Boston:
               Gould, Kendall and Lincoln, 59 Washington street. 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>On the 21st of June (O. S,) 1646, Catharine, wife of Frederick Leibnitz, gave birth to a boy, who was soon to astonish
               not only his native city of Leipsic, but even the world. When
               being baptized on the third day of his existence Godfrey
               William (this was the name he received at the baptismal
               font) raised his head and opened his tiny eyes, and seemed
               consciously to receive the symbolic rite, as became a being
               who was to live always in the presence of his Maker. The
               delighted father, noting this event in his family journal, thus
               comments: “This is my desire; and so do I prophetically
               look upon this occurrence as a sign of faith, and a most sure
               token, that this my son will walk through life with eyes upturned to heaven, burning with love to God, and abounding
               in wonderful works to the honor of the Most High, the increase and purification of the Christian Church, and the salvation of both his and our souls.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The boy lived to accomplish the prophecy. Before he was
               twelve years old, he was so far advanced in his studies, that
               he could read the Latin language with ease, and had begun
               to stammer in Greek, and wrote verses with great readiness
               and felicity. This forwardness he owed entirely to innate
               genius, for his stupid teacher would have restrained his ardor, had it not been for the timely interference of a friend.
               In his Fragment of Personal Confessions, he holds the following language: “Two things were of special service to
               
               me, even from boyhood; first, that I was strictly a self-taught
               scholar; and secondly, that in the study of every science,
               even at the outset, and before I had made myself thoroughly
               acquainted with what was commonly known and received in
               it, I thought to make original discoveries. By this course,
               I secured the advantage of not encumbering my mind with
               things of no value, which depended on authority rather than
               intrinsic merit; aad also, that of never being satisfied until
               I had laid bare the roots and fibres of every science, and had
               discovered its fundamental principles, upon which all subordinate views and minor details naturally depend.” This is
               the road that all great minds must take and which can alone
               lead to great results; but this is precisely the one which is
               most commonly disapproved of by “dull respectabilities,”
               to whom the authority of age is a guaranty of accurate
               knowledge, and who like their ease too well to allow their
               equanimity to be be disturbed by those who would attempt
               to leach them something new.
            </p>
            
            <p>Before he had attained the age of twenty, Leibnitz published a treatise De Arte Comhinatorio, upon which he looked in his after years as a depository of the germs of his subsequent manifold philosophical views and discoveries. In
               his 21st year, this precocious youth received the degree of a
               Doctor at the University of Altdorf with great applause, after being refused the honor, through intrigues, in his native
               city. In conequencc of the brilliant display of his extraordinary abilities at the examination for the doctorate, he had
               a professorship offered to him, which he declined, as it would
               have interfered with his contemplated plan of reform in
               science.
            </p>
            
            <p>Stimulated by the desire of knowledge, on his taking up
               his residence at Nuremberg, Leibnitz wished to become initiated in the mysteries of the secret society of Rosicrucians,
               who believed themselves so well versed in chemistry, that
               they hoped the day was not far distant when their labors
               would be crowned by the discovery of the long-sought philosopher’s stone. His age and want of influential friends were
               in the way of his accomplishing this object; not disheartened, however, he fell upon a stratagem which succeeded beyond his expectations. He wrote a letter to one of the directors of the society, a reverend clergyman, full of the obscurest
               terms and phrases, which he gathered from various books on
               chemistry, respectfully suing for admission into the learned
               fraternity. The artifice succeeded; not only was the mysterious circle opened, but the situation of secretary with a
               small salary was offered to him, which he gladly accepted.
               In this singular office he remained only through the winter
               of 1666; long enough to learn the follies of the gold-seeking
               fraternity.
            </p>
            
            <p>The accidental acquaintance with the distinguished statesman John Christian Baron von Boineburg, which soon ripened into friendship, was a turning point in Leibnitz’s career;
               it gave him an opportunity to mingle with princes and distinguished literary men. His sphere of action was soon
               sufficiently enlarged to gratify his highest ambition; now
               we find him busy in politics, law or philosophy,—now in
               theology or scientific discovery; thus active, he rapidly
               earned an European reputation. In what esteem his sagacious friend the Baron held him, we learn from a letter introducing him to the acquaintance of the distinguished statesman Hermann Conring. “He is a young man from Leipsic,
               of four-and-twenty, doctor of laws, and learned beyond all
               credence. Being acquainted with the whole course of philosophy, he is a good mediator between the old and new
               systems; he is a mathematician, also understanding physics,
               medicine, and the whole range of mechanics; and is, withal,
               ardent and industrious. In religion he is an independent
               
               
               thinker; and for the rest, belongs to your (the Lutheran)
               church. The theory, and what is to be wondered at, the
               practice also, of law, is perfectly familiar to him. He is devoted to you with love and veneration.” The Baron’s generous and correct opinion of the young man, proved him to be
               an equally uncommon individual—“Genius too seldom has
               the privilege of being tried by its peers.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Leibnitz continued to deserve this high opinion by his untiring activity and brilliant discoveries. Some men arrive
               at the climax of their greatness long before the evening of
               their life sets in, and then only contemplate the trophies of
               their early days. But it was not so with Leibnitz; he may
               be said to have lived each day on new glories.
            </p>
            
            <p>We cannot think of the discovery of the differential calculus without regretting that it should have been the cause of
               so much bitter feeling between such illustrious rivals as
               Leibnitz and Newton, who, unknown to each other, about
               the same time wrought out of their meditations such a
               treasure for science; and we regret the more, for Sir Isaac
               showed the want of that ingenuousness which elevates his
               rival so much above him. Although the Royal Society in
               London decided upon the claims of priority in favor of their
               countryman, such competent judges as Euler, Lagrange,
               La Place, and Poisson have reversed the verdict, and at last
               justice has been done to the long neglected name of Leibnitz, whom national partiality would have deprived of his
               due meed of praise.
            </p>
            
            <p>To show how much philosophy is indebted to Leibnitz,
               we should have to give an account of its condition previous
               to his lime and since. Although his philosophy is scattered
               through different essays, prompted by variety of causes, and
               always bearing some relation to time and circumstances, it is
               sufficiently complete and original; and as his biographer attests, much of its wisdom passed into his living.
            </p>
            
            <p>That he brought a capacious mind and a right spirit to the
               investigation of truth, is evident from what he says in a letter to De Montserat—“I have found that the greater number
               of sects are right in much which they affirm, but not in
               what they deny. The Formalists, like the Platonists and the
               Aristotelians, are in the right when they recognise the fountain of things in the final and formal causes; but they are in
               the wrong, when they neglect the efficient and material
               causes, and, like Henry More in England, and certain Platonists, conclude that there are appearances which cannot be
               accounted for mechanically. On the other side, the materialists, or those who occupy themselves exclusively with mechanical philosophy, are in error in discarding metaphysics
               and attempting to explain everything directly or indirectly,
               through the imagination. I flatter myself that I have penetrated into the harmony of the different kingdoms; and have
               seen that both parties are right, if they only would not exclude each other.” 'Would that man should always bring
               such spirit to all investigation; our common stock of knowledge, besides being purified, would receive large additions.
               There would be then but little chance for sects or fanatics,
               either in science or philosophy. All error presupposes some
               truth, and its success is only proportionate to the truth it
               may involve; for pure falsehood can never exist.
            </p>
            
            <p>After repeated unsuccessful attempts at a reconciliation of
               the Romish church with the Protestant, Leibnitz abandoned
               his darling idea for a union of all the Protestant churches in
               Europe against the church of Rome. But as the only fruit
               of these noble efforts, he secured himself a place in the ranks
               of the first Protestant theologians. That age was not far
               enough advanced to comprehend his Christian spirit; and
               even our own is not yet ripe for such a union of Christians:
               as long as ignorance and vice wear the mask of sanctity, and
               faith in sectarian dogmas supplies the place of love to man
               manifest in good deeds, we shall look in vain for that blessed event.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of all that Leibnitz has written, the Theodicea has, perhaps, made him most widely known. In it his philosophy is
               reduced to practical life, and made intelligible to all minds,
               and by the very quality which makes it an incomplete work
               as a systematic exposition of philosophy, it has been made
               more serviceable to the spread of sound views of life. It is
               a pity that while this work is known to other nations, and
               highly valued by them, it is not, to our knowledge, translated into English.
            </p>
            
            <p>His intellectual activity finds no parallel in history; he
               
               knew all that was of importance to others to know, and besides he excogitated many new things, that the world was
               some time or other to learn from him, and some of which it
               has not learnt yet. He was always laboring to extend his
               own information and that of others, and spared no efforts to
               acquaint himself with discoveries in science or art. And all
               this he did for the sake of knowledge, as well as for the good
               of the race; for we are willing to take kis own testimony.
               In a letter to Magliabechi, thus he says: „For I can suggest
               much to others, but cannot alone execute all that occurs to
               me; and I would gladly give to others the fame of many of
               my inventions, if only the public welfare, the good of the
               race, and the glory of God might thereby be promoted.” And
               in another instance, alluding to the publication of his discovery of the differential calculus, he gives utterance to the following generous sentiment: “But it gives me pleasure to
               see the fruits of seeds scattered by my own hand growing in
               the gardens of others.” His unlimited good will towards
               man manifested itself in his activity for the welfare of the
               own nation as well as of others: now we see him serve the
               Imperial Elector of Hanover—now zealously engaged in laying the foundation of the Academy of Sciences at Berlin—or
               projecting one at Dresden; then advising Peter the Great
               upon the best means of civilizing his Russians; and now
               holding counsel with Charles VI. in Vienna.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have a corroboration of his noble character from the
               pen of his secretary and friend Eckhart, who says “He spoke
               well of every one—put the best construction upon the actions
               of others, and ever spared his enemies, when having it in his
               power to dispossess them of their places.”
            </p>
            
            <p>To our apprehension, the crowning eminence in Leibnitz’s
               character is his capacity for friendship. A person that is
               capable of generous and devoted friendship, is incapable of
               much wrong; for that pure flame either purifies the dross of
               the human heart, or it is extinguished; we speak of friendship that is unchangeable, ready for all sacrifice, and knows
               no sex—a friendship that is very rare, and of which great
               souls alone are capable. The capacity for such a friendship
               is the test of true greatness.
            </p>
            
            <p>Such a friendship existed between Sophia Charlotte, queen
               of Prussia, and Leibnitz, who, on her demise, writing to their
               mutual friend, Miss Von Pollnitz, gives vent to his grief in
               the following strain: “I infer your feelings from my own.
               I weep not: I complain not; but I know not where to look
               for relief. The loss of the queen appears to me like a dream;
               but when I awake from my reverie, I find it but too true.—
               Your misfortune is not greater than mine, only your feelings
               are more lively, and you stood in the midst of the general
               calamity. This encourages me to write to you and beg that
               you will moderate your sorrow, if possible, lest you do yourself an injury. It is not by excessive grief we shall best honor
               the memory of one of the most perfect princesses of the earth,
               but rather by our admiration of her virtues; and the reasonable world will be on our side. My letter is more philosophical than my heart, and I am unable to follow my own
               counsel; but it is, notwithstanding, rational.” This affliction
               deranged his usual course of life for some time, and he himself narrowly escaped an attack of severe illness.
            </p>
            
            <p>Great as Leibnitz was, yet his influence, while active, was
               diminished by the fact of his being unmarried. A single
               man is never identified so much with society as to exert all
               his powers for its benefit. A great man, when he lives single, may be said to bury a good half of himself under the
               ground, for no better purpose than that, when grown old, he
               may enjoy his own reproaches for his folly. Yet these are
               the very men who can seldom find a counterpart of themselves in woman; their union in the marriage bond is unfrequently but a separation in spirit. They seem to be destined,
               socially and intellectually, to live solitary, like the eagle on
               its rocky peak, occupied with their brood of thoughts, and
               surveying with aching eyes the wide universe spread before
               I them, the greatest bliss of which—communion, they are not
               allowed to taste. That Leibnitz was aware of the advantages and disadvantages of marriage, we learn from his saying, “Marriage is a good thing—only a wise man must
               spend his whole life in meditating it.” Although alive to the
               kindly sympathies of the softer sex, he lived alone; and the
               world lost the benefit of that part of his character which is
               only developed in wedlock.
            </p>
            
            <p>Absorbed in higher themes, he suppressed those emotions
               which pervade the mass of men, and by which only it is
               possible for another human being to gain a permanent hold
               
               
               upon mankind. His only passion was to seek after knowledge, that it may benefit the race; his writings are so purely intellectual, so free from the fire of common passions that,
               while he deserves to be ranked among the greatest geniuses, and greatest benefactors that ever lived, he has not had
               even the half of the meed of praise which was bestowed by
               the thoughtless multitude upon men of smaller stature.
            </p>
            
            <p>Leibnitz was a poet of the highest order; of course, we do
               not take the word in its vulgar and limited meaning; he was
               the highest type of genius: he had the key to Nature’s mysteries, which lie expounded to the less favored sons of Eve.
               He was permitted, priestlike, to comprehend the counsels
               of God, that he might reveal to his fellow mortals the wisdom and benevolence of our heavenly Father. To us, he is
               an intellectual Howard, visiting the dens of ignorance to rescue truth from the mire of error. In his time there was
               none equal to him, not even Newton; and since, none has
               appeared that can measure himself with the German sage.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mankind owes gratitude to its great men, as they are its
               teachers and fashioners, its ornaments and redeemers; and
               every nation should do its part in acknowledging itself their
               debtor—willing to pay the interest, although unable to discharge the full liability. And we are glad that at last there
               was found one, who took upon himself the honorable responsibility of acknowledging this indebtedness on the part of the
               Anglo-Saxon race to the genius of Leibnitz, by presenting
               the English reader with the life of the sage. The writer has
               our thanks, for he has admirably acquitted himsolf of the
               task: the interest and unity of his theme are well supported
               by a chaste diction.
            </p>
            
            <p>But while we thank him for what he has done, we beg
               leave to dissent from his conclusion; we should have been
               much better pleased had he preserved those German peculiarities, which he thought not adapted to the wants of the
               Appalachian literary public.
            </p>
            
            <p>There are two views to be taken of the life of a man;—
               first, as he makes one identity standing out in distinct lineaments of society—next, as that identity sends out its roots
               into society in different directions, both to prop itself and
               strengthen the social frame work. The writer has taken
               chiefly the first view of the life of Leibnitz. To us it would
               have been more satisfactory, had it been conformable to our
               way of viewing these matters. Biography is a key to history, and only such biographies as represent this two-fold
               view of an individual, can be good keys to unlock the
               true spirit of history that time holds in its fastnesses—the
               past and the distant.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have another reason to thank the writer for his work.
               Every thing that makes us better acquainted with the great
               and good men of other countries, is calculated either to
               strengthen national sympathies, or remove prejudices that
               ignorance or national vanity begets. The work in hand will
               contribute its share to this desirable result; inasmuch as
               there is room in the Anglo-Saxon race for the happy influence of those kindly feelings which lead us, on all occasions,
               to view the man of another clime as a brother, and deserving
               at our hands that regard to which humanity, civilization,
               and Christianity give him a title.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">Poems</div>
            <div class="biblPage">328</div>
            <p>Poems. By William W. Lord. New York: D. Apppleton &amp; Co.</p>
            
            <p>Of Mr. Lord we know nothing—although we believe that
               he is a student at Princeton College—or perhaps a graduate,
               or perhaps a Professor of that Institution. Of his book,
               lately, we have heard a good deal—that is to say, we have
               heard it announced in every possible variation of phrase, as
               “forthcoming.” For several months past, indeed, much
               amusement has been occasioned in the various literary coteries in New York, by the pertinacity and obviousness of an
               attempt made by the poet’s friends to get up an anticipatory
               excitement in his favor. There were multitudinous dark
               rumors of something in posse—whispered insinuations that
               the sun had at length arisen or would certainly arise—that
               a book was really in press which would revolutionize the
               poetical world—that the MS. had been submitted to the inspection of a junto of critics, whose fiat was well understood
               to be Fate, (Mr. Charles King, if we remember aright, formng one of the junto)—that the work had by them been approved, and its successful reception and illimitable glorification assured.—Mr. Longfellow, in consequence, countermanding an order given his publishers (Redding &amp; Co.,) to issue
               forthwith a new threepenny edition of “The Voices of the
               Night.” Suggestions of this nature, busily circulated in private, were, in good time, insinuated through the press, until
               at length the public expectation was as much on tiptoe as
               public expectation, in America, can ever be expected to be
               about so small a matter as the issue of a volume of American poems. The climax of this whole effort, however, at
               forestalling the critical opinion, and by far the most injudicious portion of the procedure, was the publisher’s announcement of the forthcoming book as “a very remarkable volume
               of poems.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The fact is, the only remarkable things about Mr. Lord’s
               compositions, are their remarkable conceit, ignorance, impudence, platitude, stupidity and bombast:—we are sorry to
               say all this, but there is an old adage about the falling of the
               Heavens. Nor must we be misunderstood. We intend to
               wrong neither Mr. Lord nor our own conscience, by denying
               him particular merits—such as they are. His book is not
               altogether contemptible—although the conduct of his friends
               has innoculated nine-tenths of the community with the opinion that it is—but what we wish to say, is that “remarkable” is by no means the epithet to be applied, in the way of
               commendation, either to anything that he has yet done or to
               anything that he may hereafter accomplish. In a word,
               while he has undoubtedly given proof of a very ordinary species of talent, no man whose opinion is entitled to the slightest respect will admit in him any indication of genius.
            </p>
            
            <p>The " particular merits” to which, in the case of Mr. Lord,
               we have allusion, are merely the accidental merits of particular passages. We say accidental—because poetical merit
               which is not simply an accident, is very sure to be found,
               more or less, in a state of diffusion throughout a poem. No
               man is entitled to the sacred name of poet, because from 160
               pages of doggrel, may be culled a few sentences of worth.
               Nor would the case be in any respect altered, if these few
               sentences, or even if a few passages of length, were of an
               excellence even supreme. For a poet is necessarily a man
               of genius, and with the spirit of true genius even its veriest
               common-places are intertwined and inextricably intertangled.
               When, therefore, amid a Sahara of platitude, we discover an
               occasional Oasis, we must not so far forget ourselves as to
               fancy any latent fertility in the sands. It is our purpose,
               however, to do the fullest justice to Mr. Lord, and we proceed at once to cull from his book whatever, in our opinion,
               will put in the fairest light his poetical pretensions.
            </p>
            
            <p>And first we extract the one brief passage which aroused
               in us what we recgnised as the Poetical Sentiment. It occurs, at page 94, in “Saint Mary’s Gift,” which, although excessively unoriginal at all points, is upon the whole, the least
               reprehensible poem of the volume. The heroine of the story
               having taken a sleeping draught, after the manner of Juliet,
               is conveyed to a vault (still in the same manner) and (still
               in the same manner) awakes in the presence of her lover
               who comes to gaze on what he supposes her corpse:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>And each unto the other was a dream;
               
               <br></br>And so they gazed without a stir or breath,
               
               <br></br>Until her head into the golden stream
               
               <br></br>Of her wide tresses, loosened from their wreath,
               
               <br></br>Sank back, as she did yield again to death.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>At page 3, in a composition of much general eloquence,
               there occur a few lines of which we should not hesitate to
               speak enthusiastically were we not perfectly well aware
               that Mr. Lord has no claim to their origination:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>------ Ye winds
               
               <br></br>That in the impalpable deep caves of air,
               
               
               <br></br>Moving your silent plumes, in dreams of flight,
               
               <br></br>Tumultuous lie, and from your half-stretched wings
               
               <br></br>Beat the faint zephyrs that disturb the air!
            </div>
            
            
            <p>At page 6, in the same poem, we meet, also, a passage of
               high merit, although sadly disfigured:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Thee the bright host of Heaven,
               
               <br></br>The stars adore:—a thousand altars, fed
               
               <br></br>By pure unwearied hands, like cressets blaze
               
               <br></br>In the blue depths of night; nor all unseen
               
               <br></br>In the pale sky of day, with tempered light
               
               <br></br>Burn radiant of thy praise.
            </div>
            
            <p>The disfiguration to which we allude, lies in the making
               a blazing altar burn merely like a blazing cresset—a simile
               about as forcible as would be the likening an apple to a pear,
               or the sea-foam to the froth on a pitcher of Burton’s ale.
            </p>
            
            <p>At page 7, still in the same poem, we find some verses
               which are very quotable, and will serve to make our
               readers understand what we mean by the eloquence of the
               piece:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Great Worshipper! hast thou no thought of Him
               
               <br></br>Who gave the Sun his brightness, winged the winds,
               
               <br></br>And on the everlasting deep bestowed
               
               <br></br>Its voiceless thunder—spread its fields of blue,
               
               <br></br>And made them glorious like an inner sky
               
               <br></br>From which the islands rise like steadfast clouds,
               
               <br></br>How beautiful! who gemmed thy zone with stars,
               
               <br></br>Around thee threw his own cerulean robe,—
               
               <br></br>And bent his coronal about thy brows,
               
               <br></br>Shaped of the seven splendors of the light—
               
               <br></br>Piled up the mountains for thy throne; and thee
               
               <br></br>The image of His beauty made and power,
               
               <br></br>And gave thee to be sharer of His state,
               
               <br></br>His majesty, His glory, and His fear!
            </div>
            
            <p>We extract this not because we like it ourselves, but because we take it for granted that there are many who will,
               and that Mr. Lord himself would desire us to extract it as a
               specimen of his power. The “Great worshipper” is Nature.
               We disapprove, however, the man-milliner method in which
               she is tricked out, item by item. The “How beautiful!”
               should be understood, we fancy, as an expression of admiration on the part of Mr. Lord, for the fine idea which immediately precedes—the idea which we have italicized. It is,
               in fact, by no means destitute of force—but we have met it
               before.
            </p>
            
            <p>At page 70, there are two stanzas addressed to “My Sister.” The first of these we cite as the best thing of equal
               length to be found in the book. Its conclusion is particularly noble.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>And shall we meet in heaven, and know and love?
               
               <br></br>Do human feelings in that world above
               
               <br></br>Unchanged survive? blest thought! but ah, I fear
               
               <br></br>That thou, dear sister, in some other sphere,
               
               <br></br>Distant from mine will (wilt) find a brighter home,
               
               <br></br>Where I, unworthy found, may never come:—
               
               <br></br>Or be so high above me glorified,
               
               <br></br>That I a meaner angel, undescried,
               
               <br></br>Seeking thine eyes, such love alone shall see
               
               <br></br>As angels give to all bestowed on me;
               
               <br></br>And when my voice upon thy ear shall fall,
               
               <br></br>Hear only such reply as angels give to all.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>We give the lines as they are: their grammatical construction is faulty; and the punctuation of the ninth line renders the sense equivocal.</p>
            
            <p>Of that species of composition which comes most appropriately under the head, Drivel, we should have no trouble
               in selecting as many specimens as our readers could desire.
               We will afflict them with one or two:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">SONG.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>O soft is the ringdove’s eye of love
               
               <br></br>When her mate returns from a weary flight;
               
               <br></br>And brightest of all the stars above
               
               <br></br>Is the one bright star that leads the night.
               
               <br></br>But softer thine eye than the dove’s by far,
               
               <br></br>When of friendship and pity thou speakest to me;
               
               <br></br>And brighter, O brighter, than eye's one star
               
               <br></br>When of love, sweet maid, I speak to thee.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>Here is another</p>
            
            <div class="ab">SONG.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Oh, a heart it loves, it loves thee,
               
               <br></br>That never loved before
               
               <br></br>Oh, a heart it loves, it loves thee,
               
               <br></br>That heart can love no more.
               
               <br></br>As the rose was in the bud, love,
               
               <br></br>Ere it opened into sight,
               
               <br></br>As yon star in drumlie daylight
               
               <br></br>Behind the blue was bright—
               
               <br></br>So thine image in my heart, love,
               
               <br></br>As pure, as bright, as fair,
               
               <br></br>Thyself unseen, unheeded,
               
               <br></br>I saw and loved it there.
               
               <br></br>Oh, a heart it loves, it loves thee
               
               <br></br>As heart ne’er loved before;
               
               <br></br>Oh, a heart, it loves, loves, loves thee,
               
               <br></br>That heart can love no more.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>In “The Widow’s Complaint’’ we are entertained after
               this fashion:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>And what are these children
               
               <br></br>I once thought my own.
               
               <br></br>What now do they seem
               
               <br></br>But his orphans alone?
            </div>
            
            <p>In “The New Castalia” we have it thus:
               
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Then a pallid beauteous maiden
               
               <br></br>Golden ghastly robes arrayed in
               
               <br></br>Such a wondrous strain displayed in,
               
               <br></br>In a wondrous song of Aidenne,
               
               <br></br>That all the gods and goddesses
               
               <br></br>Shook their golden yellow tresses,
               
               <br></br>Parnassus’ self made half afraid in.
            </div>
            
            <p>Just above this there is something about aged beldames
               dreaming
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>_____of white throats sweetly jagged
               
               <br></br>With a ragged butch-knife dull,
               
               <br></br>And of night-mares neighing, weighing,
               
               <br></br>On a sleeper’s bosom squatting.
            </div>
            
            <p>But in mercy to our readers we forbear.
               
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Lord is never elevated above the dead level of his habitual platitude, by even the happiest thesis in the world.
               That any man could, at one and the same time, fancy himself a poet and siring together as many pitiable inanities as
               we see here, on so truly suggestive a thesis as that of “A
               Lady taking the Veil,” is to our apprehension a miracle of
               miracles. The idea would seem to be, of itself, sufficient to
               elicit fire from ice—to breathe animation into the most stolid
               of stone. Mr. Lord winds up a dissertation on the subject by
               the patronizing advice—
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Ere thou, irrevocable, to that dark creed
               
               <br></br>Art yielded, think, Oh Lady, think again!
            </div>
            
            <p>the whole of which would read better if it were</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Ere thou, irrevocable, to this d—d doggrel
               
               <br></br>Art yielded, Lord, think! think!—ah think again.
            </div>
            
            <p>Even with the great theme, Niagara, our poet fails in his
               obvious effort to work himself into a fit of inspiration. One
               of his poems has for title “A Hymn to Niagara”—but from
               beginning to end it is nothing more than a very silly
               “Hymn to Mr. Lord.” Instead of describing the fall (as
               well as any Mr. Lord could be supposed to describe it) he
               rants about what I feel here, and about what I did not feel
               there—till at last the figure of little Mr. Lord, in the shape
               of a great capital I gets so thoroughly in between the reader
               and the waterfall that not a particle of the latter is to be
               discovered. At one point the poet directs his soul to issue a
               proclamation as follows:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Proclaim, my soul, proclaim it to the sky!
               
               <br></br>And tell the stars, and tell the hills whose feet
               
               <br></br>Are in the depths of earth, their peaks in heaven,
               
               <br></br>And tell the Ocean’s old familiar face
               
               <br></br>Beheld by day and night, in calm and storm.
               
               <br></br>That they, nor aught beside in earth or heaven,
               
               
               <br></br>Like thee, tremendous torrent, have so filled
               
               <br></br>Its thought of beauty, and so awed with might!
            </div>
            
            <p>The “Its” has reference to the soul of Mr. Lord, who
               thinks it necessary to issue a proclamation to the stars and
               the hills and the ocean’s old familiar face—lest the stars and
               the hills and the ocean’s old familiar face should chance to
               be unaware of the fact that it (the soul of Mr. Lord) admitted the waterfall to be a fine thing—but whether the cataract for the compliment, or the stars for the information, are
               to be considered the party chiefly obliged—that, for the life
               of us, we cannot tell.	
            </p>
            
            <p>From the “first impression” of the cataract, he says:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>At length my soul awaked—waked not again
               
               <br></br>To be o’erpressed, o’ermastered, and engulphed,
               
               <br></br>But of itself possessed, o’er all without
               
               <br></br>Felt conscious mastery!
               
               <br></br>And then
               
               <br></br>Retired within, and self-withdrawn, I stood
               
               <br></br>The two-fold centre and informing soul
               
               <br></br>Of one vast harmony of sights and sounds,
               
               <br></br>And from that deep abyss, that rock-built shrine,
               
               <br></br>Though mute my own frail voice, I poured a hymn
               
               <br></br>Of “praise and gratulation” like the noise
               
               <br></br>Of banded angels when they shout to wake
               
               <br></br>Empyreal echoes!
            </div>
            
            <p>That so vast a personage as Mr. Lord should not be o’ermastered by the cataract, but feel “conscious mastery over
               all without”—and over all within, too—is certainly nothing
               more than reasonable and proper—but then he should have
               left the detail of these little facts to the cataract or to some
               other uninterested individual—even Cicero has been held to
               blame for a want of modesty—and although, to be sure,
               Cicero was not Mr. Lord, still Mr. Lord may be in danger of
               blame. He may have enemies (very little men!) who will
               pretend to deny that the “hymn of praise and gratulation”
               (if this is the hymn) bears at all points more than a partial
               resemblance to the “noise of banded angels when they shout
               to wake empyreal echoes.” Not that we intend to deny it—
               but they will:—they are very little people and they will.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have said that the “remarkable” feature, or at least
               one of the “remarkable” features of this volume is its platitude—its flatness. Whenever the reader meets anything
               not decidedly flat, he may take it for granted at once, that it
               is stolen. When the poet speaks, for example, at page 148,
               of
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Flowers, of young poets the first words—
            </div>
            
            <p>who can fail to remember the line in the Merry Wives of
               Windsor.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Fairies use flowers for their charactery?
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 10 he says:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Great oaks their heavenward lifted arms stretch forth
               
               <br></br>In suppliance!
            </div>
            
            <p>The same thought will be found in “Pelham,” where the
               author is describing the dead tree beneath which is committed the murder. The grossest plagiarisms, indeed, abound.
               We would have no trouble, even, in pointing out a score from
               our most unimportant self. At page 27 Mr. Lord says:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>They, albeit with inward pain
               
               <br></br>Who thought to sing thy dirge, must sing thy Paean!
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">In a poem called “Lenore,” we have it</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Avaunt! to-night my heart is light—no dirge will I upraise,
               
               <br></br>But waft the angel on her flight with a Paean of old days.
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 13, Mr. Lord says of certain flowers that</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Ere beheld on Earth they gardened Heaven!
            </div>
            
            <p>We print it as printed—note of admiration and all. In a
               poem called “Al Aaraaf” we have it thus:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>---------A gemmy flower,
               
               <br></br>Inmate of highest stars, where erst it shamed
               
               <br></br>All other loveliness:—’twas dropped from Heaven
               
               <br></br>And fell on gardens of the unforgiven
               
               <br></br>In Trebizond.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>At page 57 Mr. Lord says:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>On the old and haunted mountain,
               
               <br></br>There in dreams I dared to climb,
               
               <br></br>Where the clear Castalian fountain
               
               <br></br>(Silver fountain) ever tinkling
               
               <br></br>All the green around it sprinkling
               
               <br></br>Makes perpetual rhyme—
               
               <br></br>To my dream enchanted, golden,
               
               <br></br>Came a vision of the olden
               
               <br></br>Long-forgotten time.
            </div>
            
            <p>There are no doubt many of our friends who will remember the commencement of our “Haunted Palace.”</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>In the greenest of our valleys
               
               <br></br>By good angels tenanted,
               
               <br></br>Once a fair and stately palace
               
               <br></br>(Radiant palace) reared its head.
               
               <br></br>In the monarch Thought’s dominion
               
               <br></br>It stood there.
               
               <br></br>Never seraph spread a pinion
               
               <br></br>Over fabric half so fair.
               
               <br></br>Banners yellow, glorious, golden,
               
               <br></br>On its roof did float and flow—
               
               <br></br>This—all this—was in the olden
               
               <br></br>Time, long ago.
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 60, Mr. Lord says:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>And the aged beldames napping,
               
               <br></br>Dreamed of gently rapping, rapping,
               
               <br></br>With a hammer gently tapping,
               
               <br></br>Tapping on an infant’s skull.
            </div>
            
            <p>In “The Raven” we have it:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>While I pondered nearly napping,
               
               <br></br>Suddenly there came a rapping,
               
               <br></br>As of some one gently tapping,
               
               <br></br>Tapping at my chamber door.
            </div>
            
            <p>But it is folly to pursue these thefts. As to any property
               of our own, Mr. Lord is very cordially welcome to whatever
               use he can make of it. But others may not be so pacifically
               disposed, and the book before us might be very materially
               thinned and reduced in cost, by discarding from it all that belongs to Miss Barrett, Tennyson, Keats, Shelley, Proctor
               Longfellow and Lowell—the very class of poets, by the way,
               whom Mr. William W. Lord, in his “New Castalia” the
               most especially effects to satirize and to contemn.
            </p>
            
            <p>It has been rumored, we say, or rather it has been announced that Mr. Lord is a graduate or perhaps a Professor
               of Princeton College—but we have had much difficulty in believing anything of the kind. The pages before us are not
               only utterly devoid of that classicism of tone and manner—th-t
               better species of classicism which a liberal education never
               fails to impart—but they abound in the most outrageously
               vulgar violations of grammar—of prosody in its most extended sense.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of versification, and all that appertains to it, Mr. Lord is
               ignorant in the extreme. We doubt if he can tell the difference between a dactyl and an anapoest. In the Heroic
               (Jambic) Pentameter he is continually introducing such
               verses as these:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>A faint symphony to Heaven ascending—
               
               <br></br>No heart of love, O God, Infinite One—
               
               <br></br>Of a thought as weak an aspiration—
               
               <br></br>Who were the original priests of this—
               
               <br></br>Of grace, magnificence and power—
               
               <br></br>O’erwhelm me; this darkness that shuts out the sky—
            </div>
            
            <p>Alexandrines, in the same metre, are encountered at every
               step—but it is very clear from the points at which they are
               met, and at which the coesura is placed, that Mr. Lord has
               no idea of employing them as Alexandrines;—They are
               merely excessive that is to say defective Pentameters. In a
               word, judging by his rhythm, we might suppose that the
               poet could neither see, hear, nor make use of his fingers.
               We do not know, in America, a versifier so utterly wretched
               and contemptible.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>His most extraordinary sins, however, are in point of English. Here is his dedication, embodied in the very first page
               of the book:—
            </p>
            
            <p>“To Professor Albert B. Dod, These Poems, the offspriug
               of an Earnest (if ineffectual) Desire towards the True
               and Beautiful, which were hardly my own by Paternity,
               when they became his by Adoption, are inscribed, with all
               Reverence and Affection, by the Author.”
            </p>
            
            <p>What is any body to make of all this? What is the
               meaning of a desire toward?—and is it the “True and
               Beautiful” or the “Poems” which were hardly Mr. Lord’s
               “own by paternity before they became his [Mr. Dod’s] by
               adoption.”
            </p>
            
            <p>At page 12, we read:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Think heedless one, or who with wanton step
               
               <br></br>Tramples the flowers.
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 75, within the compass of eleven lines, we have
               three of the grossest blunders:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Oh Thou for whom as in thyself Thou art,
               
               <br></br>And by thyself perceived, we know no name,
               
               <br></br>Nor dare not seek to express—but unto us,
               
               <br></br>Adonai! who before the heavens were built
               
               <br></br>Or Earth’s foundation laid, within thyself,
               
               <br></br>Thine own most glorious habitation dwelt,
               
               <br></br>But when within the abyss,
               
               <br></br>With sudden light illuminated,
               
               <br></br>Thou, thine image to behold,
               
               <br></br>Into its quickened depths
               
               <br></br>Looked down with brooding eye!
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 79, we read:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>But ah! my heart, unduteous to my will,
               
               <br></br>Breathes only sadness: like an instrument
               
               <br></br>From whose quick strings, when hands devoid of skill
               
               <br></br>Solicit joy, they murmur and lament.
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 86, is something even grosser than this:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>And still and rapt as pictured Saint might be
               
               <br></br>Like saint-like seemed as her she did adore.
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 129, there is a similar error:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>With half-closed eyes and ruffled feathers known
               
               <br></br>As them that fly not with the changing year.
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 128 we find—</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>And thou didst dwell therein so truly loved
               
               <br></br>As none have been nor shall be loved again,
               
               <br></br>And yet perceived not, etc.
            </div>
            
            <p>At page 155, we have—</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>But yet it may not cannot be
               
               <br></br>That thou at length hath sunk to rest.
            </div>
            
            <p>Invariably Mr. Lord writes didst did'st; couldst could’st,
               etc. The fact is he is absurdly ignorant of the commonest
               principles of grammar—and the only excuse we can make to
               our readers for annoying them with specifications in this respect is that, without the specifications, we should never
               have been believed.
            </p>
            
            <p>But enough of this folly. We are heartily tired of the
               book, and thoroughly disgusted with the impudence of the
               parties who have been aiding and abetting in thrusting it
               before the public. To the poet himself we have only to say
               —from any farther specimens of your stupidity, good Lord
               deliver us!
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Big Bear of Arkansas</div>
            <div class="biblPage">331</div>
            <p>The Big Bear of Arkansas, and Other Tales.—Illustrative of characters and incidents in the South and South-West—edited by W. T.
               Porter, with ten original engravings from Designs by Darley. Philadelphia: Carey and Hart.
            </p>
            
            <p>Most of these sketches were originally published in the
               New York “Spirit of the Times,” where they attracted
               much attention. The two first in the volume are, we think,
               much overrated by the editor—they seem to us dull and
               forced. Many of the others are irresistibly comic and
               fresh. “The great Kalamazoo Hunt" is a study in this
               
               species of writing; and “Swallowing an Oyster” by our
               friend Field, of the inimitable “Reveille,” is a jewel of a
               thought, set to perfection. The designs by Darley (who has
               genius of a high order) are good, of course, but not so good
               as we expect to see front him.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Sale of a Distillery</div>
            <div class="biblPage">331</div>
            <p>The Sale of a Distillery: A Pencilling of the Present Age. By Wm.
               Oland Bourne.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Bourne has very vigorous talent. The “Sale of a
               Distillery” is the best poem we have yet seen on the subject
               of intemperance. The conception is a most forcible one,
               and the execution (with very slight exception) masterly.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Dossay Portraits</div>
            <div class="biblPage">331</div>
            <p>The Dossay Portraits, from “Punch,” with Six Hundred Humorous
               Illustrations. Philadelphia: Carey and Hart.
            </p>
            
            <p>A reprint of a series of very pungent satirical papers—the
               point of which will not be so fully appreciated among us as
               could be desired.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Prime Minster</div>
            <div class="biblPage">331</div>
            <p>The Prime Minister; or the Singular Fortunes of a Peasant
               and a Peer. By Heinrich Zschokke, author of “Hortensia, or
               the Transfigurations,” etc. Translated from the German. New
               York. E. Winchester.
            </p>
            
            <p>Zchokke’s works have been very popular, and have in them
               all the elements of the best popularity. “The Prime Minister” is strongly marked with its author’s manner, and is
               very entertaining. The pamphlet is finely printed, and tasteful altogether.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p13">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Conqueror Worm</div>
         <div class="biblPage">331</div>
         <div class="head">THE CONQUEROR WORM.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Lo! 'tis a gala night
            
            <br></br>Within the lonesome latter years!
            
            <br></br>A mystic throng, bewing’d, bedight
            
            <br></br>In veils, and drown’d in tears,
            
            <br></br>Sit in a theatre, to see
            
            <br></br>A play of hopes and fears,
            
            <br></br>While the orchestra breathes fitfully
            
            <br></br>The music of the spheres.
            
            <br></br>Mimes, in the form of God on high,
            
            <br></br>Mutter and mumble low,
            
            <br></br>And hither and thither fly—
            
            <br></br>Mere puppets they, who come and go
            
            <br></br>At bidding of vast formless things
            
            <br></br>That shift the scenery to and fro,
            
            <br></br>Flapping from out their Condor wings
            
            <br></br>Invisible Wo!
            
            <br></br>That motley drama!—oh, be sure
            
            <br></br>It shall not be forgot!
            
            <br></br>With its Phantom chas’d forevermore,
            
            <br></br>By a crowd that seize it not,
            
            <br></br>Through a circle that ever returneth in
            
            <br></br>To the self-same spot,
            
            <br></br>And much of Madness, and more of Sin,
            
            <br></br>And Horror the soul of the plot.
            
            <br></br>But see, amid the mimic rout
            
            <br></br>A crawling shape intrude!
            
            <br></br>A blood-red thing that writhes from out
            
            <br></br>The scenic solitude!
            
            <br></br>It writhes!—it writhes —with mortal pangs
            
            <br></br>The mimes become its food,
            
            <br></br>And the angels sob at vermin fangs
            
            <br></br>In human gore imbued.
            
            <br></br>Out—out are the lights—out all!
            
            <br></br>And, over each quivering form,
            
            <br></br>The curtain, a funeral pall,
            
            <br></br>Comes down with the rush of a storm,
            
            <br></br>And the angels, all pallid and wan,
            
            <br></br>Uprising, unveiling, affirm
            
            <br></br>That the play is the tragedy, “Man,”
            
            <br></br>Its hero the Conqueror Worm.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Review</div>
         <div class="head">MUSICAL REVIEW.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">My Cynosure</div>
            <div class="biblPage">332</div>
            <p>My Cynosure. Words by Park Benjamin, composed for and dedicated
               to his friend Wynant Van Zandt, by Hermen S. Saroni.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a very charming ballad in E flat, suited to a light
               soprano or tenor voice. The melody cannot be said to be
               very original, but it is graceful, flowing, and pathetic. The
               symphony and accompaniments are both pleasing and adpropriate, and as a whole it is one of the most pleasing ballads that has come under our notice for a considerable period.
               The words, by Park Benjamin, are well adapted to music,
               having the force, passion, and terseness of diction, for which
               the author is so well known. In the third bar, third line,
               second page, the A flat in the bass should be A natural.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Slumber, Infant, Slumber</div>
            <div class="biblPage">332</div>
            <p>Slumber, Infant, Slumber. A duett for two soprano voices, poetry
               by R. Moncton Milnes, Esq. M.P., composed and dedicated to Miss
               Sarah Henriquez, by Herman S. Saroni.
            </p>
            
            <p>This duett is really beautiful from its simplicity. The
               melody is most admirably adapted to the words, and we do
               not know any simple duett that we would more gladly listen
               to when warbled from the lips of youth and innocence. We
               think that Mr. Saroni has been extremely fortunate in this
               composition; he may write many works of more pretension,
               but we prophecy for this duett a popularity far beyond
               his expectation. Were we inclined to be very critical, we
               might point out a resemblance, and a very marked one, too,
               in the first phrases, to the well known melody of “Flow on
               thou shining River,” but we believe the imitation to have
               been accidental.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Saroni is a rising and very promising young man. He
               has a happy faculty of writing for the popular taste, and yet, 
               with all the necessary simplicity, there is generally a positive 
               evidence of a power to do greater things. We feel much
               pleasure in being able to speak of him as he deserves.
            </p>
            
            <p>The poetry of this duett is by a living English poet of
               well tried celebrity. The sentiment is sad—the language is 
               simple and touching.
            </p>
            
            <p>We recommend this duett to our readers in all sincerity. 
               They will find our warm recommendation by no means ex- 
               aggerated.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">G. G. Ferari's Celebrated Instruction-Book</div>
            <div class="biblPage">332</div>
            <p>G.	G. Ferari’s celebrated Instruction-Book for the Voice. Published by 
               F. Riley, 297 Bowery.
            </p>
            
            <p>Among the numerous vocal Instruction-Books published
               within the last twenty years, the one now under consideration has best maintained its stand. It has been universally 
               praised, and is very generally adopted, particularly in England, where its sale has been really enormous. It is also
               very much used here, it being popular and comprehensive in
               its character.
            </p>
            
            <p>The introductory remarks appended by the author, are 
               very valuable to every one studying the art of singing, and 
               should be read attentively, over and over again, until the pupil has got them nearly perfect by rote. The examples in- j
               troduced, should also be studied attentively, as a knowledge 
               of them will greatly facilitate the acquirement of a correct
               and tasteful style of reading.
            </p>
            
            <p>The exercises are very copious, comprising most of the
               difficulties which are to be found in music above the common standard. Those upon the shake (il trillo) are important in many ways, and should be practised in every key. 
               There are others equally valuable, and equally deserving of
               especial attention, which we would point out, if we were
               not so limited in our space. We must, therefore, leave them
               to be dwelt upon by the teacher, or, if the pupil is studying
               alone, we must direct the attention particularly to the introductory remarks, where many special points for practice are
               strenuously advocated.
            </p>
            
            <p>We can recommend Ferari’s work to teachers and students
               as an excellent elementary work, well calculated to prepare
               the voice and mind for more advanced and difficult practice.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Riley has produced a work, valuable to the public,
               and one, which is also we trust, valuable to himself. He
               should be well remunerated, for the retting out of such a
               work as this involves considerable risk in outlay.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">Bohemian Waltzes</div>
            <div class="biblPage">332</div>
            <p>Bohemian Waltzes, arranged from the Bohemian Girl, and dedicated
               to Miss S. A. P. Bull, by J. C. Scherpf.
            </p>
            
            <p>Alpine Horn Quick Step, arranged for the Pianoforte, and dedicated to
               Miss Mary C. Baxter, by J. C. Scherpf.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Alhambra Quick Step, arranged for the Pianoforte, by J. C.
               Scherpf.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Three Sisters. No. 1 of six Rondinos, for three performers on one
               Pianoforte, by Charles C. Zerny.
            </p>
            
            <p>All of the above pieces published by F. Riley, 297 Broad-
               way.
            </p>
            
            <p>No. 1 is a second sett of the Bohemian (Girl) Waltzes.
               We like them better than the first sett; they are more carefully arranged, more natural, more flowing. They make
               very charming short waltzes, and are certain to gain extensive popularity.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the fifth bar, fourth line, first page in the bass, the chord
               in the position 4-5 with its resolution, followed by F in the
               next bar, would have been much better.
            </p>
            
            <p>The two following pieces are very melodious Quick Steps,
               which must doubtless put a very spirit into the feet of our
               volunteer companies. When Mr. Scherpf shall pay more
               attention to his general harmony and rhythm, he will become
               one of the most popular arrangers of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>The piece by C. Zerny is a very catching show piece, for
               three performers on the piano.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p18">
         <div class="biblTitle">J. Pirsson'a Pianoforte Manufactory</div>
         <div class="biblPage">332</div>
         <p>J. Pirsson’s Pianoforte Manufactory.—A visit to this
            factory will most amply repay the trouble of a journey of one
            block down Walker from Broadway. It is a neat, compact,
            and yet extensive building, covering several lots, and arranged with so much order, that the various departments seem
            to work one into the other. Mr. Pirsson has always been a
            hard-working man; by sheer industry and indomitable perseverance, combined with mechanical skill and practical ingenuity, he has worked himself to his present rank among
            the first masters in the city, and enjoys, deservedly, a very
            large share of public patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Having but recently described the manufacture of PianoFortes in our columns, we shall have but little to say on
            that head; but there are several important improvements
            which have been effected in Mr. Pirsson’s factory and patented by him, about which we purpose saying a few words.
         </p>
         
         <p>The improvement to which Mr. Pirsson attaches the most
            importance to the Arched Bottom, which differs materially
            from those used by other makers. He not only finds that it
            tends greatly to improve the quality of the lone, making it
            more rich and sonorous, but that it adds most marvellously
            to the general strength of the instrument, rendering it almost
            an impossibility, that any portion of the wood work should
            give way, the breadth of even a hair. This is undoubtedly
            an improvement, and as such is deserving of considerable attention.
         </p>
         
         <p>The other improvements connected with the action, though
            of a more minute character, are not the less important,—the
            reversed lever, by which the power is always preserved
            equal, and which prevents all noise in the working of the
            hammers; also, the improved action of the pedals—an improvement very much needed. There are many minor additions in the moveable portions of the action all tending to
            strengthen and perfect it, but of which it is not necessary for
            us to speak at present.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Pirsson’s Pianofortes are distinguished for the exceeding sweetness, brilliancy and power of their tone, the springyness of their touch, and the beauty of their exterior form, and
            material and finish.
         </p>
         
         <p>We can recommend these instruments to our friends and
            the public. Those who wish to see the instruments, will
            have every facility afforded them by Mr. Pirsson, whose extreme good nature and obliging manners have won him a
            host of friends, both in and out of the profession.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p19">
         <div class="biblTitle">Onslaught Upon the Critics</div>
         <div class="biblPage">333</div>
         <p>Onslaught upon the critics, by one of the Mirror
            School.—Our remarks under this head have been misunderstood by some of our friends. We simply used the words
            “by one of the Mirror School” in reference to a remark
            made in the Evening Mirror, which was something to this
            effect—“that the best criticisms upon Music were written
            by persons who were not professors and who were ignorant of
            Science.” We are entirely opposed to this opinion, and the
            person of whom we were writing offering so perfect an illustration of the folly of the remark, we involuntarily termed
            him “one of the Mirror School” without intending any offence to the friends of the Mirror.
         </p>
         
         <p>We would on no account institute a comparison between
            the writers in the two papers, for while we dissent from the
            opinions of the Mirror Critic, we cannot but admire him for
            the brilliancy of his imagination and the gentlemanly tone
            of all his remarks; and, disputing the truth of the remark
            which we have questioned above, we believe, sincerely, that
            were his knowledge as thorough as his feeling of the subject,
            he would be the best, as he is now the most poetical critic
            in the country,
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p20">
         <div class="biblTitle">Concert at St. Peter's Church</div>
         <div class="biblPage">333</div>
         <p>Concert at St. Peter’s Church.—The Grand Sacred
            Concert announced in our last paper, took place at St. Peter’s Church on Sunday evening last. The weather had
            been miserable all day and partially clear a short time previous to the opening of the doors; and yet, though the
            storm doubtless kept hundreds away, there were assembled
            between six and seven hundred persons.
         </p>
         
         <p>The principal performers were Mrs. Loder, Miss De
            Luce, Miss Schmidt, Miss Watson, and Mr. Massett.
         </p>
         
         <p>The chorus, all members of the N. Y. Vocal Society, with
            two exceptions, was full and efficient, and was conducted by
            Mr. H. C. Watson.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. W. A. King presided at the Organ and played a most
            lovely duett by Mozart, with Mr. H. C. Timm.
         </p>
         
         <p>The selection of music was unexceptionable, being comprised entirely of the beauties of the great masters. The
            Concert gave great and general delight,
         </p>
         
         <p>We have been promised a criticism of the performance,
            and if it reaches us in time, it shall appear.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p21">
         <div class="biblTitle">Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="biblPage">333</div>
         <div class="head">FINE ARTS.</div>
         
         <p>There are exhibiting in the rooms of the Art Union four
            landscapes by George Brown of Boston, now in Florence,
            which will place his name at the head of American landscape painters. Two are views in Florence, on the Arno,
            and two in the Bay of Naples. They bring Italy home to
            us, are rather take us to her beautiful shores. The view
            of the “Castillo de’Ova,” Bay of Naples, we regard as the
            finest of the four. It is the perfection of landscape painting; atmosphere, figures, buildings, water, ships, clouds,
            and sun-shine are perfect. It is a marvel of art. The
            “festa of St. John,” a view on the Arno, in Florence, is of
            a different character, and quite as perfect in its kind, but it
            is not as pleasing a picture as the other; the architecture is
            delightful and the river is the purest water that we have 
            ever seen upon Canvas. We heard Doctor Dewey speak of
            Mr. Brown as a copyist of Claude, but he has no need to
            copy Claude or any other painter; he copies nature with
            rare felicity and in a manner peculiar to himself, which
            stamps him as a man of genius beyond all doubt or cavil.
            But those who would enjoy these pictures must look at
            them with their hearts and thoughts full of nature, and not
            with a view to compare them with the works of other artists.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>There is one thing to regret about these paintings, that
            they should not have fallen into the hands of the Art Union,
            instead of private individuals. The public would do well
            to use and examine them before they are removed.
         </p>
         
         <p>In our remarks upon the exhibition we attributed to Mr. Casilear
            by some unaccountable dip of the pen, a small landscape in the rooms
            of the Art Union, which was painted by Mr. Durand.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p26">
         <div class="biblTitle">Miscellany</div>
         <div class="biblPage">333</div>
         <div class="head">MISCELLANY.</div>
         
         <p>Americans in Europe.—General Tom Thumb is in Paris,
            where he attracts more attention than any ono of his countrymen
            has done since the time of Doctor Franklin. One of the most unmistakable signs of his popularity is the counterfeiting his name
            and person by the Theatre des Varietes. But the General’s father
            procured an injunction upon the counterfeit dwarf, and the great
            original has all to himself in Paris.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss Cushman is still performing in London, where she is a
            ioness, although she never attained to that dignity at home. Mr.
            Forrest has been at the provinces, where he appears to have been
            well received.
         </p>
         
         <p>Professor Risley, with the young professors, has been delighting
            the Russians, in St. Petersburg and Moscow. A Mr. C. Russell,
            probably a Pennsylvanian, has been doing the people in small
            English towns, by advertising Concerts, which never came off, and
            then walking off with the money. Mr. Carter the Lion-tamer, has
            been a long while creating a sensation in Europe. Mr. Hackett is
            playing Jonathan Wildfire in Ireland.
         </p>
         
         <p>A mental calculator, in the shape of a boy six years and a half
            old, had been presented to the French Institute, by the distinguished savan, M. Arago.
         </p>
         
         <p>A hew Waterloo Dispatch.—Apropos to the Duke of Wellington’s dispatches. The captain [Allen] of the new packet ship
            Waterloo of this port, has written home a letter to Mr. Kermick,
            the agent of his ship, which strikes us a better example of a dispatch than any contained in the great English captain. We doubt
            whether a neater or better written dispatch came from the original Waterloo after the great fight.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Liverpool, May 4, 1845.</div>
         
         <p>We arrived safe at this port on the first instant, in a passage of
            nineteen and a half days. For three days after leaving New York we
            had fine and fair breezes. On the morning of the fourth day, at 9 A.M.
            our fore-topmast broke short off in the sheave hole, bringing the whole
            mass of sails, rigging, spars, &amp;c. supported by it, together with the
            main-topgallantmast, and all above it, down on deck. You may judge
            our condition, as we had the main-royal and fore-topmast steering,
            sails set at the time. Fortunately, the weather was fine and a smooth
            sea, so that we were enabled to save everything without cutting a
            rope. I cannot account for the topmast’s breaking off. I was on deck
            at the time, and saw it go; otherwise I could not have believed but
            that it was done in a squall. It was fortunate our spare topmast was
            sheaved and ready for use, as the iron sheave went overboard when
            the mast fell. This has been the hardest job I have ever experienced
            at sea, as from the length of the top-foremast I had to get down the
            fore-yard, and almost strip the foremast to get the new topmast up.
            We had to make new cross-trees. It was two days before we could
            get sail on the foremast, and in three days we were completely rigged
            again. It detained us considerably, as the wind came ahead and we
            could make but poor progress without forward sail. From long. 60
            to long. 30, we had winds east and northeast; the last five days gave
            us a fine run. The Waterloo is a fast ship. I am highly pleased with
            her: she has been much admired in Liverpool. Our passengers were
            delighted with their passage. Having ample time for it, I will copper the vessel here.
         </p>
         
         <p>Professor Hackley, of Columbia College, delivered a lecture on
            Tuesday evening last, in the chapel of the college, foot of Park place,
            on Astronomical science, but with particular reference to the establishment of an Observatory in the city.
         </p>
         
         <p>Professor Bush, on Thursday evening, delivered a lecture at the
            Stuyvesanl Institute on the Human Soul, physiologically and theologically considered, in which he adduced a large array of proof, both
            from reason and scripture, that the proper idea of the soul includes
            that of a spiritual body, and that consequently the prevalent theory
            of the future resuscitation of the material body is entirely baseless
            and delusive.
         </p>
         
         <p>Professor George Tucker has resigned his chair as professor of
            Moral Philosophy in the Virginia University, the vacancy to be filled
            on the first of July.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Franking Privilege.—During the discussion in favor of
            abolishing the franking privilege, it was contended that members of
            Congress had franked their shirts home to be washed. The romance
            created a smile, but it seems that something like it has actually occurred. A Mr. Beach, of Georgia, in debate, charged Mr. Giddings
            of Ohio, with having franked “a calico frock” marked Pub. Doc. It
            turns out to have been E. D. Potter, who franked home the frock.
            The postmaster says it was McNulty’s frank, but the package was
            directed to Mrs. E.’D. Potter, and at the next mail some more drygoods were franked in the same manner. It was time to end this
            abuse of the franking privilege.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Park Theatre.—The French company appear here early in June
            We copy a list of its members from the Courier des Etats Unis.
         </p>
         
         <p>Prima donna, M'lle Calve, who has left here such a brilliant recollection in the popular mind. Madame Canini, second prima donna,
            who disputes the palm with M’lle Calve, for talent and grace.
            Madame Coeuriot, duenna, who is considered by the Louisiana papers
            as far beyond Madame Lecourt, whose place she lakes, although
            Madame Lecourt was an excellent actress. M’lle Maria and Eugenie,
            and Madames Richer et Mathiew, all tour of whom are known to the
            public. The male part of the company consists of M. Amand, first
            tenor at the grand opera, who possesses, they say, a first rate voice.
            M. Coeuriot, first tenor of the comic opera,—Garry, barytone. Douvrv.
            first bass. Montassier, first youth, of whom every body speaks well;
            and M. M. Reecher, Dessonville and Mathiew, whom we know already.
         </p>
         
         <p>The orchestra will have M. Eugene Prevot for director, a composer
            of great talent, who will be accompanied by six of the most distinguished musicians of the New Orleans theatre. This orchestra will
            be completed by the New York artists, whose attention is called to
            the advertisement in the u Courrier.” The company intend to perform the best operas of the French repertoire, among which they mention in advance, Robert le Diable, the Hugenots, the Queen of Cyprus,
            the Favorite, and La Juive, for which the managers have already
            gone to considerable expense. It will be seen the programme is a
            brilliant one.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Sea Serpent,—The Albany Citizen says that there are the remains of a wonderful animal in that city. It is the petrified vertebra
            of a monster called by the Naturalists Zuyglycon—a creature which
            must have been half alligator and half whale. It was discovered embedded in a chalk formation on the banks of the Alabama river, and
            was boxed up and sent to Professor Emmons of that city. The vertebra, extending from a portion of the head to the tip of the tail, is
            eighty feet in length as it lies upon the floor. The creature must have
            been, in life, from ninety to one hundred feet long.
         </p>
         
         <p>The St. Louis Reveille announces a new book, entitled "The Theatrical Apprenticeship of Sol. Smith,” by the worthy of that ilk. The
            work is said to be nearly ready for the press, and is lull of instruction
            and fun as far as it has been done.
         </p>
         
         <p>T. D. McGee, editor of the Boston Pilot, is about to retain to Ireland, to become connected with a leading repeal press there, the Nation. On Tuesday evening, a company of his friends gave him a splendid complimentary supper at the Stackpole House.</p>
         
         <p>A newspaper will shortly be started in the Choctaw nation, to be
            conducted by a native editor.
         </p>
         
         <p>" Silvius, or the Roman Odd Fellow,” a new play by A. J. H. Duganne, was so murdered by the Walnut street, Philadelphia, actors,
            that the author rushed out of the theatre in despair.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Hon. Benjamin F. Butler is to deliver the annual address before the Belles Letters Society of Dickinson College, on the 9th
            day of July next, being the day preceding the commencement.
            Ralph W. Emerson is to deliver the annual address at the commencement at the Wesleyan University in August.
         </p>
         
         <p>Liabilities or an Editor.—Lord Denman has laid down the
            law recently, that an editor has no right to insert any paragraph
            before he has ascertained “that the assertion made in it is absloutely true.” So then, in the case of the late discoveries made by the
            Earl of Rosse’s telescope, an editor ought to have proceeded to the
            different planets mentioned before he inserted any statement respecting them. According to Lord Denman, the Man in the Moon
            and Orion would both recover swinging damages from almost every
            editor in the United Kingdom for the reflections cast by the Earl’s
            telescope on their characters as planets.—Punch.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p22">
         <div class="biblTitle">Works Issued in London and Edinburgh</div>
         <div class="biblPage">334</div>
         <div class="head">WORKS ISSUED IN LONDON AND EDINBURGH,</div>
         
         <div class="ab">BETWEEN THE 14TH AND 30TH APRIL.</div>
         
         <p>Abercrombie: Essays and Facts. 18mo. pp. 318. New edition, pp. 604.</p>
         
         <p>Always Happy. Written for children. By a mother.</p>
         
         <p>Arthur. The Potato Problem Solved—or the cause of disease in the pota-
            to pointed out.
         </p>
         
         <p>Bain. AEra Astroea; or the Age of Justice. An Ode.</p>
         
         <p>Balburnie. The Philosophy of the Water Cure. pp. 426.</p>
         
         <p>Bechstein. Natural History of Cage Birds, np. 320.</p>
         
         <p>Bernays. Manual of Family Prayers and Meditations.</p>
         
         <p>Bickersleth. Signs of the Times in the East a Warning to the West,
            pp. 460.
         </p>
         
         <p>Bioxam. Principles of Gothic Ecclesiastical Architecture.</p>
         
         <p>Boys E. G. Family Sermons, short, plain and practical.</p>
         
         <p>Breach of Promise, The—A novel. By the author of the Jilt.</p>
         
         <p>Brougham, Lord. Lives of Men of Letters, and Science of the time of
            Geo. 111.
         </p>
         
         <p>Budge. Practical Miner** Guide. 8vo., pp. 324.</p>
         
         <p>Brock, General. Life and Correspondence. Edited by F. B. Tupper, Esq.</p>
         
         <p>Cameron. Personal Adventures and Excursions in Georgia, Circassia and
            Russia. 2 vols., pp. 690.
         </p>
         
         <p>Chatterton, Lady. Lost Happiness, or the Effects of a Lie. A novel.</p>
         
         <p>Clark, W. G. Cottage Prayer Book and Helps to Devotion.</p>
         
         <p>Coghlan. Handbook for Central Europe. A guide for tourists through
            Belgium, Holland, Germany, France, &amp;c.
         </p>
         
         <p>Coghlan. Handbook for travellers thro' Italy.</p>
         
         <p>Connon, C. W. System of English Grammar.</p>
         
         
         <p>Cotton, H. The Succession of the Prelates and Members of the Cathedral
            Bodies in Ireland.
         </p>
         
         <p>Dinneford, C. Family Medicine Directory.</p>
         
         <p>Distinction, a Tale. By the author of “The Baroness.” 12mo. pp. 142.</p>
         
         <p>Encyclopedia Metropolitana. Part 59 and conclusion.</p>
         
         <p>Fistiana, or the Oracle of the Ring. 18mo., pp. 174.</p>
         
         <p>Gilbert, C. M. Treatise on the special diseases of the skin.</p>
         
         <p>Glossary of Forms used in Grecian, Roman, Italian and Gothic Architec-
            ture.
         </p>
         
         <p>Grover, Capt. The Bokhara Victims, pp. 316.</p>
         
         <p>Hahn-Hahn. Letters from the Orient, or Travels in Turkey, the Holy
            Land, Egyyt, &amp;c. By Ida, Countess Hahn-Hahn.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hamilton, J. Life in Earnest. Six Lectures on Christian Activity and Ardour. pp. 152. Is. 6d.</p>
         
         <p>Hook, W. F. An Ecclesiastical Biography, containing the lives of Ancient
            Fathers and Modern Divines.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hubbert; or the Orphans of St. Madeline, a legend of the Vaudois. By a
            clergyman’s daughter.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hughes, H. Female Characters of Holy Writ.</p>
         
         <p>Jackson, E. Practical Companion to the Work Table.</p>
         
         <p>Jervis, Rev. J. J. W. Five Discourses on the Book of Genesis.</p>
         
         <p>John Ronge. The Holy Coat of Treves and the New German-Catholic
            Church.
         </p>
         
         <p>Johnson, G. W. The Principles of Practical Gardening.</p>
         
         <p>Jonathan Sharp: or the Adventures of a Kentuckian.</p>
         
         <p>Jones, W. The Dissenter’s Plea for his Non-Conformity.</p>
         
         <p>Jones, W. The Gardener’s Receipt Book: containing methods for des-
            troying all kinds of vermin.
         </p>
         
         <p>Knight’s Weekly Volume. Vol. 43, The Dutch in the Medway. Vol. 44,
            The History of the Dog.
         </p>
         
         <p>Lane, W. System of Practical Arithmetic.</p>
         
         <p>Lives of the English Saints. Part 2.</p>
         
         <p>Marks, R. Sermons: with Prayers for Families and Sick Rooms.</p>
         
         <p>Mary Aston; or the Events of a Year. “A moral tale, though gay.”</p>
         
         <p>Maxwell, W. H. History of the Irish Rebellion of 1798, and the Insurrection of 1803.</p>
         
         <p>Melvill, H. Sermons on the Less Prominent Facts and References in Sacred History.</p>
         
         <p>Monti, V. The Death of Basseville. A poem.</p>
         
         <p>Neale, E. W. Essay on the Laws relating to Sundays and Hollidays, and
            of the Vacating of the Courts.
         </p>
         
         <p>Letters from the Orient.</p>
         
         <p>Paley, F. A. Manual of Gothic Mouldings, 16 plates.</p>
         
         <p>Pearson, E. Brief Memoir of the Life, Writings and Correspondence of
            the Rev. E. Pearson.
         </p>
         
         <p>Peel, Sir R., the Greatest Radical of the age, and the Best Friend of
            O’Connell.
         </p>
         
         <p>Petrie, G. Ecclesiastical Architecture of Ireland.</p>
         
         <p>Reports of the Committee of the Board of Trade, on the various railways
            now projected and in progress.
         </p>
         
         <p>Romer, F. The Philosophy of the Human Voice.</p>
         
         <p>Smyth, W. Evidences of Christianity.</p>
         
         <p>French. Memoir of the Hon. and Rev. Power L. P. French, Archishop of
            Tuam.
         </p>
         
         <p>Sweet. Concise Precedents in Conveyancing.</p>
         
         <p>Thiers. History of the Consulate and Empire under Napoleon. Vol. 3.</p>
         
         <p>Vanherman. Every man his own House Painter and Colorman. 12mo.
            PP- 124.
         </p>
         
         <p>Violina, a Miniature Romance. By Frederic Baron de la Motte Fouque.</p>
         
         <div class="ab">NEW WORKS FORTHCOMING FROM THE LONDON PRESS.</div>
         
         <p>***Among numerous other works which are noticed to appear in London,
            during the present month of May, we find the following:
         </p>
         
         <p>The Hope of the Apostolic Church, or the Duties and Privileges of Christians in Connection with the Second Advent: being lectures in Lent,
            1845, by 12 clergymen of the Church of England. Among these are
            Messrs. Bickersteth, Marsh, Dibdin, &amp;c.
         </p>
         
         <p>Sybil, or the Two Nations. By D’lsraeLi.</p>
         
         <p>Bishop Thirlwall’s History of Greece, revised throughout.</p>
         
         <p>The Ascent of Mount Ararat, achieved for the first time. By Professor
            Parrot. Being one of the volumes of Cooley’s “World Surveyed.”
         </p>
         
         <p>The Mission, or Scenes in Africa. By Capt. Maryatt.</p>
         
         <p>Memoirs of John Constable, Esq. By C. R. Leslie, R. A.</p>
         
         <p>Dr. Wolf’s Narrative of his Mission to Bokhara, (preparing for early publication.)</p>
         
         <p>Outlines of Organic Chemistry, for the use of students. By William Gregory, M. D.</p>
         
         <p>Flowers of the Matin and Even Song. By Mary Roberts.</p>
         
         <p>Temper and Temperament. By Mrs. Ellis.</p>
         
         <div class="ab">BY HARPER AND BROTHERS.</div>
         
         <p>Memoirs of Celebrated Statesmen of the English Commonwealth. By
            John Forester. With additions by the Rev. J. O. Charles, of Boston.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hallam. Constitutional History of England from the accession of Henry
            VII to the death of George II.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mackenzie. Life of Commodore John Paul Jones.</p>
         
         <p>Burton. Anatomy of Melancholy.</p>
         
         <p>Dick. Practical Astronomy. By the author of “Celestial Scenery” and
            “Improvement of Society.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Mrs. Sherwood. The Life of John Martin, a sequel to Henry Milner.</p>
         
         <p>G. P. R. James. The Smuggler, a novel.</p>
         
         <p>Eugene Sue. De Kohah, or the Court Conspirator.</p>
         
         <p>Gardner, D. P. The Farmer’s Dictionary.</p>
         
         <p>Liddell and Scott. New Greek and English Lexicon: edited by H. Drialer, A. M., and Professor Anthon.</p>
         
         <p>Beecher, Miss. Treatise on Domestic Economy.</p>
         
         <p>Beecher, Miss. The Duty of American Women to their Country.</p>
         
         <p>Beecher, Miss. The American Housekeeper’s Receipt Book.</p>
         
         <p>Marco Polo. Travels and Noyages of Marco Polo. With notes by Hugh
            Murray, Esq.
         </p>
         
         <p>Anthon. Eclogues and Georgies of Virgil. With English notes.</p>
         
         <p>Anthon; The Anabasis of Xenophon. With English notes.</p>
         
         <p>Dr. Galt. A New Treatise on Insanity.</p>
         
         <p>Anthon. A Key to Latin Versification.</p>
         
         <p>Lever. The Nevilles of Garretstown.</p>
         
         <p>Life of the Rev. Dr. Proudfit. By the Rev. Dr. Forsyth.
            Aids to Composition, &amp;c. By R. G. Parker.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p23">
         <div class="biblTitle">Notice to Correspondents</div>
         <div class="biblPage">334</div>
         <p>Notice to Correspondents.—The author of “Night, a Poem,” will
            find a notice of his book in one of our back numbers, we will give
            it a review of greater length if he should desire it.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">335</div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">MANESCA’S ORAL SYSTEM OF TEACHING</div>
            
            <p>THE FRENCH LANGUAGE, pursued by his daughter, Madame
               Durand, either in class or private lessons, to Ladies and Gentlemen,
               at No. 35 Walker street.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Family books.</div>
            <div class="ab">—new amd important
               
               <br></br>WORKS, designed especially for Families.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">1.	The Pictorial Sunday Book. By John Kitts, D.D. A very hand-
               
               <br></br>some volume, folio, with many hundred engravings  -  $7 00
               
               <br></br>2.	Old England: a Pictorial Museum of Regal, Ecclesiastical,
               
               <br></br>Baronial, and Popular Antiquities. Vol. 1, large folio, with
               
               <br></br>many hundred fine engravings  -  -  -  -  -  7	00
               
               <br></br>3.	The Pictorial Museum of Animated Nature. 2 vols. large
               
               <br></br>folio, with many hundred fine engravings  -  -  - 	12 00
               
               <br></br>4.	Pictorial History of England. 8 very large vols., with many
               
               <br></br>hundred engravings  -  -  -  -  -  -  -   27	00
               
               <br></br>5.	Pictorial History of Palestine. 2 very large vols. with many
               
               <br></br>hundred engravings  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  8	00
               
               <br></br>6.	Chambers’ Cyclopaedia of English Literature. 2 large vols.
               
               <br></br>octavo  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  6 00
               
               <br></br>7.	Chambers’ Information for the People. 2 large vols. 8vo 	6 00
               
               <br></br>8.	Chambers’ Tracts of Useful Information. Vol. 1, with en-
               
               <br></br>gravings -	-  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  -  50
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Imported and for sale by	       WILEY &amp; PUTNAM,
               
               <br></br>may24	                         161 Broadway.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE PURCHASE OF BOOKS
               FOR AMERICA.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Agents to the Library of Congress,
               
               <br></br>The New York Society Library,
               
               <br></br>The Albany Institute,
               
               <br></br>The Boston Athenaeum, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>12 Red Lion Square, London.
               
               <br></br>12 Rue Pot do Fer, Paris.
            </div>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich respectfully informs his friends and fellow-citizens that he has
               formed an establishment in Paris, in connexion with his old establishment in Red
               Lion square, for the purpose of furnishing BOOKS published on the continent
               without the heavy expense attending their transmission through England.
               Each of these establishments will be conducted by one of his sons, under his
               own general superintendence. This new arrangement, he trusts, will prove of
               signal advantage to his correspondents, and no exertions will be wanting to execute their orders on the most advantageous terms. Orders may be sent through,
               and small sums paid to Messrs. Goodhue &amp; Co. of New York. Two and a half
               per cent, will be allowed to all those who make a remittance with their orders.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich, having made Bibliography his special study for forty years, possesses a knowledge of books and editions not often to be met with, and will be
               happy to give any advice and information respecting the formation of Libraries
               or Collections of Books in any particular branch of literature or science. For
               information in regard to his efficiency, he begs to refer to Messrs. Prescott,
               Tichnor, Sparks, Irving, and other literary characters in the United States, to
               whom he is known. Intending to devote the remainder of his life to literary
               pursuits, his greatest pleasure will arise from sending rare and valuable books
               to his own country; and he trusts to live long enough to see in the United States
               a Library which may bear a comparison with the most celebrated in Europe. If
               he can live to say, “I also assisted in its formation,” his most ardent wishes
               will be gratified.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich has in the press—Bibliotheca Americana Nova: a Catalogue of
               Books relating to America, including Voyages to the South Seas and round the
               World: Part III. from 1831 to 1845, with supplement and index completing the
               work.
            </p>
            
            <p>He has also nearly ready for the press, Bibliotheca Americana vetus: a
               Catalogue of Books relating to America from the Discovery to the year 1700;
               with notes and observations: in one volume, 8vo., of about 400 pages.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich has also nearly ready, a reprint from Mevenot—Collection of Father
               Marquette's account of the discovery of the Mississippi, entitled, "Decouverte
               de quelques Parp et Nations de l'Amerique Septentrionale.” Only 125 copies
               are printed, which will be distributed among Mr. Rich’s friends and correspondents.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rich has also purchased the remaining copies of the part relating to
               America of L’Art de Verifier les Dates: of which ten volumes in octavo, by
               D. B. Warden, Esq., arc printed, and two volumes more, completing the work,
               will be published in the course of the present year.
            </p>
            
            <p>Price of the ten volumes published - - - - - - 40 francs</p>
            
            <p>Complete sets of the Art de Verifier les Dates, in 44 vols. 8vo. - 160 francs
               instead of 308, the original price.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Paris, May 1, 1845.			           	may24</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">REJOICINGS! HOLIDAYS!! BIRTHDAYS!!!</div>
            
            <div class="head">CAREY’S MONTGOLFIERS</div>
            <div class="ab"> or Fire Balloons and
               
               <br></br>Air Balloons may be obtained from stationers and fancy stores in New
               
               <br></br>York, on and after the 20th of May, price $2 00 and upward— a list of which
               
               <br></br>will be published on that date. Directions upon each box.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">J. B. CAREY &amp; CO. 323 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>With Pyrotechnists arrangements can be made.	    my17
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
            
            <p>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANOFORTE,
               ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street, where his terms for
               giving instruction can be ascertained.
            </p>          
            <div class="ab">my 17</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">TITIAN’S VENUS.</div>
            
            <p>THIS TRULY BEAUTIFUL PRODUCTION, A
               repetition of the great picture in the Florentine Gallery is now on exhibition at 449 Broadway, an undoubted work of this never-to-be-excelled
               master in the art of coloring.
            </p>
            
            <p>Open during day and evening. Admittance 25 cts. Season tickets, 50
               cents.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BOARD IN BROOKLYN.</div>
            <p>—A Single Gentleman,
               who is partial to Chess and Music, can be provided with a furnished
               room, and breakfast and tea, in a private family, residing near Fulton street,
               Brooklyn, in one of its most pleasant streets.
            </p>
            
            <p>Address W. S. Office of Broadway Journal: or enquire at said office.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES.</div>
            <p>—A. H. GALE &amp; CO.’S WARE-
               Rooms, No. 289 Broadway—Manufactory Third Avenue, corner of 13th
               street.
            </p>
            
            <p>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assortment of
               Rosewood and Mahogany Piano-Fortes, with from six to seven octaves, embracing ever variety of patterns, made in their well known substantial manner, under their immediate and personal superintendence, by skillful and
               experienced mechanics, from the best seasoned materials.
            </p>
            
            <p>These instruments embrace many important improvements, which will recommend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of perfection, with
               the best French grand action, warranted in every respect by the manufacturer.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to
               Duhois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the latest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most superior
               quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone,
               Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano
               Fortes aways on hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their
               numerous friends, and to the public, would, at the same time, call atten-
               tton to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, in
               elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of the
               business, have been enabled to add several important improvements to the
               action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp;: DUNHAM.
               
               <br></br>361 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>Manufactory 13th St., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
               
               <br></br>N. B.—A good second-hand Piano Forte for sale.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as iron frames,
               &amp;C with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of
               23 years experience in the business.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">F. RILEY &amp; CO.,</div>
            <p>No. 297 Broadway, (between
               Reade and Duane streets,) New York, Publishers of Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition to their
               own catalogue, (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep on hand
               he publications of all the principal Music houses. They are erecting a large
               Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes of a superior quality,
               will be constantly kept on hand.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO - FORTES.</div>
            <p>—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to the elegant and varied aesortment he now has at his Old Establishment, Corner of
               Cottage-place and Bleeckcr Street, which he will sell at prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twenty
               years. and for a large portion of that time manufacturer for two of the largest Music Stores in this city, feels warranted in saying that his instruments
               will bear a favorable comparison with those of the best makers in this country or Europe, and that they contain all the real improvements of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and Repaired</p>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, April 23d. 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER,
               
               <br></br>88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.
               
               <br></br>A large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
               
               <br></br>TERMS MODERATE.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BERTINI'S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
               work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method
               the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies, are
               given in such PROGRESSIVE order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
               carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
               otherwise, are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
               has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,
               and it is only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will be en
               abled to Read music with facility, and at the same time become good musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the rudments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each lesson
               is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest reccommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of Bertini’s Method
               over all others yet published in this country, most of them having used the
               foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
               names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Boston.	                  New York.
               
               <br></br>Messrs. G. J. Webb.	      Messrs. H. C. Timm.
               
               <br></br>J.G Maedar.	              W. Alpers.
               
               <br></br>H.T. Hach.	              U. C. Hill.
               
               <br></br>E. L. White.	            F. H. Brown.
               
               <br></br>David Paine.	           Philadelphia.
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek.	                B. C. Cross.
               
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.	            Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>         Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
               American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Wash
               ington street, Boston.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MR. AND MRS. KIRKLAND’S
               SCHOOL FOR YOUNG LADIES,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 255 Greene Street,
               
               <br></br>One door above Waverly Place, New York.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS School differs essentially from most others in
               this city, in one particular: the number admitted is so limited that each
               scholar receives the personal attention and instruction of the principals.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Kirkland resided some years in Europe for the express purpose of
               qualifying himself as an instructor.
            </p>
            
            <p>The French language is taught by an approved master, a native of France;
               and every facility is afforded for practice, both in the school and in the family.
            </p>
            
            <p>The plan of instruction embraces three divisions. The Initiatory Course includes Grammar, Geography, American History, Writing and Arithmetic,
               with Composition. Reading aloud, Spelling and Definition, form part of the
               daily exercises of the whole school.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Second continues the above-named studies, with the addition of Ancient and Modern History and the French Language.</p>
            
            <p>In the higher or Aesthetic course all the usual branches of a thorough English course of education are included, with French, German, Latin and
               Greek, according to the wish of the parent and the capacity of the scholar.
            </p>
            
            <p>Pupils in this course pay particular attention to Poetry, to the art of Composition, and to the Philosophy of History. Moral Philosophy is taught from
               Dymond, as abridged and prepared for schools by Mrs. Kirkland. Lectures
               on various subjects are delivered by Mr. and Mrs. Kirkland, and others; and
               the general course of study is advanced and rendered interesting by copious
               Illustrations from French and English Literature.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS.
               
               <br></br>Primary Course,  -      -      -    	$12 50 Per Quarter.
               
               <br></br>Second “(including French, &amp;c.)  	18 00	       “
               
               <br></br>Third, or highest course,   -   -     25 00	       "
               
               <br></br>Music—Piano Forte,	-	   -	   -      15 00      	“
               
               <br></br>“     Singing,     -	   -	   -	    15 00     	“
               
               <br></br>Drawing,	   -   	 -	    -	   -       10 00	      "
               
               <br></br>Dancing,     -	   -	    -    -       12 00	    "
               
               <br></br>For Board, (payable Quarterly in advance,) $175 per Annum. 
            </div>
            
            <p>Board during vacations at the same rate.</p>
            
            <p>The young ladies are required to bring towels, spoons, fork and napkin
               ring—every article fully marked,
            </p>
            
            <p>Washing $7 50 per Quarter.</p>
            
            <p>No Extras—whether for fuel, use of instruments, or any thing not here
               specified.
            </p>
            
            <p>Pupils received at any time, and charged in proportion only.</p>
            
            <p>References to parents and guardians given if desired.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">SHEPARD</div>
            
            <p>IS SELLING BOOKS AND STATIONARY AS
               cheap as ever.
            </p>
            
            <p>He has added a large assortment of Books bought at very low prices at
               the late trade sale.
            </p>
            
            <p>Niebuhr’s Rome, just published at $5, he will sell far below that price.</p>
            
            <p>Encyclopedia Americana, in 13 vols., he will sell low enough.</p>
            
            <p>He has also added a beautiful assortment of Gold Pencils—some of which
               he will sell as low as $1,87 1-2 cents, warranted.
            </p>
            
            <p>Another lot of that beautiful Letter Paper at $1,50 per ream—well worth
               $2,25.
            </p>
            
            <p>Please call and see if you cannot buy to suit you at
               SHEPARD’S, 101 Broadway,
               opposite John street.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">UNITED STATES’ EXPLORING EXPEDITION.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">CHEAP EDITION.</div>
            
            <p>NARRATIVE OF THE U. S. EXPLORING EXPEDITION, during the years 1838, 39, 40, 41, 42. By Charles Wilkes,
               U. S. Navy, Commander of the Expedition. With Illustrations and Maps. In
               Five Volumes. Vol. 1, $2 00.
            </p>
            
            <p>This edition contains precisely the same type, page, and reading
               matter, as the one in imperial octavo; the difference between them being in
               the quality and size of the paper, and the omission of the steel plates, and
               some of the maps. The number of wood illustrations in this edition is nearly three hundred. A volume will be published about every two weeks, unlil the whole work shall be completed. For sale by
               WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">NOW READY, (Gratis,) </div>
            <div class="head">WILEY &amp; PUTNAM’S</div>
            
            <div class="ab">LITERARY NEWS-LETTER FOR MAY, containing—</div>
            
            <div class="ab">1.	—Foreign Literary Intelligence.
               
               <br></br>2.	—American Literary Intelligence.
               
               <br></br>3.	—Important English Works in press.
               
               <br></br>4.	—List of new English Works just published.
               
               <br></br>5.	—New American Works published in April.
               
               <br></br>6.	—Works recently imported, with the prices.
               
               <br></br>7.	—W. &amp; P.’s recent Publications, with Critical Notices.
               
               <br></br>8.	—Books which are Books: Library of Choice Reading.
               
               <br></br>9.	—The United States’ Exploring Expedition,
               
               <br></br>WILEY &amp;: PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </div>
            
            <p>This News-Letter will be distributed gratuitously to all who will
               leave their address with the publishers. Single copies of English books imported to order per steamer or packet.
            </p>	
            <div class="ab">my 10</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.</div>
            
            <p>The first Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for the
               best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </p>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
               NO. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            </p>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of one hour each.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen
               and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale “Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Pr ce Five Dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
           
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE
               SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published Monthly at Richmond, Va.; price Five Dollars per Year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835,
               has a large subscription list among the elite of the Southern Aristocracy,
               and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the “Broadway Journal, 135 Nassau st.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">IMPORTANT. WORKS FOR PUBLIC LIBRARIES.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">FOR SALE BY
               
               <br></br>BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, NEW YORK.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE TRANSACTIONS OF THE ROYAL SOCIETY OF LONDON, or Philosophical Transactions, from the
               commencement, in 1665 to 1800. By Drs. Hutton and Shaw:
               in 18 vols. 4 to., and from 1600 to 1835, in 36 vols., together
               54 vols. royal, 4 to. uniformly bound in half calf.	$250 00
            </p>
            
            <p>THE ARCHAEOLEGIA; or Miscellaneous Tracts, relating to
               Antiquity, by the Society of Antiquaries of Sweden, complete
               from the beginning in 1770 to 1843, in 30 vols. uniformly
               bound in half russia.		225 00
            </p>
            
            <p>THE DELPHIN EDITION OF THE LATIN CLASSICS: by
               Valpy, with various notes, the best edition, (published at £150
               sterling) m 142 vols. 8 vo. boards.	200 00
            </p>
            
            <p>PINKERTONS' COLLECTIONS OF VOYAGES AND TRAVELS in various parts of the world, 17 large vols., 4 to. half
               bound in calf.	 70 00
            </p>
            
            <p>BAYLE'S GREAT HISTORICAL AND CRITICAL DICTIONARY; by Des Maizeaux, best edition, 5 vols. folio, bound in
               calf. 	30 	00
            </p>
            
            <p>ANDERSONS’ BRITISH POETS; from Chaucer to Warton; 14
               vols. royal 8 vo. bound in calf extra. 	40 00
            </p>
            
            <p>COLONEL VYSE'S ACCOUNT OF OPERATIONS CARRIED
               ON IN EXPLORING THE PYRAMIDS OF EGYPT; with
               numerous plates; 3 vols. 4 to.	  14 00
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DESIGNING AND ENGRAVING</div>
            
            <div class="ab">ON WOOD.</div>
            
            <p>SAMUEL E. BROWN, 70 Nassau Street, Corner of
               John, New York.
            </p>
            
            <p>Portraits, Views of Buildings, Scenery, Original Designs, &amp;c. &amp;c. furnished
               at this establishment.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">(new invention.)</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the Conservatorie at
               
               <br></br>Paris, and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
            </div>
            
            <p>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the “BOehm
               Flute,” 110 Fulton St. N. Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of
               rec cities the above Important Invention, which has been so enthusiastically
               haeived and generally used by the most distinguished European Artists, feels
               happy in being able to place before them the following testimonial to its
               merits, signed by two of the most distinguished of our resident Artists.
            </p>
            
            <p>We hereby certify to the the excellence of Boehm Flute as manufactured
               by Mr. J.D. Larrabee; to the beauty of its tone, the perfection of its tune,
               and the simplicity of its fingering, which renders a brilliant execution
               comparatively easy.
            </p>
            
            <p>Philip Ernst (who has already introduced it
               successfully among his pupils.
            </p>
            
            <p>John A. Kyle, Principal Flute of the Philharmonic Society and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm Flute,
               41 Forsyth street, New York.
            </p>
            
            <p>Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory, 110
               Fulton st. and judge for themselves.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
               The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
               professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, anil beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo.        Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
               
               <br></br>Joshua Herrick, Me.	               John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               
               <br></br>James Irvin, Pa.	                 J. Thompson, Miss.
               
               <br></br>Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p24">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">336</div>
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co., ....	Boston, Mass.
            Colon &amp; Adriance,	... Philadelphia, Pa.
            R. G. H. Huntington, ... Hartford, Ct.
            George Jones,	...	Albany,N, Y.
            Thomas H. Pease, ... New Haven, Ct.
            L. Willard, ......	Troy.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         <div class="biblTitle">John Douglas</div>
         <div class="biblPage">336</div>
         <p>John Douglas, Printer, 106 Fulton Street.</p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>