<div>
   <div class="front">
          <div>
         <div class="head">&gt;THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
            <div class="ab">VOL. 1.
              NEW YORK, SATURDAY, MAY 31, 1845.	NO. 22.</div>
            <div class="ab">Three Dollars per Annum.	Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.</div>
         <div class="ab">C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.</div>
         <div class="ab">Published at 135 Nassau St. By JOHN BISCO.</div>
          </div>
        </div>
   <div class="body">
       
                <br/>
      <div class="columnbreak"/>
      <div>
        <div>
            <div class="head">THE NORTH AND THE SOUTH.</div>
            <p>The South has just triumphed on northern soil. The <br/>mare Peytona beat the mare
            Fashion nearly half a neck’s <br/>length in a race of two heats. This is a glorious
            victory for <br/>the South, and being the first of the kind that she has <br/>won, must
            produce an immense sensation among the “ do- <br/>mestic institutions.” There
            will be a tremendous rustling <br/>of the palmettos. In all trials of skill between the
            South <br/>and the North, the North has heretofore come off conqueror ; <br/>Eclipse and
            Henry, Webster and Hayne, Fashion and Boston. <br/>But now the tide has turned, and
            success is flowing from <br/>north of Mason and Dixon’s Line towards Cottondom. First
            <br/>the chivalry of the palmetto State triumphed over old Mr. <br/>Hoar and his young
            daughter, then Peytona beat Fashion, <br/>and now we perceive that Mr. Simms is
            fluttering the Vol- <br/>scians in Cambridge ; having taken the Ursa Major of
            lite- <br/>rary Yankeedom by the ears, in his last magazine. We have <br/>not
            much faith in the “ parochial review,”as some of our lite- <br/>rary people
            irreverently call the North American, ourselves, <br/>particularly since it passed into
            the hands of its present keep- <br/>er, and we are not disposed to regard Mr.
            Simms’ attack with <br/>much dismay, for if the “conservative” North American <br/>were
            altogether extinguished, we doubt whether its loss <br/>would have any sensible, or,
            rather, perceptible effect upon <br/>the literature or the morals of the nation. As it
            is not pro- <br/>bable that many of our readers are readers of the Southern
            <br/>Magazine, we will extract a part of Mr. Simms’ article, that <br/>they may see in
            what estimation the North American is <br/>held at the South.</p>
            <p/>
            <p>A CIRCULAR, recently issued by the publishers of the North <br/>American Review,
            somewhat earnestly insists upon the claims of <br/>this “ veteran” periodical to the
            favor of the public, in “ having <br/>done its part in representing the taste, science
            and literature of the <br/>country, for a period of nearly thirty years.” It is
            certainly matter <br/>of surprise that it should become necessary for a periodical,
            situated <br/>in the very heart of a region equally rich and populous, to send
            <br/>forth a paper which dwells, in language of doubtful delicacy, upon <br/>its claims
            to public favor, in order to obtain if,—particularly, too, <br/>when you shall not meet
            a man in the whole country who is not <br/>willing to attest the perfect fidelity of
            this work to a people equally <br/>ambitious of ascendancy and needing a champion. That
            the <br/>“North American Review” has worked religiously for New Eng- <br/>land, her sons, her institutions, her claims of every sort, there is no <br/>manner of
            question. Whatever doubts we may entertain of the <br/>American character of this
            periodical, of its catholic tendency, and <br/>its equal regard to the claims of the
            nation, as a whole, we can <br/>have none, and none have ever been felt or expressed, of
            its per- <br/>fect devotedness to the region from which it more immediately is- <br/>sues. None can deny the exclusive and jealous vigilance with <br/>which it
            insists upon the pretensions of Massachusetts Bay—the <br/>merits of its policy, the
            wisdom of its statesmen, the superior ex- <br/>cellence of its genius
            generally—of its works of arts, its works of <br/>imagination, its historians, its
            poets, its romances. The very hum- <br/>blest of these is not suffered to
            escape recognition and land, and it <br/>is a daily surprise to other parts of the
            world, to perceive how little <br/>effort of their own, the Birds of the Charles, and
            other contiguous <br/>waters—rare birds indeed—are lifted into the perfect purity and
            <br/>size of the Swan, with only a little pleasant puffing from the plumes <br/>of the "
            North American.” With a gift like this, it is certainly <br/>matter of wonder to us all,
            that such a circular as the one before <br/>us, should need to pass beyond the single
            province of the Review <br/>itself. Why, the poets alone, and the essayists, the writers
            of pil- <br/>grim-orations, the tractarians and sermonizers, the makers of
            na- <br/>ional school books and Parley books—all of whom have been glo- 
          <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>rified in its pages—should alone be sufficiently numerous, as we <br/>take for granted
            they are sufficiently grateful, to prevent a neces- <br/>sity so humiliating
            to themselves and their organ. It has certainly <br/>done its duty—and, perhaps,
            something more than its duty—by all <br/>this class of persons; and there must be
            something wrong in the <br/>system by which it works, if, after all, it is compelled to
            look abroad, <br/>to regions for whose cash alone it seems to care, for the miserable
            <br/>support which is necessary to its prolonged existence. Had it but <br/>as
            religiously performed its duty by the whole broad country, the <br/>name of which it
            modestly appropriates to itself—had it regarded <br/>the nation, east and west, north
            and south, with an equal eye to its <br/>glory, progress and advancement—we cannot think
            that its condi- <br/>tion would be so greatly straitened now. That it has not
            done <br/>so, is one of those unpleasant convictions in the public mind, to <br/>which,
            without too great a stretch of inference, we may ascribe the <br/>pregnant necessity
            which has led to the issue of the present circular. <br/>With a little perversion of the
            text of Shakspeare, the mournful <br/>speech of Wolsey to Cromwell, in the day of his
            decline, would <br/>admirably suit the editor of the North American.—</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Oh ! Otis, Olis— 
            <br/>Had I but served my country with the zeal 
            <br/>I served my state, it would
            not in mine age, 
            <br/>Have left me naked to mine enemies.” </div>
            <p>The publishers proceed :—“ The tone of the work has become <br/>somewhat bolder of
            late—and some energetic essays on general <br/>politics have appeared in it.” This is
            certainly a very extraordinary <br/>assurance, and should be productive of very general
            satisfaction <br/>among its readers. We must not now be startled at any thing that
            <br/>may appear in these pages, for there is to be an infusion of new <br/>blood into
            the old veins; not that we are to suppose, (for how <br/>could this be, in the veteran
            service of this Journal for nearly thirty <br/>years, in representing the taste,
            science, and literature of the <br/>country—under such men, too, as Channing, and
            Everett, and <br/>Sparks, and Palfrey,) that it ever was deficient in the necessary
            <br/>courage and energy of a periodical. But, us “veteran journals,” <br/>like veteran
            soldiers, are apt to lapse into feebleness with years, it <br/>is thought advisable to
            show, that such cannot be the case with <br/>our “ North American,” which draws from a
            perennial fountain, <br/>and can exhibit, whenever the thing is necessary, quite as much
            of <br/>the proper fluid, the genuine red blood, as will suffice, not only for <br/>all
            periodical, but all mortal purposes. To the good old names of <br/>Channing, the
            Everetts, Bancroft and Sparks, Story, Wheaton and <br/>Prescott, there succeed others,
            of whom, as worthy to wear the <br/>mantles which these have cast aside, we have liberal
            assurance— <br/>though we hear, for the first time, of some of the persons named.
            <br/>There are, for example. “ Mr. Peabody, of Springfield, and his <br/>brother of
            Boston.” Peabody is a good name enough, particularly <br/>to an agricultural country,
            though it reminds us irresistibly of one <br/>of the personages in the “ Midsummer
            Night’s Dream”—and we <br/>catch ourselves quoting from Nicholas Bottom, at a rate which
            <br/>scarcely seems appropriate in dealing with a reviewer.—“ I pray <br/>you, commend
            me to Mistress Squash, your mother; and to mas- <br/>ter Peascod, your
            father. Good Master Pease-blossom, I shall de- <br/>sire of you more
            acquaintance.” We shall certainly hope to know <br/>more of the Peabodys, both of Boston
            and Springfield. And there <br/>is " Mr. Sabine, of Eastport.” We should be more
            satisfied of his <br/>catholic tendencies were he written down, “ Mr. Eastport, of Sa-
              <br/>bine,” but “ Sessa—let it pass!” Here is the very curse of this re-
              <br/>view. It is New England only and all over—nothing but New
            <br/>England. Of all the contributors enumerated by the editor, in his <br/>laudable
            desire to attract subscribers to his list from all the States <br/>of the American
            confederacy, he mentions but one name—that of <br/>Mr. Win. B. Read, of
            Philadelphia—which is not absolutely and <br/>entirely New England. There is not a
            single New-Yorker, not a <br/>Virginian, not a Marylander, not a Carolinian, Kentuckian,
            or Ten- <br/>nesseean in the catalogue. This is surely a strange way to bait
            <br/>for subscribers in other States, and bet ays, quite as strongly as any <br/>thing
            can do, the miserable selfishness of that policy, so notorious of <br/>New England,
            which, even when its object is to find favor abroad, <br/>overlooks the most obvious
            method of doing so, in the slavish blind- <br/>ness of its early training.
            Surely, it is not pretended that good men <br/>and true—able writers, profound and
            elegant thinkers—are not to <br/>be found in all that stretch of country which has the
            Atlantic for <br/>its base, from Long Island to the western limits of Georgia. But
            <br/>no ! this “ North American Review” is a neat contrivance for teach-
          <br/>
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page338"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>ing North America by means of New England. It is to embody <br/>and spread abroad the
            tastes and the fashions, the philosophies <br/>and the bigotries, of a trim little
            group, squat, complacent, that sits, <br/>unquestioning and utterly unquestioned, in all
            the suavity of assumed <br/>authority, within the colossal shadow of the Bunker
            Monument. <br/>Undoubtedly, these are all either able or clever men—correct wri- <br/>ters generally, knowing and circumspect—not so remarkable for <br/>the
            profundity of their philosophy, as for their familiarity with the <br/>received modes of
            thinking, and the pleasant graces of expression. <br/>Their writers are usually
            fastidious gentlemen, rather more solicit- <br/>ous of style than of more
            important matters, and apt to write so <br/>very like one another, that it will be
            somewhat difficult for one, not <br/>accustomed to note the various degrees in which
            they severally <br/>exhibit their energies, to detect the difference between them.
            <br/>They will give you, most generally, a well written article, which <br/>will show
            you the absolute position of the question—where it was <br/>in the time of Noah, what
            changes were effected by the policy of <br/>Solomon, how, and by whose hands it came
            down to us, and where <br/>it is at the present moment in New England. But, unhappily,
            they <br/>will try to keep it in this position, till the Hood of events sweeps <br/>over
            it, and them, rooting up their neat little landmarks, accurately <br/>cut and chiselled,
            to drift away upon the broad waste of ocean, for <br/>the curiosity and edification of
            each future Columbus of philosophy. <br/>This tenacity of position, in their mental
            concerns, being the fruit <br/>of certain inherent qualities of their blood, and a
            certain regimen <br/>of which they make much, and which they call conservatism. Of
            <br/>this conservatism we shall know more hereafter.</p>
       
            <p>We do not know that the middle States have fared very much <br/>better than those of
            the South, in the treatment which they have <br/>received at the hands of this journal.
            Their favorite writers are <br/>not employed upon its pages, and their publications are
            noticed <br/>slowly and with evident reluctance. When reviewed, it is very <br/>certain
            that the New England critic employs in the case of the <br/>New-Yorker, a very different
            and less indulgent standard of judg- <br/>ment than that which regulates his
            criticism when one of his own <br/>writers is under analysis. Procrustes was not more
            inexorable in <br/>the use of his bedstead when the limbs of the stranger were to be
            <br/>adjusted—while, in the case of a native, his excesses are gently inti- <br/>mated, and what he has good about him—whatever is simply cor- <br/>rect and inoffensive proves the occasion for as much delighted
            <br/>cackling as is made by an old hen, suddenly put in possession of <br/>a nest egg
            which she never laid herself.</p>
         
            <p>Thus it is, that, with all the finish and polish of Boston —in spite <br/>of the phrase
            on which the New Englander so much insists, when <br/>he speaks of that city—“ the
            Athens of America,” is immeasura- <br/>bly behind New-York in the measure and
            value of its literary pro- <br/>ductions. It is from New-York, with all its
            deficiencies of taste, <br/>its rough-and-tumble enthusiasm—blundering constantly
            against <br/>the proprieties—provoking constantly the sneer of our polished
            <br/>gentlemen down east—that we have the greatest amount of literary <br/>performance.
            Here we have Cooper and Irving; and Bryant and <br/>Halleck; and Hoffman and Willis; and
            Paulding and Herbert— <br/>and many more, who will give us, and who have given us,
            works, <br/>with which your Fadladeens, no doubt, will make sad havoc with <br/>thumb
            and fore finger, but which said works will be read, and read <br/>with delight, long
            after the critic by whom they were made mince- <br/>meat of, will be
            famishing upon his circulars.</p>
          
            <p>Much of this is true and well said, and much is untrue <br/>and badly said. The New
            York names which are quoted as <br/>evidence of the superior literary pretensions of
            this city over <br/>Boston, were unhappily selected, three of them, Halleck,
            <br/>Willis, and Bryant are New Englanders of New England, <br/>and Mr. Herbert is an
            old Englander, but a short time a re- <br/>sident of this country, and a good
            part of the time a resident <br/>in Pennsylvania ; as to Mr. Irving, there is as little
            of the <br/>‘‘rough and tumble enthusiasm” about him as any other <br/>man possesses who
            ever blotted paper. New Englanders, <br/>do, indeed, possess this very quality of
            rough-and-tumble en- <br/>thusiasm in a greater degree than the writers of
            any other <br/>portion of the country. Instead of writing with the fear of <br/>the
            North American before them, their great defect has been <br/>to write without any fear
            of any review whatever. As an <br/>offset to Cooper, Irving, and Hoffman, the New
            Englander <br/>may point with great complacency to Percival, Hawthorne, <br/>R. W.
            Emerson, Channing, John Neal, Prescott, Brownson, <br/>Lowell, Bancroft, Story, and
            Maria Child. These authors <br/>owe nothing to the North American Review, the Review
            <br/>nothing to them. Their style is as dissimilar as though <br/>they had been reared
            in different hemispheres.</p>
          
            <p>The truth is that the North American is held in as little <br/>reverence in Boston as
            in South Carolina—probably it is not <br/>held in as much. The tremendous onslaught of
            Mr. Simms’ <br/>article upon the poor old decrepit Quarterly magazine, which
            <br/>exercises much less influence in the New England mind than <br/>many penny papers
            do, shows how highly it is estimated at <br/>the South.</p>
        
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <p>It has had its day, as nearly every other quarterly review <br/>has; and but for this
            attack in the Southern Magazine, we <br/>should never have been reminded of its
            existence. It seems <br/>to have been given over to the new school of Whipple
            <br/>critics who are fast rocking it to an eternal slumber. The <br/>article on the
            British Poets, was an unmistakable sign that <br/>the breath was fast leaving its body.
            We would recom- <br/>mend the publishers to buy up the whole edition of the
            Sou- <br/>thern magazine for gratuitous distribution : it is a capital
            <br/>puff, and will remind many of its old friends that the Review <br/>is still in
            existence.</p>
         
            <p>There is certainly great truth in the following remarks, <br/>but we do not see that
            any quarterly review could do any bet- <br/>ter. What the literary interests
            of the country need, is an <br/>able weekly review, somewhat of the character of the
            Lon- <br/>don Athenaeum and the Literary Gazette; a deficiency in our
            <br/>periodical literature which we hope to fill by our Journal.</p>
          
            <p>The substantial particular in which this Review might have been <br/>equally national
            and useful to this country,—much more so, indeed, <br/>than by vainly attempting to
            combat the assaults and refute the <br/>calumnies of foreign journals,—is in the
            countenance, the encourage- <br/>ment, and the assistance, which it might
            have shown to the imma- <br/>ture genius of the country, struggling to give
            proper utterance to <br/>its crude conceptions,—struggling here and there, in the cities
            and <br/>the forest, under the thousand discouragements and disadvantages <br/>which
            every where, in the great interior, beset the footsteps of the <br/>infant intellect.
            But we have not seen, in the pages of this jour- <br/>nal, a single instance
            where it has shown the slightest solicitude in <br/>behalf of any young writer,—always
            assuming that he is not a sprout <br/>of New England,—detecting his genius through its
            rags, and seek- <br/>ing, by gentle reproof and benignant counsel, to train
            it in the way <br/>it should go, in the pursuit of its high calling. We see no young
            <br/>beginner taken by the hand, his course and models suggested, and <br/>patient
            efforts made to give the true direction to his vague and im- <br/>perfect
            conceptions. Where is the youth, whose first attempts have <br/>signified the
            possessions of his mind, upon whom, at first, this jour- <br/>nal has
            bestowed any of that notice which brings encouragement ? <br/>If one of these can be
            indicated, who has afterwards arrived at ex- <br/>cellence and fame, we shall
            make such admissions in the case of <br/>this “veteran periodical,” as we have not been
            prepared to make <br/>before. And this is no improper test for a journal that boasts of
            <br/>its being the organ of the nation for thirty years. How can that <br/>critic claim
            to have fostered the native literature, who cannot in a <br/>single instance, point to
            the verification of his own predictions,— <br/>who cannot point to some one individual
            whom he has designated <br/>in the first blush of authorship, and urged with kind
            suggestion and <br/>just counsel, to the attainment of an honourable eminence? Such
            <br/>should be no unreasonable requisition in the case of a veteran pe- <br/>riodical like this; and one instance of this sort, honestly proven, <br/>would be of
            more avail in adding to the subscription list, than ten <br/>thousand self-complacent
            assurances of merit, embodied in a begging <br/>Circular.</p>
          
            <p>In the matter of North and South, we claim to be per- <br/>fectly
            disinterested spectators. It is quite impossible that <br/>men who have never travelled
            should be able to entertain a <br/>very comprehensive patriotism, particularly in a
            country like <br/>ours whose borders are so widely extended. There are many
            <br/>kind-hearted people who are all alive to hear something <br/>from the moon by means
            of Lord Rosse’s telescope, who will <br/>sit down in happy ignorance of the opposite
            side of the town <br/>in which they live. It is hardly credible but it is true, that
            <br/>the people who live West of Broadway, affect an utter igno- <br/>rance
            of the territory lying east of the Bowery. We heard a <br/>stranger inquire of a New
            Yorker, a Knickerbocker of the <br/>Knickerbockers, the other day the way to Eldridge
            street— <br/>“’Pon my word,” said the Knickerbocker patriot, “ I cannot <br/>tell you, I
            believe there is such a street, but I think it must lie <br/>east of Broadway, for I
            have never seen it.” A great country <br/>is like a great city—one half of the
            inhabitants must be stran- <br/>gers and enemies to the other half. The
            Southern Magazine <br/>laughs incredulously at the mention of “Mr Sabine of East- <br/>port,” and thinks that it should read Mr. Eastport of Sabine; <br/>but the
            North American is equally incredulous in respect to <br/>Stephen Elliot of Charleston,
            whom the Southern Magazine <br/>speaks of in a tone which implies that not to know
            Stephen, <br/>argues one's self unknown. Now we were born at the North, <br/>but have
            lived at the South, and have wandered over a good <br/>portion of the east and the west;
            our affections, are, therefore, <br/>pretty equally quartered, and it has always been a
            matter of <br/>astonishment to us that the different sections of the Union <br/>should
            quarrel with each other, when we knew by observa- <br/>tion that they were
            all very much alike. Railroads and <br/>steamboats are doing something, and the electric
            telegraph <br/>is doing more towards annihilating space and bringing all the
         <br/>
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page339"/>
          
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>inhabitants of the Union in close proximity to each other; <br/>and this will have the
            effect of allaying many unpleasant jeal- <br/>ousies and suspicions which now
            exist between sections re- <br/>mote from each other. This very article in
            the Southern <br/>Magazine, chuckles over its chivalry to the fair sex like a <br/>cock
            in a barnyard, and so blesses itself that they do not <br/>murder women at the South as
            they do at the North. <br/>What the Magazine means by this insinuation we cannot
            <br/>possibly conceive : whether it has been reading Miss <br/>Fuller’s book, or some
            wicked wag has circulated a report <br/>down South that they have suttees in the Bay
            State, we do <br/>not know, but it is very evident that some of the literary
            <br/>circles in Charleston, have discovered a mare’s nest. We <br/>once heard a literary
            Carolinian say very seriously, in a com- <br/>pany of learned men at the
            North, that there were no clas- <br/>sical scholars in this country except at
            the South—and he <br/>said it in a manner, too, that left no doubt that he believed
            <br/>what he said. The same liberal gentleman also asserted <br/>very positively that
            there was no such thing as humor at the <br/>North. Now it so happens that the few
            humorous editors of <br/>whom they can boast at the South, are all New England- <br/>ers — Fields of the Reveille, and the Picayune people, <br/>being the most
            eminent among them. In New York, near- <br/>ly the entire press is in the
            hands of New Englanders, <br/>Bryant of the Post, Willis and Morris of the Mirror, the
            <br/>Townsends and Brookses (a score of them) of the Ex- <br/>press, Greely
            and Fuller of the Tribune, Hunt of the Mer- <br/>chant’s Magazine, Colton of
            the Whig Review, Hale and <br/>Hillock of the Journal of Commerce, Raymond and Daniels
            <br/>and King of the Courier, Cheever of the Evangelist, Morse of <br/>the Observer,
            Seabury of the Churchman, Beach of the Sun, <br/>Green, Deming &amp; Co. of the
            Emporium, Park Benjamin of <br/>something to be brought out by-and-by, and a dozen more
            of <br/>less prominence. Even the editor of the Southern Quarterly <br/>Review is a New
            Englander.</p>
          
            <p>For our own part, we think it a matter of precious little mo-: <br/>ment on which side
            of Mason and Dixon’s line a man is born <br/>if he is only a man “for a’that.” A few
            years ago when <br/>Mr. Webster attended a mass meeting in Richmond, the <br/>people
            were greatly astonished to find him so nearly resem- <br/>bling one of themselves, and
            we have no doubt that Mc- <br/>Duffie or Calhoun would create the same kind
            of astonish- <br/>ment in Boston or Bangor. A gentleman, Mr. Tyler we be- <br/>lieve, recommended, in a speech before some historical soci- <br/>ety in
            Philadelphia a year or two since, that a certain num- <br/>ber of citizens
            should be sent over to England yearly, upon a <br/>reciprocal mission, to preserve peace
            between the two na- <br/>tions by the amenity of their manners. This was a
            very <br/>sensible recommendation, but we do not remember that any <br/>member of
            Congress has ever made any motion in relation to <br/>it. But it would be one of the
            cheapest and most agreeable <br/>methods of preserving the peaceable relations of
            England and <br/>America that could be devised. Our array and navy which <br/>are now
            kept up as scare-crows, and invite rather than re- <br/>pel invasion, cost
            the nation some fifteen millions annually. <br/>But ten millions would defray the annual
            expenses of at least <br/>thirty-five hundred gentlemen in the best London Society, and
            <br/>the peace-compelling effect of their intercourse with John <br/>Bull, more
            especially if they were single, no one can doubt <br/>would be much greater than our
            whole armed force now <br/>can produce, and the nation would be a clear gainer of some
            <br/>five millions of dollars which might be profitably expended <br/>in promotion of
            the same end, in founding public libraries, or <br/>erecting telegraphs and
            observatories. Some discretion <br/>would be necessary in the selection of these
            travelling peace <br/>makers and promoters of national good-will, but if they were
            <br/>elected by the people, in the manner of our representatives, <br/>there would be
            little danger of improper persons being sent. <br/>The same system might be adopted by
            the States with refe- <br/>rence to each other, but on a much smaller scale
            and at a <br/>less expense.</p>
          
            <p>The experiment tried by Massachusetts in sending old Mr. <br/>Hoar and his young
            daughter to South Carolina, did not turn- <br/>out very well it must be
            confessed, but that is no reason <br/>why the experiment should not he tried again on a
            more ex- <br/>tensive scale, or it might be well to try the plan upon a less
            <br/>belligerent people. North Carolina, for instance, as a test. <br/>We are not
            without hope that some spirited member of the <br/>next Congress will propose some
            measure like this that we <br/>have hinted at, and the inducement to good behavior in
            our <br/>citizens who might be ambitious of being sent abroad by the <br/>people would
            alone have the happiest tendency. Imagine <br/>the sensation that would be created in
            our fashionable
         
          <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>squares and avenues by an announcement that one of Her <br/>Majesty’s steamers was
            below, freighted with two or three <br/>hundred of the elite of young England sent over
            here to pro- <br/>mote good feeling towards the mother country ! Would even
            <br/>Mr. Benton, or the tremendously war-like Senator from <br/>Ohio, ever dream of war
            after such an announcement ?</p>
        </div>
                
        <div>
            <div class="head">THE THREE MAXIMS.</div>
            <div class="ab">From the Gesta Romanorum.</div>
            <p>There was an emperor of Rome named Domitian, a good <br/>and a wise prince, who
            suffered no offenders to escape. <br/>There was a high feast in his hall, the tables
            glittered with <br/>gold and silver, and groaned with plenteous provision: his
            <br/>nobles feasted with him—</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>‘ And ’twas merry with all
            <br/>In the king’s great hall.
            <br/>When his nobles and kinsmen, great and small,
            <br/>Were keeping their Christmas holiday.’
          </div>
            <p>The porter in his lodge made his fire blaze brightly, and so- <br/>laced
            himself with Christmas cheer; every now and then <br/>grumbling at his office, that kept
            him from the gaieties of <br/>the retainer’s hall. The wind blew cold, the sleet fell
            <br/>quick, as the bell of the king’s gate sounded heavy and dull. <br/>“ Who comes
            now?” grumbled the porter; “ a pretty night <br/>to turn out from fire and food. Why,
            the very bell itself <br/>finds it too cold to clank loudly. Well, well—duty is duty:
            <br/>some says it’s a pleasure—humph ! Hilloa, friend, who are <br/>you ? what do you
            want, man ?”</p>
            <p>The traveller whom the porter thus addressed was a tall, <br/>weather-beaten man, with
            long white hair that fluttered <br/>from beneath his cap of furs, and whose figure,
            naturally <br/>tall and robust, seemed taller and larger from the vast cloak <br/>of
            bearskins with which he was enveloped.</p>
            <p>“I am a merchant from a far country,” said the man; <br/>“many wonderful things do I
            bring to your emperor, if he <br/>will purchase of my valuables.”</p>
            <p>“ Well, come in, come in, man,” said the porter: “the <br/>king keeps high Christmas
            feast, and on this night all men <br/>may seek his presence. Wilt take some refreshment,
            good <br/>sir ?” </p>
            <p>“ I am never hungry, nor thirsty, nor cold.” </p>
            <p>“ I’m all—there—straight before you, good sir—the hall <br/>porter will usher you
            in—straight before,” muttered the old <br/>porter, as he returned to his fire and his
            supper. “Never <br/>hungry, thirsty, nor cold—what a good poor man he would <br/>make!
            humph! he loses many a pleasure though,” con- <br/>tinued the porter, as he
            closed the door of the lodge.</p>
            <p>The strange merchant presented himself to the hall porter, and was ushered by him into
            the presence of the emperor.</p>
            <p>“Who have we here?” said Domitian, as the strange visiter made his obeisance. “ What
            seekest thou of me?”</p>
            <p>“ I bring many things from far countries. Wilt thou buy of my curiosities ?”</p>
            <p>“ Let us see them,” rejoined Domitian.</p>
            <p>“ I have three maxims of especial wisdom and excellence, my lord.”</p>
            <p>“ Let us hear them.”</p>
            <p>“ Nay, my lord ; if thou hearest them, and likest not, then I have lost both my maxims
            and my money.”</p>
            <p>“ And if I pay without hearing them, and they are useless, I lose my time and my money.
            What is the price ?”</p>
            <p>" A thousand florins, my lord.”</p>
            <p>“ A thousand florins for that of the which I know not what it is,” replied the
            king.</p>
            <p>“ My lord,” rejoined the merchant, “ if the maxims do not stand you in good stead, I
            will return the money.”</p>
            <p>“ Be it so then : let us hear your maxims."</p>
            <p>“The first, my lord,on this wise: Never begin anything UNTIL YOU HAVE CALCULATED WHAT
            THE END WILL BE.”</p>
            <p>“ I like your maxim much,” said the king ; “ let it be re- <br/>corded in
            the chronicles of the kingdom, inscribed on the <br/>walls and over the doors of my
            palaces and halls of justice, <br/>and interwoven on the borders of the linen of my
            table and <br/>my chamber.”</p>
            <p>“The second, my Lord, is, Never leave a highway for A BYE-WAY.”</p>
            <p>" I see not the value of this maxim: but to the third.”</p>
            <p>“ Never sleep in the house where the master is an old <br/>man and the wife a young
            woman. These three maxims, <br/>if attended to, my lord, will stand you in good
            stead.”</p>
            <br/>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page340"/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <p>“We shall see,” said the king ; “ a year and a day for the <br/>trial of each, at the
            end of this time we will settle accounts.”</p>
            <p>
               <br/>“Good master,” said the king's jester, “wilt sell thy <br/>chance of the thousand
            florins for my fool’s cap?”</p>
            <p>“ Wait, and see what the end will he,” rejoined the mer- <br/>chant ; “ a
            year and a day hence I will return to see how <br/>my first maxim has fared. Farewell,
            my lord.’’ . . .</p>
            <p>The year and a day were nearly elapsed, and yet the first <br/>maxim had not been
            clearly proved. Domitian remained <br/>severely just, and the ill-intentioned of his
            nobles plotted his <br/>destruction in the hopes of indulging their vices more freely
            <br/>under the rule of his successor. Many were the plots they <br/>concocted to put him
            to death, but all were foiled by his <br/>foresight and prudence.</p>
            <p>“ Every failure,” said the conspirators at a midnight meet- ing, “ brings danger nearer
            to ourselves.” </p>
            <p>“Even so, brothers, but this time we will not fail,” said <br/>one of the number; “ do
            ye not mind that I am the king’s <br/>barber: every day he bares his throat to my razor:
            it is but <br/>one slash, and we are free; promise me the crown: in re- <br/>turn for this, I will give you freedom by the king’s death, <br/>and free license
            during my reign.”</p>
            <p>“ It is well spoken,” cried all the conspirators; “the bar- ber shall be our king.” </p>
            <p>On the next morning, the barber entered the chamber of <br/>Domitian, and prepared to
            shave the king. The razor was <br/>stropped, the lather spread upon the royal chin, and
            the tow- <br/>el fastened round the royal breast. On the edge of the nap- <br/>kin were these words in letters of gold, “ Never begin any- <br/>thing until you have calculated what the end will be.”</p>
            <p>The barber’s eye fell on these words, they arrested his attention, he paused in his
            labors. </p>
            <p>“What am I about to do ?" thought he to himself, “to <br/>kill the king, to gain his
            crown; am I sure of the crown ? <br/>shall I not rather be slain miserably, and die amid
            unheard <br/>of tortures and infamy ? whilst those that plot with me will <br/>turn
            against me, and make me their scape-goat.”</p>
            <p>“Art dreaming, sir barber?” exclaimed the king. </p>
            <p>At the king's voice, the barber trembled exceedingly, he <br/>dropt the razor from his
            hand, and fell at his sovereign’s <br/>feet.</p>
            <p>“ What means all this? </p>
            <p>“Oh, my good lord !” exclaimed the barber, as he knelt <br/>at Domitian’s feet, “ this
            day was I to have killed thee: but <br/>I saw the maxim written on the napkin: I thought
            of the <br/>consequences, and now repent me of my wickedness. Mercy, <br/>my good lord,
            mercy !"</p>
            <p>“Be faithful, and fear not,” replied the king. </p>
            <p>“The merchant, my lord the king,’ said a servant of the <br/>chamber, who entered at
            that moment, followed by the old <br/>merchant.</p>
            <p>“ Thou art come at a good time, sir merchant; the first <br/>maxim has been proved ; it
            has saved my life: it was wor- <br/>thy of its price.”</p>
            <p>“ Even as I expected, my lord—a year and a day hence expect me again.” </p>
            <p>“ We will trust no more to a single hand,” said one of the <br/>conspirators, when they
            met again, after the barber’s re- <br/>pentance; “ this time we will all
            share.”</p>
            <p>“ I propose, ’ said one of the rebel lords, “ an ambush on <br/>the road to Naples.
            Every year, on the day after Christmas, <br/>the king journeys thither; the bye-path
            near to the city <br/>gates is the nearest road, peradventure he will go that way.’’</p>

            <p>
               <br/>When the Christmas night was over, the king prepared <br/>to journey to Naples; a
            great company of nobles, knights, <br/>and men at arms, went with him. Not far from the
            city, he <br/>came to the place where the highway and bye path di- <br/>verged.</p>
            <p>“ My lord,” said an old noble, “ the day is far spent, the <br/>sun sinks fast in the
            horizon; will not my lord turn by the <br/>bye-path, as it is far shorter than the high
            road ?”</p>
            <p>“ Nay,” said the king, “it’s a year and a day since the <br/>merchant's first maxim
            saved my life: now will I test the <br/>second admonition. ‘ Never leave a highway for a
            bye-path,' <br/>but go part of ye by that path, and prepare for me in the <br/>city ; I
            and the rest will pursue the highway.”</p>
            <p>Onward rode the knights and the soldiers by the bye-path, <br/>and hastened towards the
            city; as they neared the ambush, <br/>the traitors sprang upon them, for they thought
            the king was <br/>among them. Every man slew his opponent, and there re-<br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>mained not one of the king's company, to bear the tidings <br/>to the king, but a
            youth, a little page, whom the conspira- <br/>tors did not remark during the
            attack.</p>
            <p>At the city gates, the king found the merchant who had sold him his maxims.</p>
            <p>“ Halt, O king!” said he—the second maxim has been proved.”</p>
            <p>“How so?” replied the king.</p>
            <p>“The company that rode by the bye-path are slain, every <br/>one of them save this
            little page, who is here to tell the sad <br/>tale.”</p>
            <p>“ Is this so, good youth ?”</p>
            <p>“Alas, my lord, it is too true : from behind the trees they <br/>rushed upon our
            company as we rode lightly and merrily, <br/>and no one, save your poor page, lives to
            tell the tale.”</p>
            <p>“ For a second time is my life saved by the maxim ; let it <br/>be inscribed in gold, ‘
            Never leave a highway for a bye- <br/>way.' ”</p>
            <p>“ For a year and a day, O king, fare thee well.”</p>




            <p>“ A murrain on the old fool’s maxims!” grumbled the chief <br/>of the conspirators,
            when they discovered that the king had <br/>escaped their wicked design ; “ we are
            beaten out of every <br/>plot, and had best submit to his dominion.”</p>
            <p>“ Nay,” exclaimed a young and icentious noble, “ there is <br/>luck in odd numbers, let
            us have one more trial, a sink or a <br/>swim.”</p>
            <p>“ I care not if we try once more,” said the old rebel; “ but come, who suggests a
            scheme ?”</p>
            <p>“ I, and I, and I!” exclaimed several at once; but their schemes were pronounced
            futile.</p>
            <p>“ What say ye to this ?” said the young man who had before <br/>spoken : “ every year
            the king goes to the small village town, <br/>where his old nurse lives ; there is but
            one house in the vil- <br/>lage where he can be lodged, let us bribe the
            master of the <br/>house, that he slay our tyrant while he sleeps.”</p>
            <p>The plan was approved by the rebel lords, the bribe offer- <br/>ed and
            accepted by the old man, to whose house the king <br/>always came. The king came as
            usual to the village town, <br/>and to his old lodgings. As he entered, the old man
            received <br/>him with humility and feigned delight, and a young damsel, <br/>not
            eighteen, attended at the door step. The king noticed <br/>the damsel, he arrested his
            steps, and called to the old man.</p>
            <p>“ Good father,’’asked he, “ is yonder damsel thy daughter, or thy niece ?”</p>
            <p>“Neither, my lord,” replied the old man, “she is my newly-married wife.”</p>
            <p>“ Away, away,” said the king to his chamberlain, “pre- <br/>pare me a bed in
            another house, for I will not sleep here to- <br/>night.”</p>
            <p>“Even as my lord wishes,” rejoined the chamberlain; <br/>“but my lord knows there is no
            other house in this place fit <br/>for a king’s residence, save this one; here
            everything is pre- <br/>pared, everything commodious.”</p>
            <p>“ I have spoken,” replied the king: “remain thou here; I will sleep elsewhere.”</p>
            <p>In the night, the old man and his wife arose, stole on tip- <br/>toe to the
            chamber which was prepared for the king, and <br/>where the chamberlain now slept in the
            royal bed ; all was <br/>dark as they approached the bed, and plunged a dagger into
            <br/>the breast of the sleeping noble.</p>
            <p>“ It is done,” said they ; “ to bed, to bed.” </p>
            <p>Early the next morning, the king’s page knocked at the <br/>door of the humble abode
            where the king had passed the <br/>night.</p>
            <p>“ Why so early, good page ?” asked the king.</p>
            <p>“My lord, the old merchant waits thy rising; and even now strange news is come from the
            village.’’</p>
            <p>“ Let the merchant and the messenger come in.” </p>
            <p>The merchant seemed greatly elated, his eye glistened <br/>with joy, and his figure
            appeared dilated beyond its ordinary <br/>height. The messenger was pale and trembling,
            and staring <br/>aghast with fear.</p>
            <p>"My lord, my good lord,” exclaimed the pallid messenger, <br/>“ a horrible murder has
            been committed on your chamber- <br/>lain : he lies dead in the royal
            bed.”</p>
            <p>" The third maxim is tried and proved," said the mer- chant. </p>
            <p>“Give God the praise,” said the king; “thy reward is <br/>earned: a robe of honor, and
            thrice thy bargained price ; to <br/>the old man and his wife, immediate death.”</p>
        </div>
         <br/>
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page341"/>

         <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/>
        <div>
            <div class="head">THE UNSEEN RIVER.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Through a valley green and golden,
            <br/>In the purple time and olden,
            <br/>When the East was growing grey ;
            <br/>
               <br/>When the mists were star-ward creeping—
            <br/>
               <br/>Weeping—being woke from sleeping
            <br/>
               <br/>By the anthems of the Day ;—
            <br/>While, like vapor o’er a city, fluctuating still they lay ;
            <br/>Walking through their shrouding shadows,
            <br/>Over daisy-dimpled meadows,
            <br/>Moved a proud and princely youth,
            <br/>With a foot-fall light and airy
            <br/>As the sylphid step of fairy,
            <br/>And a forehead stamped with truth :—
            <br/>An Apollo ! incarnating lofty scorn and living ruth.
            <br/>From the valley,—from a river,—
            <br/>Which, with many a silver quiver,
            <br/>Through the landscape stole in light;—
            <br/>From the bushes, shrubs, and blossoms,—
            <br/>Flowers unfolding fragrant bosoms,—
            <br/>Curled the shadows out of sight;
            <br/>Fading, like a ghost, in air. 
            <br/>And ever the river rippled bright.
            <br/>Fruits of crimson—purple—azure—
            <br/>Thrilled his Poet-soul with pleasure
            <br/>Which, from all, new glory won;
            <br/>While around him birds were chaunting,—
            <br/>Birds that fairy valley haunting,—
            <br/>Such as Mother Earth had none :
            <br/>And like gems their pinious glistened, glancing in the aspiring sun.
            <br/>In a sweet excitemeut swimming,
            <br/>All his soul with beauty brimming,
            <br/>While the morning grew to noon;
            <br/>In that glorious valley—listening
            <br/>
               <br/>To the music—by the glistening
            <br/>
               <br/>River—sung with lulling tune,
            <br/>While his heart throbbed echo 'neath Lethean languor born of June—
            <br/>Carelessly the youth went straying
            <br/>Like a merry child a-Maying.
            <br/>And the river rippled on.
            <br/>While now that a hirst pursued him,
            <br/>And the noon tide heat subdued him,
            <br/>And he felt him weak and wan,
            <br/>Thinking of the stream, he turned him, fevered ; but the stream was gone!
            <br/>Searching for it, on he wandered
            <br/>
               <br/>Hour by hour ! and sadly pondered
            <br/>
               <br/>As to where its waves might be :
            <br/>And the valley slowly faded
            <br/>
               <br/>To a primal forest, shaded
            <br/>
               <br/>By full many a mossy tree.
            <br/>Still he could not see the stream meandering through the mead- owy lea.
            <br/>But the murmur of the river,
            <br/>Rippling, miming, plashing ever,
            <br/>Floated on his yearning ear:
            <br/>Still before he heard it flowing—
            <br/>Heard it kiss the rocks while going,
            <br/>Seeming us he heard it, near;
            <br/>Whispering nearer, flowing onward, gurgling every instant hear.
            <br/>More luxuriant, greener, brighter,
            <br/>Glossier, loftier, aud lighter
            <br/>Grew the foliage where it seemed:
            <br/>And the woodland birds sang clearer,
            <br/>And the waters near and nearer
            <br/>Murmured, 'till he thought they gleamed;
            <br/>And, between the emerald leaves, he dreamed the silver wave- lets beamed:
            <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>Through the trees, among the bushes,
            <br/>Looking for the river rushes,
            <br/>Onward, onward, still he went,
            <br/>Listening to the water’s plashing—
            <br/>Listening to the eddies dashing
            <br/>In their chrystal merriment:
            <br/>But he found it not, though stooping—gazing 'till his form grew bent.
            <br/>All around grew dark and dreary,
            <br/>And our wanderer, very weary,
            <br/>Tottered feebly, full of pain,
            <br/>From the forest; with his figure
            <br/>Robbed of all its youthful vigor:—
            <br/>And the sun was on the wane—
            <br/>And night’s swarthy, solemn shadow slowly gathered round the plain,
            <br/>And—among those shades lamenting,—
            <br/>Urged by old Time unrelenting,—
            <br/>Where was never else but gloom—
            <br/>From the sight the wanderer faded,
            <br/>By chaotic blackness shaded.
            <br/>While the silence of the tomb
            <br/>Wrapped him, shroud-like; and that silence was the requiem of his doom.
          </div>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">HENRY B. HIRST</span>.</div>
        </div>

        <div>
            <div class="head">SHADOW-A PARABLE.</div>
            <div class="ab">Yes! though I walk through the valley of the Shadow:--Psalm of David.</div>
            <p>Ye who read are still among the living: but I who write <br/>shall have long since gone
            my wav into the region of sha- <br/>dows. For indeed strange things shall
            happen, and secret <br/>things be known, and many centuries shall pass away, ere
            <br/>these memorials be seen of men. And, when seen, there <br/>will be some to
            disbelieve, and some to doubt, and yet a few <br/>who will find much to ponder upon in
            the characters here <br/>graven with a stylus of iron.</p>
            <p>The year had been a year of terror, and of feelings more <br/>intense than terror for
            which there is no name upon the <br/>earth. For many prodigies and signs had taken
            place, and <br/>far and wide, over sea and land, the black wings of the Pes- <br/>tilence were spread abroad. To those, nevertheless, cun- <br/>ning in the stars, it was not unknown that the heavens wore <br/>an aspect of ill; and
            to me, the Greek Oinos, among others, <br/>it was evident that now had arrived the
            alternation of that <br/>seven hundred and ninety-fourth year when, at the entrance
            <br/>of Aries, the planet Jupiter is conjoined with the red ring of <br/>the terrible
            Saturnus. The peculiar spirit of the skies, if I <br/>mistake not greatly, made itself
            manifest, not only in the <br/>physical orb of the earth, but in the souls,
            imaginations, and <br/>meditations of mankind.</p>
            <p>Over some flasks of the red Chian wine, within the walls <br/>of a noble ball, in a dim
            city called Ptolemais, we sat, at <br/>night, a company of seven. And to our chamber
            there was <br/>no entrance save by a lofty door of brass: and the door was
            <br/>fashioned by the artizan Corinnos, and, being of rare work- <br/>manship, was fastened from within. Black draperies, like- <br/>wise, in the
            gloomy room, shut cut from our view the moon, the lurid stars, and the peopleless
            streets—but the boding <br/>and the memory of Evil, they would not be so excluded.
            <br/>There were things around us and about of which I can ren- <br/>der no
            distinct account —things material and spiritual—hea- <br/>viness in the
            atmosphere—a sense of suffocation—anxiety— <br/>and, above all, that terrible state of
            existence which the <br/>nervous experience when the senses are keenly living and
            <br/>awake, and meanwhile the powers of thought lie dormant. <br/>A dead weight hung
            upon us. It hung upon our limbs— <br/>upon the household furniture—upon the goblets from
            which <br/> we drank ; and all things were depressed, and borne down <br/> thereby—all
            things save only the flames of the seven iron <br/>lamps which illumined our revel.
            Uprearing themselves in <br/>tall slender lines of light, they thus remained burning all
            <br/>pallid and motionless; and in the mirror which their lustre <br/>formed upon the
            round table of ebony at which we sat, each <br/>of us there assembled beheld the pallor
            of his own counte- <br/>nance, and the unquiet glare in the downcast eyes of
            his <br/>companions. Yet we laughed and were merry in our pro<br/>
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page342"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>per way—which was hysterical; and sang the songs of An- <br/>acreon—which are madness; and drank deeply—although <br/>the purple wine reminded us
            of blood. For there was yet <br/>another tenant of our chamber in the person of young
            Zoilus. <br/>Dead, and at full length he lay, enshrouded;—the genius <br/>and the demon
            of the scene. Alas ! he bore no portion in <br/>our mirth, save that his countenance,
            distorted with the <br/>plague, and his eyes in which Death had but half extinguish- <br/>ed the fire of the pestilence, seemed to take such interest in <br/>our
            merriment as the dead may haply take in the merriment <br/>of those who are to die. But
            although I, Oinos, felt that <br/>the eyes of the departed were upon me, still I forced
            myself <br/>not to perceive the bitterness of their expression, and, gazing <br/>down
            steadily into the depths of the ebony mirror, sang with <br/>a loud and sonorous voice
            the songs of the son of Teios. <br/>But gradually my songs they ceased, and their
            echoes, roll- <br/>ing afar off among the sable draperies of the chamber, be-
              <br/>came weak, and undistinguishable, and so faded away. <br/>And lo !
            from among those sable draperies where the sounds <br/>of the song departed, there came
            forth a dark and undefined <br/>shadow—a shadow such as the moon, when low in heaven,
            <br/>might fashion from the figure of a man : but it was the sha- <br/>dow
            neither of man, nor of God, nor of any familiar thing. <br/>And, quivering awhile among
            the draperies of the room, it <br/>at length rested in full view upon the surface of the
            door <br/>of brass. But the shadow was vague, and formless, and in- <br/>definite, and was the shadow neither of man nor of God— <br/>neither God of Greece,
            nor God of Chaldaea, nor any Egypt- <br/>ian God. And the shadow rested upon
            the brazen doorway, <br/>and under the arch of the entablature of the door, and mov- <br/>ed not, nor spoke any word, but there became stationary and <br/>remained.
            And the door whereupon the shadow rested was, <br/>if I remember aright, over against
            the feet of the young Zoi- <br/>lus enshrouded. But we, the seven there
            assembled, having <br/>seen the shadow as it came out from among the draperies,
            <br/>dared not steadily behold it, but cast down our eyes, and <br/>gazed continually
            into the depths of the mirror of ebony. <br/>And at length I, Oinos, speaking some low
            words, demanded <br/>of the shadow its dwelling and its appellation. And the <br/>shadow
            answered, “ I am SHADOW, and my dwelling is <br/>near to the Catacombs of Ptolemais, and
            hard by those dim <br/>plains of Helusion which border upon the foul Charonian
            <br/>canal.” And then did we, the seven, start from our seats in <br/>horror, and stand
            trembling, and shuddering, and aghast: <br/>for the tones in the voice of the shadow
            were not the tones <br/>of any one being, but of a multitude of beings, and, varying
            <br/>in their cadences from syllable to syllable, fell duskily upon <br/>our ears in the
            well remembered and familiar accents of <br/>many thousand departed friends</p>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">edgar a. poe</span>.</div>
        </div>
                  
                  <div>
            <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">MRS. CHILD'S PHILOTHEA.</div>
               <p>Overwhelmed in a long-continued inundation of Sue-ism, <br/>we turn with a species of
              gasping satisfaction—with a deep <br/>sense of the luxury of repose—to the pure and
              quiet pages <br/>of Philothea.</p>
               <p>We regard it not only as the best work of its author—but <br/>as the best work of a
              class in which are to be ranked the Te- <br/>lemachus of Fenelon and the
              Anacharsis of Barthelemi.</p>
               <p>Its plot is simple. The scene is principally in ancient <br/>Athens during the
              administration of Pericles; and some of <br/>the chief personages of his time are
              brought, with himself, <br/>upon the stage. Among these are Aspasia, Alcibiades, Hip-
                <br/>pocrates, Anaxagoras of Clazomenae, Plato, Hermippus the <br/>comic
              writer, Phidias the sculptor, Artaxerxes of Persia, and <br/>Xerxes his son.
              Philothea, the heroine of the tale, and the <br/>grand daughter of Anaxagoras, is of a
              majestic beauty, and <br/>of great purity and elevation of mind. Her friend Eudora,
              <br/>of a more delicate loveliness, and more flexile disposition, is <br/>the adopted
              daughter of Phidias, who bought her, when an <br/>infant, of a goat-herd in
              Phelle—herseif and nurse having <br/>been stolen from the Ionian coast by Greek
              pirates, the <br/>nurse sold into slavery, and the child delivered to the care of
              <br/>the goat-herd. The ladies, of course, have lovers. Eudora<br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>is betrothed
              to Philaemon. This Athenian, the son of the <br/>wealthy Cherilaus, but whose mother
              was bom in Corinth, <br/>jhas incurred the dislike of Aspasia, the wife pf Pericles,
              <br/>She procures the revival of an ancient law subjecting to a <br/>heavy fine all
              citizens who marry foreigners, and declaring <br/>all persons whose parents were not
              both Athenians, incapa- <br/>ble of voting in the public assemblies, or of
              inheriting the <br/>estates of their fathers. Philaemon, thus deprived of citi- <br/>zenship, prevented from holding office, and without hope of <br/>any
              patrimony, is obliged to postpone, indefinitely, his union <br/>with Eudora. The
              revival of the obnoxious law has also a <br/>disastrous effect on the interests of
              Philothea. She is beloved <br/>by Paralus, the son of Pericles, and returns his
              affection.</p>
               <p/>
               <p>But in marrying she will bring upon him losses and degra- <br/>dation.
              Pericles, too, looks with an evil eye upon her po- <br/>verty; and the idea
              of marriage is therefore finally aban- <br/>doned.</p>
               <p>Matters are thus situated when Philothea, being appoint- <br/>ed one of
              the Canephorae (whose duty it is to embroider the <br/>sacred peplus, and to carry
              baskets in the precession of the <br/>Panathenaia) is rigidly secluded by law, for six
              months, <br/>within the walls of the Acropolis. During this time Eudora, <br/>deprived
              of the good counsel and example of her friend, be- <br/>comes a frequent
              visitor at the house of Aspasia, by whose <br/>pernicious influence she is insensibly
              affected. It is at the <br/>return of Philothea from the Acropolis that the story com-
                <br/>mences. At the urgent solicitation of Aspasia, who is desi- <br/>rous of strengthening her influence in Athens by the counte- <br/>nance of the virtuous, Anaxagoras is induced to attend, with <br/>his
              grand-daughter, a symposium at the house of Pericles. Eudora accompanies them. The
              other guests are Hermip- <br/>pus, Phidias, the Persian Artaphernes,
              Tithonus a learned <br/>Ethiopian, Plato, Hipparete the wife of Alcibiades, and Al-
                <br/>cibiades himself. At this symposium Eudora is dazzled by <br/>the
              graces of Alcibiades, and listens to his seductive flatte- <br/>ry—forgetful of the claims of Hipparete and of her own <br/>lover, Philaemon. The
              poison of this illicit feeling now af- <br/>fects all the action of the
              drama. Philothea discovers the <br/>danger of her friend, but is sternly repulsed upon
              the proffer <br/>of good advice. Alcibiades is appointed a secret interview <br/>by
              Eudora, which is interrupted by Philothea—not, however, <br/>before it is observed by
              Philaemon, who in consequence, <br/>abandons his mistress, and departs broken-hearted
              from <br/>Athens. The eyes of Eudora are now opened, too late, to <br/>the perfidy of
              Alcibiades, who had deceived her with the <br/>promise of marriage and of obtaining a
              divorce from Hippa- <br/>rete. It is Hipparete who appeals to the Archons
              for a di- <br/>vorce from Alcibiades, on the score of his notorious profli-
                <br/>gacy ; and in the investigations which ensue, it appears that <br/>a
              snare has been laid by Aspasia and himself to entrap Eu- <br/>dora, and
              that, with a similar end in view, he has also <br/>promised marriage to Electra, the
              Corinthian.</p>
               <p>Pericles seeks to please the populace by diminishing the <br/>power of the Areopagus.
              He causes a decree to be passed, <br/>that those who deny the existence of the Gods,
              or introduce <br/>new opinions about celestial things, shall be tried by the
              <br/>people. This, however, proves injurious to some of his own <br/>personal friends.
              Hermippus lays before the Themothetae <br/>Archons an accusation of blasphemy against
              Anaxagoras, <br/>Phidias, and Aspasia ; and the case is tried before the fourth
              <br/>assembly of the people. Anaxagoras is charged with not <br/>having offered
              victims to the Gods, and with having blas- <br/>phemed the divine Phoebus
              by saying the sun was only a <br/>huge ball of fire:—he is condemned to die. Phidias
              is ac- <br/>cused of blasphemy in having carved the likeness of himself
              <br/>and Pericles on the shield of heaven-born Pallas—of having<br/>
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page343"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/> said that he approved the worship of the Gods merely be- <br/>cause he wished to have his own works adored—and of de- <br/>coying to
              his own house the maids and matrons of Athens, <br/>under pretence of seeing
              sculpture, but in fact, to administer <br/>to the profligacy of Pericles. He also is
              sentenced to death. <br/>Aspasia is accused of saying that the sacred baskets of De-
                <br/>meter contained nothing of so much importance as the beau- <br/>tiful maidens who carried them ; and that the temple of Po- <br/>seidon was enriched with no offerings from those who had <br/>been
              wrecked notwithstanding their supplications—thereby <br/>implying irreverent doubts of
              the power of Ocean’s God. Her <br/>sentence is exile. Pericles, however, succeeds in
              getting the <br/>execution of the decrees suspended until the oracle of Am- <br/>phiaraus can be consulted. Antiphon, a celebrated diviner, <br/>is
              appointed to consult it. He is absent for many days, and <br/>in the meantime Pericles
              has an opportunity of tampering <br/>with the people, as he has already tampered with
              Anti- <br/>phon. The response of the oracle opportunely declares that
              <br/>the sentences be re-considered. They are; Phidias and <br/>Anaxagoras are merely
              banished, while Aspasia is acquitted. <br/>These trials form, perhaps, the most
              interesting portion of <br/>the book.</p>
               <p>Chapter XI. introduces us to Anaxagoras, the contented <br/>resident of a small
              village near Lampsacus in Ionia. He is <br/>old, feeble and poor. Philothea watches by
              his side, and <br/>supports him with the labor of her hands, Plato visits the
              <br/>sage of Clazomenae in his retreat, and brings news of the <br/>still beloved
              Athens. The pestilence is raging—the Piraeus is <br/>heaped with the unburied dead.
              Hipparete has fallen a vic- <br/>tim. Pericles was one of the first
              sufferers, but has recover- <br/>ed through the skill of Hippocrates. Phidias who,
              after his <br/>sentence of exile, departed with Eudora to Elis, and grew in <br/>honor
              among the Eleans—is dead. Eudora still remains at <br/>his house, Elis having bestowed
              on her the yearly revenues <br/>of a farm in consideration of the affectionate care
              bestowed <br/>upon her illustrious benefactor. Philaemon is in Persia in- <br/>structing the sons of the wealthy satrap Megabyzus. Alci- <br/>biades is living in unbridled license at Athens. But the vis- <br/>iter
              has not vet spoken of Paralus, the lover of Philothea.— <br/>“ Daughter of Alcimenes,”
              he at length says—we copy here <br/>a page of the volume as a specimen of the grace of
              the nar- <br/>rative:</p>
               <p>“ Daughter of Alcimenes, your heart reproaches me that I forbear <br/>to speak of
              Paralus. That I have done so, has not been from for- <br/>getfulness, but because I
              have with vain and self-defeating prudence <br/>sought for cheerful words to convey
              sad thoughts. Paralus breathes <br/>and moves, but is apparently unconscious of
              existence in this world. <br/>He is silent and abstracted, like one just returned from
              the cave of <br/>Troponius. Yet beautiful forms are ever with him in infinite va- <br/>riety ; for his quiescent soul has now undisturbed recollection of the
              <br/>divine archetypes in the ideal world, of which all earthly beauty is <br/>the
              shadow.”</p>
               <p>" He is happy, then, though living in the midst of death,” an- swered Philothea. “
              But does his memory retain no traces of his friends ?” </p>
               <p>"One—and one only,” he replied. “The name of Philothea <br/>was too deeply engraven
              to be washed away by the waters of obli- <br/>vion. He seldom speaks; but
              when he does you are ever in his <br/>visions. The sound of a female voice
              accompanying the lyre is the <br/>only thing that makes him smile; and nothing moves
              him to tears ; <br/>save the farewell song of Orpheus to Eurydice. In his drawings
              <br/>there is more of majesty and beauty than Phydias or Myron ever <br/>conceived;
              and one figure is always there—the Pythia, the Muse, <br/>the Grace, or something
              combining all these, more spiritual than <br/>either.”</p>
               <p>The special object of Plato's visit is the hearing of a mes- <br/>sage
              from Pericles. Hippocrates has expressed a hope that <br/>the presence of Philothea
              may restore, in some measure, <br/>the health and understanding of Paralus, and the
              once ambi- <br/>tious father has sent to beg the maiden’s consent to a union <br/>with
              the now deeply afflicted son. </p>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <p>“ Philothea would not leave me even if I urged it with tears," replied Anaxagoras,
              “and I am forbidden to return to Athens.” </p>
               <p>“ Pericles has provided an asylum for you, on the borders of At- <br/>tica,” answered Plato, “and the young people would soon join <br/>you after their
              marriage. He did not suppose that his former <br/>proud opposition to their loves
              would be forgotten ; but he said <br/>hearts like yours would forgive it all, the more
              readily because he <br/>was now a man deprived of power, and his son suffering under a
              <br/>visitation of the gods. Alcibiades laughed aloud when he heard <br/>of this
              proposition ; and said his uncle would never think of ma- <br/>king it to
              any but a maiden who sees the zephyrs run, and hears <br/>the stars sing. He spoke
              truth in his profane merriment. Peri- <br/>cles knows that she who
              obediently listens to the inward voice, <br/>will be most likely to seek the happiness
              of others, forgetful of her <br/>own wrongs.”</p>
               <p>“ I do not believe the tender hearted maiden ever cherished re- <br/>sentment against any living thing,” replied Anaxagoras. “She <br/>often reminds me
              of Hesiod’s description of Leto:</p>
               <div class="lg">
                  <br/>Placid to men and to immortal gods;
              <br/>Mild from the first beginning of her days;
              <br/>Gentlest of all in Heaven.
            </div>
               <p>She has indeed been a precious gift to my old age. Simple and <br/>loving as she is,
              there are times when her looks and words fill me <br/>with awe, as if I stood in the
              presence of divinity.”</p>
               <p>“It is a most lovely union when the Muses and the Gharitioe <br/>inhabit the same
              temple,” said Plato. “ I think she learned of you <br/>to be a constant worshipper of
              the innocent and graceful nymphs, <br/>who preside over kind and gentle actions. But
              tell me, Anaxago- <br/>ras, if this marriage is declined, who will protect
              the daughter of <br/>Aleimenes when you are gone ?”</p>
               <p>The philosopher replied, “ I have a sister, Helidora, the youngest <br/>of my
              father’s Rock, who is a Priestess of the Sun, at Ephesus.— <br/>Of all my family, she
              has least despised me for preferring philoso- <br/>phy to gold; and report
              bespeaks her wise and virtuous. I have ask- <br/>ed and obtained from her a
              promise to protect Philothea when I am <br/>gone; but I will tell my child the wishes
              of Pericles, and leave her <br/>to the guidance of her own heart. If she enters the
              home of Para- <br/>lus, she will be to him, as she has been to me, a bounty
              like the <br/>sunshine.”</p>
               <p>Philothea assents joyfully to the union, although Chry- <br/>sippus, the
              wealthy prince of Clazomenae, has offered her <br/>his hand. Anaxagoras dies. His
              grand-daughter, attended <br/>by Plato and some female acquaintances, departs for
              Athens <br/>and arrives safely in the harbor of Phalerum. No import- <br/>ant change has occurred in Paralus, who still hows a total <br/>unconsciousness of
              past events. The lovers however, are <br/>united. Many long passages about this
              portion of the narra- <br/>tive are of a lofty beauty. The dreamy,
              distraught, yet, un- <br/>embittered existence of the husband, revelling in
              the visions <br/>of the Platonic philosophy—the anxiety of the father and <br/>his
              friends—the ardent, the pure and chivalric love, with <br/>the uncompromising devotion
              and soothing attentions of the <br/>wife—are pictures of which the rare merit will not
              fail to be <br/>appreciated by all whose opinion Mrs. Child would be likely <br/>to
              value.</p>
               <p>Hippocrates has been informed that Tithonus, the Ethio- <br/>pian,
              possesses the power of leading the soul from the body, <br/>“by means of a soul
              dissecting wand,” and the idea arises <br/>that the process may produce a salutary
              effect upon Paralus. <br/>Tithonus will be present at the Olympian games, and thith-
                <br/>er the patient is conveyed, under charge of Pericles, Plato,
              <br/>and his wife. On the route to Corinth, a letter from Philae- <br/>mon,
              addressed to Anaxagoras, is handed by Artaphernes the <br/>Persian, to Philothea. At
              the close of this letter the writer <br/>expresses a wish to be informed of Eudora’s
              fate, and an <br/>earnest hope that she is not beyond the reach of Philothea’s
              <br/>influence. The travellers finally stop at a small town in the <br/>neighborhood
              of Olympia, and at the residence of Proclus <br/>and his wife Melissa, “worthy
              simple-hearted people with <br/>whom Phidias had died, and under whose protection he
              had <br/>placed his adopted daughter.” The meeting between this <br/>maiden and
              Philothea is full of interest. The giddy heart of <br/>Eudora is chastened by sorrow.
              Phidias had designed her <br/>marriage with his nephew Pandoenus—but her first love is
              not <br/>yet forgotten. A letter is secretly written by Philothea to<br/>
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page344"/>, <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>Philaemon, acquainting him with the change in Eudora’s character, and with
              her unabated affection for himself,— </p>
               <p>“ Sometimes,” she writes,“ a stream is polluted at the foun- <br/>tain and
              its waters are tainted through all its wanderings; <br/>and sometimes the traveller
              throws into a pure rivulet some <br/>unclean thing which floats awhile and then is
              rejected from <br/>its bosom. Eudora is the pure rivulet. A foreign stain <br/>floated
              on its surface, but never mingled with its waters.”</p>
               <p>The efforts of Tithonus are inadequate to the effectual re- <br/>lief of
              Paralus. We quote in full the account of the Ethio- <br/>pian’s attempt.
              Mrs. Child is here, however, partially in- <br/>debted to a statement by
              Clearchus, of an operation some- <br/>what similar to that of Tithonus,
              performed either by the <br/>aid or in the presence of Aristotle. The subject has
              derived <br/>additional interest of late, from the manner in which it has <br/>been
              touched by Hare Townshend and Newnham.</p>
               <p>The relation of Clearchus mentions a diviner with a spirit <br/>drawing wand and a
              youth whose soul was thereby taken from <br/>the body, leaving it inanimate. The soul
              being replaced by <br/>the aid of the magician, the youth enters into a wild account
              <br/>of what befel him during the trance. The passage in “Philo- <br/>thea”
              runs thus :—</p>
               <p>Tithonus stood behind the invalid and remained perfectly <br/>quiet for many minutes.
              He then gently touched the back part of <br/>his head with a small wand, and leaning
              over him, whispered in <br/>his car. An unpleasant change immediately passed over the
              coun- <br/>tenance of Paralus. He endeavored to place his hand on his head,
              <br/>and a cold shivering seized him. Philothea shuddered, and Peri- <br/>cles grew pale, as they watched these symptoms; but the silence <br/>remained
              unbroken. A second and a third time the Ethiopian <br/>touched him with his wand, and
              spoke in whispers. The expres- <br/>sion of pain deepened; insomuch that
              his friends could not look <br/>upon him without anguish of heart. Finally his limbs
              straight- <br/>ened, and became perfectly rigid and motionless.</p>
               <p>Tithonus, perceiving the terror he had excited, said soothingly, </p>
               <p>" O Athenians, be not afraid. I have never seen the soul with- <br/>drawn
              without a struggle with the body. Believe me it will re- <br/>turn. The
              words I whispered, were those I once heard from the <br/>lips of Plato. ‘ The human
              soul is guided by two horses—one <br/>white with a flowing mane, earnest eye, and
              wings like a swan, <br/>whereby he seeks to fly ; but the other is black, heavy, and
              sleepy-eyed--ever prone to lie down upon the earth.’ The second time I whispered, ‘
              Lo, the soul seeketh to ascend !’ And the third lime <br/>I said, ‘Behold the winged
              separates from that which has no <br/>wings.’ When life returns, Paralus will have
              remembrance of <br/>these words.”</p>
               <p>“ Oh, restore him ! restore him !” exclaimed Philothea, in tones of agonised
              intreaty. </p>
               <p>Tithonus answered with respectful tenderness, and again stood <br/>in profound
              silence several minutes, before he raised the wand. <br/>At the first touch, a feeble
              shivering gave indication of returning <br/>life. As it was repeated a second and a
              third lime, with a brief <br/>interval between each movement, the countenance of the
              sufferer <br/>grew more dark and troubled, until it became fearful to look upon.
              <br/>But the heavy shadow gradually passed away, and a dreamy smile <br/>returned like
              a gleam of sunshine after storms. The moment <br/>Philothea perceived an expression
              familiar to her heart, she knelt <br/>by the couch, seized the hand of Paralus, and
              bathed it with her <br/>tears.</p>
               <p>When the first gush of emotion had subsided, she said in a soft, <br/>low voice, “
              Where have you been, dear Paralus?” The invalid <br/>answered, “A thick vapor
              enveloped me, as with a dark cloud; <br/>and a stunning noise pained my head with its
              violence. A voice <br/>said to me, ‘ The human soul is guided by two horses; one
              white, <br/>with a flowing mane, earnest eyes, and wings like a swan, whereby <br/>he
              seeks lo fly; but the other is black, heavy, and sleepy-eyed— <br/>ever prone to lie
              down upon the earth.’ Then the darkness began <br/>to clear away. But there was
              strange confusion. All things <br/>seemed rapidly to interchange their colors and
              their forms—the <br/>sound of a storm was in mine ears—the elements and the stars
              <br/>seemed to crowd upon me—and my breath was taken away. Then <br/>I heard a voice
              saying, ‘ Lo, the soul seeketh to ascend !’ And I <br/>looked and saw the chariot and
              horses, of which the voice again <br/>said, ‘ Behold, the winged separates from that
              which hath no wings!’ <br/>And suddenly the chariot ascended, and I saw the white
              horse on <br/>light, fleecy clouds, in n far blue sky. Then I heard a pleasing
              <br/>silent sound—as if dew-drops made music as they fell. I breathed <br/>freely, and
              my form seemed to expand itself with buoyant life. <br/>All at once I was floating in
              the air above a quiet lake, where re- <br/>posed seven beautiful islands,
              full of the sound of harps; and Phi- <br/>lothea slept at my side, with a garland on
              her head. I asked, ‘ Is <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/> this the divine home whence I departed into the
              body ?’ And a <br/>voice above my head answered : It is the divine home. Man never
              <br/>leaves it. He ceases to perceive. Afterward I looked down- <br/>ward,
              and saw my dead body lying on a couch. Then again there <br/>came strange
              confusion—and a painful clashing of sounds—and <br/>all things rushing together. But
              Philothea look my hand and <br/>spoke to me in gentle tones, and the discord
              ceased.”</p>
               <p>The mind of Paralus derives but a temporary benefit from <br/>the skill of Tithonus,
              and even the attendance of the patient <br/>upon the Olympian games (a suggestion of
              Pericles) fails of <br/>the desired effect. A partial revival is indeed thus brought
              <br/>about—but death rapidly ensues. The friends of the de- <br/>ceased
              return to Athens, accompanied by the adopted daugh- <br/>ter of Phidias.
              Philothea dies. Not many days after the <br/>funeral ceremonies, Eudora suddenly
              disappears. Alci- <br/>biades is suspected (justly) of having entrapped her
              to his <br/>summer residence in Salamis. The pages which follow this <br/>event detail
              the rescue of the maiden by the ingenuity of <br/>two faithful slaves—the discovery of
              her father in Artapher- <br/>nes the Persian, whom she accompanies to the
              court of Ar- <br/>taxerxes—her joyful meeting there and marriage with Phi-
                <br/>laemon, after refusing the proffered hand of Xerxes him- <br/>self.</p>
               <p>In regard to the species of novel of which “ Philothea " is <br/>so fine a specimen,
              we may say that no powers can render <br/>it, at the present day, popular. Nor is the
              voice of the peo- <br/>ple, in this respect, to be adduced as any evidence
              of corrupt- <br/>ed taste. We have little of purely human sympathy in the
              <br/>distantly antique; and what little we have is weakened by <br/>the necessity for
              effort in conceiving appropriateness in man- <br/>ners, habits, costume,
              and modes of thought, so widely at <br/>variance with those around us. The “ Pompeii ”
              of Bulwer <br/>cannot be considered as altogether belonging to the species, <br/>and
              fails in popularity only as it does so belong to it. This <br/>justly admired work
              owes what it possesses of attraction for <br/>the mass, to the stupendousness of its
              leading event—an <br/>event rendered only the more thrillingly interesting by the
              <br/>obscurity which years have thrown over its details—to the <br/>skill with which
              the mind of the reader is prepared for this <br/>event—to the vigor with which it is
              depicted—and to the <br/>commingling with this event human passions wildly affected
              <br/>thereby—passions the sternest of our nature and common to <br/>all character and
              lime. By means so effectual we are <br/>hurried over, and observe not, unless with a
              critical eye, <br/>those radical defects or difficulties (coincident with the
              <br/>choice of epoch) of which we have spoken above. The <br/>fine perception of
              Bulwer endured these difficulties as insep- <br/>arable from the
              ground-work of his narrative—did not mis- <br/>take them for facilities.
              The plot of "Philothea,” like that <br/>of the “ Telemachus’’ and of the “
              Anarcharsts,” should <br/>be regarded, on the other hand, as merely the vehicle for
              <br/>the “antique manners, habits and modes of thought” which <br/>are at variance
              with a popular interest to-day. Regarding <br/>it in this, its only proper light, we
              are justified in speaking of <br/>the work as an honor to our country, and a triumph
              for our <br/>country-women.</p>
               <p>“ Philothea” might be introduced, with advantage, into <br/>our female academies. Its
              purity of thought and elevation <br/>of tone are admirably adapted to scholastic
              purposes. It <br/>would prove an effectual aid in the study of Greek antiquity,
              <br/>with the spirit of which it is wonderfully imbued. We say <br/>wonderfully—for
              the authoress disclaims all knowledge of the <br/>classical tongues. There are some
              points, to be sure, at <br/>which a pedant might cavil—some perversions of the cha-
                <br/>racter of Pericles—of the philosophy of Anaxagoras—and <br/>there
              might be found more than one flaw in the arrangement <br/>of Aspasia’s symposium. On
              the other hand the work af-<br/>
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page345"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>fords evidence of an even intimate acquaintance with the <br/>genius of the
              times, places, and people depicted; and with <br/>the many egregious blunders of so
              fine a scholar as Barthe- <br/>lemi still fresh in our remembrance, it will
              never do to find <br/>fault with a few peccadilloes on the part of Mrs. Child. As
              <br/>a mere narrative, “ Philothea” is, moreover, entitled to high <br/>praise, and
              its exceeding purity of style should especially re- <br/>commend it to the
              attention of teachers.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">NEW BOOKS, AND NEW EDITIONS. An Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy,
              comprising such subjects as are most immediately connected with house-keeping,
              &amp;c., &amp;c.-- Illustrated with nearly one thousand wood cuts. To be completed
              <br/>in twelve numbers at 25 cents. Parts 1, 2, and 3. Harper and Bro- <br/>thers.</div>
               <p>This is unquestionably the most comprehensive work on the <br/>subject of
              Housekeeping, that has ever been undertaken <br/>since the days of Noah, and
              considering the great number <br/>of its illustrations, and their general excellence,
              it must be <br/>pronounced the cheapest. The first part is very properly <br/>devoted
              to architecture, the construction of a house being the <br/>first consideration
              towards house-keeping. The illustrations <br/>are mainly taken from Gwilt, one of the
              most reliable sources <br/>for architectural accuracy, with which we have any acquain-
                <br/>tance. The publishers have very strangely introduced a view <br/>of
              Trinity church in this part, but for what reason we can- <br/>not possibly
              divine. There are plenty of domestic buildings <br/>in Downing’s two books, which
              would have given a much <br/>better idea of an American house than Trinity church. It
              is <br/>greatly to be regretted that in a work of this importance, a <br/>few pages
              and a few designs had not been given to American <br/>houses, types of which may be
              found in great abundance <br/>both in town and country. The view of Wallaton Hall is
              <br/>given without the central pile, which imparts to that re- <br/>markable building its chief characteristic ; there is enough <br/>given, however, to
              enable those who have never seen it to <br/>form some idea of its picturesque beauty.
              The methods of <br/>warming and ventilating houses are peculiarly valuable. <br/>The
              second part is devoted mainly to artificial illumination, <br/>and the third, which is
              most profusely illustrated, to furni- <br/>ture, plate, and upholstery.
              Each part contains more than a <br/>hundred and twenty pages of closely printed matter
              in clear <br/>type, on handsome paper. Every man, when he takes a wife, <br/>should
              also procure a copy of this valuable Encyclopaedia.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <br/>
               <div class="head">Harper's Illuminated and Illustrated Shakspeare. Nos. 53,
              54.</div>
               <p>There are two or three things about this edition of the <br/>great poet especially
              worthy of commendation, although <br/>there are others, which we shall point out next
              week, not <br/>to be passed over without reprehension. We particularly <br/>admire the
              illustrated corn, which is one of the best speci- <br/>men’s of that kind
              of drawing which any of our publishers <br/>have put forth. The present number
              contains “As you Like <br/>it,” entire. The illustrations are very beautiful, well
              con- <br/>ceived, well drawn, and cut with great neatness and preci- <br/>sion. The names of the artists should be given. One of the <br/>points
              which we particularly admire is the good taste of the <br/>editor in choosing the old
              and most correct manner of spel- <br/>ling Shakespeare's name.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">A Treatise on the Knowledge necessary to Amateurs in Pictures.—
              Translated and abridged from the French of M. Francis Zavier de <br/>Burtin, first
              stipendiary member of the Royal Academy of Brus- <br/>sels in the class of
              sciences, &amp;c. By <span class="person">Robert White</span>.</div>
               <p>It contains, indeed, so much of that kind of practical in- <br/>formation
              which amateurs must acquire, either through some <br/>such aid, or through the more
              tedious path of their own indi- <br/>vidual experience, and at the same
              time affords to persons of <br/>more matured taste such an insight into the state of
              con- <br/>noisseurship on the continent, that it is to be wondered that <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>no one has, until now, endeavored to make it more generally <br/>acceptable
              by means of an English version. Although Mr. <br/>Burtin’s work, which was published
              in 1808, at Brussels, <br/>cannot now be considered as new, and makes no pretension
              <br/>to the character of a profound disquisition on the art of <br/>paintings, yet no
              publication of a previous or later date, ad- <br/>dressed itself so
              directly to the wants and wishes of ama- <br/>teurs, or supplies so
              compendious a general view of the sub- <br/>ject of which it treats.</p>
               <div class="ab"> This little volume contains plates after the following paintings.</div>
               <div class="ab">I. Cupid Shaping his Bow.—From Correggio or Parme- giano.</div>
               <div class="ab">II. The Adoration of the Shepherds.—From Poelemburg.</div>
               <div class="ab">III. Fruit Piece.—From Ean Oelst.</div>
               <div class="ab">IV. Village Festival.—From Teniers:</div>
               <div class="ab">The principal subjects of the Treatise are as follows.</div>
               <p>Of the qualities which are required to make a good pic- <br/>ture. How to
              judge pictures. How to judge whether a <br/>picture is in good preservation or not.
              How to know and <br/>appreciate copies. Of the manner of analyzing and describ- <br/>ing pictures. Of the general schools of painting. On the <br/>causes of
              the characteristics which distinguish the different <br/>schools from each other. Of
              the classification of pictures <br/>according to their subjects. On the causes of the
              superiority <br/>of the l6th and 17th centuries over those of the present
              <br/>century. Of the different methods of cleaning pictures and <br/>of restoring
              them. On the public galleries of Paris, Vienna, <br/>Dresden, Duseldorf and
              Munich.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">The Mysteries of Berlin, from the papers of a Berlin Criminal
              officer. Translated from the German by C.B. Burkhardt, with illustrations on Steel by
              P. Habelmann. Part 1st., price 12 1-2 cts. New-York. William H. Colyer. I845.</div>
               <p>This serial is much better printed and illustrated than the <br/>great majority of
              similarly published works. We must read <br/>more than the first number before we can
              form any opinion <br/>of the Berlin mysteries, but they seem to have fallen into
              <br/>suitable hands to present them to English readers.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Wyoming.—A Tale.—No. 50 of Harper’s Library of Select Novels, pp
              124, price 25 cts.</div>
               <p>Wyoming is said to be the production of a lady, and it <br/>certainly contains
              nothing to indicate that it is from the pen <br/>of a man. It is modelled after the
              Cooper-James school, <br/>and, as its name seems to promise, relates the adventures of
              <br/>the early settlers of northern Pennsylvania in ante-revoiution- <br/>ary times.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">The Pictorial History of the World, by <span class="person">John
                Frost</span>, LLD. Nos. 1,2,3, 4. Walker and Gillis. Philadelphia.</div>
               <p>This is among the very best of the numerous illustrated <br/>books that are daily
              issuing from our press ; the cuts, with <br/>but few exceptions, are admirably
              executed from designs <br/>selected with great taste and judgment. Our only regret in
              <br/>respect to them is that they are not original drawings, but <br/> their intrinsic
              value is not a whit diminished by their being <br/>copied from other works which are
              not accessible to the <br/>masses.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Table-talk, by <span class="person">William Hazlitt</span>, part 2d, and
              talcs from the Gesta <br/>Romanorum, or nights with the old story tellers. Nos. 9 and
              10 of <br/>Wiley and Putman’s Library of choice reading.</div>
               <p>The table talk is better known to our reading public than <br/>the Gesta Romanorum,
              but both books will be alike accep- <br/>table to those who will form their
              first acquaintance with <br/>them in the form that they are here presented in. It
              would <br/>be difficult to find pleasanter or better reading for a summer<br/>
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page346"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>afternoon. We have extracted a short story from the Gesta Romanorum in
              another part of our journal. </p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">The Battle of the Factions, and other tales of Ireland, by
                <span class="person">William Carleton,</span> with engravings. Price 25 cts.
              Philadelphia. Carey &amp; <br/>Hart.</div>
               <p>The author of these stories enjoys a better reputation in <br/>his own country than
              in ours, while the case with Lever, <br/>and Maxwell, is reversed. The reason is that
              Carleton is <br/>more true to nature than the other Irish Romancists; and from <br/>a
              similar cause, Sam Slick was infinitely more popular in <br/>England than in
              America.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Harper’s Pictorial Bible. No. 27.</div>
               <p>The present number is, in every respect, a fitting com- <br/>panion to
              those that have gone before it. In some of the lit- <br/>tle vignettes we
              perceive, or at least think that we do, the <br/>hand of a new cutter. The
              illustrations of the 14th and 19th <br/>chapters of Isaiah, are exceedingly neat and
              spirited.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Dashes at Life with a free pencil, by <span class="person">N. P.
                Willis</span>. Part 1st. High <br/>Life in Europe and American Life. New-York.
              Published by J. <br/>S. Redford.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">The Blind Girl, with other tales, by <span class="person">Emma C.
                Embury</span>. Harper &amp; <br/>Brothers. A new and neat Edition of some of
              Mrs. Embury’s most <br/>popular stories.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Philothea, a Grecian Romance, by <span class="person">L. Maria
                Child</span>. A new correct- ed edition. C. L. Francis &amp; Co. 252
              Broadway.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Night and Morning, by <span class="person">Sir E. L. Bulwer</span>, 2
              Vols. in one. No. 10 of Harper’s Pocket Edition of Select Novels.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">No Cross, No Crown, a discourse showing the nature and discipline
              <br/>of the Holy Cross of Christ, &amp;c. &amp;c., to which are added the living
              <br/>and dying testimonies of many persons of fame and learning, both of <br/>ancient
              and modern times, in favor of this treatise, in two parts. <br/>By <span class="person">William
                Penn</span>. New-York. Collins, Brothers, &amp; Co. 1845.</div>
            </div>
         </div>
                  
        <div>
            <div class="head">THE MAGAZINES.</div>
            <p>The only Magazine of the better class which has reached <br/>us, for June, is the
            Knickerbocker, which has an unusually <br/>good table of contents. It contains a long
            and well-written <br/>criticism on the young English poetry, from the pen of Mr.
            <br/>Bristed, a grandson of John Jacob Astor’s, of whose scholar- <br/>ship
            we have often heard most extravagant reports. The <br/>Knickerbocker also contains an
            original poem by Tennyson, <br/>which the editor received from the same gentleman.</p>
            <p>The Blackwood for May has been issued by Leonard Scott &amp; Co., Fulton street.</p>
        </div>

        <div>
            <div class="head">MUSICAL REVIEW. The Glee Club Companion, containing a selection of Glees, Catches,
            <br/>Trios and Duetts, from the best English composers. Published by <br/>F. Riley, 297
            Broadway, N. Y.</div>
            <p>We have had occasion to remark several times the <br/>increasing love for vocal
            part-music among the young men <br/>of this city ; we do so again and with sincere
            satisfaction, <br/>for a taste formed by the practice of good compositions is <br/>sure
            to be well grounded, and is almost certain to lead to a <br/>fine perception of the
            beautiful in every class of music. The <br/>popularity which several of the Amateur Glee
            Clubs have <br/>gained in the best classes of society in this city and in Brook- <br/>lyn, cannot fail, by arousing emulation, to give a powerful <br/>impetus
            to the tide which is now setting in the right way. </p>
            <p>
               <br/>Glee Books of any worth are very scarce, not more than <br/>one or two
            collections, and these but limited, being publish- <br/>ed. The market is, to
            be sure, positively glutted with mise- <br/>rably printed, inconvenient, namby pamby,
            trashy “collec- <br/>tions,” which no teacher of any knowledge or taste,
            would <br/>recommend to his pupils for practice. The collections of <br/>German Glees
            published in this city, contain a large amount<br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>of exquisite music by the first
            writers of Germany. The en- <br/>terprize in producing such works is truly
            praiseworthy. <br/>There are two German collections ; one published in very
            <br/>excellent style by F. P. Dyer, Hudson st.; the other we have <br/>not seen. But,
            beautiful as these glees are, a constant prac- <br/>tice of them will be sure
            to induce a hard, constrained, and <br/>mechanical method of singing. They are charming
            in mel- <br/>ody and rich in harmony, but they are, for the most part,<br/>
            simply harmonized airs. </p>
            <p>Not so the glees before us. These are not inferior to the <br/>German glees either in
            melody or in harmony, while as com- <br/>positions they rank far above them.
            In fact the English <br/>Glees form a school of music entirely peculiar to England :
            <br/>no other nation possesses the same class of music, or if they <br/>do, only in an
            inferior degree. The English Glees are gene- <br/>rally found to consist of
            two, three, or more movements, all <br/>carrying out one clear and broad design, and
            they are dis- <br/>tinguished by the beautiful simplicity of their melody,
            the <br/>richness and clearness of their harmony, and the freedom <br/>and vigor of
            their counterpoint. There cannot be found any <br/>compositions more beautiful, in the
            whole range of vocal <br/>music, than many of the four and five-voiced glees by Web- <br/>ber, Horsly, Calcott, Mornington, Bishop, &amp;c. &amp;c. Besides,<br/>the
            class of glees now under notice does not require such an <br/>incessant strain upon the
            extreme parts—1st tenor and 2d <br/>bass—as is the case with the German Glees; they are
            in <br/>fact more truly vocal.</p>
            <p>There are many beautiful glees in Riley’s collection, such <br/>as “Here in cool Grot
            and Mossy Cell,” “Peace to the <br/>Souls of the Heroes,” “O ! happy Fair your Eves are
            Load- <br/>stars,” “ The Friars,” &amp;c. &amp;c.; beside some capital
            duetts,<br/>catches, and rounds. We can recommend the Glee Club <br/>Companion to all
            our glee singing friends, as a work select, <br/>if not extensive; well got up, and very
            cheap.</p>
        </div>
                  
        <div>
            <div class="head">MUSICAL ITEMS.</div>
            <p>We are positively to have a French Opera at the Park in a <br/>few weeks. Its success
            will be, we feel assured, quite com- <br/>plete. The company is stronger than
            any we have seen here, <br/>and comprises both beauty and talent. The school of music
            <br/>too, is, to our taste, much, very much superior to the modern <br/>Italian music so
            hackneyed now on every hand. We shall <br/>be glad to find it better known and
            appreciated by the public.</p>
            <p>That most delightful of all summer resorts, Niblo’s Gar- <br/>den, opens
            next Monday. There will be an English Vaude- <br/>ville Company in addition
            to the attractions of the locality. <br/>We have not heard anything positive respecting
            the engage- <br/>ments made, but we presume as Mr. Chippendale is the man-
              <br/>ager, he will gather around him a strong and attractive com- <br/>pany. We shall be glad to see the place thronged as it al- <br/>ways has been with the beauty and the fashion of the city.</p>
            <p>The season at Castle Garden can scarcely be said to have <br/>begun, for the weather
            has been so wretchedly unpropitious <br/>since it opened, that the attractions of that
            lovely spot have <br/>not as yet been fairly tested.</p>
            <p>It is understood that the Italians are engaged to appear, <br/>with a whole host of
            novelties of an attractive nature. All <br/>those who really enjoy music, society, pure
            air and lovely <br/>scenery, should visit Castle Garden often.</p>
            <p>Madl’le Borghese, it is said, will be on here this summer <br/>her intention of
            visiting Mexico having been abandoned in <br/>consequence of not being able to form a
            full company. It is <br/>more than probable that Mr. Krev’s Opera, if successful in
            <br/>Philadelphia, will be produced here within a short time.</p>
            <p>We hear of a Concert, upon a grand scale, to be given ve- <br/>ry shortly.
            The performance will consist of a Sacred Drama, <br/>never before given in this city.
            The composer is Carl Lowe, <br/>and the music is of a high order and so full of melody
            that its <br/>popularity is certain. The best talent of the City will be<br/>
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page347"/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>engaged, the chorus will not only be large but efficient, and <br/>every
            thing will be conducted on a scale of liberality which <br/>cannot fail to meet with
            public approbation and support.— <br/>We shall be able to speak more positively in our
            next <br/>number.</p>
        </div>
        <div>
            <div class="head">TO LENORE.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Oh ! fragile and fair as the delicate chalices,
            <br/>
               <br/>Wrought with so rare and so subtle a skill,
            <br/>
               <br/>Bright relics, that tell of the pomp of those palaces
            <br/>
               <br/>Venice—the sea-goddess—glories in still!
            <br/>Their exquisite texture, transparent and tender,
            <br/>A pure blush alone from the ruby vine takes:
            <br/>
               <br/>Yet ah! if some false hand, profaning its splendor,
            <br/>
               <br/>Dares but to taint it with poison,—it breaks!
            <br/>So when Love poured thro thy pure heart his lightning,
            <br/>On thy pale cheek, the soft rose-hues awoke;—
            <br/>So when wild Passion, that timid heart frightening,
            <br/>Poisoned the treasure,—it trembled and broke !
          </div>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">CLARICE</span>.</div>
        </div>

        <div>
            <div class="head">DELIGHTFUL SIGHTS.</div>
            <p>New-York can boast of more charming pictures, tableaux <br/>vivants, than any other
            city in the world. The assertion is a <br/>very broad one, but we believe that nobody
            who has been <br/>over the world, will deny its truth. Since the season has fair- <br/>ly become sunny and natural, and the streets intolerably dusty, <br/>and
            uncomfortable, the most delightful sights are to be seen <br/>on the water. The Bay has
            been unusually lively during the <br/>past week. A few days since as we were crossing
            one of the <br/>lower ferries, our eyes lighted upon the most showy tableaux <br/>of
            sea-grouping that they had ever been gladdened by. On one <br/>hand lay the majestic
            three-decker North Carolina, the beau- <br/>tiful Sicilian frigate, a revenue
            Cutter, and a host of smaller <br/>craft; and on the other side were the stately
            Columbus, the <br/>corvette Vincennes, and a crowd of East river sloops, inter- <br/>mingled with a Liverpool packet and a dozen small steam- <br/>ers ; the large Sound-boats, Narragansett, Rhode-Island, and <br/>Worcester, came
            plunging their vast white bodies with <br/>a multitude of human beings on their upper
            decks, and <br/>setting everything afloat in commotion by the waves raised <br/>by their
            huge paddles. A tow-boat from Philadelphia with <br/>a long string of barges in her
            wake, and another from Al- <br/>bany, looking like a floating village, came
            along at the same <br/>moment, and filled up the picture, when suddenly there dart- <br/>ed out from among the apparently inextricable mass of float- <br/>ing worlds, a little fairy looking yacht, with “ Ospray” em- <br/>blazoned on her stern, and with sails that sat like a new <br/>coat on a
            dandy. The wind was brisk and for a moment <br/>appearances threatened a general crash,
            but there proved to be <br/>sea room enough, and each bark went on its way rejoicing,
            <br/>throwing the spray like snow-drifts all over the broad Bay.</p>
            <p>There is always something to be seen worth a walk down <br/>to the Battery, besides the
            new Opera House. The corpora- <br/>tion owe it to the inhabitants of the city
            to introduce two or <br/>three fountains into the Battery, and then it would be with-
              <br/>out a rival in the world. The Park is always pleasant, tho’ <br/>just
            now dusty ; one day this week, with all its green trees, <br/>and fountain and sun
            shine, it looked sad enough; a poor <br/>gentleman, weary of the world, selected this
            spot to blow out <br/>his brains in. Crossing over from Broadway to Chatham <br/>street,
            in the rear of the Hall, we heard the report of a pis- <br/>tol, and, turning
            our head, saw at a few paces off, a <br/>well-dressed man fall to the ground. The poor
            man's name <br/>was Wilson, his profession was the law, and pecuniary trou- <br/>ble is said to have caused the deed.</p>
        </div>




                 <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/> 
        <div>
            <div class="head">NATIVE TALENT VS. FOREIGN TALENT.</div>
            <p>The following observances apply with so much force to <br/>the violent and exclusive
            principle, which has been so broad- <br/>ly laid down, in reference to
            “American Artists,” “Ameri- <br/>can Poets,” “American Native talent,”
            &amp;c. that we can with <br/>great propriety give them a place in our columns. They
            <br/>are selected from an European, continental journal. The <br/>origin however, of the
            article we have nothing to do with— <br/>it is the truth and the force of the remarks to
            which we claim <br/>attention. We assume that taste and talent, in music, in
            <br/>paintings, in writing, &amp;c. whatever be their origin or birth- <br/>place, belongs to the whole world. We can rarely listen to a <br/>speech in congress,
            to a lecture upon any subject, by an Amer- <br/>ican, or read any American
            work upon the Arts, in which we <br/>do not find a laboured effort to show forth the
            vast strength <br/>and beauty of Native American talent. It is in bad taste, and
            <br/>about as appropriate, as if a comely youth possessing nature’s <br/>finest personal
            graces were to stand in Broadway and lay <br/>claim to the admiration of all passers by,
            in order to distin- <br/>guish him from the vulgar or less prepossessing
            multitude.</p>
            <p>These observations apply especially lo the literature of <br/>our country, and perhaps
            with as much justice to the works <br/>of art.</p>
            <p>From a Hamburgh paper, respecting an Architectural competition we copy the following: </p>
            <p>“Is it true patriotism to prefer the design of a native artist, <br/>excellent though
            it be, when confessedly less corres- <br/>pondent than that of another, to
            the true genius of German <br/>architecture? The English are not thus limited in their
            <br/>views. It is well known that M. de Chateauneauf received <br/>one of the prizes in
            the competition for the new London Ex- <br/>change. It is a spurious
            patriotism that would give to our <br/>whole city a church of an inferior design, merely
            that we <br/>might bestow our patronage (?) on one of its inhabitants.— <br/>The love of
            our country, the love of German art in its most <br/>sublime and most significant sense,
            speaks most unquestion- <br/>ably for the design of the English architect,
            who, deriving his <br/>inspiration from the genius of Germany, has entered with
            <br/>love into his work, and given us what pre-eminently belongs <br/>to us—the purest
            Gothic form—the national architecture of <br/>our father-land. Let us away then with the
            petty patronage, <br/>that has no fellowship with the beautiful, but to envy it.—
            <br/>Follow, rather, the better example.”</p>
        </div>

        <div>
            <div class="head">LITERARY GOSSIP.</div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">THOMAS HOOD.</div>
               <p>“It is the heaviest stone melancholy can throw at a man,” says <br/>old Fuller, “ to
              tell him that he is at the end of his being; a truth, <br/>which excellent, witty,
              stout-hearted Thomas Hood has been rather <br/>playing with as a football or
              shuttlecock any time these ten years <br/>than receiving as so gloomy a missive. But
              alas, the time for skir- <br/>mishing with so severe au antagonist, seems
              welll nigh over, and <br/>Hood, with the certainty of immediate death before him, is
              receiving <br/>from friends and the press, those honors which are too often withheld
              <br/>for posterity and the “ dull cold ear.” A late number of the maga- <br/>zine which be has just established, announces his approaching disso- <br/>lution, and commends him as a very great author. His merits will <br/>appear to us
              the greater when the light is withdrawn and we sit in <br/>darkness. A writer starts
              up to amuse and enlighten us through the <br/>press—day after day, month after month,
              he pours out an unceasing <br/>flow of jests, and sentiment, and wisdom ; we take the
              gift, and never <br/>look for the giver : it seems a matter of course that the morning
              paper <br/>should be wise and witty, just as the morning sun is expected to shine.
              <br/>But little reputation is formed in this benevolent and beneficial way. <br/>But
              let a pompous author time his appearance with a due attention to <br/>self and his own
              want of power, and come forward in au octavo, we <br/>hail the man. We are willing to
              praise the one, but we cannot live <br/>without the other. This is the difference, but
              the honor should be <br/>more wisely distributed.</p>
               <br/>
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page348"/>

               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <p>How Hood has borne up against the inroads of a long disease, the <br/>consumption,
              let him tell us himself in a passage of his mirthful phi- <br/>losophy
              written in 1839—the very fingers so aristocratically slender, <br/>that now hold the
              pen, hint plainly of the ‘ills that flesh is heir <br/>to;’ my coats have become
              great-coats, my pantaloons have been <br/>turned into trowsers, and, by a worse
              bargain than Peter Schlemihl’s <br/>I seem to have retained my shadow and sold my
              substance. In short, <br/>as happens to prematurely old port wine, I am of a bad color
              with <br/>very little body. But what then ? That emaciated hand still lends a
              <br/>hand to embody words, and sketches the creations and recreations of a <br/>Merry
              Faney: those gaunt sides yet shake heartily as ever at the <br/>Grotesques and
              Arabesques, and dull Picturesques that my Good Ge- <br/>nius (a
              Pantagruelian familiar) charitably conjures up to divert me <br/>from more sombre
              realities. * * * * The raven croaked,<br/>but I persuaded myself that it was the
              nightingale : there was the <br/>smell of the mould, but I remembered that it
              nourished the violets.” <br/>There was faith and a sound heart there. It was not for
              nothing. <br/>Since that day Hood has written some of his best verses, his quaintest
              <br/>stories are his most philanthropic appeals. English readers and En- <br/>glish hearts will not soon forget them. If Hood revives once more,
              <br/>he will be a sacred man while he lives. The sympathy of the good is <br/>with
              him. We trust we are violating no courtesy of private life while <br/>we quote from a
              letter received by the last steamer, from a source <br/>which adds pathos to every
              line, if that were necessary :</p>
               <p>" Poor Hood is dying—in a state of perfect preparation and compo- <br/>sure, among the tears of his friends. His disease has been consump- <br/>tion—is, in fact—but the crisis is combined with water on the chest, <br/>which is
              expected to bring death. To a friend who asked him the <br/>other morning how it was
              with him, he answered with a characteristic <br/>playful pathos, “ The tide is
              rising—and I shall soon he in port.” It <br/>is said of him, that he has no regrets
              for life, except for the unborn <br/>works which he feels striving impotently in his
              dying brain—a species <br/>of regret which is peculiarly affecting to me, as it must
              be to all who <br/>understand it: also it is plain to me that he has genius greater
              than <br/>anything he has produced—and if this is plain and sad to us, how
              <br/>profoundly melancholy it must be to him. The only comfort is that <br/>the end of
              development is not here. Sir Robert Peel wrote a long let- <br/>ter to him
              lately in a tone of respect and consideration, which was <br/>honorable to the
              minister, and relieved him from becoming anxiety <br/>by attaching his pension to the
              life of his wife rather than to bis own. <br/>Poor Hood and poor Sydney Smith ! How we
              are losing our Yoricks !<br/>' all dumb’—‘ all gone !’ ”</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">The Author or Eothen.</div>
               <p>—The correspondent of the Knicker- <br/>bocker in Constantinople, says
              that Eothen gives the best description <br/>of Constantinople of any book of travels
              that have been published, and <br/>that the author’s name is White.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">An American gentleman who has lately returned from Europe,</div>
               <p>
                  <br/>brings with him the following anecdote of Tennyson. At a German <br/>inn he met
              with an Englishman remarkable in a three-fold manner; <br/>for his appearance, which
              was interesting and striking—for his con- <br/>versation, which was
              markedly peculiar—and for his hat, which, for <br/>the length of time it had been
              ignorant of a nap, might have balanced <br/>the seven sleepers in the economy of
              nature. One day the two stran- <br/>gers were put into the same vehicle to
              visit a ruin or a waterfall, and, <br/>then, for the first time, the Englishman
              discovered that his companion <br/>was an American. Upon learning this, he drew a note
              book from his <br/>pocket, and taking from it a copy in MS. of “ Tennyson’s Mariana in
              <br/>the Moated Grange,” asked the American if he had ever seen it. <br/>“ Certainly,”
              was the reply ; “ I am very familiar with it.” “ But is <br/>Tennyson much esteemed in
              America ?” “ He is admired by all whose <br/>admiration is an honor.” “ Is he ?”
              exclaimed the Englishman, with <br/>boyish delight glowing from his face, “ Why, I ’m
              Tennyson !”</p>
               <p>The anecdote is highly characteristic of Tennyson ; he appears to <br/>be in the
              habit of showing his poems in manuscript to his acquaintan- <br/>ces. The
              last number of the Knickerbocker contains a poem which an <br/>American gentleman in
              England obtained from him in this manner. <br/>As it has never appeared before in
              print, we copy it for its novelty.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <br/>
               <div class="head">MY EARLY LOVE.</div>
               <div class="lg">
                  <br/>Oh that it were possible.
              <br/>After long years of pain,
              <br/>To find the arms of my true love
              <br/>Around me once again !
              <br/>When I was wont to meet her
              <br/>
                  <br/>In the silent woody places
              <br/>
                  <br/>Of the land that gave us birth,
              <br/>We stood tranced in long embraces,
              <br/>Mixed with kisses sweeter, sweeter
              <br/>Than any thing on earth !
              <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>A shadow flits before me.
              <br/>Not thou, but like to thee
              <br/>Oh, Christ ! that it were possible,
              <br/>For one short hour, to see
              <br/>
                  <br/>The souls we love, that they might tell us
              <br/>
                  <br/>What and where they be !
              <br/>
                  <br/>It leads me forth at evening.
              <br/>And lightly winds and steals
              <br/>In a cold white robe before me,
              <br/>When all my spirit reels
              <br/>At the shouts, the leagues of light,
              <br/>The roaring of the wheels !
              <br/>Half the night I waste in sighs,
              <br/>Half in dreams I sorrow alter
              <br/>The hand, the lip, the eyes,
              <br/>The winsome laughter;
              <br/>And I hear the pleasant ditty
              <br/>That I heard her chaunt of old ;
              <br/>But I wake—my dream is fled !
              <br/>Without knowledge, without pity,
              <br/>In the shuddering gray behold,
              <br/>By the curtains of my bed,
              <br/>That dreadful phantom cold.
              <br/>Pass, thou death-like type of pain !
              <br/>
                  <br/>Pass, and cease to move about :
              <br/>
                  <br/>'Tis the blot upon the brain,
              <br/>That will show itself without.
              <br/>Now I rise ; the eave-drops fall,
              <br/>And the yellow vapors choke
              <br/>The great city sounding wide ;
              <br/>Day comes ; a dull red ball
              <br/>In a drift of lurid smoke,
              <br/>O’er the misty river tide.
              <br/>Through the hubbub of the market
              <br/>I steal a wasted frame ;
              <br/>It crosseth here, it crosseth there,
              <br/>Through all that crowd confused and loud,
              <br/>That shadow still the some;
              <br/>And on my heavy eyelids
              <br/>My anguish hangs like shame.
              <br/>Alas ! for her that met me,
              <br/>That heard me softly call,
              <br/>Came glimmering through the laurels,
              <br/>At the quiet evening full,
              <br/>In the garden by the terrace
              <br/>Of the old memorial hall.
              <br/>The broad light glares and heats,
              <br/>And the sunk eve flits and fleets,
              <br/>And will not let me be ;
              <br/>I loathe the squares and streets,
              <br/>And the faces that one meets,
              <br/>Hearts with no love for me ;
              <br/>Only I long to creep
              <br/>To some still cavern deep,
              <br/>And weep, and weep, and weep
              <br/>My whole soul out to thee .'
            </div>
            </div>
        </div>

        <div>
            <div class="head">MISCELLANEA.</div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Anastatic Printing.</div>
               <p>—We extract the following inter- <br/>esting particulars in regard to
              Anastatic Printing, from Ap- <br/>pleton’s Literary Bulletin.</p>
               <p>On the 25th ult., I attended a Lecture at the Royal Institution, <br/>by Prof.
              Faraday, on the Philosophy of the Anastatic Process of <br/>Printing, in which all the
              details of the practice were explained <br/>and exhibited. The principle rests on some
              of the properties of the <br/>articles employed: “as water attracts water, oil oil,
              though they <br/>mutually repel each other. Metals are much more easily welted
              <br/>with oil than with water; but they may readily be moistened by a <br/>weak
              solution of gum, and still more when a portion of phos- <br/>phoric acid is
              added.” (The lecturer here alluded to some re- <br/>markable investigations
              recently made on these phenomena, by <br/>Prof. Henry, of Princeton, N.J.) To these
              properties of oil, <br/>water, and the metals, may be added, as one of the principles
              of <br/>the Anastatic Process, the readiness with which part of the ink <br/>of any
              newly printed book, &amp;c., can be transferred by pressure to <br/>any smooth
              surface, an effect well known to bookbinders. The <br/>subject to be copied is first
              moistened with diluted nitric acid, the <br/>superfluous moisture pressed out between
              folds of bibulous paper, <br/>and then pressed with sufficient force in a rolling
              press on a <br/>sheet of clean polished zinc. The acid etches the metal, and the
              <br/>printed portion is left slightly in relief. The principles above <br/>stated are
              now brought into operation. The zinc plate is washed <br/>with a weak solution of gum
              and phosphatic acid, by which the <br/>etched surface is completely welled, while that
              portion to which <br/>the ink has adhered remains perfectly dry. An inked roller is
              now <br/>passed over the surface, inking only those parts untouched by the <br/>water
              ; the strung repulsion between the oily and watery surfaces <br/>preserves the design
              in the clearest manner. In this condition of <br/>the plate impressions can be taken
              in the same manner as from<br/>
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page349"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>lithographic stone, nnd as many as three thousand impressions <br/>have
              been when without any deterioration being apparent. Should, <br/>however, the
              impressions yielded prove deficient in clearness, it is <br/>only necessary to wash
              the zinc plate with turpentine, when it is <br/>immediately restored to its pristine
              condition. Old books, in which <br/>the ink has become hardened, are first soaked in a
              solution of pot- <br/>ass, and then of tartaric acid, producing the
              bitartrate of potass; <br/>this permeating the texture of the paper, resists oil, and
              the ink- <br/>roller passed over its surface, the ink only adheres to the
              printed <br/>parts. The tartrate is then washed out, and the copy proceeded <br/>with
              as before, commencing with the nitric acid.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="head">We made an announcement a few months back of a vol- <br/>ume in
              preparation,</div>
               <p>by the American Ethnological Society; <br/>from the following intelligence in the
              Bulletin, it appears to <br/>be nearly ready for publication.</p>
               <p>The American Ethnological Society, of which the Hon. Albert <br/>Gallatin is
              President, will publish in a few days the first volume <br/>of its “ Transactions,” in
              one large octavo volume. This work <br/>will consist of articles by members of the
              Society, relating to vari- <br/>ous topics of interest to the Antiquary and
              Philologist. The first <br/>article, filling more than half the volume, is by the
              venerable Presi- <br/>dent of the Society, on Ancient Mexico, its History,
              Chronology, <br/>Language, Civilization, &amp;c., including an analysis of Lord Kings-
                <br/>borough’s great work. Mr. Schoolcraft has “an Essay on the
              <br/>Grave Creek mound of Virginia.” Mr. Turner a “Dissertation <br/>on the Himyaritic
              Inscriptions lately discovered in Southern <br/>Arabia,” together with notices of the
              Ancient Hamyatites. Mr. <br/>Catherwood has an article giving an account of his visit
              to the site <br/>of ancient Carthage, with a particular account of the Lybia- <br/>Phoenician Monument at Dugga. The volume will contain nu- <br/>merous engravings, price $2 50. Copies may be obtained through <br/>D. Appleton
              &amp; Co.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Piano Fortes.</div>
               <p>—We mentioned a week or two since, a <br/>very fine toned and mahogany cased piano,
              made by J. H. <br/>Chambers, 385 Broadway. We spoke of it in terms of strong
              <br/>praise, because it deserved it in every way, and we refer to <br/>it now simply
              to inform those who are in want of a piano, that <br/>Mr. Chambers has now in his
              store a fac-simile of the very <br/>instrument we then praised. It is worth calling at
              the store <br/>if only to see its form and hear its tone.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">The Last Piece, or the Le Morceau Honteux.</div>
               <p>—A public <br/>story-teller related an anecdote of two or three persons being in
              <br/>company where a simple piece of cake had long defied all ap- <br/>proach, from the circumstance of its being the last piece in the <br/>dish. It so
              happened, however, that the candle was accidentally <br/>extinguished, when each of
              the party immediately encountered the <br/>hand of his neighbor on the devoted
              morsel.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">The editor of the Knickerbocker</div>
               <p>announces in his “ Editor’s Table” <br/>a volume, which, in its externals, will be
              all that could be desired, to <br/>be entitled “ Old Knick’s Sketch Book, or the
              Omissions and Com <br/>missions, Fore-thoughts and after-thoughts, of the last fifteen
              years <br/>to be published by Burgess, Stringer &amp; Co. We have no very clear
              <br/>idea of what the work will be, but should infer from the title that it <br/>will
              be made up from the amusing contents of the “ Editor’s Table.”</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Douglas Gerold’s idea or Conservatives.</div>
               <p>—There’s a sort of peo- <br/>ple in the world that can’t bear making any
              progress. I wonder they <br/>ever walk, unless they walk backwards ! I wonder they
              don’t refuse <br/>to go out when there’s a new moon—and all out of love and respect
              for <br/>that “ ancient institution,” the old one. But there always were such
              <br/>people, and always will be. When lucifers first came in, how many <br/>old women,
              staunch old souls—many of them worthy to be members <br/>of parliament—stood by their
              matches and tinder boxes, and cried out <br/>“ no surrender!" And how many of these
              old women—disguised in <br/>small attire—every day go about at public meetings,
              professing to be <br/>ready to die for any tinder-box question that may come up! Yes,
              <br/>ready, quite ready to die for it; all the readier, perhaps, because dy- <br/>ing for any thing of the sort’s gone out of fashion.”</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Births, Deaths, and MaRriages.</div>
               <p>—Within the past three <br/>weeks the New Wordl weekly paper has died, the Plebeian,
              daily, <br/>has been married to the Morning News, and the Alleghanian, <br/>weekly,
              has been born. The first of these journals was an admi- <br/>rable paper
              from the beginning, the only bad thing about it was<br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>its name, which was very
              good per se. as Captain Tyler says, but <br/>quite inapplicable, the contents of the
              paper being mainly extract- <br/>ed from the Old World ; the cause of its
              untimely departure from <br/>this sorrowing world we have never learned. The newly bom
              <br/>“ Alleghenian " has a very pleasant appearance, and we hope will <br/>live to
              bless the day that gave it birth.</p>
               <p>The death (we beg the printer not to make this word rend <br/>dearth) of newspapers
              is a subject full of matter for an article, and <br/>we intend to enlarge upon it by
              and by, after we have collected a <br/>sufficient amount of statistics. All men are
              born to die, but some <br/>newspapers seem born for immortality, they live in an
              atmosphere <br/>of eternal sun-shine and prosperity; while others, like young
              <br/>cauliflowers and other tender vegetables, are nipped by the frost <br/>in the
              first year of their existence.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">The Consequerces of Curtailment.</div>
               <p>—A London paper contains <br/>the following: “Messrs Chalcn, Stanfield, Leslie,
              Ceristail, Stump <br/>and Ward, have left in the ship Victoria for New York,it is
              under- <br/>stood, to paint the Hall of Congress of the United States.
              There were <br/>a large number of persons to see them off. They left on the 20th.”</p>
               <p>The indignation this called forth was particularly frightful—the <br/>loss of the
              whole region of Oregon, on both sides of the Columbia <br/>river, was as nothing
              compared to the insult thus offered by Congress <br/>to American artists. We met with
              the paragraph in the course of <br/>our porings over foreign files, and really it
              excited neither alarm or as- <br/>tonishment, because we happened to read
              to the end. The paragraph <br/>concluded thus, and clearly proved the joke—“ and
              returned the same <br/>evening to London, having gone no further than Gravesend.”</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">The “ Dashes at Life "</div>
               <p>by Mr. Willis were received at so <br/>late a period, that we have been unable to do
              more than an- <br/>nounce it. We shall, of course, speak of it very fully
              hereafter. Our opinion of Mr. Willis is well known. </p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">The beautiful “Unseen River,”</div>
               <p>published in this week’s Jour- <br/>nal, is the composition of Henry B.
              Hirst. We extract it, by <br/>permission, from a volume of forthcoming poems.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">The Largest Letter in the World.</div>
               <p>—Mr. John R. Peters, <br/>junr., who accompanied the American Embassy to China,
              strived <br/>this morning in the ship Bazaar, and informs us that the Emperor <br/>of
              the Celestial dominions has written a letter, in the Chinese and <br/>Mantchon
              languages, to the President of the United States, which is <br/>six feet long by three
              feet wide ! Mr. Peters saw the letter. It <br/>is written on yellow paper, enclosed in
              a yellow silk case, and is <br/>now in the hands of Dr Parker for translation. It is
              expected that <br/>it will be sent home in the next ship.</p>
               <p>No one can imagine what gratification we feel in communicating <br/>this intelligence
              to the President, that functionary having hereto- <br/>fore borne away the
              palm for long messages. Though we have <br/>“ licked the Britishers, who licked the
              world,” it is not improba- <br/>ble that the Emperor of China has “licked”
              us by out-presidenting <br/>the President. At any rate Mr. Polk will have this
              consolation— <br/>the reading of the document and the necessary reflection thereupon,
              <br/>will be a task weighty enough to excuse his being “ at home,” to <br/>those who
              still pester him about office. By the way might he not, <br/>with great propriety,
              create a new office—that of reader of the <br/>Emperor of China’s letters ? Verily it
              would bo no sinecure.</p>
               <p>But this long epistle is not the only great thing emanating from <br/>the empire of
              China. Mr. Peters has brought home the largest col- <br/>lection of Chinese
              curiosities yet made, exceeding, we are told, <br/>even that made by the late Mr.
              Dunn. We are not informed <br/>whether any measures will be taken to gratify the
              curiosity which <br/>this information will excite.</p>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="head">Pippin.</div>
               <p>—This word is derived, by Dr. Johnson, from puppynghe <br/>[Dutch]; but it is surely
              more reasonable to suppose it, with other <br/>etymologists, from Pepin, the king of
              the country from whence <br/>the fruit is derived ; as " filberd," from Philibert of
              Franee ; while <br/>the “ rennett ” apple is la reinette, or the “little queen;" as
              the <br/>“ geniting” is from Janeton, or Jeannetin, in honor of some queen <br/>or
              lady of that name. The “ Bigoroon " cherry is so called from <br/> "Bigorre, the
              French province where it is grown; as the original <br/>word “ cherry ” is from
              Cerasus, in Asia Minor; while “may <br/>duke” cherry derives its name from Medoc, in
              Burgundy. The <br/>brown “ bury ’’ pear is so named from its buttered or melting qual-
                <br/>ity [beurre]; the ‘“Colmor” pear is from Colmar, in Alsace; and
              <br/>the “ Cnisse-madame " pear, from its figure. The “ arline ” is <br/>corruption
              from Orleans; the “ currant ” is the grape of Corinth; <br/>and the “ damson ”
              [properly damascene] is the plum of Da- <br/>mascus. Menage considers “
              melon ” as a large apple, and derives<br/>
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page350"/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>t from the Latin and Greek. If esculent vegetables may be no- <br/>ticed, the “ Jerusalem artichoke" is a curious instance of the corrup-
                <br/>tion of language, it being the sunflower artichoke, or girasole,
              [the <br/>plant turning to the sun,] “ Jerusalem ” being thus corrupted from
              <br/>girasole. Not less remarkable is “ John Dory ” [the fish] as a <br/>corruption of
              il janitore, or, 'the door-keeper for that fish being <br/>called, on the Italian
              coast, by the name of St. Peter, and he being <br/>supposed to be the door-keeper of
              heaven, and therefore called il <br/>janitore by our sailors, we thus derived the term
              of John Dory.</p>
            </div>
        </div>
                  
        <div>
            <div class="head">THE WHIPPOORWILL.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Sleep, sleep ! be thine the sleeep that throws
            <br/>Elysium o’er the soul’s repose,
            <br/>Without a dream, save such as wind
            <br/>Like midnight angels, through the mind ;
            <br/>While I am watching on the hill
            <br/>I, and the wailing whippoorwill.
            <br/>Oh whippoorwill, oh whippoorwill!
            <br/>Sleep, sleep! and once again I’11 tell
            <br/>The oft pronounced yet vain farewell:
            <br/>Such should his word, oh maiden, be
            <br/>Who lifts the fated eye to thee ;
            <br/>Such should it be, before the chain
            <br/>That wraps his spirit, binds his brain.
            <br/>Oh whippoorwill, oh whippoorwill!
            <br/>Sleep, sleep ! the ship hath left the shore,
            <br/>The steed awaits his lord no more ;
            <br/>His lord still madly lingers by,
            <br/>The fatal maid he cannot fly—
            <br/>And thirds the wood, and climbs the hill——
            <br/>He and the wailing whippoorwill.
            <br/>Oh whippoorwill, oh whippoorwill!
            <br/>Sleep, sleep ! the morrow hastens on ;
            <br/>Then shall the wailing slave be gone,
            <br/>Flitting the hill-top fur for fear
            <br/>The sounds of joy may reach his ear;
            <br/>The sounds of joy !—the hollow knell
            <br/>Pealed from the mocking chapel bell.
            <br/>Oh whippoorwill, oh whippoorwill!
          </div>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">W. GILMORE SIMMS</span>.</div>
        </div>

        <div>
            <div class="head">NEW AMERICAN PUBLICATIONS.</div>
            <div class="ab">Brougham, Lord. Instinct together with Fossil Osteology,by Cuvier, 18mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">
               <br/>Bolies, William. Explanatory and Phonographic Dictionary of the English
            <br/>Language, large 8vo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Copland, Dr. Dictionary of Medicine, Nos. 6 and 7.</div>
            <div class="ab">Cunningham. Capt. Recollections of Service in China.</div>
            <div class="ab">Evarts, Jeremiah. Memoir of, by E. C. Tracy. 8vo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Everest, Rev. C. W. The Snow Drop. Miniature vol.</div>
            <div class="ab">Everest. C. W. The Vision of Death and other Poems.</div>
            <div class="ab">Farnham, Thos. J. Hi dory of the Oregon Territory.</div>
            <div class="ab">Hitchcock, Prof. Elements of Geology, new edition, 12mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Ireland. Impressions of Ireland and the Irish.</div>
            <div class="ab">Knickerbocker Sketch Book, edited by L. G. Clark.</div>
            <div class="ab">Kidder, Danl. P. Sketches of Residence and Travel in Brazil. 2 vols 12mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Lardner, Dr. Popular Lectures on Science and Art, Nos. 1 and 2.</div>
            <div class="ab">Lincoln, Mrs. Lectures on Botany, new edition.</div>
            <div class="ab">Marshall, I. T. Farmer’s and Emigrant’s Hand Book. 12mo. plates, $1 00 Cheap edition,
            paper cover 63c.</div>
            <div class="ab"> McElligott, James, Manual of Orthography and Definition, 12mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">McCullough, Rev. J. W. The Dead in Christ, I8mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Mackey, Albert G. Lexicon of Freemasonry, 12mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Pickering, Ellen. The Secret Foe, a novel.</div>
            <div class="ab">Plato against the Atheists, with Critical Notes. by Prof. Taylor Lewis, 12mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Ricord, Dr. On Syphilis, translated by Dr. Doane, new edition.</div>
            <div class="ab">Ranke, Prof. History of the Popes, new cheap edition, 8vo., cloth.</div>
            <div class="ab">
               <br/>Stevenson, Rev. John. Christ on the Cross, an Exposition of the 22d <br/>Psalm,
            l2mo.</div>
            <div class="ab">Wagner, Dr. Comparative Anatomy of Vertebrated Animals, 8vo.</div>
            <div class="ab">De Kohan, or the Court Conspirator. From the French of Eugene Sue. <br/>(Two Editions:
            one by Harper &amp; Brothers, and the other by Mr. Winches- <br/>ter of the "
            New World” press</div>
            <div class="ab">Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy, No. 4. To be completed in about 12 numbers.</div>
            <div class="ab">Fleetwood, or the Stain of Birth, a novel of American Life. By the author of “ Philip
            in Search of a Wife."</div>
            <div class="ab">Eveline Neville. By a Lady of the North.</div>
            <div class="ab">The Eastern Belle, or the Betrayed One; a Tale of Boston and Bangor.</div>
            <div class="ab">An Order of Family Prayer for every day in the week and for Holy Days and Seasons of
            the Church. By the Rev. J. W. Wainwright, D. D.</div>
            <div class="ab">Lee &amp; Blanchard have published vol. 2d of their cheap edition of Capt. Wil- okes’
            Narrative of the Exploring Expedition.</div>
            <div class="ab">Historical Collections of Virginia; by Henry Howe. One vol. pp. 544, with a map and
            100 illustrations. Published at Charleston, S. C., by Babcock &amp; co.</div>
        </div>

        <div>
            <div class="ab">Notice to correspondents.--The communication of "H.C.L." will appear next week.</div>
        </div>

                  <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/>
         <div>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">SMITH’S WEEKLY VOLUME, A SELECT CIRCULATING LIBRARY BY THE Original Editor of
              Waslie’s Library. This popular periodical is regu- <br/>larly revived at
              the office of the Broadway Journal. Terms $4 per annum, <br/>single numbers 8 cts.
              JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 133 Nassau, st., Clinton Hall.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">WILL BE PUBLISHED, On Saturday, THE PROGRESS OF PASSION; A Poem; in Four Books. By
              Rev. Henry W. Swerber, A. M. C. SHEPARD, Publisher, 101 Broadway, opposite John
              St.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">82 Cliff-street, May, 1845. MESSRS. HARPER AND BROTHERS HAVE In Press, among others,
              the following IMPORTANT NEW WORKS. 1. —MEMOIRS OF CELEBRATED STATESMEN OF THE ENG- <br/>LISH COMMONWEALTH. By John Forster. Edited by Rev. <br/>J. O. Choules,
              A. M. 2. —THE CONSTITUTIONAL HISTORY OF ENGLAND, from the <br/>Accession of Henry VII.
              to the Death of George II. By Henry <br/>Hallam. 3. —THE FARMER’S DICTIONARY. By D. P.
              Gardner, M. D. 4. —NEW GREEK AND ENGLISH LEXICON, Including Liddell <br/>and Scott’s
              enlarged Translation of Passow’s Greek and German <br/>Lexicon Under the Supervision
              of Henry Drisler, A. M. 5. —A PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES. 6. —MACKENZIE’S LIFE OF PAUL
              JONES. New Edition. 7. —A TREATISE ON DOMESTIC ECONOMY. By Catherine E. Beecher. 8.
              —THE DUTY OF AMERICAN WOMEN TO THEIR COUNTRY. By the same Author. 9. —THE AMERICAN
              HOUSEKEEPER’S RECEIPT BOOK. By the same Author. 10. —THE TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO. With
              Notes. By Hugh Murray. [Just Ready.] 11— THE ECLOGUES AND GEORGICS OF VIRGIL. By
              Charles Anthon, LL. D. 12— XENOPHON’S ANABASIS. By the same Editor. 13— BURTON’S
              ANATOMY OF MELANCHOLY. From the new improved Edition. 14— PRACTICAL ASTRONOMY. By
              Thomas Dick, LL. D. 15. —A NEW ANATOMICAL ATLAS. From the French. 16. —THE LIFE OF
              JOHN MARTIN. A Sequel to Henry Milner. By Mrs. Sherwood. 17— A KEY TO LATIN
              VERSIFICATION. By Prof. Anthon. 18— LIFE OF THE REV. DR. PROUDFIT. By the Rev. Dr.
              For- syth. 19— A NEW WORK BY EPES SARGENT. 20— THE AMERICAN SHEPHERD. By L. A.
              Morrell. 21— AIDS TO ENGLISH COMPOSITION, ETC. By R. G. Parker. 22— —PRAISE AND
              PRINCIPLE. By the Author of " Conquest and Self-Conquest,” &amp;c. 23— SELF. A Novel.
              By the Author of " Cecil.” [Just Ready.] 24— A NEW WORK ON INSANITY. By Dr. Galt
              25.—THE SMUGGLER. By J. P. R. James, Esq. [Just ready.] 26— AN ILLUSTRATED EDITION OF
              THE WANDERING JEW. 27— MRS. LOUDON’S COUNTRY COMPANION, AND FARMING FOR LADIES. 28—
              MISS BREMER’S NEW WORK. Dalekarlien. 29— DE ROHAN; OR, THE COURT CONSPIRATOR. By
              Eugene Sue. [Now ready.] 30. —THE BOOK OF THE FARM. By Stephens. 31. —ILLUSTRATED
              COMMON PRAYER. Embellished with about 700 fine Engravings. 32. —BOOK OF COMMON PRAYER.
              Standard Edition revised, un- <br/>der the Superintendence of Drs.
              Wainwright and Coil. In thirty va- <br/>rieties of size and binding.</div>
            </div>
                    
            <div>
               <div class="ab">TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL. sIR—WE WILL THANK YOU TO CAUTION the public
              against a set of impostor who are calling upon our customers, <br/>asserting that they
              are engaged by us in the capacity of agents. In several <br/>instances they have
              succeeded in obtaining orders. But when the goods are <br/>delivered great
              dissatisfaction has been given by the infamous and utterly <br/>base imitations. But
              still persisting that the cards are our manufacture, <br/>they too often succeed in
              foisting them upon the unsuspecting. We our- <br/>selves would strenuously
              caution the said parties that should they persist af- <br/>ter this notice,
              we will try what effect a State Prison will have upon them. We are, sir, Your most
              obt’y, J. B. CAREY &amp; CO., Ornamental Show Card Manufacturers, 323 Broadway. An
              agent wanted for New York City. Also one for New York State-- whose name will be
              published as our authorized agent. Albany Evening Journal please copy for 7 days.</div>
            </div>

            <br/>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page351"/>
                    <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">MR. AND MRS. KIRKLAND’S SCHOOL FOR YOUNG LADIES, No. 255 Greene Street, One door
              above Waverly Place, New York. THIS School differs essentially from most others in
              this city, in one particular: the number admitted is so limited that each scholar
              receives the personal attention and instruction of the principals. Mr. Kirkland
              resided some years in Europe for the express purpose of qualifying himself as an
              instructor. The French language is taught by an approved master, a native of France;
              and every facility is afforded for practice, both in the school and in the family. The
              plan of instruction embraces three divisions. The Initiatory Course in- <br/>cludes Grammar, Geography, American History, Writing and Arithmetic <br/>with
              Composition. Reading aloud, Spelling and Definition, form part of the <br/>daily
              exercises of the whole school. The Seond continues the above-named studies, with the
              addition of An- cient and Modern History and the French Language. In the higher or
              AEsthetic course all the usual branches of a thorough En- <br/>glish course
              of education are included, with French, German, Latin and <br/>Greek, according to the
              wish of the parent and the capacity of the scholar. Pupils in this course pay
              particular attention to Poetry, to the art of Com- <br/>position, and to
              the Philosophy of History. Moral Philosophy is taught from <br/>Dymond, as abridged
              and prepared for schools by Mrs. Kirkland. Lectures <br/>on various subjects are
              delivered by Mr. and Mrs. Kirkland, and others; and <br/>the general course of study
              is advanced and rendered interesting by copious <br/>illustrations from French and
              English Literature. TERMS. Primary Course, - $12 50 Per Quarter. Second “ (including
              French, &amp;c.) 18 00 " Third, or highest course, - - 25 00 " Music—Piano Forte, - -
              - 15 00 " “ Singing, - - 15 00 " Drawing, - - - 10 00 " Dancing, - - - 12 00 " For
              Board, (payable Quarterly in advance,) §175 per Annum. Board during vacations at the
              same rate. The young ladies are required to bring towels, spoons, fork and napkin
              ring—every article fully marked, Washing $7 50 per Quarter. No Extras—whether for
              fuel, use of instruments, or any thing not here specified. Pupils received at any
              time, and charged in proportion only, References to parents and guardians given if
              desired.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">SHEPARD IS SELLING BOOKS AND STATIONARY AS cheap as ever. He has added a large
              assortment of Books bought at very low prices at the late trade sale. Niebuhr’s Rome,
              just published at $5, he will sell far below that price. Encyclopedia Americana, in 13
              vols., he will sell low enough. He has also added a beautiful assortment of Gold
              Pencils—some of which he will sell as low as $1,87 1-2 cents, warranted. Another lot
              of that beautiful Letter Paper at $1,60 per ream—well worth $2,25. Please call and see
              if you cannot buy to suit you at SHEPARD’S, 191 Broadway, opposite John street.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">UNITED STATES EXPLORING EXPEDITION. CHEAP EDITION NARRATIVE OF THE U. S. EXPLORING
              EX-PEDITION, during the years 1833, 39, 40, 41, 42. By Charles Wilkes, <br/>U.S. Navy
              Commander of the Expedition. With Illustrations and Maps. In <br/>Five Volumes. Vol.
              1, $ 2 00. This edition contains precisely the same type, page, and reading
              <br/>matter, as the one in imperial octavo ; the difference between them being in
              <br/>the quality and size of the paper, and the omission of the steel plates, and
              <br/>some of the maps. The number of wood illustrations in this edition is near- <br/>ly three hundred. A volume will be published about every two weeks, un-
                <br/>til the whale work shall be completed. For sale bv WILEY &amp;
              PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">NOW READY, (Gratis,) WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'S LITERARY NEWS-LETTER FOR MAY, containing—
              1. —Foreign Literary Intelligence. 2. —American Literary Intelligence. 3. —Important
              English works in press. 4. — List of new English Works just published. 6.-New American
              Works published in April. 6. —Works recently imported, with the prices. 7. —W.
              &amp;P.’s recent Publications with Critical Notices. 8. —Books which are Books'
              Library of Choice Reading. 9. — The United States’ Exploring Expedition, WILEY &amp;
              PUTNAM, 161 Broadway. This News-Letter will be distributed gratuitously to all who
              will <br/>leave their address with the publishers. Single copies of English books im-
                <br/>ported to order per -steamer or packet. my 10</div>
            </div>
                    
            <div>
               <div class="ab"> GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE. The first Premium awarded five years by the American
              Institute for the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship. GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND
              BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY, NO. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK. GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of
              Mercan- tile and Epistolary Waiti.nG, guaranteed to all (old and young) in 10 lessons
              of one hour each. Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars for a thorough
              <br/>course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
              <br/>Stationery. Payable at the commencement. Class hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P.
              M. daily for gentlemen and from 11 to 1 o'clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
              For sale “ Goldsmith's Gems or PeNMANship," elegantly bound. Price Fve Dollars.</div>
            </div>

                    <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">THE SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER. B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor. Published
              Monthly at Richmond, Va. ; price Five Dollars per Year. THE MESSENGER has been
              established since 1835, has a large subscription list among the elite of the Southern
              Aristocracy, and is the principal organ of Southern opinion. Subscriptions received by
              John Bisco, at the office of the “ Broadway Jour- nal,” 135 Nassau st.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">IMPORTANT WORKS FOR PUBLIC LIBRARIES. FOR SALE BY BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, NEW YORK.
              THE TRANSACTIONS OF THE ROYAL SOCI- ETY OF LONDON, or Philosophical Transactions, from
              the <br/>commencement, in 1665 to I800. By Drs. Hutton and Shaw ; <br/>in 18 vols. 4
              to., and from 1600 to 1835, in 36 vols., together <br/>54 vols. royal, 4 to. uniformly
              bound in half calf. $250 00 <br/>THE ARCHAEOLEGIA ; or Miscellaneous Tracts, relating
              to <br/>Antiquity, by the Society of Antiquaries of Sweden, complete <br/>from the
              beginning in 1770 to 1843, in 30 vols. uniformly <br/>bound in half russia. 225 00
              <br/>THE DELPHIN EDITION OF THE LATIN CLASSICS; by <br/>Valpy, with various notes, the
              best edition, (published at 150 <br/>sterling) in 142 vols. 8 vo. boards. 200
              00<br/>PINKERTONS’ COLLECTIONS OF VOYAGES AND TRAV- <br/>ELS in various
              parts of the world, 17 large vols., 4 to. half <br/>bound in calf. 70 00<br/>BAYLE’S
              GREAT HISTORICAL AND CRITICAL DICTION- <br/>ARY ; by Des Maizeaux, best
              edition, 5 vols. folio, bound in <br/>calf. 30 00<br/>ANDERSON’S’BRITISH POETS;
              from-Chaucer to Warton ; 14 vols. royal 8 vo. bound in calf extra. 40 00 <br/>COLONEL
              VYSE’S ACCOUNT OF OPERATIONS CARRIED <br/>ON IN EXPLORING THE PYRAMIDS OF EGYPT; with
              <br/>numerous plates; 3 vols. 4 to. 14 00</div>
            </div>
                    
            <div>
               <div class="ab">DESIGNING AND ENGRAVING ON WOOD. SAMUEL E. BROWN, 70 Nassau Street, Corner of John,
              New Yoik. Portraits, Views of Buildings, Scenery. Original Designs, &amp;c. &amp;c.
              furnished at this establishment.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">the BOEHM FLUTE. (new invention.) Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music. London, the
              Conservatorie at Paris, and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe. MR.
              LARRABEE, Manufacturer, of the “Boehm <br/>Flute," 110 Fulton St. N. Y., anxious to
              introduce to the Amateurs of <br/>rec cities the above Important Invention, which has
              been so enthusiastically <br/>received and generally used by the most distinguished
              European Artists, feels <br/>happy in being able to place before them the following
              testimonial to its <br/>merits, signed by two of the most distinguished of our
              resident Artists.<br/>We hereby certify to the the excellence of Boehm Flute as
              manufactured <br/>by Mr. J.D. Larrabee ; to the beauty of its tone, the perfection of
              its tune, <br/>and the simplicity of its fingering, which renders a brilliant
              execution <br/>comparatively easy.<br/>Philip Ernst (who has already introduced it
              successfully among his pupils. <br/>John A. Kyle, Principal Flute of the Philhar- <br/>monic Society and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm
              Flute, <br/>41 Forsyth street. New York. <br/>Amateurs and Professors are requested to
              call at the manufactory, 110 Fulton st. and judge for themselves.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">DISEASES OF THE TEETH. Washington, D. C., May, 1844. <br/>THE neglect of the Teeth
              is the cause of much suffering <br/>and regret, and should not be disregarded by the
              most thoughtless. <br/>The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G.
              Bigelow’s <br/>professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
              <br/>Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
              <br/>cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs <br/>the
              various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness, <br/>durability, and
              beauty of the Teeth.<br/>on. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo. on. John B. Dawson, La.
              Joshua“errick, Me. John H. Lumpkin, Geo. James Irvin, Pa. J. Thompson. Miss. Dr. A. G.
              Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL, REDDING &amp; CO., - - - - Boston, Mass. COLON
              &amp; ADRIANCE, - - - - Philadelphia, Pa. R.G.H. HUNTINGTON, - - - - Hartford, Ct.
              GEORGE JONES, - - - - Albany, N.Y. THOMAS H. PEASE, - - - - New Haven, Ct. L. WILLARD,
              - - - - - Troy.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 106 Fulton Street.</div>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page352"/>
                    <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">MANESCA’S oral system of teaching <br/>THE FRENCH LANGUAGE, pursued by his daughter,
              Madame <br/>Durand, either in class or private lessons, to Ladies and Gentlemen,
              <br/>at No. 35 Walker street. <br/>AMILY BOOKS.—NEW AMD IMPORTANT WORKS, designed
              especially for Families. 1. The Pictorial Sunday Book. By John Kitts, D.D. A very
              hand- some volume, folio, with many hundred engravings - $7 00 2. Old England: a
              Pictorial Museum of Regal, Ecclesiastical, Baronial, and Popular Antiquities. Vol. 1,
              large folio, with many hundred tine engravings.........................7 00 3. The
              Pictorial Museum of Animated Nature. 2 vols. large folio, with many hundred fine
              engravings - - - 12 00 4. Pictorial History of England. 8 very large vols., with many
              hundred engravings.........................- - 27 00 5. Pictorial History of
              Palestine. 2 very large vols. with many hundred
              engravings................................ -8 00 6. Chambers’ Cyclopaedia of English
              Literature. 2 large vols. octavo...............................................6 00 7
              Chambers’ Information for the People. 2 large vols. 8vo 6 00 8. Chambers’ Tracts of
              Useful Information. Vol. 1, with en- gravings - - - - . - - - . - 50 Imported and fo‘r
              sale' by ' ' ' WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, may24 __________________________l6l Broadway.
              _</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">LONDON &amp; PARIS LITERARY AGENCY. O. RICH AND SONS, AGENTS FOR THE PURCHASE OF
              BOOKS FOR AMERICA. Agents to the Library of Congress, The New York Society Library,
              The Albany Institute, The Boston Atheuaeum, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c. 12 Red Lion
              Square, London. 12 Rue Pot de Fer, Paris. <br/>Mr. RICH respectfully informs his
              friends and fellow-citizens that he has <br/>formed an establishment in Paris, in
              connexion with his old establishment in Red <br/>Lion square, for the purpose of
              furnishing BOOKS published on the continent <br/>without the heavy expense attending
              their transmission through England. <br/>Each of these establishments will be
              conducted by one of his sons, under his <br/>own general superintendence. This new
              arrangement, he trusts, will prove of <br/>signal advantage to his correspondents, and
              no exertions will be wanting to exe- <br/>cute their orders on the most
              advantageous terms. Orders may be sent through, <br/>and small sums paid to Messrs.
              Goodhue &amp; Co. of New York. Two and a half <br/>per cent, will be allowed to all
              those who make a remittance with their orders.<br/>Mr. Rich, having made Bibliography
              his special study for forty years, pos- <br/>sesses a knowledge of books
              and editious not often to be met with, and will be <br/>happy to give any advice and
              information respecting the formation of Libraries <br/>or Collections of Books in any
              particular branch of literature or science. For <br/>information in regard to his
              efficiency, he begs to refer to Messrs. Prescott, <br/>Ticknor, Sparks, Irving, and
              other literary characters in the United States, to <br/>whom he is known. Intending to
              devote the remainder of his life to literary <br/>pursuits, his greatest pleasure will
              arise from sending rare and valuable books <br/>to his own country; and he trusts to
              live long enough to see in the United States <br/>a Library which may bear a
              comparison with the most celebrated iu Europe. If <br/>he can live to say, " I also
              assisted IN its formation," his most ardent wishes <br/>will be gratified.<br/>Mr.
              Rich has in the press—Bibliotheca Americana Nova : a Catalogue of <br/>Books relating
              to America, including Voyages to the South Seas and round the <br/>World : Part III.
              from 1831 to 1845, with supplement and index completing the <br/>work. ,<br/>He has
              also nearly ready for the press, Bibliotheca Americana Vetus : a <br/>Catalogue of
              Books relating to America from the Discovery to the year 1700; <br/>with notes and
              observations: in one volume, 8vo., of about 400 pages.<br/>Mr. Rich has also nearly
              ready, a reprin from Taervenot’s Collection of Father <br/>Marquette’s account of the
              discovery of the Mississippi, entitled, " Decouverte <br/>de quelques Pays et Nations
              de l'Amerique Septentrionale.” Only 125 copies <br/>are printed, which will be
              distributed among Mr. Rich’s friends and corre- <br/>spondents.<br/>Mr.
              Rich has also purchased the remaining copies of the part relating to <br/>America of
              L’Art do Verifier les Dates: of which ten volumes in octavo, by <br/>D. B. Warden,
              Esq., are printed, and two volumes more, completing the work, <br/>will be published
              in the course of the present year.<br/>Price of the ten volumes published ------ 40
              francs Complete sets of the Art de Verifier les Dates, in 44 vols. 8vo. - 160 francs
              instead of 308, the original price. Paris, May 1, 1845. may24</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">REJOICINGS! HOLIDAYS!! BIRTHDAYS!!! CAREY’S MONTGOLFIERS or Fire Balloons and
              <br/>Air Balloons may be obtained from stationers and fancy stores in New <br/>York,
              on and after the 20th of May, price $2 00 and upward—a list of which <br/>will be
              published on that date. Directions upon each box.<br/>J. B. CAREY &amp; CO. 323
              Broadway. With Pyrotechnists arrangements can he made. my 17</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">A CARD. W.M. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANOFORTE, ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No.
              22 Bank street, where his terms for giving instruction can be ascertained. my 17</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">TITIAN’S VENUS. THIS TRULY BEAUTIFUL PRODUCTION, A <br/>repetition of the great
              picture in the Florentine Gallery is now on exhi- <br/>bition at 449
              Broadway, an undoubted work of this never-to-be-excelled <br/>master in the art of
              coloring.<br/>Open during day and evening. Admittance 25 cts. Season tickets, 50
              cents.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO-FORTES.—A. H. GALE &amp; CO.’S WARE- Rooms, No. 289 Broadway—Manufactory Third
              Avenue, corner of 13th street. <br/>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their
              extensive assortment of <br/>Rosewood and Mahogany Piano-Fortes, with from six to
              seven octaves, em- <br/>bracing ever variety of patterns, made in their
              well known substantial man- <br/>ner, under their immediate and personal
              superintendence, by skillful and <br/>experienced mechanics, from the best seasoned
              materials.<br/>These instruments embrace many important improvements, which will re-
                <br/>commend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of
              perfection, with <br/>the best French grand action, warranted in every respect by the
              manufac- <br/>turer.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to <br/>Duhois &amp; Stodart),
              No. 335 Broadway, will keep a complete assort- <br/>ment of the latest
              approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most superior <br/>quality ; such as he is
              prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone.<br/>Touch, and External Finish,
              and to endure in any climate. A liberal dis- <br/>count from the standard
              prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano <br/>Fortes aways on hire.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES. THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their <br/>numerous
              friends, and to the public, would, at the same time, call atten- <br/>tion
              to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, in
              <br/>elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.<br/>The Subscribers, from their long
              experience in every department of the <br/>business, have been enabled to add several
              important improvements to the <br/>action, so that their Instrument, they feel assured
              will prove, upon examina- <br/>tion, equal to any in the
              market.<br/>STODART &amp; DUNHAM. 361 Broadway. Manufactory 13th St., between 3d and
              4th Avenues. N. B.—A good second-hand Piano Forte for sale.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO FORTES.—V. F. HARRISON. 23 Canal Street, N. Y. <br/>Instruments made with the
              most recent improvements, such as iron frames, <br/>&amp;c.f with a compass of 6 and 7
              octaves. They are made from choice mate- <br/>rials and highly finished,
              with the most faithful workmanship, the result of <br/>23 years experience in the
              business.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">F RILEY &amp; CO., No. 297 Broadway, (between <br/>Reade and Duane streets,) New
              York, Publishers of Music, and Man- <br/>ufacturers of Musical Instruments,
              wholesale and retail. In addition to their <br/>own catalogue, (one of the largest in
              the United States,) they keep on hand <br/>he publications of all the principal Music
              houses. They are electing a large <br/>Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano
              Fortes of a superior quality, <br/>will be constantly kept on hand.</div>
            </div>
                    
            <div>
               <div class="ab">PIANO - FORTES.—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly <br/>Mundy &amp; Pethick.) invites the
              Attention of the musical public to the ele- <br/>gant and varied aesortment
              he now has at his Old Establishment, Corner of <br/>Cottage-place and Bleecker Street,
              which he will sell at prices unusually low.<br/>J. P. having been actively engaged in
              the business for the last twenty <br/>years, and for a large portion of that time
              manufacturer for two of the larg- <br/>est Music Stores in this city, feels
              warranted in saying that his instruments <br/>will bear a favorable chmparison with
              those of the best makers in this coun - <br/>try or Europe, and that they
              contain all the real improvements of the dav. <br/>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and
              Exchanged, also Tuned and Repaired <br/>New York, April 23d. 1845.<br/>Cottage-flace
              and lilceckcr Street, which he will sell at prices unusually low. <br/>P. having been
              actively engaged in the but-iness f.»r the last twenty <br/>years, and‘for a large
              jmr.ion of that time manufacturer for two of the luig <br/>eat Mu-ic Stores in this
              city, feels warranted in *u) ing that his instruments <br/>will bear a favorable
              chinporison w ilh tho»c of the be:-t makeis in thi* coun - <br/>try or
              Eurepe, and that they contain all the real improvements of the dav. <br/>Second
              hnndPiano* Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and Retailed <br/>New York, April
              23d. 1S45.</div>
            </div>
            <div>
               <div class="ab">JAMES PIRSSON, PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER, 88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM. A
              large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand. TERMS MODERATE.</div>
            </div>

            <div>
               <div class="ab">BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO. THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
              <br/>work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method <br/>the
              most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prom- <br/>inent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies, are
              <br/>given in such PROGRESSIVE order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
              <br/>carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
              <br/>otherwise, are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
              <br/>has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,
              <br/>and it is only by the study of such methods as Bertini's that pupils will be en
              <br/>abled to READ music with facility, and at the same time become good musi- <br/>cians.<br/>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ;
              the rud- <br/>ments of music being given and illustrated at the same time,
              and each lesson <br/>is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.<br/>The
              publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations from pro- <br/>fessional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of BERTINI's Method <br/>over
              all others yet published in this country, most of them having used the <br/>foreign
              copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the <br/>names in the
              principal cities.<br/>Boston. New York. Messrs. G. J. Webb. Messrs. H. C. Timm. J. G
              Maedar. W. Alpers. H.T. Hath. U.C. Hill. E L. White. F. H. Brown. David Paine.
              Philadelphia. A. Kurek. B. C. Cross. T. B. Moses. Joseph Duggan. Albany—O. J. Shaw .
              <br/>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
              <br/>American edition published by E. H. WaDE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Wash <br/>ington
              street, Boston.</div>
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back">
        </div>
</div>
