<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 2     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, AUGUST 9, 1845    NO. 5
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>EDITED BY
         
         <br></br>EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau St.
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="head">Eulalie—A Song.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>I dwelt alone
            
            <br></br>In a world of moan,
            
            <br></br>And my soul was a stagnant tide,
            
            <br></br>Till the fair and gentle Eulalie became my blushing bride—
            
            <br></br>Till the yellow-haired young Eulalie became my smiling bride.
            
            
            <br></br>Ah, less—less bright
            
            <br></br>The stars of the night
            
            <br></br>Than the eyes of the radiant girl!
            
            <br></br>And never a flake
            
            <br></br>That the vapor can make
            
            <br></br>With the moon-tints of purple and pearl,
            
            <br></br>Can vie with the modest Eulalie’s most unregarded curl—
            
            <br></br>Can compare with the bright-eyed Eulalie’s most humble and care-
            
            <br></br>less curl.
            
            
            <br></br>Now Doubt—now Pain
            
            <br></br>Come never again,
            
            <br></br>For her soul gives me sigh for sigh,
            
            <br></br>While all day long
            
            <br></br>Shines, bright and strong,
            
            <br></br>Astarté within the sky,
            
            <br></br>And ever to her dear Eulalie upturns her matron eye—
            
            <br></br>And ever to her young Eulalie upturns her violet eye.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="head">More Words with Alcibiades.</div>
         
         <p>Since the night I supped with Alcibiades, or rather since the
            symposium, where Alcibiades in the spirit was with me, I
            had forgotten that he had promised to come and catch some
            glimpse of the modern drama. Since that time, by some association, not at present intelligible, but with which Alcibiades (who had been initiated in the Eleusinian mysteries)
            must have been familiar, and Mesmerism or the Persian
            Magia, may some day explain—whenever I slept, my mind
            was apt to recur to that imaginary conversation. In the
            evening crepuscula, not long after, when a cool and refreshing breeze had followed in the footsteps of an African day, I
            was roused from a siesta, (a habit of yielding to these luxuries, I learned from some Spanish friends,) by a gentle tap
            at my chamber-door. Not more surprised was the lover of
            the lost Lenore, at the unseemly raven’s entrance, than I by
            the salutation of a classic troupe, headed by my friend Alcibiades, consisting of Sallustius; Pratinas, the Athenian actor;
            the glorious Calderon; and our own immortal dramatist,
            Shakspeare. Besides these, were others of the plebs umbrarum, among whom the most conspicuous were three females, (whom by some inscrutable mental process, I recognised as Sappho, Corinna, and Aspasia,) escorted by one of
            our own day, Walter Savage Landor.
         </p>
         
         <p>Alcibiades was dressed as he was at our last symposium.
            In fact, the luxurious Greeks, even in their attire, were more
            consistent than we; changing often the garments, but never
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            the fashion of the garb. One thing struck me, however—
            that the robe he wore, bore not the least resemblance to that
            of Macready, or Anderson, in the character of Gisippus;
            equally unlike which was the senatorial purple of Sallustius. From them, however, I turned quickly to look upon
            Shakspeare. Picture to yourselves his high and thoughtful
            brow—his manly athletic form, clad in the sad-colored doublet and ruff which Vandyke so loved to paint, with the dark
            chestnut hair parted in the middle, falling profusely over his
            shoulders, and you will have evoked the very type of the
            Norman Saxon, the true Cavalier, who, fifty years later than
            Shakspeare lived, would have fought for Charles. So Shakspeare appeared to me. Near to him I saw a gallant looking
            blade in the bravery of the same age, of whom I shall have
            more to say anon.
         </p>
         
         <p>After a few incidental remarks, said Alcibiades: “I and
            these shadows of shades, as Saliustius would call them, are
            come to witness a new comedy, the rumor forerunning which,
            we have caught the echo of ϵυϵρϴϵυ, and before we go
            to the theatre, wish you to supply for us something like the
            προϓϵϒοuϵυa which our grammarians prefixed to the manuscripts of ancient plays; that we may form some juster
            idea of what is that Fashion which the Comic Poet has taken
            for the theme of the new play. To tell you the truth, we
            can form no idea of that enigmatical word!”
         </p>
         
         <p>What presents no difficulties to ourselves, we are prone
            to imagine equally plain to others—and therefore, at first,
            the question of Alcibiades very much astonished me, on account of its apparent simplicity. In a second or two, however, I wished very much for Leslie’s aid, that by one of his
            witty and antithetical remarks, he might extricate me from
            a dilemma. He, however, not being with me, I attempted to
            make the best explanation in my power—which was somewhat after this manner:
         </p>
         
         <p>“Fashion is the peculiar mode arrogated by those who
            hold their way of doing things, to be essentially the way in
            which things should be done; not that this way is the best,
            or even the pleasantest; and they do not desire in these matters their example to be followed; because, were this the
            case, fashion would lose its charm. They would have it,
            as it were, a religion to be believed in, a kind of worship offered at altars, of which they should be the priests, and no
            hand but theirs be esteemed meet to make the libation. Its
            objects are manifold—the wearing of the toga; the school
            of philosophy; the dish to be partaken of, and the manner of
            partaking of it; the things to be talked of and the manner of
            talking of them; the place to walk, and the manner of walking; in fact, as far as may be, the very mode of thought, and
            all earthly things, spiritual or mental, come within its compass and the dominion which it claims. In fine, oh, Alcibiades! it is easy to say when you sin against the bequests
            of this inscrutable power, but not to say what are its rights
            and demands.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“I think I understand you. Fashion permits not itsadherents
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page66"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            to drink wine or dally with dancing girls; it does not permit
            what Socrates would call indecencies?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“You err: fashion does not forbid these things, it rather
            approves them.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“It is this, then, which now makes you pay such atten-
            tion to certain studies and arts?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“By no means. Fashion is a substitute for all arts. Want
            of fashion renders all knowledge useless, and fashion renders
            ignorance excusable. It excuses vice; it oppresses virtue;
            it does anything it pleases!”
         </p>
         
         <p>“I do not understand you, and possibly will not; so I will
            not torment you with more questions.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Said Shakspeare: “I possibly may make my self intelligible.
            Fashion is the moral, physical, and esoteric bearing of the
            great. Therefore is it that it changes so suddenly, because
            the great of to-day are by no means those of yesterday. For
            instance: The Earl of Essex, in the days of Queen Elizabeth,
            was not always her favorite; and Falstaff, the favorite of
            Prince Hal, was not admitted at the Court of King
            Henry.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“By-the-bye,” said Landor, “was Elizabeth virtuous? and
            are the tales told of Raleigh, my friend here, (he was the gallant who stood by the side of Shakspeare,) of Essex, Leicester, and others, true?”
         </p>
         
         <p>Shakspeare replied in a stern voice: “No slander, sir,
            about Queen Elizabeth!” and immediately continued to define fashion, as the echo in the hearts of the many, of the
            thoughts of the few. (I use here my own language.)
         </p>
         
         <p>We sate and chatted over the new play; not, however, in
            soberness, for I uncorked a bottle of œil de perdrix, which
            seemed wonderfully to take the fancy of my friends.
         </p>
         
         <p>Said Alcibiades: “I feel a God! Verily, it bursteth through
            my lips, diviner than the inspiration of the Pythoness. Hebe
            has poured out to the Olympiadae nothing so delicious! The
            nectar of the Gods is to it as nothing! Again—again fill up!
            The bubbles rise to the sun like the afflatus of a God, or
            spirits soaring towards Olympus. We knew not that wine
            in our day—where grew it?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“In Gaul, in the country of the Allobroges.”</p>
         
         <p>“In Gaul! nay, verily you err; it cannot have been among
            the Allobroges; for I have heard merchants from Massillia
            say that Gaul beyond the Alps produced no wine; the Gaul
            nearest Italy is somewhat milder.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Ah! so it was; but that now is changed, and no wine
            is better than that of Champagne and the Rhine.”
         </p>
         
         <p>We went to the theatre and sate, not too conspicuously, in
            one of the side boxes. On that night, there was a fair array
            of beauty in the dress circle, and more than one bright dame
            sate eyeing herself in the glances cast on her by numerous
            admirers. At length, the corner of the curtain was drawn
            back, and the actor whose task it was to speak the prologue,
            advanced to the foot of the stage. Alcibiades was as attentive to him as possible, and from that time to the end of the
            first act, spoke scarcely a word. He evidently pondered
            upon what could be the meaning of the dialogue; missing
            the explanation which, had the play been Grecian, Zeke, or
            Millinette, would have given. Of them he had nothing
            to say; possibly because he esteemed their characters too
            unimportant to merit comment. The Count, however, he
            at once began to compare with the parasite of some of
            the plays of Menander. Upon this point, I regret to say, I
            was unable to follow him; having little of that information I
            ever esteemed more curious than useful, touching those last
            works.
         </p>
         
         <p>“The chaplet of Aristophanes,’’said I, “need fear no com
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            parison with the leaf to be bestowed on the work now being
            performed.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Ah no; there is no similitude between them: this comedy more resembles old Menander. The comedies of Aristophanes were not written simply to paint a moral; they had
            all some philosophical or political objects, viz: the destruction of the influence of Socrates, and the exalting of the
            power of the wealthier classes. Only in one play has he
            condescended even to notice the literary contests of the
            greatest of our two tragedians.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus we chatted until the curtain rose again. The poet he
            seemed to esteem an useless character enough. The old
            maid, he remarked, might, without any violation of the propriety of her character, have been made to give some explanation of the involved nature of the plot, for she is a gossiping, talkative creature, doing and saying things she knew
            not why. That passion the dramatic poet might have taken
            advantage of.
         </p>
         
         <p>“There is in the character of the fable nothing dramatic,”
            said Alcibiades; and I was compelled to agree with him;
            not meaning that there is no incident crowded into its acts,
            but that no dilemma, no great mistake pervaded the whole
            action. The heroine of the serious part of the drama seemed to please my companion much, and he pronounced her,
            even, very tragic. The other part, Mrs. Tiffany, in itself ungracefully conceived, was ungracefully performed; and too
            refined to be amused at forced errors of grammar and phraseology, Alcibiades found her róle very tedious. The blustering character of the old farmer, like the sailor-like personages in the plays of Menander, he passed by as a matter
            of course, and gave up his whole attention to the Count.
         </p>
         
         <p>“For the sake of your institutions,” said he, “of that republicanism which was the boast of Athens, as it is of Atlantis, I trust this character satirizes an individual, not a
            class. I trust there is more pride of country—that you look
            more contemptuously upon strangers. Some countrymen of
            yours who joined us below, in the last year, told something
            of a contest in a city of Philadelphia, between two parties,
            the watch-word of one of which was, “Americans should
            rule America." I see not how this can be, if you permit
            strangers to intermarry with you. Do so, and the women,
            ever prone to run after something new, will always prefer a
            broidered robe of whose texture they are ignorant, even to
            a garment of a cloth of gold, woven at home. So it was
            though, once with us: the father of Miltiades, a Thracian,
            with some eastern refinements, won the fairest of our Athenian maids. For this however he made us some reparation,
            and gave us his son, whose name is, I suppose, unforgotten.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Miltiades unforgotten! aye, and will remain so while
            Greece and Persia are remembered. But the course of
            things with us is different: we wish to exclude foreigners
            from civil rights, but would admit them to social equality.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“In that you err. There must be an uniform system
            throughout; if you admit them to a social equality you can
            not refuse them the rights of the agora."
         </p>
         
         <p>“Our laws teach that all men are equal.”</p>
         
         <p>“Your laws inculcate that maxim, but your practice contradicts it. Have not the men in your southern districts
            slaves? Like the Ionians, they have somewhat varied from
            the customs of the rest of their brethren. They have taken
            something of the Persian refinement. Men of warm climates are ever luxurious.”
         </p>
         
         <p>When the play was over, the party accompanied me home,
            where, after a few cursory remarks, the play was dismissed,
            as being below all criticism, while the manner in which it
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page67"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            was represented, was esteemed worthy of the highest praise.
            We made merry with more than one flagon of that champaigne which previously had seemed so much to delight Alcibiades. Strangely enough, Landor and the ladies (except
            Aspasia) were water-drinkers. She, however, took to the
            œil de perdrix kindly, as her pet had done, and casting herself back in her chair, drank it with the gusto of a Bacchante. Sallust did not like the champaigne so well, drinking in
            preference the Markbrunnen, to which I confess I set him a
            fair example, ever thinking the strong Rhenish wines a very
            pretty tipple.
         </p>
         
         <p>One cannot drink, however, either the one or the other
            with impunity, and in a short time Sallust began to feel
            most deliciously Epicurean, and to assert that the summum
            bonum was pleasure. Indeed he was a fair specimen of that
            school, physically speaking; a fat round paunch, which shook
            as he walked; a face rosy with wine and fun; the whitest
            teeth and the merriest smile conceivable.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Per Jovem!’’ said he, “it recalls to me the sports I had
            with Lentulus and Catiline in the days when Cicero was
            Consul. Poor Catiline! history has done him an injustice.
            Little thought I, when I wrote my Catilinarian War, that
            posterity would fancy a piece of serious satire to be history.
            Aspasia, you should have known him; the difference between us was, that he was proud, and would not disown
            anything he did, even to please the Censor. Therefore
            it was old Cato hated him so. He carried that boldness even
            to a fault. Witness his presenting himself in the Senate
            house, on the day of the discovery of his plan. Cæsar went
            there with impunity, for though cognizant of the plan, he
            had not overtly participated in it. Nothing but mens conscia
            recti, a conviction that he was toiling for the good of the
            Roman people, enabled him to brave the Senate. Cicero,
            however, in his eastern government, had learned something
            of Persian magic, and raised a spell Catiline could not allay.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Aspasia had listened to this impatiently, and turning to
            Alcibiades said, “come sit by me, my pet, as you used to do,
            while I toyed with your curls. While I do so Corinna or
            Sappho will sing to us one of those odes which made Lesbos
            holy as Marathon or Platæa.”
         </p>
         
         <p>He obeyed her, while Corinna, without any of that shame-
            facedness so often affected in modern days, thus sung:
         </p>
         
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Our native land! our fathers’ land!
            
            <br></br>Still the Ӕgean laves its strand,
            
            <br></br>As when Platæa’s hero band
            
            <br></br>Obtained the victor’s palm.
            
            
            <br></br>Still the laurel and the vine
            
            <br></br>In its woods’ recesses twine,
            
            <br></br>And oft the peasant maids combine
            
            <br></br>Their tender leaves in crowns.
            
            
            <br></br>But rarely—oh how rarely now!
            
            <br></br>Those crowns are for a victor’s brow,
            
            <br></br>For Greeks must to a stranger bow,
            
            <br></br>As ne’er their fathers did.
            
            
            <br></br>’Tis true, beneath a tyrant’s sway,
            
            <br></br>Our fathers knelt in earlier days,
            
            <br></br>Put then their kings were Greeks—not they
            
            <br></br>Who rule our country now.
            
            
            <br></br>We wept to leave our friends and home,
            
            <br></br>We trembled when the hour was come,
            
            <br></br>Like marble, passionless and dumb,
            
            <br></br>We trod the ghostly shore.
            
            
            <br></br>But now, in thankfulness we bless
            
            <br></br>The Gods that spared us the distress
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            
            <br></br>To see Barbaric lords possess
            
            <br></br>Our hearths and fathers’ graves.
         </div>
         
         
         <p>“Per Jovem! I agree with you Corinna. Canaris or
            Mavrocordato should have been king of Greece, or Alexander Ypsilanti; not yon dolt of a German who sleeps near
            the spots where Socrates taught and Demosthenes thundered.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“The English people,” said Count Anthony, “have a passion for Dutchmen: having chosen one for themselves, they
            seem to think consistency requires they should do as much
            for others. Les pauvres Grecs et les braves Beiges! Ah!
            in my time, what with the Highlanders and les Irlandais
            they could do nothing more than keep possession of their,
            island-homes. But they have re-enacted Cressy and Poictiers,
            and absolutely have been in Paris. What would the Regent
            have said to this? And his grandson now is not King of
            France, but Roi des Francois. Well, there is a difference.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Come, Sallust,” said Aspasia, “Alcibiades cannot sing,
            but he can admire music. Sing you something!”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Most willingly:</p>
         
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Philosophers tell us in story
            
            <br></br>That care is the lot of mankind—
            
            <br></br>That its love and its riches and glory
            
            <br></br>All fade and leave nothing behind.
            
            
            <br></br>That e’en o’er the son of Alcmœna
            
            <br></br>Whose labors now all the world sings,
            
            <br></br>Like a corse in the deadly arena,
            
            <br></br>Heedless, the winter wind rings.
            
            
            <br></br>That Crœsus, in long vanished ages,
            
            <br></br>Saw his wealth and his fortune decay,
            
            <br></br>And that we, as erst reasoned the sages,
            
            <br></br>Repent of the years flown away.
            
            
            <br></br>Now all that they say may be true;
            
            <br></br>But Bacchus I tell you was blest,
            
            <br></br>He was gayer, the graver he grew,
            
            <br></br>And, a God, now he’s taking his rest.”
         </div>
         
         
         <p>“That leaf, Sallust, came not from Horatius’ chapter, or
            from Catullus.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“No,” said Sallust, “it is from a poet almost unknown.
            I heard a Spanish slave, one day, sing it at the baths. As
            it took my fancy, for a few sesterces he wrote it in my tablets. Fill up though! Fillup! When you join us below,
            my fine fellow, we’ll do the honors to you.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Holy mother forfend!” said I.</p>
         
         <p>The words had no sooner passed my lips than I awoke.</p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">FAY. ROBINSON.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="head">Greek Mariner’s Song.</div>
         
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>On yonder wave-girt cliff behold—
            
            <br></br>Her bine eyes gazing o’er the sea,
            
            <br></br>Robed in her flowing locks of gold—
            
            <br></br>The syren maid, Parthenopé!
            
            <br></br>Oh! brightly through the dashing spray
            
            <br></br>Gleam her fair feet the crag that press—
            
            <br></br>White as the waves that round them play,
            
            <br></br>Enamoured of her loveliness.
            
            
            <br></br>There, just emerged from out the brine,
            
            <br></br>As Aphrodite fair, she stands;
            
            <br></br>She sings to me in strains divine,
            
            <br></br>She wares to me her beauteous hands.
            
            <br></br>Put up the helm for where yon isle
            
            <br></br>Enshrines my radiant deity!
            
            <br></br>For I would live but in her smile,
            
            <br></br>Or die beneath its witchery!
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">MARY E. HEWITT</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page68"></div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div class="head">The Man That Was Used Up.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">A TALE OF THE LATE BUGABOO AND KICKAPOO CAMPAIGN.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Pleurez, pleurez, mes yeux, et fondez vous en eau!
            
            <br></br>La moitie de ma vie a mis l’ autre au tombeau.
            
            <br></br>Corneille.
         </div>
         
         <p>I cannot just now remember when or where I first made
            the acquaintance of that truly fine-looking fellow, Brevet
            Brigadier General John A. B. C. Smith. Some one did introduce me to the gentleman, I am sure—at some public
            meeting, I know very well—held about something of great
            importance, no doubt—at someplace or other, I feel convinced—whose name I have unaccountably forgotten. The truth
            is—that the introduction was attended, upon my part, with
            a degree of anxious embarrassment which operated to prevent any definite impressions of either time or place. I am
            constitutionally nervous—this, with me, is a family failing,
            and I can’t help it. In especial, the slightest appearance of
            mystery—of any point I cannot exactly comprehend—puts
            me at once into a pitiable state of agitation.
         </p>
         
         <p>There was something, as it were, remarkable—yes, remarkable, although this is but a feeble term to express my
            full meaning—about the entire individuality of the personage
            in question. He was, perhaps, six feet in height, and of a
            presence singularly commanding. There was an air distingué pervading the whole man, which spoke of high breeding,
            and hinted at high birth. Upon this topic—the topic of
            Smith’s personal appearance—I have a kind of melancholy
            satisfaction in being minute. His head of hair would have
            done honor to a Brutus;—nothing could be more richly flowing, or possess a brighter gloss. It was of a jetty black
            which was also the color, or more properly the no color, of
            his unimaginable whiskers. You perceive I cannot speak of
            these latter without enthusiasm; it is not too much to say
            that they were the handsomest pair of whiskers under the
            sun. At all events, they encircled, and at times partially
            overshadowed, a mouth utterly unequalled. Here were the
            most entirely even, and the most brilliantly white of all conceivable teeth. From between them, upon every proper occasion, issued a voice of surpassing clearness, melody, and
            strength. In the matter of eyes, also, my acquaintance was
            pre-eminently endowed. Either one of such a pair was
            worth a couple of the ordinary ocular organs. They were of
            a deep hazel, exceedingly large and lustrous; and there was
            perceptible about them, ever and anon, just that amount of
            interesting obliquity which gives pregnancy to expression.
         </p>
         
         <p>The bust of the General was unquestionably the finest bust
            I ever saw. For your life you could not have found a fault
            with its wonderful proportion. This rare peculiarity set off
            to great advantage a pair of shoulders which would have called up a blush of conscious inferiority into the countenance
            of the marble Apollo. I have a passion for fine shoulders,
            and may say that I never beheld them in perfection before.
            The arms altogether were admirably modelled. Nor were the
            lower limbs less superb. These were, indeed, the ne plus
            ultra of good legs. Every connoisseur in such matters admitted the legs to be good. There was neither too much
            flesh, nor too little,—neither rudeness nor fragility. I could
            not imagine a more graceful curve than that of the os femoris, and there was just that due gentle prominence in the
            rear of the fibula which goes to the conformation of a properly proportioned calf. I wish to God my young and talented
            friend Chiponchipino, the sculptor, had but seen the legs of
            Brevet Brigadier General John A. B. C. Smith.
         </p>
         
         <p>But although men so absolutely fine-looking are neither as
            plenty as reasons or blackberries, still I could not bring my
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            self to believe that the remarkable something to which I al
            luded just now,—that the odd air of je ne sais quoi which
            hung about my new acquaintance,—lay altogether, or indeed
            at all, in the supreme excellence of his bodily endowments.
            Perhaps it might be traced to the manner;—yet here again
            I could not pretend to be positive. There was a primness,
            not to say stiffness, in his carriage—a degree of measured,
            and, if I may so express it, of rectangular precision, attending his every movement, which, observed in a more diminutive figure, would have had the least little savor in the
            world, of affectation, pomposity or constraint, but which, noticed in a gentleman of his undoubted dimension, was readily
            placed to the account of reserve, hauteur—of a commendable sense, in short, of what is due to the dignity of colossal
            proportion.
         </p>
         
         <p>The kind friend who presented me to General Smith whispered in my ear some few words of comment upon the man.
            He was a remarkable man—a very remarkable man—indeed
            one of the most remarkable men of the age. He was an especial favorite, too, with the ladies—chiefly on account of
            his high reputation for courage.
         </p>
         
         <p>"In that point he is unrivalled—indeed he is a perfect
            desperado—a down-right fire-eater, and no mistake,” said my
            friend, here dropping his voice excessively low, and thrilling
            me with the mystery of his tone.
         </p>
         
         <p>“A downright fire-eater, and no mistake. Showed that, I
            should say, to some purpose, in the late tremendous swampfight away down South, with the Bugaboo and Kickapoo Indians.” [Here my friend opened his eyes to some extent.]
            “Bless my soul!—blood and thunder, and all that!—prodigies of valor!—heard of him of course?—you know he’s the
            man"—
         </p>
         
         <p>“Man alive, how do you do? why how are ye? very glad
            to see ye, indeed!” here interrupted the General himself,
            seizing my companion by the hand as he drew near, and
            bowing stiffly, but profoundly, as I was presented. I then
            thought, (and I think so still,) that I never heard a clearer
            nor a stronger voice, nor beheld a finer set of teeth: but I must
            say that I was sorry for the interruption just at that moment,
            as, owing to the whispers and insinuations aforesaid, my interest had been greatly excited in the hero of the Bugaboo
            and Kickapoo campaign.
         </p>
         
         <p>However, the delightfully luminous conversation of Brevet
            Brigadier General John A. B. C. Smith soon completely dis
            sipated this chagrin. My friend leaving us immediately, we
            had quite a long tête-à-tête, and I was not only pleased but
            really—instructed. I never heard a more fluent talker, or a
            man of greater general information. With becoming modesty, he forebore, nevertheless, to touch upon the theme I had
            just then most at heart—I mean the mysterious circumstances attending the Bugaboo war—and, on my own part, what
            I conceive to be a proper sense of delicacy forbade me to
            broach the subject; although, in truth, I was exceedingly
            tempted to do so. I perceived, too, that the gallant soldier
            preferred topics of philosophical interest, and that he delighted, especially, in commenting upon the rapid march of mechanical invention. Indeed, lead him where I would, this
            was a point to which he invariably came back.
         </p>
         
         <p>“There is nothing at all like it,” he would say; “we are
            a wonderful people, and live in a wonderful age, Parachutes
            and rail-roads—man-traps and spring-guns! Our steam-boats
            are upon every sea, and the Nassau balloon packet is about
            to run regular trips (fare either way only twenty pounds
            sterling) between London and Timbuctoo. And who shall
            calculate the immense influence upon social life—upon arts
            —upon commerce—upon literature—which will be the im
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page69"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            mediate result of the great principles of electro-magnetics?
            Nor is this all, let me assure you! There is really no end to
            the march of invention. The most wonderful—the most ingenious—and let me add, Mr.—Mr.—Thompson, I believe, is
            your name—let me add, I say, the most useful—the most
            truly useful mechanical contrivances, are daily springing
            up like mushrooms, if I may so express myself, or, more figuratively, like—ah—grasshoppers—like grasshoppers, Mr.
            Thompson—about us and ah—ah—ah—around us!”
         </p>
         
         <p>Thompson, to be sure, is not my name; but it is needless
            to say that I left General Smith with a heightened interest
            in the man, with an exalted opinion of his conversational
            powers, and a deep sense of the valuable privileges we enjoy
            in living in this age of mechanical invention. My curiosity,
            however, had not been altogether satisfied, and I resolved to
            prosecute immediate inquiry among my acquaintances touching the Brevet Brigadier General himself, and particularly
            respecting the tremendous events quorum pars magna fuit,
            during the Bugaboo and Kickapoo campaign.
         </p>
         
         <p>The first opportunity which presented itself, and which
            (horresco referens) I did not in the least scruple to seize, occurred at the Church of the Reverend Doctor Drummummupp, where I found myself established, one Sunday just at
            sermon time, not only in the pew, but by the side, of that
            worthy and communicative little friend of mine, Miss Tabitha T. Thus seated, I congratulated myself, and with
            much reason, upon the very flattering state of affairs. If any
            person knew anything about Brevet Brigadier General John
            A. B. C. Smith, that person, it was clear to me, was Miss
            Tabitha T. We telegraphed a few signals, and then commenced, sotto voce, a brisk tête-à-tête.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Smith!” said she, in reply to my very earnest inquiry;
            “Smith!—why, not General John A. B. C.? Bless me, I
            thought you knew all about him! This is a wonderfully inventive age! Horrid affair that!—a bloody set of wretches,
            those Kickapoos!—fought like a hero—prodigies of valor—
            immortal renown. Smith!—Brevet Brigadier General John
            A. B. C.!—why, you know he’s the man”—
         </p>
         
         <p>“Man,” here broke in Doctor Drummummupp, at the top
            of his voice, and with a thump that came near knocking
            the pulpit about our ears; “man that is born of a woman
            hath but a short time to live; he cometh up and is cut down
            like a flower!” I started to the extremity of the pew, and
            perceived by the animated looks of the divine, that the wrath
            which had nearly proved fatal to the pulpit had been excited by the whispers of the lady and myself. There was no
            help for it; so I submitted with a good grace, and listened,
            in all the martyrdom of dignified silence, to the balance of
            that very capital discourse.
         </p>
         
         <p>Next evening found me a somewhat late visitor at the
            Rantipole theatre, where I felt sure of satsifying my curiosity at once, by merely stepping into the box of those exquisite specimens of affability and omniscience, the Misses Arabella and Miranda Cognoscenti. That fine tragedian, Climax, was doing Iago to a very crowded house, and I experienced some little difficulty in making my wishes understood;
            especially as our box was next the slips, and completely overlooked the stage.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Smith?" said Miss Arabella, as she at length comprehended the purport of my query; "Smith?—why, not General John A. B. C.?”</p>
         
         <p>“Smith?" inquired Miranda, musingly. “God bless me,
            did you ever behold a finer figure?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Never, madam, but do tell me”——</p>
         
         <p>“Or so inimitable grace?"</p>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>“Never, upon my word!—but pray inform me”——</p>
         
         <p>“Or so just an appreciation of stage effect?”</p>
         
         <p>“Madam!”</p>
         
         <p>“Or a more delicate sense of the true beauties of Shakespeare? Be so good as to look at that leg!”</p>
         
         <p>“The devil!” and I turned again to her sister.</p>
         
         <p>“Smith?” said she, “why, not General John A. B. C.?
            Horrid affair that, wasn’t it?—great wretches, those Bugaboos—savage and so on—but we live in a wonderfully inventive age!—Smith!—O yes! great man!—perfect desperado
            —immortal renown—prodigies of valor! Never heard!"
            [This was given in a scream.] “Bless my soul!—why he’s
            the man”—
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>“—mandragora
            
            <br></br>Nor all the drowsy syrups of the world
            
            <br></br>Shall ever medicine thee to that sweet sleep
            
            <br></br>Which thou owd’st yesterday!”
         </div>
         
         <p>here roared out Climax just in my ear, and shaking his fist
            in my face all the time, in a way that I couldn't stand, and I
            wouldn't. I left the Misses Cognoscenti immediately, went
            behind the scenes forthwith, and gave the beggarly scoundrel such a thrashing as I trust he will remember to the day
            of his death.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the soirée of the lovely widow, Mrs. Kathleen O’Trump,
            I was confident that I should meet with no similar disappointment. Accordingly, I was no sooner seated at the card
            table, with my pretty hostess for a vis-à-vis, than I propounded those questions the solution of which had become a matter so essential to my peace.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Smith?” said my partner, “why, not General John A.
            B. C.? Horrid affair that, wasn’t it?—diamonds, did you
            say?—terrible wretches those Kickapoos!—we are playing
            whist, if you please, Mr. Tattle—however, this is the age of
            invention, most certainly—the age, one may say—the age par
            excellence—speak French?—oh, quite a hero—perfect desperado!—no hearts, Mr. Tattle? I don’t believe it!—immortal renown and all that—prodigies of valor! Never
            heard!!—why, bless me, he’s the man”—
         </p>
         
         <p>“Mann?—Captain Mann?” here screamed some little feminine interloper from the farthest corner of the room. “Are
            you talking about Captain Mann and the duel?—oh, I must
            hear—do tell—go on, Mrs. O’Trump!—do now go on!” And
            go on Mrs. O’Trump did—all about a certain Captain Mann
            who was either shot or hung, or should have been both shot
            and hung. Yes! Mrs. O’Trump, she went on, and I—I went
            off. There was no chance of hearing anything farther that
            evening in regard to Brevet Brigadier General John A. B. C.
            Smith.
         </p>
         
         <p>Still I consoled myself with the reflection that the tide of
            ill luck would not run against me forever, and so determined
            to make a bold push for information at the rout of that bewitching little angel, the graceful Mrs Pirouette.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Smith?” said Mrs. P., as we twirled about together in a
            pas de zephyr, “Smith?—why not General John A. B. C.?
            Dreadful business that of the Bugaboos, wasn’t it?—terrible
            creatures those Indians!—do turn out your toes! I really am
            ashamed of you—man of great courage, poor fellow!—but this
            is a wonderful age for invention—O dear me, I’m out of breath
            —quite a desperado—prodigies of valor—never heard!!—
            can’t believe it—I shall have to sit down and enlighten you
            —Smith! why he’s the man”—
         </p>
         
         <p>“Man-Fred, I tell you!” here bawled out Miss Bas-Bleu,
            as I led Mrs. Pirouette to a seat. “Did ever anybody hear
            the like? It’s Man-Fred, I say, and not at all by any means
            Man-Friday.” Here Miss Bas-Bleu beckoned to me in a very
            peremptory manner; and I was obliged, will I nill I, to leave
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page70"></div>
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>Mrs. P. for the purpose of deciding a dispute touching the title of a certain poetical drama of Lord Byron’s. Although I
            pronounced, with great promptness, that the true title was
            Man-Friday, and not by any means Man-Fred, yet when I
            returned to seek Mrs. Pirouette she was not to be discovered, and I made my retreat from the house in a very bitter
            spirit of animosity against the whole race of the Bas-Bleus.
         </p>
         
         <p>Matters had now assumed a really serious aspect, and I
            resolved to call at once upon my particular friend, Mr. Theodore Sinivate; for I knew that here at least I should get
            something like definite information.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Smith?” said he, in his well known peculiar way of
            drawling out his syllables; “Smith?—why, not General
            John A—B—C? Savage affair that with the Kickapo-o-o-os,
            wasn’t it? Say! don’t you think so?—perfect despera-a-ado
            —great pity, ’pon my honor!—wonderfully inventive age!—
            pro-o-odigies of valor! By the by, did you ever hear about
            Captain Ma-a-a-a-n?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Captain Mann be d—d!” said I, “please to go on with
            your story.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Hem!—oh well!—quite la même cho-o-ose, as we say in
            France. Smith, eh? Brigadier General John A—B—C.?
            I say”—[here Mr. S. thought proper to put his finger to the
            side of his nose]—“I say, you don’t mean to insinuate now,
            really, and truly, and conscientiously, that you don’t know
            all about that affair of Smith’s, as well as I do, eh? Smith?
            John A—B—C.? Why bless me, he’s the ma-a-an”—
         </p>
         
         <p>“Mr. Sinivate,” said I imploringly, “is he the man in the
            mask?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“No-o-o!” said he, looking wise, "nor the man in the
            mo-o-o-on.”
         </p>
         
         <p>This reply I considered a pointed and positive insult, and
            so left the house at once in high dudgeon, with a firm resolve
            to call my friend, Mr. Sinivate, to a speedy account for his
            ungentlemanly conduct and ill breeding.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the meantime, however, I had no notion of being thwarted touching the information I desired. There was one resource left me yet. I would go to the fountain head. I
            would call forthwith upon the General himself, and demand,
            in explicit terms, a solution of this abominable piece of mystery. Here at least there should be no chance for equivocation. would be plain, positive, peremptory—as short as
            pie-crust—as concise as Tacitus or Montesquieu.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was early when I called, and the general was dressing;
            but I pleaded urgent business, and was shown at once into
            his bed-room by an old negro valet, who remained in attendance during my visit. As I entered the chamber, I looked
            about, of course, for the occupant, but did not immediately
            perceive him. There was a large and exceedingly odd looking bundle of something which lay close by my feet on the
            floor, and, as I was not in the best humor in the world, I
            gave it a kick out of the way.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Hem! ahem! rather civil that, I should say!” said the
            bundle, in one of the smallest, and altogether the funniest
            little voices, between a squeak and a whistle, that I ever
            heard in all the days of my existence.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Ahem! rather civil that, I should observe.”</p>
         
         <p>I fairly shouted with terror, and made off, at a tangent, into the farthest extremity of the room.</p>
         
         <p>“God bless me! my dear fellow,’’ here again whistled the
            bundle “what—what—what—why, what is the matter? I
            really believe you don’t know me at all.”
         </p>
         
         <p>What could I say to all this—what could I? I staggered
            into an arm-chair, and, with staring eyes and open mouth,
            awaited the solution of the wonder.
         </p>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>“Strange you shouldn’t know me though, isn’t it?” presently re-squeaked the nondescript, which I now perceived
            was performing, upon the floor, some inexplicable evolution,
            very analagous to the drawing on of a stocking. There was
            only a single leg, however, apparent.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Strange you shouldn’t know me, though, isn’t it? Pompey, bring me that leg!” Here Pompey handed the bundle
            a very capital cork leg, all ready dressed, which it screwed
            on in a trice; and then it stood upright before my eyes.
         </p>
         
         <p>“And a bloody action it was," continued the thing, as if in
            a soliloquy; “but then one musn't fight with the Bugaboos
            and Kickapoos, and think of coming off with a mere scratch.
            Pompey, I’ll thank you now for that arm. Thomas” [turning to me] “is decidedly the best hand at a cork leg;
            but if you should ever want an arm, my dear fellow, you
            must really let me recommend you to Bishop.” Here Pompey screwed on an arm.
         </p>
         
         <p>“We had rather hot work of it, that you may say. Now,
            you dog, slip on my shoulders and bosom! Pettitt makes
            the best shoulders, but for a bosom you will have to go to Ducrow.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Bosom!” said I.</p>
         
         <p>“Pompey, will you never be ready with that wig? Scalping is a rough process after all; but then you can procure
            such a capital scratch at De L’Orme’s.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Scratch!”</p>
         
         <p>“Now, you nigger, my teeth! For a good set of these
            you had better go to Parmly’s at once; high prices, but excellent work. I swallowed some very capital articles, though,
            when the big Bugaboo rammed me down with the butt end
            of his rifle.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Butt end! ram down!! my eye!!!”</p>
         
         <p>“O yes, by the by, my eye—here, Tompey, you scamp,
            screw it in! Those Kickapoos are not so very slow at a
            gouge; but he’s a belied man, that Dr. Williams, after all;
            you can’t imagine how well I see with the eyes of his
            make.”
         </p>
         
         <p>I now began very clearly to perceive that the object before
            me was nothing more nor less than my new acquaintance,
            Brevet Brigadier General John A. B. C. Smith. The manipulations of Pompey had made, I must confess, a very striking difference in the appearance of the personal man. The
            voice, however, still puzzled me no little; but even this apparent mystery was speedily cleared up.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Pompey, you black rascal,” squeaked the General, “I
            really do believe you would let me go out without my palate.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Hereupon the negro, grumbling out an apology, went up
            to his master, opened his mouth with the knowing air of a
            horse-jockey, and adjusted therein a somewhat singular-looking machine, in a very dexterous manner, that I could not
            altogether comprehend. The alteration, however, in the
            entire expression of the General’s countenance was instantaneous and surprising. When he again spoke, his voice had
            resumed all that rich melody and strength which I had noticed upon our original introduction.
         </p>
         
         <p>“D—n the vagabonds!” said he, in so clear a tone that I
            positively started at the change, “D—n the vagabonds! they
            not only knocked in the roof of my mouth, but took the trouble to cut off at least seven-eighths of my tongue. There
            is’nt Bonfanti’s equal, however, in America, for really good
            articles of this description. I can recommend you to him
            with confidence,” [here the General bowed,] “and assure
            you that I have the greatest pleasure in so doing.”
         </p>
         
         <p>I acknowledged his kindness in my best manner, and took
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page71"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>leave of him at once, with a perfect understanding of the true
            state of aflairs—with a full comprehension of the mystery
            which had troubled me so long. It was evident. It was a
            clear case. Brevet Brigadier General John A. B. C. Smith
            was the man----was the man that was used up.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            <div class="ab">Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XVI.
               
               <br></br>Prose and Verse. By Thomas Hood. Part I. New-York:
               
               <br></br>Wi/ey and Putnam.
            </div>
            
            <p>Of this number of the Library we said a few words last
               week—but Hood was far too remarkable a man to be passed
               over in so cursory a manner.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Frequently since his recent death,” says the American
               editor, “he has been called a great author, a phrase used not
               inconsiderately or in vain.” Yet, if we adopt the conventional idea of “a great author,” there has lived, perhaps, no
               writer of the last half century who, with equal notoriety,
               was less entitled than Hood to the term. In fact, he was a
               literary merchant whose principal stock in trade was littleness—for during the larger portion of his life he seemed to
               breathe only for the purpose of perpetrating puns—things of
               such despicable platitude, that the man who is capable of
               habitually committing them, is very seldom capable of anything else. In especial, whatever merit may accidentally be
               discovered in a pun, arises altogether from unexpectedness.
               This is its element, and is twofold. First, we demand that
               the combination of the pun be unexpected, and secondly, we
               demand the most entire unexpectedness in the pun per se. A
               rare pun, rarely appearing, is, to a certain extent, a pleasurable
               effect—but to no mind, however debased in taste, is a continuous effort at punning otherwise than unendurable. The
               man who maintains that he derives gratification from any
               such chapters of punnage as Hood was in the daily habit of
               putting to paper, has no claim to be believed upon his oath.
               What, for example, is any rational being to make of such jargon as this, which we copy from the very first page of the
               volume before us?
            </p>
            
            <p>Courteous Reader!</p>
            
            <p>Presuming that you have known something of the Comic Annual
               from its Child-Hood, when it was first put into half binding and began
               to run alone, I make bold to consider you as an old friend of the family, and shall accordingly treat you with all the freedom and confidence
               that pertain to such ripe connexions.
            </p>
            
            <p>How many years is it, think you, "since we were first acquent?”</p>
            
            <p>"By the deep nine!” sings out the old bald Count Fathom with the
               lead-line: no great lapse in the world's chronology, but a space of infinite importance in individual history. For instance, it has wrought
               a serious change on the body, if not on the mind, of your very humble servant;—it is not, however, to bespeak your sympathy, or to indulge in what Lord Byron calls "the gloomy vanity of drawing from
               self,” that I allude to my personal experience. The Scot and lot character of the dispensation forbids me to think that the world in general can be particularly interested in the state of my Household Sufferage, or that the public ear will be as open to my Maladies as to my
               Melodies.
            </p>
            
            <p>Here is something better from page five—but still we look
               upon the whole thing as a nuisance:
            </p>
            
            <p>A rope is a bad Cordon Sanitaire. Let not anxiety have thee on
               the hyp. Consider your health as your best friend, and think as well
               of it, in spite of all its foibles as you can. For instance, never dream,
               though you may have a “clever hack,” of galloping consumption, or
               indulge in the Meltonian belief that you are going the pace. Never
               fancy every time you cough, that you are going to coughypot. Hold
               up as the shooter says, over the heaviest ground. Despondency in a
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               nice case is the over-weight that may make you kick the beam and the
               bucket both at once. In short, as with other cases, never meet trouble
               half-way, but let him have the whole walk for his pains; though it
               should be a Scotch mile and a bittock. I have even known him to give
               up his visit in sight of the house. Besides, the best fence against care
               is a ha! ha!—wherefore take care to have one all around you whereever you can. Let your “lungs crow like Chanticleer,” and as like a
               Game cock as possible. It expands the chest, enlarges the heart,
               quickens the circulation, and “like a trumpet makes the spirit dance.’”
            </p>
            
            <p>The continuous and premeditated puns of Hood, however,
               are to be regarded as the weak points of the man. Independently of their ill effect, in a literary view, as mere puns,
               they leave upon us a painful impression; for too evidently
               they are the hypochondriac’s struggles at mirth—they are the
               grinnings of the death’s-head. No one can read his Literary
               Reminiscences without being convinced of his habitual despondency—and the species of pseudo wit in question, is precisely of that character which would be adopted by an author of Hood’s temperament and cast of intellect, when compelled to write, at an emergency. That his heart had no interest in these niaiseries, is clear. We allude, of course, to
               his mere puns for the pun’s sake—-a class of letters by which
               he attained his most extensive renown. That he did more in
               this way than in any other, would follow as a corollary
               from what we have already said—for, generally, he was unhappy, and, almost continually, he was obliged to write, invita Minerva. But his true element was a very rare and
               ethereal class of humor, in which the mere pun was left altogether out of sight, or took the character of the richest grotesquerie, impressing the imaginative reader with very remarkable force, as if by a new phase of the ideal. It is in
               this species of brilliant grotesquerie,'uttered with a rushing
               abandon which wonderfully aided its efTcct, that Hood’s marked originality of manner consisted; and it is this which fairly
               entitles him, at times, to the epithet “great—we say fairly
               so entitles him; for that undeniably may be considered great
               —(of whatever seeming littleness in itself) which has the
               capability of producing intense emotion in the minds of those
               who are themselves undeniably great.
            </p>
            
            <p>When we said, however, that Hood wrought profound impressions upon imaginative men, we spoke only of what is
               imagination in the popular acceptance of the term. His
               true province—that is to say the field in which he is distinctive—is a kind of border land between the Fancy and the
               Fantasy—but in this region he reigns supreme. That we
               may be the more clearly understood on this head, we will
               venture to quote a few passages of definition which were
               used by ourselves on a former occasion—while commenting
               on the prose style of Mr. Willis:—it is indeed too much the
               custom to employ at absolute random such words as Wit,
               Humor, Fantasy, the Fancy, and the Imagination.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the style of Mr. Willis wo easily detect this idiosyncrasy. We
               have no trouble in tracing it home—and when we reach it and look
               it fairly in the face, we recognize it on the instant.—It is Fancy.
            </p>
            
            <p>To be sure there is quite a tribe of Fancies—although one half of
               them never suspected themselves to be such until so told by the metaphysicians—but the one of which we speak has never yet been accredited among men, and we beg pardon of Mr. Willis for the liberty we
               take in employing the topic of bis style, as the best possible vehicle and
               opportunity for the introduction of this, our protégé, to the consideration of the literary world.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Fancy,” says the author of “Aids to Reflection” (who aided Reflection to much better purpose in his “Genevieve”)—“Fancy combines—Imagination creates.” This was intended, and has been received, as a distinction; but it is a distinction without a difference—
               without even a difference of degree. The Fancy as nearly creates as
               the imagination, and neither at all. Novel conceptions are merely unusual combinations. The mind of man can imagine nothing which
               does not exist:—if it could, it would create not only ideally, but sub
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page72"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               stantially—as do the thoughts of God. It may be said—“We imagine a griffin, yet a griffin does not exist/’ Not the griffin certainly,
               but its component parts. It is no more than a collation of known
               limbs—features—qualities. Thus with all which claims to be new—
               which appears to be a creation of the intellect:—it is re-soluble into
               the old. The wildest effort of the mind cannot stand the test of the
               analysis.
            </p>
            
            <p>We might make a distinction of degree between the fancy and the
               imagination, in calling the latter the former loftily employed. But
               experience would prove this distinction to be unsatisfactory. What
               we feel to be fancy, will be found still fanciful, whatever be the theme
               which engages it. No subject exalts it into imagination. When
               Moore is termed a fanciful poet, the epithet is precisely applied; he is.
               He is fanciful in “Lalla Rookh,” and had he written the “Inferno,” j
               there he would have been fanciful still: for not only is he essentially
               fanciful, but he has no ability to be any thing more, unless at rare intervals—by snatches—and with effort. What we say of him at this
               point, moreover, is equally true of all little frisky men, personally considered.
            </p>
            
            <p>The fact seems to be that Imagination, Fancy, Fantasy, and Humor, have in common the elements, Combination, and Novelty. The
               Imagination is the artist of the four. From novel arrangements of old
               forms which present themselves to it, it selects only such as are harmonious:—the result, of course, is beauty itself—using the term in its
               most extended sense, and as inclusive of the sublime. The pure imagination chooses, from either beauty or deformity, only the most combinable things hitherto uncombined;—the compound, as a genera!
               rule, partaking (in character) of sublimity or beauty, in the ratio of
               the respective sublimity or beauty of the things combined—which are
               themselves still to be considered as atomic—that is to say, as previous combinations. But, as often analogously happens in physical
               chemistry, so not unfrequently does it occur in this chemistry of the
               intellect, that the admixture of two elements will result in a something
               that shall have nothing of the quality of one of them—or even nothing of the qualities of either. The range of Imagination is therefore,
               unlimited. Its materials extend throughout the Universe. Even out
               of deformities it fabricates that beauty which is at once its sole object
               and its inevitable test. But, in general, the richness or force of the
               matters combined—the facility of discovering combinable novelties
               worth combining—and the absolute “chemical combination” and proportion of the completed mass—are the particulars to be regarded in
               our estimate of Imagination. It is this thorough harmony of an imaginative work which so often causes it to be under-valued by the
               undiscriminating, through the character of obviousness which is superinduced. We are apt to find ourselves asking "why is it that these
               combinations have never been imagined before?”
            </p>
            
            <p>Now, when this question does not occur—when the harmony of the
               combination is comparatively neglected, and when in addition to the
               clement of novelty, there is introduced the sub-element of unexpectedness—when, for example, matters are brought into combination which
               not only have never been combined but whose combination strikes us
               as a difficulty happily overcome—the result then appertains to the
               Fancy—and is, to the majority of mnnkind more grateful than the
               purely harmonious one—although, absolutely, it is less beautiful (or
               grand) for the reason that it is less harmonious.
            </p>
            
            <p>Carrying its errors into excess—for, however enticing, they are errors still, or Nature lies,—Fancy is at length found impinging upon
               the province of Fantasy. The votaries of this latter delight not only
               in novelty and unexpectedness of combination, but in the avoidance of 
               proportion. The result is therefore abnormal, and to a healthy mind
               aflords less of pleasure through its novelty, than of pain through its incoherence. When, proceeding a step farther, however, Fantasy seeks
               not merely disproportionate but incongruous or antagonistical elements, the effect is rendered moie pleasurable from its greater positiveness;—there is a merry effort of Truth to shake from her that
               which is no property of hers;—and we laugh outright in recognizing
               Humor.
            </p>
            
            <p>The four faculties in question appear to me all of their class;—but
               when either Fancy or Humor is expressed to gain an end—is pointed
               at a purpose—whenever either becomes objective in place of subjective
               —then it becomes, also, pure Wit or Sarcasm, just us the purpose is
               well-intaulioned or malevolent.
            </p>
            
            <p>These, we grant, are entirely new views, but we do not
               consider them as the less surely deduced. At all events their
               admission ior the present will enable us to be lucid on the
               topic of Hood. When we speak of his province as a border
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               ground between Fantasy and Fancy, of course we do not
               mean rigorously to confine him to this province. He has
               made very successful and frequent incursions into the dominions of Humor (in general he has been too benevolent to be
               witty), and there have been one or two occasions—(those,
               for instance, of his “Eugene Aram” and “Bridge of Sighs,”)
               in which he has stepped boldly, yet vacillatingly, into the
               realm of Imagination herself. We mean to say, however, that
               he is never truly imaginative for more than a paragraph
               at a time.
            </p>
            
            <p>In a word, the genius of Hood is the result of vivid Fancy
               impelled, or controlled,—certainly tinctured, at all points, by
               hypochondriasis. In his wild “Ode to Melancholy,” which
               forms the closing poem of the volume now reviewed, we perceive this result in the very clearest of manifestations. Few
               things have ever more deeply affected us than the passages
               which follow:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“O clasp me, sweet, whilst thou art mine,
               
               <br></br>And do not take my tears amiss;
               
               <br></br>For tears must flow to wash away
               
               <br></br>A thought that shows so stern as this:
               
               <br></br>Forgive, if somewhile I forget,
               
               <br></br>In wo to come, the present bliss.
               
               <br></br>As frighted Proserpine let fall
               
               <br></br>Her flowers at the sight of Dis,
               
               <br></br>Ev’n so the dark and bright will kiss.
               
               <br></br>The sunniest things throw sternest shade,
               
               <br></br>And there is ev’n a happiness
               
               <br></br>That makes the heart afraid!
               
               
               <br></br>All things are touched with Melancholy,
               
               <br></br>Born of the secret soul’s mistrust,
               
               <br></br>To feel her fair ethereal wings
               
               <br></br>Weigh’d down with vile degraded dust;
               
               <br></br>Even the bright extremes of joy
               
               <br></br>Bring on conclusions of disgust,
               
               <br></br>Like the sweet blossoms of the May,
               
               <br></br>Whose fragrance ends in must.
               
               <br></br>Oh give her, then, her tribute just,
               
               <br></br>Her sighs and tears, and musings holy!
               
               <br></br>There is no music in the life
               
               <br></br>That sounds with idiot laughter solely;
               
               <br></br>There’s not a string attuned to mirth,
               
               <br></br>But has its chords of Melancholy.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>In “The Pugsley Papers,” with which the volume opens,
               we have the correspondence of a Cockney family of shoemakers, who, receiving a rich legacy, retire at once to the
               otium cum dignitate of a country mansion. The mishaps
               and mismanagements of the party are told in the broadest
               extravaganza admissible or conceivable—very much in the
               Ramsbottom way—although the tone of Hood’s jeu d'esprit
               is the better of the two. It is not so much humorous in itself, as productive of the usual humorous effect. We laugh
               not altogether at the incongruities of the narrative, but at the
               incongruity of Hood’s supposing that we will laugh at anything so absurdand it must be confessed, that it all
               amounts to pretty much the same thing in the end.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Elack, White and Brown,” is an Abolition tale — or
               rather a squib against Abolition. Its finale has some point
               —but, on the whole, the story has the air of an effort, and is
               quite unworthy of Hood.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The Portrait,” “The Apology,” and “The Literary Reminiscences” (which form one subject,) have, we think, exceedingly little interest. The author himself acknowledges
               that he has no capacity for Boswellism—and we agree with
               him altogether.
            </p>
            
            <p>“An Undertaker” is a mere string of puns—giving no idea
               of the true spirit of the author.
            </p>
            
            <p>The rest of the book is verse—and much of it very remarkable verse indeed.</p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page73"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            
            <p>“The Dream of Eugene Aram,” is too well known in
               America to need comment from us. It has (as we observed
               just now,) more of true imagination than any composition of
               its author;—but even when engaged on so serious a subject,
               he found great difficulty in keeping aloof from the grotesque
               —the result (we say) of warm Fancy impelled by Hypochondriasis. The opening stanza affords an example:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>’Twas in the prime of summer time,
               
               <br></br>An evening calm and cool,
               
               <br></br>When four-and-twenty happy boys
               
               <br></br>Came bounding out of school;
               
               <br></br>There were some that ran, and some Vial leapt,
               
               <br></br>Like troutlets in a pool.”
            </div>
            
            
            <p>Stanza the twenty-fourth approaches more nearly the imaginative spirit than any passage in the poem—but the taint
               of the fantastical is over it still:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>“And peace went with them one and all,
               
               <br></br>And each calm pillow spread;
               
               <br></br>But Guilt was my grim chamberlain
               
               <br></br>That lighted me to bed.
               
               <br></br>And drew my midnight curtains round,
               
               <br></br>With fingers bloody red!”
            </div>
            
            
            <p>“The Lost Heir” is possibly aimed at a well-known novel
               of the same title. The effect depends upon the principle to
               which we referred when speaking of “The Pugsley Papers.”
               We laugh chiefly (although not altogether) at the author's
               absurdity. The lines belong to the class helter-skelter—that
               is to say, they are the flattest of all possible prose—intentionally so, of course. The story (if story it can be called) embodies the lamentations of a poor Irish woman who has lost
               her son.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Autumn” and “A Song,” (occupying each one page)
               have nothing about them especially remarkable. “Fair
               Ines” is so beautiful' that we shall purloin it in full—although we have no doubt that it is familiar to our readers:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br> I.
               
               <br></br>O saw ye not fair Ines?
               
               <br></br>She’s gone into the West,
               
               <br></br>To dazzle when the sun is down,
               
               <br></br>And rob the world of rest;
               
               <br></br>She took our daylight with her,
               
               <br></br>The smiles that we love best,
               
               <br></br>With morning blushes on her cheek,
               
               <br></br>And pearls upon her breast,
               
               
               <br></br>II.
               
               <br></br>O	turn again, fair Ines,
               
               <br></br>Before the full of night,
               
               <br></br>For fear the moon should shine alone,
               
               <br></br>And stars unrivalled bright;
               
               <br></br>And blessed will the lover be
               
               <br></br>That walks beneath their light,
               
               <br></br>And breathes the love against thy cheek
               
               <br></br>I dare not even write!
               
               
               <br></br>III.
               
               <br></br>Would I had been, fair Ines,
               
               <br></br>That gallant cavalier,
               
               <br></br>Who rode so gaily by thy side,
               
               <br></br>And whispered thee so near!
               
               <br></br>Were there no bonny dames at home,
               
               <br></br>Or no true lovers here,
               
               <br></br>That he should cross the seas to win
               
               <br></br>The dearest of the dear?
               
               
               <br></br>IV.
               
               <br></br>I	saw thee, lovely Ines,
               
               <br></br>Descend along the shore,
               
               <br></br>With bands of noble gentlemen.
               
               <br></br>And banners waved before;
               
               <br></br>And gentle youth and maidens gay,
               
               <br></br>And snowy plumes they wore;
               
               <br></br>It would have been a beauteous dream,
               
               <br></br>— If it had been no more!
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               
               
               <br></br>V.
               
               <br></br>Alas, alas, fair Ines,
               
               <br></br>She went away with song,
               
               <br></br>With Music waiting on her steps,
               
               <br></br>And shoutings of the throng;
               
               <br></br>But some were sad and felt no mirth,
               
               <br></br>But only Music’s wrong,
               
               <br></br>In sounds that sang Farewell, Farewell,
               
               <br></br>To her you’ve loved so long,
               
               
               <br></br>VI.
               
               <br></br>Farewell, farewell, fair Ines,
               
               <br></br>That vessel never bore
               
               <br></br>So fair a lady on its deck,
               
               <br></br>Nor danced so light before,—
               
               <br></br>Alas, for pleasure on the sea,
               
               <br></br>And sorrow on the shore!
               
               <br></br>The smile that blest one lover’s heart
               
               <br></br>Has broken many more!
            </div>
            
            
            <p>The only article which remains to be noticed, is “Miss
               Killmansegg and Her Precious Leg”—and it is, perhaps,
               more thoroughly characteristic of Hood’s genius than any
               single thing which he has written. It is quite a long poem
               —comprising nearly 3000 lines—and its author has evidently
               laboured it much. Its chief defect is in its versification; and
               for this Hood had no ear—of its principles he knew nothing
               at all. Not that his verses, individually, are very lame, but
               they have no capacity for running together. The reader is
               continually getting baulked—not because the lines are unreadable, but because the lapse from one rhythm to another
               is so inarlistically managed.
            </p>
            
            <p>The story concerns a very rich heiress who is excessively
               pampered by her parents, and who at length gets thrown
               from a horse and so injures a leg as to render amputation
               inevitable. To supply the place of the true limb, she insists
               upon a leg of solid gold—a leg of the exact proportions of
               the original. She puts up with its inconvenience for the
               sake of the admiration it excites. Its attractions, however,
               excite the cupidity of a chevalier d'industrie, who cajoles her
               into wedlock, dissipates her fortune, and, finally, purloining
               her golden leg, dashes out her brains with it, elopes, and
               puts an end to the story.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is wonderfully well told, and abounds in the most brilliant points—embracing something of each of the elementary
               faculties which we have been discussing—but most especially rich in that which we have termed Fantasy. We quote
               at random some brief passages, which will serve to exemplify our meaning:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>A Lord of Land, on his own estate,
               
               <br></br>He lived at a lively rate,
               
               <br></br>   But his income would bear carousing;
               
               <br></br>Such acres he had of pasture and heath,
               
               <br></br>With herbage so rich from the ore beneath,
               
               <br></br>The very ewe’s and lambkin’s teeth
               
               <br></br>   Were turn’d into gold by browsing.
               
               
               <br></br>He gave, without any extra thrift,
               
               <br></br>A Hock of sheep for a birthday gift
               
               <br></br>   To each son of his loins, or daughter:
               
               <br></br>And his debts—if debts he had—at will
               
               <br></br>He liquidated by giving each bill
               
               <br></br>   A dip in Pactolian water.
               
               
               <br></br>’Twas said that even his pigs of lead,
               
               <br></br>By crossing with some by Midas bred,
               
               <br></br>   Made a perfect mine of his piggery.
               
               <br></br>And as for cattle, one yearling bull
               
               <br></br>Was worth all Smithfield-market full
               
               <br></br>   Of the Golden Bulls of Pope Gregory.
               
               
               <br></br>The high-bred horses within his stud.
               
               <br></br>Like human creatures of birth and blood,
               
               <br></br>   Had their Golden Cups and flagons:
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page74"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               
               <br></br>And as for the common husbandry nags,
               
               <br></br>Their noses were tied in money-bags,
               
               <br></br>   When they stopp’d with the carts and wagons.
               
               
               <br></br>Into this world we come like ships,
               
               <br></br>Launched from the docks and stocks and slips,
               
               <br></br>   For fortune fair or fatal;
               
               <br></br>And one little craft is cast away
               
               <br></br>In its very first trip to Babbicome Bay,
               
               <br></br>   While another rides safe at Port Natal.
               
               
               <br></br>Whilst Margaret, charm’d by the Bulbul rare,
               
               <br></br>   In a garden of Gul reposes—
               
               <br></br>Poor Peggy hawks nosegays from street to street,
               
               <br></br>Till—think of that, who find life so sweet—
               
               <br></br>   She hates the smell of roses!
               
               
               <br></br>To paint the maternal Kilmansegg
               
               <br></br>The pen of an Eastern Poet would beg,
               
               <br></br>   And need an elaborate sonnet;
               
               <br></br>How she sparkled with gems whenever she stirred,
               
               <br></br>And her head niddle-nodded at every word,
               
               <br></br>And seem’d so happy, a Paradise bird
               
               <br></br>   Had nidificated upon it.
               
               
               <br></br>And Sir Jacob the Father strutted and bow’d,
               
               <br></br>And smiled to himself, and laugh’d aloud,
               
               <br></br>   To think of his heiress and daughter—
               
               <br></br>And then in his pockets he made a grope,
               
               <br></br>And then in the fulness of joy and hope,
               
               <br></br>Seem’d washing himself with invisible soap,
               
               <br></br>   In imperceptible water.
               
               
               <br></br>Gold! and gold! and besides the gold
               
               <br></br>The very robe of the infant told
               
               <br></br>A tale of wealth in every told,
               
               <br></br>It lapp’d her like a vapor!
               
               <br></br>So fine! so thin! the mind at a loss
               
               <br></br>Could compare it to nothing except a cross
               
               <br></br>Of cobweb with bank-note paper.
               
               
               <br></br>They praised—how they praised—her very small talk,
               
               <br></br>   As if it fell from a Solon;
               
               <br></br>Or the girl who at each pretty phrase let drop
               
               <br></br>A ruby comma, ora pearl full stop,
               
               <br></br>   Or an emerald semi-colon.
               
               
               <br></br>Plays she perused—but she liked the best
               
               <br></br>Those comedy gentlefolks always possess’d
               
               <br></br>   Of fortunes so truly romantic—
               
               <br></br>Of money so ready that right or wrong
               
               <br></br>It is always ready to go for a song,
               
               <br></br>Throwing it, going it, pitching it strong—
               
               <br></br>They ought to have purses as green and long
               
               <br></br>   As the cucumber called the Gigantic.
               
               
               <br></br>A load of treasure?—alas! alas!
               
               <br></br>Had her horse been fed upon English grass,
               
               <br></br>   And sheltered in Yorkshire Spinneys,
               
               <br></br>Had he scour’d the sand with the Desert Ass,
               
               <br></br>   Or where the American whinnies—
               
               <br></br>But a hunter from Erin's Turf and gorse,
               
               <br></br>A regular thorough bred Irish horse,
               
               <br></br>Why, he ran away, as a matter of course,
               
               <br></br>   With a girl worth her weight in guineas!
               
               
               <br></br>"Batter her! shatter her!
               
               <br></br>Throw her and scatter her!”
               
               <br></br>Shouts each stony-hearted clalterer—
               
               <br></br>   “Dash at the heavy Dover!
               
               <br></br>Spill her! kill her! tear her aud tatter her!
               
               <br></br>Smash her! crash her!” (the stones did’nt flatter her!)
               
               <br></br>“Kick her brains out! let her blood spatter her!
               
               <br></br>   Roll on her over and over!”
               
               <br></br>For so she gather’d the awful sense
               
               <br></br>Of the street in its past unmacadamised tense,
               
               <br></br>   As the wild horse overran it,—
               
               <br></br>His four heels making the clatter of six,
               
               <br></br>Like a Devil’s tattoo, played with iron sticks
               
               <br></br>   On a kettle-drum of granite!
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               
               
               <br></br>A Breaktast—no unsubstantial mess,
               
               <br></br>But one in the style of good Queen Bess,
               
               <br></br>   Who,—hearty as hippocampus,—
               
               <br></br>Broke her fast with ale and beef,
               
               <br></br>Instead of toast and the Chinese leaf,
               
               <br></br>   And in lieu of anchovy—grampus!
               
               
               <br></br>In they went, and hunted about,
               
               <br></br>Open-mouth’d, like chub and trout,
               
               <br></br>And some with the upper lip thrust out,
               
               <br></br>   Like that fish for routing, a barbel—
               
               <br></br>While Sir Jacob stood to welcome the crowd,
               
               <br></br>And rubb’d his hands, and smiled aloud,
               
               <br></br>And bow’d, and bow’d, and bow’d, and bou’d,
               
               <br></br>   Like a man who is sawing marble.
               
               
               <br></br>But a child—that bids the world good night
               
               <br></br>In downright earnest and cuts it quite—
               
               <br></br>   A Cherub no art can copy,—
               
               <br></br>’Tis a perfect picture to see him lie
               
               <br></br>As if he had supped on dormouse pie,
               
               <br></br>(An ancient classical dish by the by)
               
               <br></br>   With a sauce of syrup of poppy.
               
               
               <br></br>So still without,—so still within;—
               
               <br></br>   It had been a sin
               
               <br></br>   To drop a pin—
               
               <br></br>So intense is silence after a din,
               
               <br></br>   It seem’d like Death’s rehearsal!
               
               <br></br>To stir the air no eddy came;
               
               <br></br>And the taper burnt uith as still aflame,
               
               <br></br>As to flicker had been a burning shame,
               
               <br></br>In a calm so universal.
               
               
               <br></br>And oh! when the blessed diurnal light
               
               <br></br>Is quench’d by the providential night,
               
               <br></br>   To render our slumber more certain,
               
               <br></br>Pity, pity the wretches that weep,
               
               <br></br>For they must be wretched that cannot sleep
               
               <br></br>   When God himself draws the Curtain!
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="ab">Ettore Fieramosca, or The Challenge of Barletta, an Histor-
               
               <br></br>ical Romance of the Times of the Medici, by Massino D’
               
               <br></br>Azeglio. Translated from the Italian by C. Edwards
               
               <br></br>Lester, U. S. Consul at Genoa, author of "The Glory and
               
               <br></br>Shame of England," member of the Aleneo Ilaliano at
               
               <br></br>Florence, etc. New- York: Panic Burgess.
            </div>
            
            <p>This is a neatly printed duodecimo of nearly 300 pages, and
               forms the first number of “The Medici Series of Italian
               Prose.” The design of this series is to supply the American
               public with translations of the best Italian prose romances.
               Mr. Lester is to be translator and editor. Something of this
               kind is certainly much needed. While we have been fairly
               overwhelmed with both good and bad from the literature of
               France, Germany, and Sweden, that of Italy has been of late
               altogether, or nearly altogether neglected. The present enterprise extends, we believe, no farther than to the Italian
               Romance, in its ordinary acceptation; but it is not generally
               known that there exists a vast mine of Italian Comedy, some
               of which would amply repay the working. Marmontel, in
               his “Encyclopedic,” roundly declares that there is not a single comedy in the language worth reading; and the usual
               error on this subject has probably found its origin in his ignorance. Some of the greatest names in Italian Literature
               were writers of Comedy. Baretti mentions four thousand
               dramas collected by Apostolo Zeno; the greater portion of
               these were comedies; and many of them possessed not only
               high but very peculiar excellence. It is time that some of
               these works should be unearthed.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The Challenge of Barletta” has been frequently designated, by the Italian and British critics, as the best romance
               of its language. It is certainly a vivacious work, but is defective in having little of what we understand by the “auto
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page75"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               rial comment”—that which adds so deep a charm to the
               novels of Scott, of Bulwer, or of D’Israeli—more especially
               to the works of Godwin and Brockden Brown. The book
               before us is feeble, too frequently, from its excess of simplicity in form and tone. The narrative proceeds as if to narrate
               were the author’s sole business. The interest of mere incident, is all.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="ab">A Cyclopcedia of Several Thousand Practical Receipts, and
               
               <br></br>Collateral Information in the Arts, Manufactures, and
               
               <br></br>Trades, — including Medicine, Pharmacy, and Domes-
               
               <br></br>tic Economy. Designed as a Compendious Book of Ref-
               
               <br></br>erence for the Manufacturer, Tradesman, Amateur, and
               
               <br></br>Heads of Families. By Arnold James Cooley. Illustra-
               
               <br></br>ted with Numerous Engravings. New-York: D. Apple-
               
               <br></br>ton &amp; Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>We give in full the comprehensive title of this work, as the
               best mode of explaining its design. No. 1 has been just issued, at 25 cents. It proceeds (alphabetically) as far as the
               word Beans.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="ab">The Parting Spirit's Address to his Mother. By William
               
               <br></br>Edward Wyatt, D. D., Rector of St. Paul's Parish, Balti-
               
               <br></br>more. New York: Stanford &amp; Swords.
            </div>
            
            <p>A very small pamphlet of poetical prose.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="ab">Wiley and Putnam's Library of American Books. No. III.
               
               <br></br>Letters from Italy. By J. T. Headley. Wiley and Put-
               
               <br></br>nam.
            </div>
            
            <p>This is a work to be read. Of books generally it is said,
               that one is fine, another artistical, another elegant, another
               vigorous: but the peculiar property of this book of Mr. Headley’s is, that it is written to be read. He writes as a rapid
               talker speaks. He carries you along just as a man of animated gesture, quick eye, and earnest utterance takes you
               with him in the recital of a story or a sketch of character.
               Mr. Headley is an observer of great quickness; he sees at
               once and seizes all that suits his purpose. There is no escaping him, if he has the least interest to arrest an object
               and fix it on his page. These are perhaps more literally
               First Impressions of Travel than any ever published. They
               appear to have sprung directly to the eye of the traveller,
               flashed an instant in the brain, and then through a speedy
               pen to the reader. By relying merely on his own honest
               spontaneous impressions, he makes old things look new, and
               by steaming along, in true American style, through and over
               guide-books, itineraries, Eustace, Forsyth and company, he
               attains a merit analogous to that of high invention in imaginative writing. And although this spirit carries him at limes
               too far, it gives constant freshness to his record; merging
               faults of style and expression in the hurry of description and
               the eagerness with which he constantly presents the results
               of his observations to the reader. We are now and then
               taken aback, we confess, by an assertion of so broad and
               comprehensive a nature as to sweep the field of criticism and
               statement from end to end. For instance, he encounters at
               Florence a new artist, by name Dupre—a Frenchman by extraction, though an Italian by birth, who executed last year,
               unknown to any body, the model of a dead Abel, and Mr.
               Headley regards this figure “as equal, if not superior in its
               kind, to any statue ever wrought by any sculptor of any age.”
               Another peculiarity of this traveller of ours is, that by some
               happiness in his arrangement, by some good fortune for which
               he has bargained with Veturino, clerk of the weather, or
               other sufficient authority, whenever or wherever any thing
               marvellous or wonderful is to happen, he is always there to
               see. Whoever can be dissatisfied or object to such a com
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               panion, has a soul of adamant, and is altogether wanting in
               that gum elasticity, which has lately been set down as an
               attribute of the imagination of infants. We have nothing to
               say now of the Man Overboard (a small matter) nor of the
               Man in the Wall, nor of the Convulsed Man in the pit of the
               opera, nor of the six-barrelled Avalanches. Mr. Headley had
               gone, on a certain evening, to the well-known royal farms,
               constituting the great public drive and promenade of Florence. “The Duke’s family were strolling around quite at
               their ease, and the whole place was as lively as Hyde Park
               at 5 o’clock in the evening. I walked home by the Arno,
               and entering the city, witnessed one of those spectacles that
               are constantly intruding themselves in our brightest dreams,
               and turning this world into a place of tears. As I was passing along the street, a little child hung playfully across the
               sill of a window, in the fourth story; suddenly it lost its balance, and came like a flash of light to the pavement. Its
               delicate form was crushed into one common mass by the
               blow. The mother rushed down like a frantic creature,”
               &amp;c., &amp;c. Now we will venture to say that no other Italian
               traveller encountered this sight. Nor do we impeach the
               credit of Mr. Headley. According to a homely saying, it is
               the early bird that catches the worm, and it is due to Mr.
               H’s great spirit and courage that he should have and enjoy
               to the full, windfalls like this. He is often much more careful in his style and description than what we have said might
               seem to indicate. There are not a few passages tersely
               rendered, and, where he chooses, no one can be more pointed
               and descriptive in epithet than the author of these Letters.
               He has a good eye for the picturesque, as he often proves.
               His description of a dandy peasant is well made out.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Returning from these mines just at evening we met one of those
               dandy peasants we often see painted, but seldom encounter. A perfect rustic Adonis with flowing locks and rosy cheeks, and beautiful
               bright and laughing eye—he had that jaunty air and rollicking gait
               which characterize your peasant beau. But he was a handsome fellow, and as he passed us with his oxen and cart he trolled away a
               careless ditty. A peasant girl stepped into the road that moment and
               joined him, but it did not look exactly like a casual meeting. As they
               walked on side by side, he had such a good-for-nothing scape-grace
               look that I could not help calling out to him. They both looked back
               and laughed, when he suddenly seized her by the waist and gaVe her
               a kiss that fairly rung again. The blow that followed sent him half
               way across the road and made my cars tingle in sympathy.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Regretting one or two ommissions in his account of American artists abroad, whom he should have seen and spoken of.
               we part with Mr. Headley, in the hope of an early meeting
               again. Find whatever fault we may with him, doubt his
               facts, denounce his grammar, grow angry over his prejudices, we cannot fail to read whatever he writes, and rising
               superior to our necessities as reviewers, read on to the end.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="ab">Hunt's Merchants' Magazine and Commercial Review. Au-
               
               <br></br>gust, 1S45. New- York: Freeman Hunt.
            </div>
            
            <p>Mr. Hunt’s admirable Magazine is now in its seventy-fourth
               number—a pregnant example of what may be effected by
               combined talent and energy. The work is undoubtedly the
               best properly of its kind in America; yet, if we are not mistaken, Mr. Hunt engaged, without a dollar, in the arduous
               task of its establishment. Its progress has never faltered for
               an instant. The steps taken were infallible, and the triumph
               sure. The Merchants’ Magazine was erected, and is now
               owned, edited, and conducted generally, by Mr. Hunt alone.
            </p>
            
            <p>The August number contains many papers of high value
               and interest—among others, “The Government and the Currency," “The Main Line of the State Works of Pennsylvania," “Our Merchant Seamen,” “Maritime Law,” “A Biog
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page76"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               raphy of the late Joseph Peabody, of Salem,” a “New Theory of the Gulf Stream," “Commercial History of Norwich,
               Conn.,” and “The Silver Mines of North Carolina.”
            </p>
            
            <p>The biography of Mr. Peabody is one of the most interesting and instructive papers we have read for years. Few
               more remarkable men have lived in the commercial world.
               Among other things it is stated of him, that he built and
               owned eighty-three ships, which, in every instance, he
               freighted himself; and for the navigation of them, he shipped at different times, upwards of seven thousand seamen.
               Since the year 1811, he has advanced thirty-five to the rank
               of ship-master, who entered his employ as boys. He had
               performed by these vessels the following voyages, viz:—to
               Calcutta, 38; Canton, 17; Sumatra, 32; St. Petersburg, 47;
               other ports in the north of Europe, 10; the Mediterranean,
               20, before the war of 1812.
            </p>
            
            <p>Perhaps the most able article in the number, however, and
               one which we especially recommend to our readers, is “The
               Government and the Country,” by Mr. Middleton, the author
               of the admirable essay (with a similar title) which was published last year by Carey &amp; Hart, and which attracted so general an attention. The North American Review, among other
               journals, spoke of it in the warmest terms of commendation.
               The present article is not more remarkable for the lucidity
               and profundity of its views, than for the vigor, simplicity,
               and general excellence of its style.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="ab">Godey's Lady's Book, for August,</div>
            
            <p>Has been issued for some days. It contains three engravings—one a very good one, (Scene on the Schuylkill)—and
               contributions from Miss Leslie, Mrs. Seba Smith, Mrs. Hale,
               and other ladies and gentlemen of eminence.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <p>French Opera.—Auber’s grand opera of La Muette de
               Portici was produced at the Park Theatre on Monday evening last. This work, when it was first produced, created an
               extraordinary sensation throughout Europe. Its melodies
               became at once, as it were, the property of every people.
               They were upon every lip; they were drummed upon every
               conceivable instrument, from the Grand Piano down to the
               Pandean Pipes or the Hurdy-Gurdy. In short, the whole
               continent of Europe was for a time spell-bound by the force
               of Auber's genius. We can find no parallel to the universality of its success, but in the case of Weber’s “Der Freyschutz.” Of the character of the music it will be scarcely
               necessary to speak, it is so well known on every hand. The
               chorusses are full of melody, and are remarkably characteristic. Nothing can exceed the masterly conception displayed by Auber, in the working of these chorusses; particularly
               in the one commencing Venez amis!
            </p>
            
            <p>In the public highway a conspiracy is being formed; man
               whispers to man, and a plot to overturn a powerful goverment is purposed and decided, while to all appearance the
               fishermen and their wives are merely amusing themselves,
               dancing and singing a light-hearted Barcarole. The bitter
               hatred and determined revenge, mingled with the assumed
               gaiety and the reckless merriment, are expressed by the music with a fidelity perfectly startling. While listening, we
               are one of the people; their wrongs are ours, and we feel
               an intense fearfulness lest they should be overheard, and
               their noble undertaking be disconcerted. Again, in the last
               Act, where Masaniello, delirious from poison administered
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               by Pietro, rushes into the midst of the people, and in the interval of his madness chaunts forth the Barcarole, whose hidden meaning was the watchword of the revolution— how
               masterly a thought! how metaphysically correct!
            </p>
            
            <p>The Ballet music, which, to our regret, was entirely omitted, is eminently beautiful and entirely characteristic — in
               short, with one or two trifling exceptions, the whole work
               is a masterpiece, and will carry Auber’s fame far into futurity.
            </p>
            
            <p>The instrumentation throughout is worthy of Auber, but
               there was one passage at the close of the 2nd Act which, in
               effect, surpasses all others, and which, for its extreme beauty, has rarely, if ever, been equalled by any writer.
            </p>
            
            <p>The following was the caste of the piece:</p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">Masaniello -	-	-	- M. Arnaud
               
               <br></br>Alphonso	- - - - Cœuriot
               
               <br></br>Pietro 	            -	-	-	Garry
               
               <br></br>Borello   Fishermen -	-	- Bernard
               
               <br></br>Moreno 	            -	-	-	Otteruot
               
               <br></br>Elvira - - - - M’me Casini
               
               <br></br>Fenella - -	-	-	Cœuriot
            </div>
            
            
            <p>M’me Casini, as Elvira, displayed her powers to greater
               advantage than upon any previous occasion. She is gaining
               courage fast. In her first recitative and aria, she sang most
               admirably. Her voice, though far from being powerful, is
               well in tune; her execution is rapid and brilliant, and is generally well articulated: but she displays a tendency to a redundance of fioriture, which is reprehensible, and she sometimes goes beyond her power. However, time will correct
               these faults. There is also an important point in which
               M’me Casini is deficient—namely, husbanding the voice for
               important passages in the score: for instance, in the finale
               to the 1st Act two pauses occur in the chorus when at a
               double ⨍⨍, which are filled up by rapid passages upon (as a
               learned critic expresses it) high keys: these passages are
               given to Elvira, and should be given with immense force,
               but M’me Casini barely whispered them. A judicious husbanding of power would have insured the necessary effect.
            </p>
            
            <p>M’me Stephen Cœuriot is in no way fitted for the part of
               Fenella. Her conception of the character, although at times
               just, was badly sustained. She was Fenella only when in
               action; when in repose the character was dropped, and the
               lady became as one of the common group. M’me Cœuriot
               was exhuberant in passion, displaying an almost tiger-like
               ferocity in many places, quite at variance with the state of
               mind of one who, slighted, wronged and broken-hearted, still
               loves with a deep and enduring faithfulness. In the tender
               phases of Fenella’s character, M’me Cœuriot was also unsuccessful. She was at no period of the performance the
               tender, confiding, child-like girl, whose beauty and misfortune were the admiration and the pity of a whole people,
               and roused them to resent their wrongs in hers. It is no
               discredit to M’me Cœuriot that she does not play this character well, for it is out of her line of business Our admiration of her excellent abilities we have often expressed,
               and we regret that we are unable to give her praise on this
               occasion.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Arnaud, as Masaniello, sung with his accustomed
               force and skill; particularly in the duo with Pietro in the
               second act—Mieux vaut mourir que rester misérable! In this
               he displayed the full force of his extraordinary voice, and, assisted by M. Garry, who also sang with great force and judgment, drew down tumultuous applause. In that exquisite
               song, Du pauvre seul ami fidéle, while watching his sleeping sister, he expressed the absorbing—almost fraternal love
               for the injured girl, with admirable fidelity. It was a chaste
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page77"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               and masterly performance. We cannot, however, understand
               why he persists in using his ‘voce de testa’ so incessantly.
               He used it so frequently and so unnecessarily on Monday
               evening, that it marred many beautiful passages in the music,
               besides producing an effect by no means pleasing to his
               hearers.
            </p>
            
            <p>M. Garry is improving most rapidly. He has been but a
               few months upon the stage, and, judging by the rank he has
               already gained for himself, and which he so ably sustains,
               we may safely prognosticate for him a career of distinguished success and enviable popularity. We have noticed, in
               another paragraph, his performance in one portion of the
               opera; we can only add, that he was equally excellent
               throughout. We should however advise him to pay more
               attention to his deportment upon the stage. All the time he
               is singing, his attitude leads us to suppose that he is preparing to leap into the parquette.
            </p>
            
            <p>The choruses, with the exception of the two prayers
               which were indifferently executed, were given with great precision; particularly the finale of the second act, the whole of
               the third act and the opening of the fifth act. The trebles
               were singularly good.
            </p>
            
            <p>The overture was admirably played. It deserved and
               should have met with an encore. Throughout the evening
               we had repeated occasion to remark the admirable performance of the orchestra, collectively and individually,—and we
               are sure that all competent judges will agree with us in the
               opinion, that, with the exception of the New York Philharmonic Society, the French opera band, as it is at present
               consituted, is the best that we have had within the walls of
               a New York theatre.
            </p>
            
            <p>To M. Prevost, much of this excellence is to be attributed. He is a man in every way calculated to bring out the
               best efforts of those confided to his charge. The members of
               the band place unfaltering reliance upon his skill and judgment, knowing him to be an accomplished musician and an
               experienced leader—one who is perfectly familiar with every
               point, remote or prominent, in the partition of each opera.
               M. Prevost is without affectation in the orchestra;—he goes
               to his work earnestly but quietly;—directs by his eye and
               hand, but eschews thumping with the bow or stamping with
               the feet. One of the most admirable points in M. Prevost’s
               method of conducting an orchestra is the exceeding clearness of his beat. There is no hesitation—no change; no useless, bewildering multiplication of divisions. It is a clear,
               straight-forward, manly beat, which every one can understand. We consider that the public owe M. Prevost, and the
               whole orchestra, a substantial tribute to their excellence in
               the way of a crowded benefit.
            </p>
            
            <p>The getting up of the opera was, as usual, excellent; but
               we would ask of what use is that large horse in the fourth
               act? Apart from the absurdity of making it parade round
               the interior of a hut, which is absurd enough without doubt,
               is it not a wanton exposure of life or limb to bring a powerful
               animal into the midst of a throng of females, while the shouting of the people and the din of the Orchestra astound its
               cars, and a strange and dazzling light astonishes its eyes. There
               was but a narrow escape from a severe accident on Monday
               night, and despite the laughter of the audience, we cannot
               hut justify M. Arnaud entirely, in making his escape, in
               any way, from the back of the terrified animal. A man
               upon a horse in the open air, with plenty of space, can generally control it by the force of his will, but upon the stage, he
               is entirely at the mercy of the beast. We trust on the next
               representation, the horse will be omitted from the programme, by particular desire.
            </p>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            
            <p>Dubois’ Horizontal Grand Pianoforte.—It has long
               been a subject of regret to solo players in this country, that
               the only description of instrument they could procure to display their powers on, was a so-called square instrument.—
               The squares, as all pianists well know, are vastly inferior to
               the horizontal grand pianofortes, not only in the quality but
               in the power of the tone. They are also much inferior in
               point of elegance of form. The square instruments made in
               this city, are infinitely superior to any of the same class of instruments that we have seen abroad; they are superior in
               every respect—tone, touch, and beauty of design. But the
               manufacture of Grand Pianos has hitherto proved a comparative, if not a total, failure. Many causes have tended to
               produce this result; among the most prominent, we will
               mention one—the custom of the wealthy amateurs to import, at an enormous expense, their Grand Pianos; another:
               the Squares having become universal in this country, there
               has been hitherto literally no demand for any other class of
               instrument. To construct such an instrument, the first outlay is exceedingly great, and this has doubtless deterred
               many manufacturers from trying an experiment which, necessarily, involves much risk. We cannot but acknowledge
               that the risk is great, but we are confident that the chances
               of success are more than sufficient to warrant any established maker in regarding such risk as nothing. If the experiment
               succeed—that is to say, if the instrument is substantially
               good—if it is a perfect instrument in every particular—we
               prognosticate that in all the polished circles where great
               players do congregate, and in all Concert Rooms, the Grand
               Piano will supersede the humble Square.
            </p>
            
            <p>We will now proceed to examine the piano manufactured by Mr. Dubois. The exterior of the instrument is exceedingly beautiful; the case is made of rosewood of rare
               and choice figure; its form is elegant, at once light and massive—in short, a more exquisite piece of handicraft we never
               beheld. The construction of the interior exhibits many peculiarities. In the first place, the strength, instead of being
               found in the bottom, as in the Square, will be found in the
               top. Experience proved to the English manufacturers that
               all the strength that could be centered in the bottom was
               quite insufficient to resist the tremendous draw upon the
               strings; the instrument would in a measure yield up. To
               obviate this signal defect, occupied the attention of the makers for a length of time. At last the present simple plan
               was hit upon, (by Stodart of London, we believe,) namely,
               the placing above the strings of the instrument longitudinal
               iron tubes, so disposed as to offer a perfect resistance to the
               draw of the strings in every part. The importance of the
               improvement cannot fail to strike our readers at once; it insures the instrument against yielding to any pressure, renders it more light and portable, and adds much to its appearance when open.
            </p>
            
            <p>Each note is produced upon three separate strings, which
               from their great length yield a powerful body of sound. The
               lever which impels the hammer is of course increased in
               proportion, without rendering the touch more heavy; consequently, the performer, on sitting down to this piano,
               finds himself in possession of a wonderfully increased power
               of effect. The tone of the instrument is of the most charming quality; it is at once clear, sweet, and brilliant, and approaches nearer the tone of the best English Grands, than
               any we have heard this side of the Atlantic.
            </p>
            
            <p>On the whole, we consider this experiment a most successful one—it promises a most brilliant future. We shall
               look forward with much anxiety to the next Grand Instrument from the factory of Mr. Dubois. All our musical
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page78"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               friends, and amateurs, should visit Broadway, and examine
               this fine Piano, and he who has the means to indulge in its
               purchase, will be fortunate indeed.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="head">MUSICAL AND THEATRICAL ITEMS.</div>
            
            <p>We have every reason to believe that the ensuing season
               will be a fortunate period for music and the drama. The
               large amount of talent now tending towards this shore from
               England, will make our people glad from one end of the
               country to the other.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the dramatic way, we are promised some very important additions. Mr. and Mrs. Charles Kean (formerly Miss
               Ellen Tree,) will be here early in the season. How welcome
               they will be, we need not attempt to say. Mrs. Kean is the
               undoubted favourite of the whole of this vast continent;—she
               has a host of friends in every city of the Union, and her success is certain. Mr. Kean has also many admirers, and will,
               doubtless, return home with an increased fame and much
               “money in his purse.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. and Mrs. Bland are also announced. Mrs. Bland is
               the sister of Helen Faucitt. She is a lady of fine abilities.
               We remember before she went to London, she was then
               an excellent actress and an extraordinary favourite in Liver
               pool. We have heard that her success in London was very
               decisive, and we may reasonably expect that during the period of five years, she must have improved greatly. Her appearance is much in her favour. Her figure is well-proportioned and singularly commanding, and her face is expressive and
               intellectual. Mr. Bland, when we saw him in the Provinces,
               was filling a very difficult line of business, that is, the generally useful line. He displayed good talent, and we shall
               doubtless find him much improved after a lapse of years. He
               is well known in theatrical circles for his literary abilities;
               having written several successful dramas.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the musical way, we are to receive a vast accession of
               strength, both in the vocal and instrumental department.
            </p>
            
            <p>Leopold de Meyer, whose name is known all over Europe,
               is, we believe, already on his passage hither. As a pianist,
               it is said that he has not a superior: even Listz and Thalberg have to acknowledge him their equal. So says the
               world. We will not answer for its correctness in every particular. Leopold de Meyer is the only one, out of the many
               extraordinary pianists now in Europe, that we have not
               heard; we cannot, therefore, speak from personal knowledge,
               but we find that good critics agree in according him a high
               reputation.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Templeton is on his way here. He has held a prominent rank in the London theatres for many years, and he
               comes to us now in the pride of his health and strength, with
               his voice in no way impaired by age. He has been giving
               entertainments and lectures lately; finding them, we presume,
               more profitable than theatrical engagements. We doubt the
               success of his speculation. Henry Phillips tried the same
               thing, but with all his acknowledged talent, he failed—totally failed. With an operatic company, Mr. Templeton
               would have been highly popular, but as a musical lecturer,
               &amp;c., we fear for him.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Horncastle, brother to the Horncastle lately of the
               Olympic, is coming with the same class of entertainment.
               We remember him for many years—he is indeed one of our
               earliest recollections, and as a chaste and refined singer, he
               has maintained his reputation up to this day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Rophino Lacy has effected an arrangement with Mr.
               Simpson, for his daughter, Miss Delcy. She is a young lady
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               of much personal appearance and excellent capabilities, and
               will, we think, become a great favourite throughout the
               country.
            </p>
            
            <p>A Mr. Arthurson, whose name is new to us, is engaged
               as tenor to the company, of which Miss Delcy is prima donna;
               we hear that much is expected from him in London. His
               voice is said to be truly beautiful—of extraordinary compass,
               and equal throughout.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Brough is said to be the bass of this party.
               Mr. D. W. King is also coming to the Park theatre. He
               is a most charming singer. His voice is a light tenor of excellent quality, and his school of singing is pure and refined.
               He is a thorough musician, for he was educated as a King’s
               Chapel Boy. Mr. D. W. King will prove a very welcome
               addition to our musical strength.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <p>Mess. Wm. D. Ticknor &amp; Co., of Boston, have in press
               and will soon publish a volume of Poems by Mrs. Mary E.
               Hewitt, of this city. Mrs. Hewitt has written numerous
               short pieces, characterized by feeling and grace. We presume the forthcoming volume will comprise someone or two
               compositions of greater length than any she has yet published.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mess. Clark and Austen have in preparation a collection
               of the poetical writings of Mrs. Osgood. Although the welldeserved celebrity of Mrs. O. is fully equal to that of any
               American poetess, there has hitherto been no compilation of
               her works—with the exception of the English “Wreath of
               Wild Flowers from New England.” She has been sadly
               neglectful, we fear, both of her interest and her fame. We
               shall give her new volume the most cordial of welcomes.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <p>Great preparations are being made in the way of giftbooks for the holidays. “The Missionary Memorial" is the
               title of a very elegant volume to be edited by Mr. Saunders,
               of this city. It is to be superbly printed on the finest paper,
               and bound in gilt silk. The illustrative title and frontispiece
               will be executed in the new process of oil colors by Baxter,
               of London, expressly for the work. Among the contributors
               will be Mrs. Sigourney, Miss Gould, Mrs. Osgood, Halleck,
               Whittier, Tuckerman, Lowell, Sprague, Drs. Alexander,
               Schroeder, Williams, Gardiner, Spring, S. H. Cone; Professors Mason and Fisher; Rev. Mess. Spalding, Dowling, Griswold, Charles; Colton, Hoffman, Poe, and some others.
               The title “Missionary Memorial” is used, we presume, to
               avoid the hackneyed term (or idea) Annual.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. John Keese is preparing “The Opal,” which has now
               been in course of publication, we believe, for five years. It
               will be unusually rich, however, this year, its contributions
               are to be especially good, and the external book will be
               greatly improved.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. T. S. Arthur, of Philadelphia, the well known editor
               of “Arthur’s Magazine,” is also preparing an annual, which
               we have good reason to believe, will vie with any of the
               season. It will be issued by Ferret &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Robert Hamilton, is getting ready “The May-Flower,” of which we have seen some specimen sheets which
               promise remarkably well. This souvenir will at least equal
               any of the others. Saxton and Kelt, of Boston, are the publishers.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Ihe Gift,” so long and successfully issued by Mess.
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page79"></div>
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               Carey and Hart, is suspended—will not be published this
               season, if ever again.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <p>The Corporation of Harvard University have invited, or
               voted to invite, the Hon. Edward Everett to assume the Presidency of the College. It is presumed he will accept the invitation.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <p>In the “Times,” published at Columbus, Ga., we meet
               with a very remarkable story entitled “The Little Governess
               and the Authoress." The narrative itself has great interest;
               but we call it “remarkable,” because we learn that it is the
               work of a girl of fourteen—Miss Annabella S. Phelps—a
               niece of Joseph Wallis, Esq., of this city. She is, or was,
               a pupil at the Moravian (Litiz) Seminary, (in Lancaster,
               Pa.,) of which the Rev. Eugene A. Freauff is principal. We
               have seen several of Miss Phelps’ MSS—all evincing a high
               order of talent.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <p>We find the following in the Express (of this city,) where
               it is accredited to the New-York Correspondent of the Cincinnati Gazette:
            </p>
            
            <p>“There has been a flare-up in the Broadway Journal, which prevented the appearance of one number a week or two since. It originated in some difference between one of the Editors and the Publisher.
               The Editor undertook to get a new Publisher on the paper, and so the
               Publisher turned round and put the name of the other Editor on his
               sheet. Where the merits or demerits of the case lie, we do not pretend to determine. The Journal has force—some good criticism, and
               a good deal of bad. It needs more catholicity—more liberality, aud
               a little less attempt at severity. With its flashy name exchanged for
               something more dignified, and its main plan retained, it would soon be
               the most able and entertaining weekly in the country.
            </p>
            
            <p>“I forgot to mention that there has been a flare-up in the Democratic Review, also, between the Editor and Mr. Langley, one of the
               proprietors. Both better leave, for the paper cannot live with the
               management it has had for the past year or two. It lives by plunder
               of other people’s brains—a rather uncertain mode of existence, we
               should imagine.”
            </p>
            
            <p>We thank the New-York Correspondent of the Cincinnati
               Courier for his good opinion, although given cum grano salis—but we would thank him at the same time to stick to
               the truth. He is right only in the proportion of one word in
               ten. What does he mean by “catholicity”? What does
               he mean by calling “The Broadway Journal” “a flashy
               name”? What does he mean by “putting the name of the
               other editor on the paper”? The name of the “other editor” was never off the paper. What does he mean by his
               pet phrase “a flare-up”? There has been no flare-up either
               in the case of “The Broadway Journal” or of “The Democratic Review.”
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THIS DAY IS PUBLISHED,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">VERSE AND PROSE, by Thomas Hood—Part 1,
               
               <br></br>forming No. 16 of the Library of Choice Reading, beautifully
               
               <br></br>printed. Price 50 cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>“Of all the humorists, Hood was the most poetical. When dealing with the most familiar subjects, whether it might be a sweep bewailing the suppression of his cry, or a mother searching through St.
               Giles’s for her lost infant, or a Miss Kilmansegg’s golden childhood—
               there was hardly a verse in which some touches of heart, or some play
               of fancy, did not beckon the laughing reader away into far other
               Worlds than the jester’s.”—London Athenœum.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The smile and the sigh were ever blended together; the laugh at
               the grotesque idea and whimsical imagination, (rarely seeing objects
               as others saw them,) and the tear which must flow on such pathetic
               narratives as Eugene Aram or the Old Elm Tree. Without a parallel
               and original us Hood was in the ludicrous, his more enduring fame
               will rest on the exquisitely humane and simply compassionate.”—Literary Gazette.
            </p>
            
            <p>“He was the inventer of a new sort of guano to fertilize men's
               minds, and to make them produce larger crops of good actions: or rather it was an intellectual compost that he invented, and the materials
               of which were satire softened by kindness, and ridicule tempered with
               good feeling.”—Hood's Magazine for June. Published and for sale
               by	                         WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">HARPER &amp; BROTHERS' LAST PUBLICATIONS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">I.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">HARPER’S ILLUMINATED BIBLE. No. 34.
               
               <br></br>Price Twenty-Five Cents,
            </div>
            
            <p>Comprising portions of the minor prophets to the 9th chapter of Amos.
               The embellishments to this number include some of unsurpassed beauty.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">II.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">HARPER’S ILLUMINATED SHAKSPEARE,
               
               <br></br>Nos. 61 and 62. Price Twenty-Five Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes "Measure for Measure” and the commencement of the "Tempest”—with the eqquisite designs after Kenny Meadows, Weir, and others. It should be recollected that this edition of
               Shakspeare combines the best features of the two best London editions, by Charles Knight and Tyas—rendering it the most perfect ever
               presented to the public.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">III.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO,</div>
            
            <p>Newly collected from valuable MSS. in the Geographical Societies of
               France and Italy, with copious notes and illustrations by Hugh Murray, with Maps, &amp;c. 16mo. muslin. Price 50 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>This well-known production, which forms No. 173 of “The Family
               Library,” has long been regarded as unique in geographical science.
               Marco Polo has justly been styled the "Herodotus of the Middle
               Ages.” and the discoverer of the Asiatic continent; his explorations
               in the Chinese empire alone have never been exceeded, even to the
               present day.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">IV.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE SEERESS OF PREVORST. Price 25 Cents.</div>
            
            <p>“A work replete with startling new facts on Mesmerism: the most
               remarkable on the subject we have yet seen.”—Post.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">V.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">JOHN RONGE AND THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES.
               
               <br></br>Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>“A subject of the most absorbing interest throughout the whole
               whole European Continent.”
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">VI.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">DR. LEVER’S LATEST WORK—THE NEVILLES OF
               
               <br></br>GARRETSTOWN. Complete, price 12 1-2 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>“Equal to the best works of the favourite author of Charles O'Mal-
               ley.”
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">VII.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">JAMES’S NEW WORK—THE SMUGGLER. 25 Cents.</div>
            
            <p>This new production of Mr. James is founded on on some stirring
               incidents of past times on the Southern Coast of England; it is characterised by all the author's peculiaritics of style, the story being intersected by many episodical involutions, which impart to it additional
               interest.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">VIII.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">DE ROHAN. BY EUGENE SUE. Price 25 Cents.</div>
            
            <p>“Picturesque, bold, and highly dramatic—equal to any of his pre-
               vious works.”—Sun.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">IX.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PRAISE AND PRINCIPLE—Or, For What shall I Live?</div>
            
            <p>By the author of “Conquest and Self-Conquest,” “Woman an Enigma,” &amp;c. 18 mo. cloth gilt. Price 48 1-2 Cents. A charming volume,
               elegantly written, well sustained in its interest, and rife with excellent
               moral teaching.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">X.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">CYCLOPEDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY. No. 8. Pr. 26 Cts.</div>
            
            
            <div class="ab">XI.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">MISS BREMER's NEW WORK—THE PARSONAGE OF MO-
               
               <br></br>RA, OR LIFE IN DALECARLIA. Price One Shilling.
            </div>
            
            <p>In this new work Frederika Bremer presents many of her pretty and
               picturesque scenes, add introduces many of her high minded and romantic characters, with their spirit stirring colloquies; the story also
               includes interesting sketches of those Northern subterranean worlds—
               the copper mines of Fahlua.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">XII.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">EVELINA, by Miss Burney (since Marlame D’Arblay). New
               
               <br></br>edition, 18mo. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This renowned production has long been considered as a classic of
               our language. The work appeared anonymously, the disclosure of
               the authorship of which, it will be remembered, led to the deeply interesting scene which ensued between the father and daughter—their
               mingled surprise and delight.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">XIII.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">DR. COPLAND’S MEDICAL DICTIONARY. No. 10. 60 Cts.</div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes a scries of topics of vital interest to the
               Medical faculty ot the country. The design and execution of this popular production, evince the most consummate skill and research; every person who desires a thorough digest of Medical Science, must ap
               preciate its high value.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">XV.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PROF. LEWIS’S PLATO ON ATHEISTS. Price $1 50.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page80"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANO-
               
               <br></br>FORTE, ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street,
               
               <br></br>where his terms for giving instruction can be ascertained.	my 17
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER.</div>
            <div class="ab">—JAMES
               
               <br></br>PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near Elm. A
               
               <br></br>Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms mode-
               
               <br></br>rate. FOR SALE—A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a
               
               <br></br>great bargain for cash.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
               Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made
               from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful
               workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the busines.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab"> N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ.
               
               <br></br>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to
               the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, corner of Cottage Place and Bleecker street, which he will sell
               at prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twenty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two
               of the largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that
               his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the
               best makers in this country or Europe, and that they contain all the
               real improvements of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
               Repaired.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, April 23d, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES. </div>
            <p>The Subscribers, while returning thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at
               the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and
               seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood and mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
               the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
               to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
               upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab"> STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>Manufactory, 13th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>—THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
               (formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway,
               will keep a complete assortment of the latest approved Grand Action
               Piano Fortes, of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
               guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish,
               and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard
               prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on
               hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BŒHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <p>PHILIP ERSNT, Teacher of the Flute and Guitar, would inform the lovers of Music that he has now for sale
               several of the above celebrated instruments, constructed in every respect in accordance with those now in use at the Paris and London
               Royal Academies. To he seen at PHILIP ERNST’S Music Saloon,
               395 Broadway, near Walker.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JUST PUBLISHED.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">By Paine &amp; Burgess, 62 John St.,
               
               <br></br>No. 1 of the Medici series of Italian Prose.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE CHALLENGE OF BARLETTA, AN HIStorical Romance of the Times of the Medici, by Azeglio. Translated by C. Edwards Lester, U. S. Consul at Genoa. Author of “The
               Glory and Shame of England,” &amp;c. &amp;c. This work is founded on the
               most thrilling and romantic incidents in the chivalric history of Italy.
               Chevalier Buyaul. the mirror of chivalry, Cæsar Borgia, the Colloni,
               Gonsalvo of Cordova, &amp;c., are the principal characters. Price 50
               cents.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IN PRESS.
               
               <br></br>2 and 3, The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli. 2 vols.
               
               <br></br>4.	The Citizen of a Republic.
               
               <br></br>5.	The Autobiography of Altieri.
               
               <br></br>IN PREPARATION.
               
               <br></br>The Artist, The Merchant and The Statesman. 2 vols. By C.
               
               <br></br>Edwards Lester.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE
               SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published monthly, at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since
               1835, has a large subscription list, and is the principal organ of
               Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the "Broadway Journal,” 133 Nassau streeet.</p>
         </div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. B. CAREY &amp; CO.,
               ARTISTS,
            </div>
            
            <p>MANUFACTURERS OF ORNAMENTAL SHOW
               CARDS adapted for Utility, as well Adornment, for stores in all
               kinds of business. Specimens may be seen in the leading stores of the
               principal cities of the Union.
            </p>
            
            <p>Agents for Boston: Messrs. Sowle &amp; Shaw. Mr. J. L. Lazarus is
               now visiting the Eastern States, all orders received by him will meet
               with prompt attention. 34 Beekman-Strect, (late 323 Broadway.)
            </p>
            
            <p>☞ Observe! Our names are printed at the foot of each card, and
               we caution the public that imitators are in the field.	Jy 26
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
               THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE YEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course
               of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M.. 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M., daily, for gentlemen,
               and from 11 to 1 o’clock, for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale "Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A. G. BAGLEY’S
               CELEBRATED IMPROVED EVER-POINTED
               GOLD PEN.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS PEN RECEIVED THE HIGHEST PREmium at the last Fair of the American Institute, and has been pronounced by the First Teachers of Penmanship in the country, to be
               infinitely superior to any Gold Pen ever before introduced to the American public. The lasting properties of this Pen are undoubted, owing
               to the total absence of corrosibility from any of the inks in use; and the
               peculiar shape of the nibs—which was first introduced by Bagley—
               makes it more pleasant to use, renders it less liable to damage, more
               easy to repair, and prevents the necessity of the great care that other
               articles of the kind require.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">MANUFACTORY, 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
               
               <br></br>                                           Jy 26
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work
               yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
               The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies are given in such progressive order, that they
               enlist the interest of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly
               through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often
               made irksome in other instruction books. The time has arrived when
               a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is
               only by the study of such methods us Bertini’s that pupils will be enabled to read music with facility, aud at the same time become good
               musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the
               rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and
               each lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations
               from professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of
               Bertini’s Method over all others yet published in this country, most
               of them having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be
               necessary to give a few of the names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab"> Boston.	                        New-York.
               
               <br></br>Messr. G. J. Webb,	                Messrs. H. C. Timm,
               
               <br></br>J. G. Maeder,	                    W. Alpers,
               
               <br></br>H. T. Hach,	                    U. C. Hill,
               
               <br></br>E. L. White,	                    F. H. Brown,
               
               <br></br>David Paine,	                    Philadelphia.
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek,	                        B. C. Cross
               
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.	                   Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>             Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the
               work. American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H.
               OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p18">
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co. ..................Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance,...............Philadelphia,	Pa.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. HUNTINGTON.............Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>George Jones, ........ . Albany, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Thomas H. Pease.................New-Haven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>L.	Willard.....................Troy, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>M.	Baullemet,..................Mobile, Al.
            
            <br></br>J. C. Morgan, . . , .............. New Orleans.
            
            <br></br>Robinson &amp; Jones,. ....... Cincinnati, O.
            
            <br></br>D. M. Dewey.....................Rochester. N. Y.
            
            <br></br>J. Robertson,...................Syracuse, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>W. E. Husiell,..................Schenectady, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Haliburton &amp; Dudley,............Boston, Mass.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>