<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450816</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">
         THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 2.     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, AUGUST 16, 1845.     NO. 6. 
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum. 
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.  
         
         <br></br>EDITED BY 
         
         <br></br>EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON. 
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau St., 
         
         <br></br>by JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Lenore</div>
         <div class="biblPage">81</div>
         <div class="head">Lenore.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>Ah, broken is the golden bowl! the spirit flown forever!
            
            <br></br>Let the bell toll!--a saintly soul floats on the Stygian river,
            
            <br></br>And, Guy De Vere, hast thou no tear?--weep now or never more!
            
            <br></br>See! on yon drear and rigid bier low lies thy love, Lenore!
            
            <br></br>Come! let the burial rite be read--the funeral song be sung!--
            
            <br></br>An anthem for the queenliest dead that ever died so young--
            
            <br></br>dirge for her the doubly dead in that she died so young.
            
            <br></br>"Wretches! ye loved her for her wealth and hated her for her pride,
            
            <br></br>"And when she fell in feeble health, ye blessed her--that she died!
            
            <br></br>"How shall the ritual, then, be read?--the requiem how be sung
            
            <br></br>"By you--by yours, the evil eye,--by yours, the slanderous tongue
            
            <br></br>"That did to death the innocence that died, and died so young?"
            
            <br></br>Peccavimus; but rave not thus! and let a Sabbath song
            
            <br></br>Go up to God so solemnly the dead may feel no wrong!
            
            <br></br>The sweet Lenore hath "gone before," with Hope, that flew beside,
            
            <br></br>Leaving thee wild for the dear child that should have been thy bride--
            
            <br></br>For her, the fair and debonair, that now so lowly lies,
            
            <br></br>The life upon her yellow hair but not within her eyes--
            
            <br></br>The life still there, upon her hair--the death upon her eyes.
            
            <br></br>"Avaunt! to-night my heart is light. No dirge will I upraise,
            
            <br></br>"But waft the angel on her flight with a Poean of old days!
            
            <br></br>"Let no bell toll!--lest her sweet soul, amid its hallowed mirth,
            
            <br></br>"Should catch the note, as it doth float--up from the damned Earth.
            
            <br></br>"To friends above, from fiends below, the indignant ghost is riven--
            
            <br></br>" from Hell unto a high estate far up within the Heaven--
            
            <br></br>" from moan and groan, to a golden throne, beside the King of Heaven.
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">John Randolph, of Roanoke</div>
         <div class="biblPage">81</div>
         
         <div class="head">John Randolph, of Roanoke. Great wits to madness nearly are allied.</div>
         
         <p>I REMEMBER some years since to have seen John Randolph in Baltimore. I had
            frequently read and heard descriptions of him, and one day, as I was standing in Market, now Baltimore-street, I remarked a tall, thin, unique-looking
            being hurrying towards me with a quick impatient step, evidently much annoyed by
            a crowd of boys who were following close at his heels, not in the obstreperous mirth
            with which they would have followed a crazy or a drunken man, or an organ
            grinder and his monkey, but in the silent, curious wonder, with which they would
            have haunted a Chinese bedecked in full costume. I instantly knew the individual to be Randolph from the descriptions. I therefore advanced towards 
            him, that I might make a full observation of his person without
            violating the rules of courtesy in stopping to gaze at him. As he approached, he
            occasionally turned towards the boys with an angry glance, but without saying
            anything, and then hurried on as if to outstrip them, but it would not do. They
            followed close behind the orator, each one observing him so intently that he said
            nothing to his companions. Just before I met him, he stopped a Mr. C---------, a
            cashier of one of the banks, said to be as odd a fish as John himself. I
            loitered into a store close by--and really he was the strangest
            looking being I ever beheld.
         </p>
         
         <p>His long, thin legs, about as thick as a stout walkingcane, and of much
            such a shape, were encased in a pair of tight small clothes, so tight that they seemed part and parcel of the wearer. Handsome white stockings were fastened with great tidiness at the knees by a small gold buckle,
            and over them, coming about half way up the calf, were a pair of what, I
            believe, are called hose, coarse and country knit. He wore shoes. They were old-fashioned, and fastened also with buckles--huge ones. He trod like an
            Indian, without turning his toes out, but planking them down straight ahead. It
            was the fashion in those days to wear a fan-tailed coat, with a small collar, and
            buttons far apart behind, and few on the breast. Mr. Randolph's was the reverse of
            all this. Instead of its being fan-tailed, it was what, I believe, the knights
            of the needle call swallow-tailed: the collar was immensely large, the buttons behind were in kissing proximity, and they sat together as close on the breast of the garment as the feasters at a crowded public festival. His waist
            was remarkably slender; so slender that, as he stood with his arms akimbo, he
            could easily, as I thought, with his long bony fingers, have spanned it. Around him
            his coat, which was very tight, was held together by one button and, in consequence, an inch or more of tape, to which the buttons was attached,
            was perceptible where it was pulled through the cloth. About his neck he wore a large
            white cravat, in which his chin was occasionally buried as he moved his head in
            conversation; no shirt collar was perceptible: every other person seemed to pride
            himself upon the size of his, as they were then worn large. Mr. Randolph's complexion
            was precisely that of a mummy--withered, saffron, dry, and bloodless; you could
            not have placed a pin's point on his face where you would not have touched a wrinkle.
            His lips were thin, compressed, and colorless; the chin, beardless as a boy's,
            was broad for the size of his face, which was small; his nose was straight, with
            nothing remarkable in it, except perhaps it was too short. He wore a fur cap, which
            he took off, standing a few moments uncovered.
         </p>
         
         <p>I observed that his head was quite small, a characteristic which is said to have
            marked many men of talent: 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="wscott">Walter Scott</span>, and Chief Justice Marshall, for
            instance. Judge Burnet of Cincinnati, who has been alike distinguished at the
            bar, on the bench, and in the United States Senate, has also a very small head.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Mr. Randolph's hair was remarkably fine--fine as an infant's, and thin.
            It was very long, and was parted with great care on the top of his head, and was tied
            with a bit of black ribbon about three inches from his neck; the whole of it
            formed a queue not thicker than the little finger of a delicate girl. His
            forehead was low, with no bumpology about it; but his eye, though sunken, was most
            brilliant and startling in its glance. It was not an eye of profound, but of passionate thought, with an expression at times such as physicians
            asscribe to that of insanity, but an insanity which seemed to quicken, not
            destroy, intellectual acuteness. I never beheld an eye that struck me more. It possessed a species of fascination, such as would make you wonder over
            the character of its possessor, without finding any clew in your wonderment to discover it, except that he was passionate, wayward, and
            fearless. He lilted his long bony finger impressively as he conversed, and
            gesticulated with it in a peculiar manner. His whole appearance struck me, and I
            could easily imagine how, with his great command of language, so appropriate and full, so brilliant and classical, joined to the vast information that
            his discursive oratory enabled him to exhibit in its fullest extent, from the
            storehouse of which, the vividness of his imagination was always pointing out a happy
            analogy or bitter sarcasm, that startled the more from the fact, that his
            hearers did not perceive it until the look, tone, and finger brought it down
            with the suddenness of lightning--and with its effects, upon the head of his
            adversary; taking all this into consideration, I could easily imagine, how when
            almost a boy, he won so much fame, and preserved it so long, and with so vast an influence, notwithstanding the eccentricity and inconsistency of his
            life, public and private.
         </p>
         
         <p>By-the-bye, the sudden, unexpected, and aphoristical way in which Randolph often
            expressed his sentiments, had much to do with his oratorical success. He would, like
            
            <span class="person" id="jswift">Dean Swift</span>, make a remark, seemingly a compliment, and explain it into a
            sarcasm, or he would utter an apparent sarcasm, and turn it into a compliment. Many
            speakers, when they have said a thing, hurry on to a full explanation, fearful that
            the hearer may not understand them; but when Randolph expressed one
            of these startling thoughts, he left the hearer for some time puzzling in doubt as to
            what he meant, and, when it pleased him, in the coolest manner in the world he
            explained his meaning, not a little delighted if he discovered that his audience
            were wondering the while upon whom the blow would descend, or what principle the
            remark would be brought to illustrate. A little anecdote, which I heard a Member
            of Congress from Kentucky tell of him, shows this characteristic. The Congressman, on his first visit to Washington, (he had just been elected,) was of course
            desirous of seeing the lions. Randolph, though not a member of either house, was there, and had himself daily borne into the Senate or House, by his
            faithful Juba, to listen to the debates. Every body, noted or unnoted, were calling
            on the eccentric orator, and the Member from Kentucky determined to do likewise, and gratify his curiosity. A friend, General---, promised to present him, saying though: "You must be prepared for an odd
            reception, for if Randolph is in a bad humor, he will do and say any thing; if he is
            in a good humor, you will see a most finished gentleman." They called. Mr.
            Randolph was stretched out on a sofa. "He seemed," said the member, "a skeleton
            endowed with those flashing eyes which ghost stories give to the reanimated body when
            sent upon some earthly mission."
         </p>
         
         <p>The Congressman was presented by his friend, the General, as a Member
            of Congress from Kentucky. "Ah! from Kentucky, sir!" exclaimed Randolph, in his
            shrill voice, as he rose to receive him; " from Kenlucky, sir; well, sir, I
            consider your State the Botany Bay of Virginia!" The Kentuckian
            thought that the next remark would be a quotation from Barrington's Botany Bay
            Epilogue, applied by Randolph to the Virginia settlers of Kentucky:
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>True patriots we, for be it understood,
            
            <br></br>We left our country for our country's good.
            
         </div>
         
         <p>but Randolph, after a pause, continued: "I do not make this remark, sir, in application to the morals or the mode of settlement in Kentucky. No,
            sir, I mean to say that it is my opinion, sir, that the time approaches when Botany
            Bay will, in all respects surpass England, and I fear it will soon be so with
            your State and mine."
         </p>
         
         <p>I cite this little anecdote, not from any peculiar pith that it possesses, but in
            illustration of his character, and in proof of the remark above made.
         </p>
         
         <p>If Mr. Randolph had lived in ancient times, 
            <span class="person" id="plutarch">Plutarch</span>, with all his powers in tracing
            the analogies of character, would have looked in vain for his parallel. And a modern biographer, with all ancient and modern times before him, will find
            the effort fruitless that seeks his fellow. At first, the reader might think of
            Diogenes as furnishing some resemblance to him, and that all that Randolph wanted was
            a tub; but not so. If another Alexander had asked him what he would have that
            imperial power could bestow--the answer never would have been to request to stand
            out of his sunlight. No: Randolph, if he could not have got any higher emolument and
            honor, would immediately have requested to be sent upon a foreign mission; that
            over, if Alexander had nothing more to give, and was so situated as not to be feared,
            who does not believe that the ex-minister would turn tail on him?
         </p>
         
         <p>The fact is, that Randolph was excessively ambitious, a cormorant alike for praise and plunder; and though his patriotism could point out the disinterested
            course to others, his love of money would not let him keep the track himself --at
            least in his latter years, when Mammon, the old man's God, beset him, and he turned
            an idolator to that for which he had so often expressed his detestation that his countrymen believed him. His mission to Russia broke the charm,
            that the prevailing opinion of his disinterestedness cast about him; and his
            influence in his native State was falling fast beneath the appointment and outfit and
            salary that had disenchanted it, when he died; and now old Virginia will forget
            and forgive the inconsistencies of one of her greatest sons to do reverence to his
            memory.
         </p>
         
         <p>Randolph's republicanism was never heartfelt: he was at heart an aristocrat. He
            should have been born in England, a noble--there he would stubbornly have resisted the encroachments of all below him upon his own prerogatives, station&gt;
            dignity, and quality, of all above him a little below his level, or at least
            upon an equality with his. Randolph would have lifted Wilkes up to be a thorn in the
            side of a king whom he disliked, and to overthrow his minister; had he been himself
            a minister, his loyalty would then have pronounced Wilkes an unprincipled
            demagogue. Wilkes, we know, when he got in office, said he could prove to his majesty that he himself had not been a Wilkite.
         </p>
         
         <p>Randolph was intensely selfish, and his early success as a politician and orator impressed him with an exaggerated opinion of his own importance at an early age, when such opinions are easily made and not easily eradicated.
            In the case of Randolph, this overweaning self-estimation grew monstrous. "Big man me, John," and the bigness or littleness of others' services were
            valued and proclaimed, just as they elevated or depressed the interests and personal
            dignity of (he orator of Roanoke. And often, when his interest had 
            nothing to do with the question presented to him, his caprice would sway
            his judgment--for his personal resentments led him far away from every consideration,
            save that of how he could best wound his adversary.
         </p>
         
         <p>His blow wanted neither vigor nor venom; his weapons were poisoned with such
            consummate skill, and he so well knew the vulnerable point of every character, that
            often when the wound by an observer who knew nothing of his opponent seemed slight, it was rankling in the heart. Randolph; was well acquainted
            with the private history of the eminent men of his time, the peccadilloes, frailties,
            indiscretions, weaknesses, vanities, and vices of them all. He used his tongue
            as a jockey would his whip; hit the sore place till the blood came, and there was no
            crack, or flourish, or noise, in doing it. It was done with a celerity and dexterity
            which showed the practised hand, and its unexpectedness as well as its severity,
            often dumb-founded the victim so completely, that he had not one word to say, but
            withdrew in silence.
         </p>
         
         <p>I remember hearing two anecdotes of Randolph, which strikingly type his character. One exhibits his cynical rudeness and disregard for the feelings of
            others--in fact, a wish to wound their feelings--and the other his wit. I do not
            vouch for their accuracy, but I give them as I have frequently
            heard them, as perhaps has the reader.
         </p>
         
         <p>Once, when Randolph was in the city of B----, he was in the daily habit of frequenting the bookstore of one of the largest booksellers in the
            place. He had made some purchases from him, and was very curious in looking over his
            books, &amp;c. In the course of Randolph's visits he became very familiar with Mr.------, the bookseller, and they held long chats together; the orator
            of Roanoke showing off with great cour- tesy. Mr.-----, was quite a pompous man, rather
            vain of his acquaintance with the lions who used to stop in his shop.
            Subsequently, being in Washington with a friend, he espied Randolph advancing
            towards him, and told his friend that he would introduce him to the great man. His
            friend, however, knowing the waywardness of Randolph, declined.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Well," said -Mr.----, "I'm sorry you will not be introduced. I'll go
            up and give him a shake of the hand at any rate." Up he walked, with outstretched
            hand to salute the cynic. The aristocratic republican (by the bye, how often your thoroughgoing republican is a full blooded aristocrat in his private relations) immediately threw his hands behind him, as if he
            could not dull his palm in that way, and gazed searchingly into the face of the astonished bookseller. "Oh, oh!" said he, as if recollecting himself,
            "You are Mr. B-----from Baltimore?" "Yes sir," was the reply. "A bookseller?"
            "Yes sir," again. "Ah! I bought books from you?" "Yes, sir, you did." "Did I forget
            to pay you for them?" "No, sir, you did not." "Good morning, sir!" said the
            orator, lifting his cap with offended dignity, and passing on. This anecdote does not
            show either Randolph's goodness of head or heart, but it shows his character.
         </p>
         
         <p>The other anecdote is as follows: The Honorable Peter ----, who was a watch-maker, and who represented B-------County for many years in Congress, once made a motion
            to amend a resolution ottered by Randolph, on the subject of military claims.
            Mr. Randolph rose up after the amendment had been offered, and drawing out his watch
            from his fob, asked the Honorable Peter what o'clock it was. He told him. "Sir,"
            replied the orator, "you can mend my watch, but not my motions. You understand tictics, sir, but not tactics."
         </p>
         
         <p>That too, was a fine retort, when, after he had been speaking, several members rose
            in succession and attacked him. "Sir," said he to the Speaker, "I'm in the condition
            of old Lear--
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>The little dogs and all,
            
            <br></br>Tray, Blanch, and Sweetheart,
            
            <br></br>See--they bark at me.
            
         </div>
         
         <p>"Mr. Randolph," exclaimed an acquaintance to him, hurrying to his side in the
            street, "I have tried my hardest to overtake you." "You will have to try harder than
            your hardest to keep up with me--sir, to keep up with me!" exclaimed
            the orator, running off at the top of his speed.
         </p>
         
         <p>He said of a person who refused to accept his challenge upon the ground of religious
            scruples against duelling, that "he had sculked behind the communion table." He
            called the Greeks, "Christless Christians." Of the new Constitution
            of Virginia, he said; "It was brought into life with the Sardonic grin of death upon
            its countenance."
         </p>
         
         <p>A political opponent boasted on the stump, that if his mind was not naturally as
            strong as the Orator's of Roanoke, he had done his best by an arduous collegiate
            course to improve it, &amp;c."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Not the first weak soil, gentlemen," exclaimed Randolph interrupting him, "that
            excessive cultivation has reduced to barrenness;--let him stay at home--let him lie fallowfallow."
         </p>
         
         <p>A volume of such pithy sayings of his might easily be collected.</p>
         
         <p>All accounts agree in praising the oratorical powers of Randolph. His manner was
            generally slow and impressive; his voice squeaking, but clear and distinct, and as
            far as it could be heard, what he said was clearly understood. His gesture was
            chiefly with his long and skeleton like finger. The impressiveness with which he used it has been remarked by all who have heard him. When he was sarcastic,
            amidst a thousand it would say, stronger than any language, to the individual
            whom he meant, "thou art the man." In his choice of language he was very fastidious, making sometimes a considerable pause to select a word. His reading was
            extensive, and in every department of knowledge--romances, tales, poems, plays,
            voyages, travels, history, biography, philosophy--all arrested his attention, and each
            had detained him long enough to render him familiar with the best works of the kind. Mis mind was naturally erratic, and his desultory reading, as he
            never devoted himself to a profession, and dipped a little into all, increased his
            natural and mental waywardness. He seldom reasoned, and when he did, it was with
            an effort that was painful, and which cost him more trouble than it was worth. He
            said himself in one of his speeches in the Senate of the United States, that "he had
            a defect, whether of education or nature was immaterial, perhaps
            proceeding from both--a defect which had disabled him, from his first entrance into
            public life to the present hour, from making a regular speech." The defect was,
            doubtless, both from education and nature; education might have, in some
            measure, corrected the tendencies of his nature, but there was, perhaps, an
            indiosyncrasy in the constitution of the man, which compelled him to be erratic in
            mind as well as in temper.
         </p>
         
         <p>He said that "ridicule was the keenest weapon in the whole parliamentary army," and
            he learned all the tricks of fence with it, and never played with foils. He seemed to
            have had more admiration for the oratory of Chatham than that of any other individual--if we may judge from the manner in which that great man is
            mentioned in his speeches. They were certainly unlike in character, -- very unlike.
            Chatham having had bad health, and it being well known that he went to
            Parliament and made his best efforts when almost sinking from sickness Randolph might
            have felt that, as he had done the same thing, their characters were assimilated. Chatham was seized with a fainting fit when making his last
            speech, and died a short time afterwards. And probably it is not idle speculation to
            say that Randolph, with a morbid, or perhaps insane admiration of his character
            --wished to sink as Chatham did, in the legislative hall, and be borne thence to
            die.
         </p>
         
         <p>However, there was enough in the character of Chatham to win the admiration of any one who loved eloquence, without seeking in adventitious circumstances a motive for his admiration; and Randolph appreciated such talents as his
            too highly not to have admitted them under all circumstances, but his reverence was doubtless increased, from the resemblance which he saw in their
            bodily conditions, and which he was very willing to believe extended to their minds. Chatham was bold, vehement, resistless--not often witty, but
            eminently successful when he attempted it; invective was his forte. In some of
            these points, Randolph resembled him; but then Chatham's eloquence was but a means to
            gain his ends; his judgment was intuitive, his sagacity unrivalled; he bore down
            all opposition by his fearless energies, and he compelled his enemies to admit that he was a public benefactor in the very breath in which they expressed their personal dislike. Chatham kept his ends steadily in view, and
            never wavered in his efforts to gain them. Not so Randolph. He reminds us of the urchin in the "Lay of the last Minstrel," who always used the fairy gifts with a spirit of deviltry, to provoke, to annoy, and to injure, no
            matter whom he wounded, or when, or where. Randolph did not want personal dignity, but he wanted the dignity which arises from consistent conduct, a
            want which no brilliancy of talent can supply. On the contrary, the splendor of high
            talents but serves to make such inconsistency the more apparent. He was an intellectual meteor, whose course no one could predict; but, be it where
            it might, all were certain that it would blaze, and wither, and destroy. As a statesman, it is believed that he never originated a single measure,
            though his influence often destroyed the measures of others. Some one observes,
            "that the hand which is not able to build a hovel may destroy a palace," and he
            seemed to have had a good deal of the ambition of him who fired the Ephesian dome. As
            a scholar, he left nothing behind him, though his wit was various,
            and his acquirements profound. He seems not to have written a common communication
            for a newspaper, without great labor and fastidious correction. I have been informed
            by a compositor who set a part of his speech on "Retrenchment,"
            which he dedicated to his constituents, that emendations were endless. I have a part
            of the MS. of this speech before me; it is written with a trembling hand, but with great attention to punctuation, and with a delicate stroke of the pen.
            It was as an orator he shone; and as an orator his power of chaining the
            audience has been perhaps never surpassed. In an assembly where Demosthenes, Cicero, Chatham, Mirabeau, or Henry spoke, Randolph's eloquence would have
            been listened to with profound interest, and his opposition would have been feared. As an orator, he felt his power-he knew that in eloquence he yielded a magic
            wand, and he was not only fearless of opposition, but he courted it; for who of his contemporaries has equalled him in the power of carrying on successfully the partisan warfare of desultory debate-the cut and thrust--the steady
            aim? who could wield like him the tomahawk, and who of them possessed his dexterity
            in scalping afoe? His trophies are numberless, and he wore them with the pride
            of his progenitors, for there was truly a good deal of Indian blood in his veins. It
            is said that Randolph first signalized himself by making a stump speech in Virginia
            in opposition to Patrick Henry; scarcely any one knew him 
            when he rose to reply
            to Henry, and so strong was Henry's conviction of his powers, that he spoke of them in the highest terras, and prophesied his future eminence. Randolph
            gloriously said of Henry that, "he was 
            <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> and 
            <span class="person" id="dgarrick">Garrick</span> combined."
         </p>
         
         <p>Randolph's character and conduct forcibly impress upon us the power of eloquence in
            a Republic. How many twists, and tergiversations, and obliquities were there in his
            course; yet how much influence he possessed, particularly in Virginia! How much he was feared, courted, admired, shunned, hated, and all because he
            wielded the weapon that "rules the fierce democracy!" How many men, far his superiors
            in practical usefulness, lived unhonored and without influence, and died unsung,
            because they had not eloquence. Eloquence is superior to all other gifts, even to the
            dazzling fascinations of the warrior; for it rules alike in war and peace, and it
            wins all by its spell. Randolph was the very personification of inconsistency.
            Behold him talking of the splendid misery of "office-holders;" what did he want with
            office; a cup of cold water was better in his condition; the sword of Damocles was suspended over him by a single hair, &amp;c., &amp;c.;-- when
            lo! he goes to the frigid north--for what? For health? No, for an outfit and salary!
            and dies childless, worth, it is said, nearly a million!
         </p>
         
         <p>Randolph's oratory reminds us forcibly of Don Juan; and if 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span> had written nothing
            but Don Juan, Randolph might have been called the 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span> of orators. He had all the
            wit, eccentricity, malice, and flightiness of that work--its touches that strike the heart, and sarcasms that scorn, the next moment, the tear that has
            started.
         </p>
         
         <p>In a dying state, Randolph went to Washington during the last Session of Congress,
            and although not a member, he had himself borne daily to the hall of legislation to
            witness the debate. He returned home to his constituents, and was elected to Congress, and started on a tour to Europe, if possible to regain his
            health; he said it was "the last throw of the die."
         </p>
         
         <p>He expired in Philadelphia, where he had first appeared in the councils of the
            nation, in the sixty-first year of his age, leaving a reputation behind him for
            classic wit and splendid eloquence which few of his contemporaries may hope to
            equal; and a character which his biographer may deem himself
            fortunate if he can explain to have been compatible with either the duties of social life, the sacredness of friendship, or the requirements of patriotism,
            unless he offer as an apology, partial derangement. In the letter in which the
            deceased acknowledged that he had made a misstatement with regard to the
            character of Mr. Lowndes, on the tariff, he assigned, as a reason for the error, the
            disordered state of his mind, arising from the exciting medicine which he was
            compelled to take to maintain life.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Remorse,remorse, remorse!" Shortly before he died, he repeated the word three
            times, and requested the doctor to write it upon the back of one of his (Randolph's)
            cards, and to underscore the word, so as to make it emphatic. (Remorse!) "Put it in your pocket, doctor, and recur to it when I an gone--Remorse,
            remorse, remorse!"
         </p>
         
         <p>Yet was the ruling passion strong in death. The doctor was reading the bible to him
            and mispronounced the word "omnipotent," accenting it as though it were not a
            compound word--omni-potent. "Nipotent--nipotent,sir!" he exclaimed
            with oratorical energy.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have, perhaps, expressed myself harshly--inconsistently with that charitable
            feeling which all should possess, who are :treading upon ashes under which the fire is not yet extinguished." If so, to express our conscientious opinions
            is sometimes to do wrong.
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>Why draw his frailties from their dread abode?
            
         </div>
         
         <p>For who can tell, in the close alliance between reason and madness which were so
            strongly mixed up in his character, how much his actions and words partook of the one
            or the other? Where they alternated, or where one predominated, or where they
            mingled their influence, not in the embrace of love, but in the strife for mastery,
            oh! how much he may have struggled with his mental aberrations and felt that they
            were errors, and yet struggled in vain! His spirit, like the great eye of the
            universe, may have known that clouds and storms beset it, and have felt that it was
            contending with disease and coming death, yet hoped at last to beam forth in its
            brightness.
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>The day draws on, though storms keep out the sun,
            
            <br></br>And thus the heart will break, and brokenly live on.
            
         </div>
         
         <p>And so it is with the mind, and Randolph's "brokenly lived on," until the raven shadows of the night of death gathered over him, and gave him to the dark beyond.</p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">F. W. THOMAS</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">A Dream</div>
         <div class="biblPage">85</div>
         <div class="head">A Dream.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>In visions of the dark night
            
            <br></br>I have dreamed of joy departed--
            
            <br></br>But a waking dream of life and light
            
            <br></br>Hath left me broken-hearted.
            
            <br></br>Ah! what is not a dream by day
            
            <br></br>To him whose eyes are cast
            
            <br></br>On things around him with a ray
            
            <br></br>Turned back upon the past?
            
            <br></br>That holy dream--that holy dream,
            
            <br></br>While all the world were chiding,
            
            <br></br>Hath cheered me as a lovely beam
            
            <br></br>A lonely spirit guiding.
            
            <br></br>What though that light, thro' storm and night,
            
            <br></br>So trembled from afar--
            
            <br></br>What could there bo more purely bright
            
            <br></br>In Truth's day-star?
            
         </div>	
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">P.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Never Bet the Devil Your Head</div>
         <div class="biblPage">85</div>
         
         <div class="head">Never Bet The Devil Your Head. A TALE WITH A MORAL.</div>
         
         <p>"Con tal que las costumbres de un autor," says 
            <span class="person" id="ttorres">Don Thomas De Las
               Torres
            </span>, in the preface to his "Amatory Poems" "sean puras y castas, importo muy poco que no sean igualmente severas sus obras"--meaning, in plain English,
            that, provided the morals of an author are pure, personally, it signifies nothing what are the morals of his books. We presume that 
            <span class="person" id="ttorres">Don
               Thomas
            </span> is now in Purgatory for the assertion. It would be a clever thing, too, in the way of poetical justice, to keep him there until his "Amatory Poems" get
            out of print, or are laid definitely upon the shelf through lack of readers.
            Every fiction should have a moral; and, what is more to the purpose, the critics have
            discovered that every fiction has. 
            <span class="person" id="pmelanchthon">Philip Melancthon</span>, some lime ago, wrote a
            commentary upon the "Batrachomyomachia" and proved that the poet's object was to
            excite a distaste for sedition. 
            <span class="person" id="plaseine">Pierre La Seine</span>, going a step farther, shows that the intention was to recommend to young men temperance in eating and
            drinking. Just so, too, 
            <span class="person" id="jhugues">Jacobus Hugo</span> has satisfied himself that, by
            Euenis, 
            <span class="person" id="homer">Homer</span> meant to insinuate John Calvin; by Antinous, Martin Luther; by the
            Lotophagi, Protestants in general; and, by the Harpies, the Dutch. Our more modern Scholiasts are equally acute. These fellows demonstrate a
            hidden meaning in "The Antediluvians," a parable in "Powhatan," new views in "Cock Robin," and transcendentalism in "Hop 0' My Thumb." In short, it has
            been shown that no man can sit down to write without a very profound design.
            Thus to authors in general much trouble is spared. A novelist, for example, need have
            no care of his moral. It is there--that is to say it is somewhere--and the moral
            and the critics can take care of themselves. When the proper time arrives, all that
            the gentleman intended, and all that he did not intend, will be brought to light, in
            the "Dial," or the "Down-Easter," together with all that he ought to have
            intended, and the rest that he clearly meant to intend:--so that it will all come very
            straight in the end.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is no just ground, therefore, for the charge brought against me by certain ignoramuses--that I have never written a moral tale, or, in more precise
            words, a tale with a moral. They are not the critics predestined to bring me out,
            and develop my morals:--that is the secret. By and by the "North American
            Quarterly Humdrum" will make them ashamed of their stupidity. In the meantime, by way
            of staying execution--by way of mitigating the accusations against me--I offer the
            sad history appended;--a history about whose obvious moral there can be no question whatever, since he who runs may read it in the large capitals which
            form the title of the tale. I should have credit for this arrangement--a far wiser one than that of 
            <span class="person" id="jdlafontaine">La Fontaine</span> and others, who reserve the
            impression to be conveyed until the last moment, and thus sneak it in at the fag end
            of their fables.
         </p>
         
         <p>Defuncti injuria ne afficiantur was a law of the twelve tables, and De mortuis nil nisi bonum is an excellent injunction--even if the dead in question be
            nothing but dead small beer. It is not my design, therefore, to vituperate my deceased friend, Toby Dammit. He was a sad dog, it is true, and a dog's
            death it was that he died; but he himself was not to blame for his vices. They grew out of a personal defect in his mother. She did her best in the way of
            flogging him while an infant--for duties to her well-regulated mind were always
            pleasures, and babies, like tough steaks, or the modem Greek olive trees, are invariably the better for beating--but, poor woman! she had the misfortune to be lefthanded, and a child flogged left-handedly had
            better be left unflogged. The world revolves from right to left. It will not do
            to whip a baby from left to right. If each blow in the proper direction drives an
            evil propensity out, it follows that every thump in an opposite one knocks its quota of wickedness in. I was often present at Toby's chastisements, and,
            even by the way in which he kicked, I could perceive that he was getting worse
            and worse every day. At last I saw, through the tears in my eyes, that there was no
            hope of the villain at all, and one day when he had been cuffed until he grew so
            black in the face that one might have mistaken him for a little African, and no effect had been produced beyond that of making him wriggle himself into
            a fit, I could stand it no longer, but went down upon my knees forthwith, and,
            uplifting my voice, made prophecy of his ruin.
         </p>
         
         <p>The fact is that his precocity in vice was awful. At five months of age he used to
            get into such passions that he was unable to articulate. At six months, I caught him
            gnawing a pack of cards. At seven months he was in the constant habit of
            catching and kissing the female babies. At eight months he peremptorily refused to
            put his signature to the Temperance pledge. Thus he went on increasing in iniquity, month after month, until, at the close of the first year, he not only insisted upon wearing moustaches, but had contracted a propensity for cursing and swearing, and for backing his
            assertions by bets.
         </p>
         
         <p>Through this latter most ungentlemanly practice, the ruin which I had predicted to
            Toby Dammit overtook him at last. The fashion had "grown with his growth and strengthened with his strength," so that, when he came to be a man,
            he could scarcely utter a sentence without interlarding it with a proposition to gamble. Not that he actually laid wagers--no. I will do my friend the
            justice to say that he would as soon have laid eggs. With him the thing was a
            mere formula--nothing more. His expressions on this head had no meaning attached
            to them whatever. They were simple if not altogether innocent expletives--imaginative
            phrases wherewith to round off a sentence. When he said "I'll bet you so and
            so," nobody ever thought of taking him up; but still I could not help thinking it my
            duty to put him down. The habit was an immoral one, and so I told him. It was a
            vulgar one--this I begged him to believe. It was discountenanced by society--here I
            said nothing but the truth. It was forbidden by act of Congress--here I had not
            the slightest intention of telling a lie. I remonstrated--but to no purpose. I
            demonstrated--in vain. I entreated--he smiled. I implored--he laughed. I preached--he
            sneered. I threatened--he swore. I kicked him--he called for the police. I pulled
            his nose--he blew it, and offered to bet the Devil his head that I would not venture to try that experiment again.
         </p>
         
         <p>Poverty was another vice which the peculiar physical deficiency of
            Dammit's mother had entailed upon her son. He was detestably poor; and this was the
            reason, no doubt, that his expletive expressions about betting, seldom took a
            pecuniary turn. I will not be bound to say that I ever heard him make use of
            such a figure of speech as "I'll bet you a dollar." It was usually "I'll bet you what
            you please," or "I'll bet you what you dare," or "I'll bet you a trifle," or else,
            more significantly still, "I'll bet the Devil my head."
         </p>
         
         <p>This latter form seemed to please him best:--perhaps because it involved theleast risk; for Dammit had become excessively parsimonious. Had any
            one taken him up, his head was small, and thus his loss would have been small too.
            But these are my own reflections, and I am by no means sure that I am right in
            attributing them to him. At all events the phrase in question grew daily in favor,
            notwithstanding the gross impropriety of a man's betting his brains like banknotes:--but this was a point which my friend's perversity of disposition
            would not permit him to comprehend. In the end, he abandoned all other forms of wager, and gave himself up to "I'll bet the Devil my head," with a
            pertinacity and exclusiveness of devotion that displeased not less than it
            surprised me. I am always displeased by circumstances for which I cannot account.
            Mysteries force a man to thinkt and so injure his health. The truth is, there was
            something in the air with which Mr. Dammit was wont to give utterance to his offensive expression--something in his manner of enunciation--which at
            first interested, and afterwards made me very uneasy--something which, for want of a more definite term at present, I must be permitted to call queer; but
            which Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="stcoleridge">Coleridge</span> would have called mystical, Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="ikant">Kant</span> pantheistical, Mr.
            
            <span class="person" id="tcarlyle">Carlyle</span> twistical, and Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="rwemerson">Emerson</span> hyperquizzitistical. I began not to
            like it at all. Mr. Dammit's soul was in a perilous state. I resolved to bring all my eloquence into play to save it. I vowed to serve him as St.
            Patrick, in the Irish chronicle, is said to have served the toad, that is to
            say, "awaken him to a sense of his situation." I addressed myself to the task
            forthwith. Once more I be- took myself to remonstrance. Again I
            collected my energies for a final attempt at expostulation.
         </p>
         
         <p>When I had made an end of my lecture, Mr. Dammit indulged himself in
            some very equivocal behaviour. For some moments he remained silent, merely looking me
            inquisitively in the face. But presently he threw his head to one side, and
            elevated his eyebrows to great extent. Then he spread out the palms of his hands and
            shrugged up his shoulders. Then he winked with the right eye. Then he repeated
            the operation with the left. Then he shut them both up very tight. Then he
            opened them both so very wide that I became seriously alarmed for the consequences. Then, applying his thumb to his nose, he thought proper to make an
            indescribable movement with the rest of his fingers. Finally,
            setting his arms a-kimbo, he condescended to reply.
         </p>
         
         <p>I can call to mind only the heads of his discourse. He would be obliged to me if I would hold my tongue. He wished none of my advice. He despised all my
            insinuations. He was old enough to take care of himself. Did I still think him
            baby Dammit? Did I mean to say anything against his character? Did I intend to
            insult him? Was I a fool? Was my maternal parent aware, in a word, of my absence
            from the domiciliary residence? He would put this latter question to me as to a
            man of veracity, and he would bind himself to abide by my reply. Once more he would
            demand explicitly if my mother knew that I was out. My confusion, he said, betrayed me, and he would be willing to bet the Devil his head that she
            did not.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Dammit did not pause for my rejoinder. Turning upon his heel, he left my
            presence with undignified precipitation. It was well for him that he did so. My
            feelings had been wounded. Even my anger had been aroused. For once I would have
            taken him up upon his insulting wager. I would have won for the Arch-Enemy Mr.
            Dammit's little head-- for the fact is, my mamma was very well aware of my merely
            temporary absence from home.
         </p>
         
         <p>But Khoda shefa midehed--Heaven gives relief--as the Musselmen say when you tread upon
            their toes. It was in pursuance of my duty that I had been insulted, and I bore
            the insult like a man. It now seemed to me, however, that I had done all that
            could be required of me, in the case of this miserable individual, and I resolved to
            trouble him no longer with my counsel, but to leave him to his conscience and
            himself. But although I forebore to intrude with my advice, I could not bring myself to give up his society altogether. I even went so far as to humor some of his less reprehensible propensities; and there were times when I
            found myself lauding his wicked jokes, as epicures do mustard, with tears in my
            eyes:--so profoundly did it grieve me to hear his evil talk.
         </p>
         
         <p>One fine day, having strolled out together arm in arm, our route led us in the
            direction of a river. There was a bridge, and we resolved to cross it. It was roofed
            over, by way of protection from the weather, and the arch-way, having but few
            windows, was thus very uncomfortably dark. As we entered the passage, the contrast
            between the external glare, and the interior gloom, struck heavily upon my spirits.
            Not so upon those of the unhappy Dammit, who offered to bet the Devil his head
            that I was hipped. He seemed to be in an unusual good humor. He was excessively
            lively--so much so that I entertained I know not what of uneasy suspicion. It is not impossible that he was affected with the transcendentals. I am not well enough versed, however, in the diagnosis of this disease to speak
            with decision upon the point; and unhappily there were none of my friends of the
            "Dial" pres ent. I suggest the idea, nevertheless,
            because of a certain species of austere Merry-Andrewism which seemed to beset my
            poor friend, and caused him to make quite a Tom-Fool of himself. Nothing would serve
            him but wriggling and skipping about under and over everything that came in his
            way; now shouting out, and now lisping out, all manner of odd little and big
            words, yet preserving the gravest face in the world all the time. I really could not
            make up my mind whether to kick or to pity him. At length, having passed nearly
            across the bridge, we approached the termination of the foot-way, when our progress
            was impeded by a turnstile of some height. Through this I made my way quietly,
            pushing it around as usual. But this turn would not serve the turn of Mr.
            Dammit. He insisted upon leaping the stile, and said he could cut a pigeon-wing over
            it in the air. Now this, conscientiously speaking, I did not think he could do.
            The best pigeon-winger over all kinds of style, was my friend Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="tcarlyle">Carlyle</span>, and
            as I knew he could not do it, I would not believe it could be done by Toby Dammit. I
            therefore told him, in so many words, that he was a braggadocio, and could not
            do what he said. For this, I had reason to be sorry afterwards;-for he straightway
            offered to bet the Devil his head that he could.
         </p>
         
         <p>I was about to reply, notwithstanding my previous resolutions, with
            some remonstrance against his impiety, when I heard, close at my elbow, a slight
            cough, which sounded very much like the ejaculation "ahem!" I started, and
            looked about me in surprise. My glance at length fell into a nook of the
            frame-work of the bridge, and upon the figure of a little lame old gentleman of
            venerable aspect. Nothing could be more reverend than his whole appearance; for, he
            not only had on a lull suit of black, but his shirt was perfectly
            clean and the collar turned very neatly down over a white cravat, while his hair was
            parted in front like a girl's. His hands were clasped pensively together over his
            stomach, and his two eyes were carefully rolled up into the top of his head.
         </p>
         
         <p>Upon observing him more closely, I perceived that he wore a black silk apron over
            his small-clothes; and this was a thing which I thought very odd. Before I had time
            to make any remark, however, upon so singular a circumstance, he interrupted me
            with a second "ahem!"
         </p>
         
         <p>To this observation I was not immediately prepared to reply. The fact is, remarks of
            this laconic nature are nearly unanswerable. I have known a Quarterly Review non-plused by the word :Fudge!" I am not ashamed to say, therefore, that I turned to Mr. Dammit for assistance.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Dammit," said I, "what are
            you about? don't you hear? --the gentleman says 'ahem!'"
            I looked sternly at my friend while I thus addressed him; for to say the truth, I
            felt particularly puzzled, and when a man is particularly puzzled he must knit
            his brows and look savage, or else he is pretty sure to look like a fool.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Dammit," observed I--although this sounded very much like an oath, than which
            nothing was farther from my thoughts--"Dammit," I suggested--"the gentleman says
            'ahem!'"
         </p>
         
         <p>I do not attempt to defend my remark on the score of profundity: I did not think it profound myself; but I have noticed that the effect of our speeches is not always proportionate with their importance in our own
            eyes; and if I had shot Mr. D. through and through with a Paixhan bomb, or knocked him in the head with the "Poets and Poetry of America," he could hardly have been more discomfited than when I addressed him with those
            simple wordds--"Dammit, what are you about?--don't you hear?--the gentleman says
            'ahem!'"
         </p>
         
         <p>"You don't say so?" gasped he at length, after turning more colors than a pirate
            runs up, one after the other, when chased by a man-of-war. "Are you quite sure he
            said that? Well, at all events I am in for it now, and may as well put a bold
            face upon the matter. Here goes, then--ahem!"
         </p>
         
         <p>At this the little old gentleman seemed pleased--God only knows why. He
            left his station at the nook of the bridge, limped forward with a gracious air, took
            Dammit by the hand and shook it cordially, looking all the while straight up in his face with an air of the most unadulterated benignity which it is
            possible for the mind of man to imagine.
         </p>
         
         <p>"I am quite sure you will win it, Dammit," said he with the frankest of all smiles,
            "but we are obliged to have a trial you know, for the sake of mere form."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Ahem!" replied my friend, taking off his coat with a deep sigh, tying a
            pocket-hankerchief around his waist, and producing an unaccountable alteration in his
            countenance by twisting up his eyes, and bringing down the corners of his
            mouth--"ahem!" And "ahem," said he again, after a pause; and not another word more than "ahem!" did I ever know him to say after that. "Aha!" thought
            I, without expressing myself aloud--"this is quite a remarkable silence on the
            part of Toby Dammit, and is no doubt a consequence of his verbosity upon a previous occasion. One extreme induces another. I wonder if he has forgotten the many unanswerable questions which he propounded to me so fluently
            on the day when I gave him my last lecture? At all events, he is cured of the
            transcendentals.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Ahem!" here replied Toby, just as if he had been reading my thoughts, and looking like a very old sheep in a reverie.</p>
         
         <p>The old gentleman now took him by the arm, and led him more into the shade of the
            bridge--a few paces back from the turnstile. "My good fellow," said he, "I make it a
            point of conscience to allow you this much run. Wait here, till I take my place
            by the stile, so that I may see whether you go over it handsomely, and
            transcendentally, and don't omit any flourishes of the pigeon-wing. A mere form, you
            know. I will say 'one, two, three, and away.' Mind you I start at the word
            'away.'" Here he took his position by the stile, paused a moment as if in profound reflection, then looked up and, I thought, smiled, very slightly, then
            tightened the strings of his apron, then took a long look at Dammit, and finally
            gave the word as agreed upon--
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>One--two--three.--and away!
            
         </div>
         
         <p>Punctually, at the word "away," my poor friend set off in a strong gallop. The stile
            was not very high, like Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="wwlord">Lord</span>'s --nor yet very low, like that of Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="wwlord">Lord</span>'s reviewers, but upon the whole I made sure that he would clear it. And
            then what if he did not?--ah, that was the question--what if he did not? "What
            right," said I, "had the old gentleman to make any other gentleman jump? The little old dot-andcarry-one! who is he? If he asks me to jump, I won't do it,
            that's flat, and I don't care who the devil he is." The bridge, as I say, was
            arched and covered in, in a very ridiculous manner, and there was a most
            uncomfortable echo about it at all times--an echo which I never before so particularly
            j observed as when I uttered the four last words of my remark.
         </p>
         
         <p>But what I said, or what I thought, or what I heard, occupied only an
            instant. In less than five seconds from his starting, my poor Toby had taken the
            leap. I saw him run nimbly, and spring grandly from the floor of the bridge, cutting the most awful flourishes with his legs as he went up. I saw him high in the air, pigeon-winging it to admiration just over the top
            of the stile; and of course I thought it an unusually singular thing that he did not
            continue to go over. But the whole leap was the affair of a moment, and, before
            I had a chance to make any profound reflections, down came Mr. Dammit on the
            flat of his back, on the same side of the stile from which he had started. In the
            same instant I saw the old gentleman limping off at the top of his speed, having
            caught and wrapped up in his apron something that fell heavily into it from the
            darkness of the arch just over the turnstile. At all this I was much astonished; but
            I had no leisure to think, for Mr. Dammit lay particularly still, and I
            concluded that his feelings had been hurt, and that he stood in need of my
            assistance. I hurried up to him and found that he had received what might be termed a
            serious injury. The truth is, he had been deprived of his head, which after a
            close search I could not find anywhere;--so I determined to take him home, and send
            for the homoeopathists. In the mean time a thought struck me, and I threw open an adjacent window of the bridge; when the sad truth flashed upon me at once. About five feet just above the lop of the turnstile, and
            crossing the arch of the foot-path so as to constitute a brace, there extended a flat
            iron bar, lying with its breadth horizontally, and forming one of a series that
            served to strengthen the structure throughout its extent. With the edge of this brace it appeared evident that the neck of my unfortunate friend had
            come precisely in contact.
         </p>
         
         <p>He did not long survive his terrible loss. The homoeopathists did not
            give him little enough physic, and what little they did give him he hesitated to
            take. So in the end he grew worse, and at length died, a lesson to all riotous
            livers. I bedewed his grave with my tears, worked a bar sinister on his family
            escutcheon, and, for the general expenses of his funeral, sent in my very moderate bill to the transcendendalists. The scoundrels refused to pay it, so I
            had Mr. Dammit dug up at once, and sold him for dog's meat.
         </p>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Catholic Hymn</div>
         <div class="biblPage">88</div>
         <div class="head">Catholic hymn.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>At morn--at noon--at twilight dim--
            
            <br></br>Maria! thou hast heard my hymn!
            
            <br></br>In joy and wo--in good and ill
            
            <br></br>Mother of God, be with mo still!
            
            <br></br>When the Hours flew brightly by,
            
            <br></br>And not a cloud obscured the sky.
            
            <br></br>My soul, lest it should truant be,
            
            <br></br>Thy grace did guide to thine and thee;
            
            <br></br>Now, when storms of Fate o'ercast
            
            <br></br>Darkly my Present and my Past,
            
            <br></br>Let my Future radiant shine
            
            <br></br>With sweet hopes of thee and thine!
            
         </div>
         <div class="ab">++.</div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Critical Notices</div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="biblTitle">Graham's Magazine</div>
            <div class="biblPage">88</div>
            
            <p>Graham's Magazine, for August, comes to us with a portrait and
               biography of 
               <span class="person" id="jkmitchell">J. K. Mitchell</span>, the author of "Fly to the Prairie," &amp;c. We think
               the likeness by no means a good one. Very certainly it does not flatter Dr.
               
               <span class="person" id="jkmitchell">Mitchell</span>. Following this, we have a very fine line engraving of "The
               Tower-Rock on the Mississippi," and another (quite as good) of "Rock Mountain"
               from the north.
            </p>
            
            <p>In prose, there is an interesting paper called "The Jugglers," by a New Contributor, and "Ida Grey" a tale of passion, exceedingly well
               written, by Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="fsosgood">Osgood</span>. In poetry, we notice contributions from 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>,
               
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span>, and Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="mgnichols">Nichols</span>. That of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span> is constrained and petty
               in its versification, and throughout is obviously a suggestion from "The
               Evening Wind" of 
               <span class="person" id="wcbryant">Bryant</span>, to which we refer our readers--especially for the passage about the sick man looking from his chamber. Nevertheless, the poem is
               worthy the genius of the author. We quote, from the conclusion two magnificent
               passages:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>He (the poet) can behold
               
               <br></br>Things manifold
               
               <br></br>That have not yet been wholly told--
               
               <br></br>Have not been wholly sung nor said:
               
               <br></br>For his thought, which never stops,
               
               <br></br>Follows the water-drops
               
               <br></br>Down to the graves of the dead--
               
               <br></br>Down through chasms and gulfs profound
               
               <br></br>To the dreary fountain-head
               
               <br></br>Of lakes and rivers underground,
               
               <br></br>And sees them when the rain is done
               
               <br></br>On the bridge of colours seven
               
               <br></br>Climbing up once more to Heaven,
               
               <br></br>Opposite the setting sun.
               
               <br></br>Thus the seer
               
               <br></br>With vision clear
               
               <br></br>Sees forms appear and dissappear,
               
               <br></br>In the perpetual round of strange
               
               <br></br>Mysterious change
               
               <br></br>From birth to death, from Death to birth--
               
               <br></br>From earth to heaven, from heaven to earth--
               
               <br></br>Till glimpses more sublime
               
               <br></br>Of things unseen before
               
               <br></br>Unto his wondering eyes reveal
               
               <br></br>The universe as an immeasurable wheel
               
               <br></br>Turning forever more
               
               <br></br>In the rapid and rushing river of Time.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span>'s poem, "To the Future," has a noble commencement, and is
               altogether a noble composition--although in the last stanza is a palpable
               plagiarism--e. g.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>As life's alarums nearer roll
               
               <br></br>The ancestral buckler calls
               
               <br></br>Self clanging from the walls
               
               <br></br>In the high temple of the soul.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>This is Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">L.</span>'s--but 
               <span class="person" id="wwordsworth">Wordsworth</span> has either the following lines, or something resembling them--for we quote altogether from memory.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Armor rustling on the walls
               
               <br></br>On the blood of Clifford calls,
               
               <br></br>And to clash again in the field
               
               <br></br>Is the wild longing of the shield.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>Except in its versification Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span> has by no means improved the
               idea of 
               <span class="person" id="wwordsworth">Wordsworth</span>--although "self-clanging" has great force.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">The American Review for August</div>
            <div class="biblPage">88</div>
            
            <p>The American Review for August, is an unusually fine number, and contains, among other excellent papers, a valuable "Memoir of Blennerhasset" by
               
               <span class="person" id="wrwallace">William Wallace</span>. We have no space for farther particulars this week. The Review is eminently successful.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Democratic Review</div>
            <div class="biblPage">88</div>
            
            <p>The Democratic Review is just issued in duplicate--the July and August numbers
               coming out together, with a host of excellent papers--among others an admirable one by Hudson--and "The Innocent Convict" a very clever tale by Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="cfbriggs">Briggs</span> (Harry Franco). "The Democratic" is now under the sole charge of Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="jlosullivan">O'Sullivan</span> as editor and publisher--and we may add (although this is somewhat
               supererogatory) that it could not be in belter hands. The price is reduced to three
               dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">The London Foreign Quarterly, for July</div>
            <div class="biblPage">88</div>
            
            <p>The London Foreign Quarterly, for July, reprinted by Leonard
               Scott &amp; Co. has been out for some days. The most interesting paper is on "The
               Oregon Territory."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No.XVII</div>
            <div class="biblPage">89</div>
            
            <div class="head">Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XVII. The Characters of
               Shakspeare. By 
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">William Hazlitt</span>.
            </div>
            
            <p>This is one of the most interesting numbers of "The Library" yet
               issued. If anything could induce us to read anything more in the way of commentary
               on 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>, it would be the name of 
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> prefixed. With his hackneyed theme
               he has done wonders, and those wonders well. He is emphatically a critic a brilliant, epigrammatic, startling, paradoxical, and
               suggestive, rather than accurate, luminous, or profound. For purposes of mere
               amusement, he is the best commentator who ever wrote in English. At all points, except perhaps in fancy, he is superior to 
               <span class="person" id="jhlhunt">Leigh Hunt</span>, whom
               nevertheless he remarkably resembles. It is folly to compare him with
               
               <span class="person" id="tbmacaulay">Macaulay</span>, for there is scarcely a single point of approximation, and 
               <span class="person" id="tbmacaulay">Macaulay</span> is by
               much the greater man. The author of "The Lays of Ancient Rome" has an intellect
               so well balanced and so thoroughly proportioned, as to appear, in
               the eyes of the multitude, much smaller than it really is. He needs a few foibles
               to purchase him eclat. Now, take away the innumerable foibles of 
               <span class="person" id="jhlhunt">Hunt</span> and 
               <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span>, and we should have the anomaly of finding them more diminutive
               than we fancy them while the foibles remain. Nevertheless, they are men of genius
               still.
            </p>
            
            <p>In all commentating upon 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>, there has been a radical error, never yet mentioned. It is the error of attempting to expound his characters--to account for their actions--to reconcile his inconsistencies--not as if
               they were the coinage of a human brain, but as if they had been actual
               existences upon earth. We talk of Hamlet the man, instead of Hamlet the
               dramatis persona--of Hamlet that God, in place of Hamlet that 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> created. If Hamlet had really lived, and if the tragedy were an accurate record of
               his deeds, from this record (with some trouble) we might, it is true,
               reconcile his inconsistences and settle to our satisfaction his true character. But the task becomes the purest absurdity when we deal only with a
               phantom. It is not (then) the inconsistencies of the acting man which we have as a
               subject of discussion--(although we proceed as if it were, and thus inevitably
               err,) but the whims and vacillations--the conflicting energies and indolences of the
               poet. It seems to us little less than a miracle, that this obvious point should
               have been overlooked.
            </p>
            
            <p>While on this topic, we may as well offer an ill-considered opinion of our own as to the intention of the poet in the delineation of the Dane. It must
               have been well known to 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>, that a leading feature in certain more intense
               classes of intoxication, (from whatever cause,) is an almost irresistible impulse to counterfeit a farther degree of excitement than actually exists. Analogy would lead any thoughtful person to suspect the same
               impulse in madness--where beyond doubt, it is manifest. This, 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> felt--not
               thought. He felt it through his marvellous power of identification with humanity at large--the ultimate source of his magical influence
               upon mankind. He wrote of Hamlet as if Hamlet he were; and having, in the first
               instance, imagined his hero excited to partial insanity by the disclosures of the
               ghost--he (the poet) felt that it was natural he should be impelled to
               exaggerate the insanity.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Southern Literary Messenger, for August</div>
            <div class="biblPage">89</div>
            
            <p>The Southern Literary Messenger, for August, is chiefly noticeable for a long attack on the "Massachusetts Proposition for abolishing the Slave
               Representation as guarantied by the Constitution." We have not yet read this
               article so thoroughly as we intend. Among the other contributions we observe
               one from Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="jtworthington">Jane Tayloe Worthington</span>--a lady of high accomplishments and fine
               genius.
            </p>
            
            <p>We find the following queer inquiry on the cover:</p>
            
            <p>Will our Correspondents and the Editors with whom we exchange inform us how they would like to see the form of the Messenger changed the next year--to
               the size and style of the English Blackwood?
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Farmer's Library and Monthly Journal of Agriculture</div>
            <div class="biblPage">89</div>
            
            <p>The Farmer's Library and Monthly Journal of Agriculture. Edited by 
               <span class="person" id="jsskinner">John S.
                  Skinner
               </span>. New York: Greely &amp; Mc Elrath.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have received the first and second numbers of this truly valuable Monthly--those for July and August. The success of the enterprise may
               well be phrophseied. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jsskinner">Skinner</span> has failed in none of his
               undertakings, and perhaps there is no man in America, so well qualified as himself to conduct an agricultural journal. More than twenty six years
               ago he commenced in Baltimore "The American Farmer," the first paper in this
               country devoted to the interest of the husbandman.
            </p>
            
            <p>The numbers before us abound in interesting matter. Among other
               papers we find a Biography of Stephen Van Renssellaer (with a superb portrait) and
               the commencement of a reprint of the famous Lectures of Pertzholdt. No Magazine in America equals this in the manner of its getting up. The
               price is five dollars per annum.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Lowell Offering</div>
            <div class="biblPage">89</div>
            
            <p>The Lowell Offering. A Repository of Original Articles, written by the Factory
               Girls. Lowell: Misses 
               <span class="person" id="hcurtis">Curtis</span> 4
               <span class="person" id="hfarley">Farley</span>. Price One Dollar per
               annum.
            </p>
            
            <p>The August number is received. We have been much interested in the
               "Editorial" signed 
               <span class="person" id="hfarley">"H. F."</span>--but are unable altogether to appreciate ii, as it is
               continued from numbers of the work which have never met our eye. The "Offering" has indisputable merit.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Mysteries of Berlin</div>
            <div class="biblPage">89</div>
            
            <p>The Mysteries of Berlin. New York: Wm. H. Colyer.</p>
            
            <p>Part VIII is issued.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Harper's Illuminated and Pictorial Bible. No. 35</div>
            <div class="biblPage">89</div>
            <p>Harpers' Illuminated and Pictorial Bible. No. 35.</p>
            
            <p>This number brings the work as far as the Thirteenth Chapter of
               Zechariah. There are three large and thirty-seven small designs, independently of
               the Initial Letters. The small cuts are without exception excellent, and many of
               them are not only admirable as mere specimens of wood engraving, but, as
               designs, belong to the highest class of art. We would refer especially to those
               illustrating verse 3 of the 3d Chapter of Nahum--verse 10 of the 3d Chapter of
               Habbakuk--verse 4 of the 2d Chapter of Zephaniah--verse 1 of the 6th; verse 13
               of the 7th; and verse 2d of the 10th Chapter of Zechariah. The heads of the
               Prophets are full of force and character.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is evidently no falling off in any portion of this enterprise.</p>
            
            <p>Lest there be any one of our readers unacquainted with its whole scope, we state
               that this Bible is printed from the Standard Copy of the American Bible Society,
               and contains (or will contain) Marginal References, the Apocrypha, a Concordance, Chronological Table, List of Proper Names, Index, Table of
               Weights, Measures, &amp;c. The large Frontispieces, Titles to the Old and New Testaments, Family Record, Presentation Plate, Historical Illustrations, Initial Letters, Ornamental Borders, &amp;c., are from original designs by Chapman; but, in addition, there will be numerous large engravings from designs by distinguished foreign artists--sixteen
               hundred engravings in all--exclusive of initial letters. The
               engraver is Adams. As there are no notes or comments upon the text, (which is
               the authorised version) there can be no objection to the edition on the score of
               sectarian prejudice, or opinion. Upon the whole it is the most magnificent Bible
               ever put to press.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Duty of American Women to their Country</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            
            <p>The Duty of American Women to their Country. New York: Harper &amp;
               Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This volume is put forth anonymously, and has no preface. We know not who is the author, nor any circumstance connected with its publication. It may
               be, however, the work of Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="mkirkland">Kirkland</span>. At all events it is the work of some woman of very bold and vigorous intellect--possibly of Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lmchild">Child</span> or
               Miss 
               <span class="person" id="smfuller">Fuller</span>. Its propositions speak for themselves. The design is to arouse the
               country, and more especially its women, to the necessity of forwarding the cause of general education. Our deficiencies, in this respect, are vividly
               shown:--for example;
            </p>
            
            <p>Look, then, at the indications in our census. In a population of fourteen milions,
               we can find one milllion adults who cannot read and write, and two million of
               children without schools. In a few years, then, if these children come on the stage
               with their present neglect, we shall have three millions of adults managing our
               state and national affairs, who cannot even read the Constitution they swear to
               support, nor a word in the Bible, nor any newspaper or book, Look at the West,
               where our dangers from foreign immigration are the greatest, and which, by its
               unparalleled increase, is soon to hold the sceptre of power. In Indiana and
               Illinois scarcely one half of the children have any schools. Missouri and Iowa send
               a similar or worse report. In Virginia, one quarter of the white adults cannot even
               write their names to their applications for marriage license. In North Carolina,
               more than half the adults cannot read or write. The whole South, in addition
               to her ignorant slaves, returns more than half her white children as without
               schools.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is, indeed, a lamentable picture, and not the least distressing feature of it is its absolute truth. The remedy proposed, is the
               establisment of Seminaries for the education of teachers, as well female as male:--the superior qualifications of woman for educational tasks in common schools, being very decidedly shown--if Indeed there was ever any reasonable doubt on the subject.
            </p>
            
            <p>The work is lucidly, earnestly, and vigorously written; and we recommend it to all
               readers sufficiently unprejudiced not to mistake ardor for folly--the enthusiastic for the visionary.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">Essays</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            
            <p>Essays. By 
               <span class="person" id="jabercrombie">John Abercrombie</span>, M.D., F. R. S. E., Author of "Inquiries concerning
               the Intellectual Powers," "The Philosophy of the Moral Feelings," etc., etc. From
               the 19th Edinburgh Edition. New York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of course we shall not say a word in commendation of the truly great author of "The Intellectual Powers." The present edition of his "Essays," is
               from the British copy revised by himself, and embracing, for the first time, some
               of the best of his writings. :The Intellectual Powers" and the "Moral Feelings," can be obtained of the Harpers, who issued these admirable disquisitions, some time since, as portions of "The Family
               Library."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XVIII</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            
            <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XVIII. The Crock of Gold.
               By 
               <span class="person" id="mftupper">Martin Farquhar Tupper</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="npwillis">Willis</span>, in one of his late Letters to the "Mirror," has said a good deal which may serve to excite interest in Martin 
               <span class="person" id="mftupper">Farquhar Tupper</span>. The only point
               about which the author of "Melanie" is deceived, is the age of the author. Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="mftupper">Tupper</span>, we believe, is a much older man than Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="npwillis">W.</span> supposes him. His
               talents, however, are scarcely overrated. "The Crock of Gold" is a simple, picturesque story of common life, and turns upon the danger aristing
               to the contented poor from suddenly and, in especial, from easily acquired
               wealth. The style is terse, succinct, and often sketchy. The narrative is
               skilfully managed, and frequently rises into what the critics now and then call
               "power"--of which a specimen is to be found, commencing at page 108 of the volume before us--at a point where the hero robs and murders his
               aunt.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">Travels in North America in the years 1841--2, with Geological Observations on the
               United States, Canada, and Nova Scotia.
            </div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            
            <p>Travels in North America in the years 1841--2, with Geological
               Observations on the United States, Canada, and Nova Scotia. By 
               <span class="person" id="clyell">Charles Lyell</span>, Esq.,
               F. R. S. New York: Wiley and Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>A work full of the most authentic information, and acute remark. Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="clyell">Lyell</span>'s literary acquirements are far superior to his elocution. We feel that we need say little about this volume--for it will be purchased and read by
               all who wish to keep up with the science of the day, or who have any claim,
               even, to be regarded as "general readers."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Wandering Jew</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            
            <p>The Wandering Jew. By 
               <span class="person" id="esue">Eugene Sue</span>. New York: Harper &amp;
               Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>No. XVI. is issued and ably sustains the interest of the story --which is beyond
               doubt a marvellous one.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">The London Quarterly Review</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            <p>The London Quarterly Review,</p>
            
            <p>For June, has been republished by Messrs. Leonard Scott &amp; Co. Among other
               papers, it has a discriminating notice of Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="csnorton">Norton</span>'s "Child of the Islands."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Chance Medley of Light Matter</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            
            <p>A Chance Medley of Light Matter. By 
               <span class="person" id="tcgrattan">T. Colley Grattan</span>, Author of :High-ways
               and By-ways," &amp;c. New-York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is No. 59 of the "Library of Select Novels." We need say nothing in praise of
               Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="tcgrattan">Grattan</span>. His articles invariably possess interest.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <div class="biblTitle">Pictorial History of the World</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            <p>Pictorial History of the World. By 
               <span class="person" id="jfrost">John Frost</span>, LL. D.
            </p>
            
            <p>No. VII is issued, and is superior even to the previous numbers.</p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="head">THE FINE ARTS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Welfare of the Various Professions</div>
            <div class="biblPage">90</div>
            
            <p>To those who take any interest in the welfare of the various
               professions, it cannot but be a source of deep regret, to observe how much ill-feeling, jealousy, hatred, and all uncharitableness, exist in
               every grade of every profession. If these feelings were only called into action by cases of eminent success, we should not be so Quixotic as to attempt
               to wage war against their power; for our nature is so frail, that the success
               of one offends thousands, who, consequently, seek to depreciate the genius which
               soars far above the highest flight of their imagination. But it is not only the
               successful who have to battle with these bitter enemies; the humble and lowly
               are alike oppressed. They who, steeped to the very lips in poverty, struggle in
               obscurity for a scanty subsistence--who rise with the early cock-crow, and labor
               with heavy hearts almost against hope--they too suffer with the rest--their
               daily bread is mixed with bitterness. The artists of established reputation oppose
               the rising young men, who in their turn give back the cold shoulder with
               hearty ill-will, conscious that, with youth on their side, their day must
               come. And when that day does come, what is the consequence? Does the experience of the past teach them wisdom and moderation in their
               intercourse with others? No! the oppression which they suffered in their youth,
               they repay with interest to those who are struggling as they struggled; and
               thus the system of oppression descends from generation to generation, entailing
               misery upon thousands. Wo see them daily--hourly before our eyes, and we have traced
               their sad effect upon the advancement of Arts. What can be done i to remedy
               this state of things? What can we do to make men human? How can we teach them to
               act towards their fellow men, as though the world were wide enough for all? We can hardly hope to throw down one stone from this structure of prejudice, which
               long years of brooding maliceor open hostility, have tended only to increase or to
               strengthen. We will, however, endeavour to arrive at the cause of this sad
               misconception. We believe it to arise chiefly from that most wretched of all
               habits--the habit of cliquing! Two or three men are thrown often together; their
               feelings are congenial; their tone of thought the same; they view the Art and its
               necessities with the same eye; they are drawn together; they form a little
               banded circle, hedged in by prejudice, and guarded by a powerful sense of community
               of interest, into which none other dare enter. Their views become as contracted as their circle, and all who are not of them, they oppose. This opposition begets opposition: new cliques are formed in
               self-defence, and thus a large body of intelligence, whose one great aim should be
               the advancement of Art, is split into small coteries, whose insignificant aim is party purposes. The Art is forgotten in their own individuality; the
               cause is sacrificed at the altar of self aggrandizement.
            </p>
            
            <p>The two great parties at present, are the old and the young artists. Each party is divided against itself, but each combines when the other is to be
               attacked. This feeling has been fostered by some writers for the press, who, to gain favor with one party, endeavor to set both by the ears. Such
               men should be noted and sent to Coventry by the whole--that is to say, if the
               whole body could act unanimously. We have no Utopian theory for human advancement
               to put forth; we leave that desired end to time, which worketh wonders. We
               endeavour to find a remedy in things as they at present exist. We do not believe that the evils of which we complain, have so deep a foundation but
               that social intercourse would remove them. Our nature is frail, but there is a well
               of kindly feeling in the human heart, which cannot, however we may cast in the
               dirt of this world, be entirely dammed up. The oldest established prejudices yield to familiar intercourse; then surely prejudices that are really only
               of the surface, though they sink deeper by habit, may be vanquished by the same means. How many enemies at a distance become friends on
               meeting!
            </p>
            
            <p>We therefore say--let the artists seek each other's society indiscriminately. They know not how much manly and noble feeling and generous sympathy exist, where they suppose jealousy and bigotry alone have sway. Let the old
               stretch forth the hand of friendship to the young! They would find the
               response cordial, and thus combined, the Art could no longer suffer--for,
               ill-feeling quelled, their energies could find a proper channel, and the glory of
               the Art would be the noble end, instead of the present ignoble struggle for party
               purposes.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p25">
            <div class="biblTitle">Historical Painting</div>
            <div class="biblPage">91</div>
            
            <p>Historical Painting.--We take great pleasure in giving all the publicity in our power to the following advertisement:</p>
            
            <p>One Thousand Pounds arc hereby offered to the Artist who shall produce the best Oil Painting of the Baptism or Christ by immersion in the River Jordan, to illustrate the accounts of the Evangelists:--Matthew 3rd
               chapter, 13th to 17th verses; Mark, 1st chapter, 9th to 11th verses; Luke, 3rd
               chapter, 21st to 23rd verses; and the following lines from the first book of
               
               <span class="person" id="jmilton">Milton</span>'s "Paradise Regained."
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>-----------------------------"I saw
               
               <br></br>The prophet do him reverence, on hiiji rising
               
               <br></br>Out of the water, heaven above the clouds
               
               <br></br>Unfold her crystal doors," &amp;c.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>Lines 79 to 85; again, line 288:--</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>--"As I rose out of the laving stream."
               
            </div>
            
            <p>It is required that the size of the work shall be not less than 12 feet by 10, nor
               greater than 15 feet by 12; that the two principal figures shall be at least as
               large as life; that the time shall be immediately before the immersion, while John is uttering the words of administration, or immediately after it,
               while John and Christ are standing in the water to the depth of about two-fifths of
               their height.
            </p>
            
            <p>Two years, from this date, will be allowed for the completion and sending in of
               the pictures. They must be forwarded--in frames not exceeding two inches in
               widths--to a place in London hereafter to be advertised. The whole of the works will
               be publicly exhibited in the Metropolis, for a period of time, not exceeding two
               months, during which the competing Artists (being so far their own judges) shall by
               successive eliminations reduce the number of the paintings to five, out of which we will select the one to which the prize shall be awarded.
            </p>
            
            <p>With the view of obtaining suitable accommodation for the exhibition, it is requested that the names and addresses of all Artists intending
               to compete, together, if possible, with the size of their pictures, may be sent to
               either of our addresses by the 1st of January, 1846, when the precise mode of
               elimination will be advertised and the money funded for this specific object, in
               the names of three respectable individuals in London, whose names will be
               published; and, in the meantime, references will be given, if required, both in
               London and Edinburgh.
            </p>
            
            <p>The competition is open to Artists of all Nations.</p>
            
            <p>The ?1000 will be paid to the successful competitor before the close of the exhibition: the picture and copyright to become our property.</p>
            
            <p>The utmost care will be taken of the paintings; but we cannot hold ourselves
               responsible in any case of injury or accident; nor can we defray any of the
               expenses of their conveyance or removal.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">THOMAS DELL, 
               <br></br>Don Alkali Works, South Shields. 
               <br></br>CHARLES HILL ROE,
               
               <br></br>Hermitage, Ashton Road, Birmingham. 
               <br></br>April 3, 1845.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p26">
            <div class="biblTitle">"The Sun"</div>
            <div class="biblPage">91</div>
            
            <p>We find the following in "The Sun," but do not exactly comprehend it.</p>
            
            <p>Mr. Sully, the well known and justly distinguished artist of Philadelphia, has just finished a truly admirable full length and life-size portrait
               of Gen. Jackson. It is from an original by Mr. S. and the dress is the United
               States' uniform, over which is thrown in easy and graceful style, a military cloak.
               The effort is of the highest order of art, and may well be regarded as one of
               Sully's best. The likeness, the coloring, the general effect, are all
               admirable.
            </p>
            
            <p>Is the picture an original "from an original" by Mr. S? Or is the picture by the
               "justly distinguished Mr. Sully" at all? We had supposed it the work of the younger
               Sully --but do not pretend to know.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            <div class="biblTitle">Daguerreotyping</div>
            <div class="biblPage">91</div>
            
            <p>M. Martiner, of Paris, claims to have discovered the means of Daguerreotyping an entire panorama, embracing 150 degrees--although we are at a loss to
               know how "an entire panorama" (tautological) can be said to embrace only 150
               degrees. His process consists in curving the metallic plate, and causing the
               lens which reflects the landscape to turn by clockwork. The lens, in turning,
               passes over on one side the whole space to be Daguerreotyped, and on the other side
               moves the refracted luminous cone to the plate, to which the objects are
               successively conveyed.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p28">
            <div class="biblTitle">Paintings at the Rotunda</div>
            <div class="biblPage">91</div>
            
            <p>We shall endeavour to give, in our next, a full account of the paintings at the
               Rotunda. No tickets received.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p29">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Department</div>
         <div class="biblPage">92</div>
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
         
         <p>Park Theatre.--There has been a gloom thrown over this establishment for the past
            week, by the death of M. Coeuriot, who died suddenly, or at least unexpectedly, at
            his residence, on Wednesday morning, August the sixth. The public will have
            reason to regret his loss, for he was a man of fine talents--correct and tasteful as a
            singer--as an actor, admirable! His place will not easily be filled in the company of which he was a member. In private life he bore an estimable
            character, and was highly respected. Funeral honors were paid to him in the French
            Church, Canal street, and he was followed to the grave by a large body of the
            musical profession. Madame Cceuriot has not performed since the death of her
            husband.
         </p>
         
         <p>Meyerbeer's grand Historical Opera, Les Huguenots, was produced by the French
            company on Monday last. The weather was very stormy, but despite its surly
            threatenings, a large and fashionable audience attended the first representation of this great work.
         </p>
         
         <p>The following was the caste of the Opera:</p>
         
         <div class="ab">Raoul - - - - M. Amaud 
            <br></br>Marcel- - - - Douvry 
            <br></br>Le Compte de Nevers - - Garry
            
            <br></br>Le Compte de St. Bris - - Bernard 
            <br></br>Rois Rosse - - - Dessonville 
            <br></br>Maurevert -
            - - - Montassier 
            <br></br>Cosse - - - - Buscher 
            <br></br>Valentine - - - Mad'lle Calve
            
            <br></br>Marguerite de Valois - - M'me Casini 
            <br></br>Urban, a Page - - Mad'lle Richer
         </div>
         
         <p>The following is a short account of the plot. The first scene is a grand Banquet
            Hall in the mansion of the Comte de Nevers. All the gallants of the Court are
            present, and with them a young Protestant nobleman, Raoul. He tells them how he rescued from a band of libertines, a young, noble, and lovely lady, and
            how they became mutually and passionately attached. The merriment of the party is disturbed by Marcel, a stern old Huguenot, who, seeing his young
            lord Raoul feasting with his enemies, or rather with the enemies of his religion,
            endeavors to make him cease; but failing in his endeavors, he determines to stem the
            tide of licentiousness, and chants forth, in a voice of thunder, a Huguenot
            Chorale. The young lords, for the sake of Raoul, do not resent the insult. At this
            moment, the Comte de Nevers is called from the room, his presence being desired
            by a lady. The guests, being all pretty high from the effects of
            the revel, are full of curiosity to learn who the fair lady may be. They peep through the curtain which conceals the window, and are enchanted by her beauty.
            They persuade Raoul to do the same. He advances, but is horror-struck; for the first glance reveals to him the lady of his love, in earnest
            and familiar converse with his host. The lady retires past the banquet hall, and the
            Count enters. All but Raoul congratulate him upon his conquest. Before any
            explanation can take place, the Queen's Page enters, bearing a letter to Raoul. He opens it, and finds it an appointment, to which he
            is to be conducted blindfolded. He con- sents to go, and shows the letter to all
            assembled; the cour- tiers know the Queen's hand and seal, and congratulate Ra- oul
            upon
            his favor.
         </p>
         
         <p>The second scene exhibits a view of the Queen's gardens. The Queen is surrounded by her maids of honor. Her favorite, Valentine, approaches; Marguerite
            comforts her with the assurance that she shall be the wife of Raoul, who shortly after is led in blindfolded. All the ladies retire, leaving the
            Queen alone with Raoul: he takes the bandage from his eyes, and is ravished at the
            fairy-like beauty of the scene, and the surpassing loveliness of the Queen, with whom
            he at once falls desperately in love. Fickle Raoul! where was thy love for Valentine? The Queen finds herself in a delicate situation, and observes
            that had she not promised to win him for another, it would be a rare opportunity to
            gain him for herself. She promises him, however, that he shall have the lady
            whom he loves; and at this juncture, the courtiers enter to pay their respects to the
            Queen. Raoul then learns to whom he has been making love, and is overwhelmed with astonishment. He is introduced to the Comte de St. Bris, and the Queen
            declares that it being the dearest wish of the King, her husband, to unite the two great factions, the Huguenot and the Catholic, in enduring bonds of
            unity, she has decided, in order to accomplish this end, to bestow the hand of
            Valentine, daughter of the Comte de St. Bris, upon Raoul. The Queen then leads
            Valentine from the midst of the ladies, and presents her to Raoul, who starts
            back with horror, and indignantly rejects her. A scene of great confusion lakes
            place, and high words pass between St. Bris and Raoul.
         </p>
         
         <p>The third Act shows a chapel on the left, with a view of the distant country.
            Valentine enters the chapel to pass a few hours in prayer, previous to her marriage
            with Comte de Nevers, to whom she had been previously betrothed, although
            against her will. Marcel brings a letter from Raoul to St. Bris, which contains a challenge, though the bearer is ignorant of its contents. St. Bris and
            others conspire to surround and kill Raoul. This plot is overheard by Valentine, who
            informs Marcel of it. Raoul and St. Bris meet, but before the plot can be carried into effect, Marcel shouts out his Chorale, and a number of
            Huguenot soldiers come to his aid. A scene of great confusion ensues, which is
            quelled by the appearance of the Queen. The Comte de Nevers then enters, and conveys the Queen and his affianced to celebrate the nuptials.
         </p>
         
         <p>The fourth Act discovers Valentine alone in a chamber, she having escaped from the
            banquet. Raoul enters, having also stolen away, to speak one last word to one whom he
            so fondly loved, and by whom he was so basely deceived. A hurried explanation
            ensues -- he finds that he has been the victim of suspicious circumstances; that Valentine only visited the Comte de Nevers to annul the contract of
            marriage existing between the Count and herself for years; she never having
            loved him, and being now under the influence of a first passion. In the midst of his regrets at his want of confidence, at his headlong jealousy, footsteps
            are heard, and he has scarcely time to conceal himself behind some drapery, when
            St. Bris, de Nevers, accompanied by others, enter the room. St. Bris requests his
            daughter to withdraw, as he has secrets of importance to impart; she is, however,
            permitted to remain at the desire of her husband. The dreadful secret of the
            Massacre is then disclosed. De Nevers indignantly refuses to join the conspiracy, declaring that he would rather die than tarnish the bright name of his
            family, or the sword which he has borne in honorable conflict. St. Bris causes
            him to be at once arrested; then, forgetful of the presence of Valentine, the signal
            for the commencement of the Massacre, and the mode of action, are arranged. Three
            priests then enter, who sanctify the daggers destined ere long to reek with
            Christian blood. They depart. Raoul, who has heard the whole of the dreadful design,
            almost stupified with horror, rushes from bis concealment, and is on the point
            of leaving the palace, when he is stopped by Valentine, who urges him to remain
            where he is, secure from the daggers of the assassins. He pleads his honor, duty, and
            love to the friends about to be sacrificed. Valentine, in despair, confesses how deeply she loves him, and for her sake begs him
            to remain; for a moment the delirium of passion triumphs, and he
            forgets all in the happiness of love returned. But the tolling of the Bell--the signal
            of the Massacre--arouses him from a dream of bliss; and, regardless of all entreaty,
            he leaps from the window, and Valentine falls as dead upon the ground. The fifth
            Act brings the terrible drama to an end. Raoul, after leaping from the window,
            encounters the faithful Marcel, who is wounded to death. They are joined by
            Valentine, who, regardless of all danger, follows to save her lover. Marcel relates
            how the noble de Nevers died in the endeavor to save him from the mob. Valentine,
            finding herself released from a tie she never sought, abjuring a religion which sanctified wholesale murder and indiscriminate massacre, consents to
            fly with Raoul. They are, however, intercepted, and die together.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of the chief actors in this piece, we cannot speak too highly. On no occasion has
            M'lle Calve exhibited so much excellence. In the fourth Act, her singing and her
            acting were beyond cavil. Her wild and passionate endeavors to restrain Raoul,
            and her overwhelming despair at his escape, reached, from the beginning to the end,
            the highest point of artistic excellence. So powerfully were the feelings of the
            audience excited, that the applause continued until it was thought advisable to
            raise the curtain, so that Calve, and Arnaud, (who deserved the like compliment,
            might receive a token of the public admiration. We regret that we are unable,
            this week, to enlarge upon the great merits of these artists, for though it would be
            a labor of love, a want of space denies us this indulgence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Messrs. Douvry, Garry, and Bernard, were excellent in their respective parts; and Madame Casini, though sadly deficient in power, and M'lle Richer,
            received, and deservedly, much applause.
         </p>
         
         <p>Of the music we shall speak, in our next, in connection with Robert le Diable by the
            same author.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Opera was got out in most magnificent style.</p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p30">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Drama</div>
         <div class="biblPage">93</div>
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>The most important theatrical event (in New York) since we spoke last of the drama,
            has been the opening of the New Bowery Theatre by Mr. A. W. Jackson, as Manager
            and Proprietor. The house is very large, and may even accommodate 4000 persons. Its general arrangements are excellent. The stage is
            capacious, and well appointed. Much of the scenery is well painted and effective--but
            the wild forest scenes are grossly exaggerated and unnatural, and the drop
            curtain is atrocious. These broad appeals to the patriotism of an audience, at the
            expense of their good taste and common sense, are out of date and should be
            abandoned. There is not a Pittite who would not look with greater relish at a glowing landscape than at a rigmarole burlesque upon Washington, even although perched upon a high pedestal and surrounded by
            Corinthian columns.
         </p>
         
         <p>The boxes and gallery are what is called "elegant" rather than
            gaudy--but a little more of the gaudiness would be better taste, and infinitely more to the purpose. The panneling lacks color--as it now stands it has rather a Quakerish air--and this evil is increased by the hue of the plaster on
            the walls. If these latter were showily papered, the increase of
            effect would surprise every one. We think, too, that, in so large a theatre, a little more light upon the audience would be desirable. Unquestionably there
            should be two additional rows of chandeliers--one on the lower boxes, and one on
            the gallery.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>The theatre has been crowded every night since its opening. The
            performances have been "Money," "Nick of the Woods," "Richelieu," "Damon and Pythias"
            and "The Sleeping Beauty." The latter piece has been brought out very
            effectively, and elicited great applause. Among the company are J.
            R. Scott, Henkins, Hadaway, Davenport, Mrs. Philips, Mrs. Sergeant, Mrs. Isherwood,
            &amp;c., &amp;c.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Park has been doing well with the French troupe, for a detailed account of "Les
            Huguenots" see another part of the paper.
         </p>
         
         <p>At Niblo's, Burton, the Placides, Chippendale, John Sefton, Brougham,
            Miss Taylor and other celebrities have been "drawing crowded houses."
         </p>
         
         <p>Castle Garden has been a little depressed, but is reviving.</p>
         
         <p>At Palmo's a German company have made a successful commencement. On the 8th inst.
            the house was opened for the benefit of Mess. Stuyvesant and Harris, when Mr. and
            Mrs. Flynn, with Winans, appeared. Mrs. Flynn (who is a capital actress not
            sufficiently appreciated) evinced great talent and a very rare versatility in
            "Perfection," "The Four Sisters," and "The Loan of a Lover."
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Flynn's theatre, we learn, is making rapid progress.</p>
         
         <p>Mr. Champlin is erecting a House in the East Bowery.</p>
         
         <p>In England--Charles Mathews and his wife have seceded from the Haymarket; Mr. Webster
            the manager, states in "direct violation of their engagement."
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Editorial Miscellany</div>
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p31">
            <div class="biblTitle">Misrepresentation</div>
            <div class="biblPage">93</div>
            
            <p>Misrepresentation is not only one of the commonest but one of the most despicable tricks resorted to, for its own purposes, by the more depraved portion
               of the press. From this more depraved portion we look for it--all honest men look
               for it as a matter of course--and, when here observed, it is seldom by any one,
               and never by us, considered as meriting or requiring reply. "The Evening Gazette,"
               then, will give us credit for very sincerely respecting it, (or at least the personal character of its editors) since we put ourselves to the
               trouble of taking it to task for some words of sheer misrepresentation which appeared in one of its late numbers, under the heading of "The Knickerbocker and The American Review." In alluding to an article, by
               ourselves, contained in the latter Magazine, the Gazette says, in substance: "Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">Poe</span>, however, is one of those who can never find anything to admire in
               anything written by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>."
            </p>
            
            <p>Now this is doing us the grossest injustice--and this no one better knows than the inditer of the accusation. For every one paragraph written by any one
               person in America, commending Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>, we can point to ten similar
               paragraphs of our own. From Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">L.</span>'s first appearance in the literary world
               until the present moment, we have been, if not his warmest admirer and most
               steadfast defender, at least one of his warmest and most steadfast. We even so
               far committed ourselves in a late public Lecture, as to place him (without
               sufficient consideration) at the very head of American poets. Yet, because we are
               not so childish as to suppose that every book is thoroughly good or thoroughly
               bad--because we are not so absurd as to adopt the common practice of wholesale and indiscriminate abuse or commendation--because upon several occasions we have thought proper to demonstrate the sins, while
               displaying the virtues of Professor 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>, is it just, or proper, or even
               courteous on the part of "The Gazette" to accuse us, in round terms, of
               uncompromising hostility to this poet?
            </p>
            
            
            <p>We make use of the word "demonstrate"--for it has always been a point
               with us to sustain as far as possible, by evidence or argument, whatever
               propositions we put forth. But has "The Gazette," in the present instance, been
               equally careful? Do we understand it as inclined to dispute the accuracy of any statement, or the validity of any deduction, embodied
               in the critique to which it has referred? If so, we are prepared to try the case
               upon its merits. If, however, it is the simple opinion of "The Gazette" which is thus pitted against our own--we are by far too modest to say another word upon the subject--and must submit to the stern necessity of letting the whole matter remain precisely where it is.
            </p>
            
            <p>For the frank admission that our criticism is "worth reading" we very
               cordially return thanks--but we have been considering whether any temptation (short of a copy of "Isabel") could induce us to make any similar acknowledgement in regard to any criticisms of "The Evening
               Gazette."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p32">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Very Just Observations</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>The very just observations which follow are from the pen of one of the most
               distinguished of American novelists-- 
               <span class="person" id="wgsimms">William Gilmore Simms</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>The original "Library" of Wiley and Putnam was meant to be composed of European
               writings chiefly. As an offset and parallel scheme to this, the same publishers
               have conceived the idea of an American collection on a similar plan. It is for the
               American public to determine, whether this latter, and highly patriotic purpose,
               shall receive their countenance. The American series necessarily labors under
               a disadvantage to which the English is not subject. The works constituting the latter collection, are, not only obtained by the pub-lishers for nothing, but they are at liberty to choose the very best pro-ductions
               of the London market and the quality and character of these works are indicated, to
               their hands, by the imprimatur of the foreign, and, if need be, the domestic
               critic. In procuring the works of the American series, the case is very different. In the first place, the native author requires pay for his
               writings.--As he has no English public among which to secure his copyright, the home
               market is required to do for him all that it can, by way of giving him compensation
               for his labor. This is a charge on the pocket and patriotism of the publisher;
               and, when it is remembered that he can procure from the British press, a
               hundred times as many books as he has capital to print, all saleable, and many good,--some credit is certainly due to him for this disinterested and
               generous proceeding in behalf of native literature; and we may reasonably hope that
               the public will not suffer its patriotism to be outdone by that of its publisher.
               He risks his thousands, where, if seconded by the public, each citizen will expend
               a trifle only. Nor is it in the cost of copyright merely, that the difference
               exists between the English and American copy. In the former, he prints from a clear
               type, in the latter from an imperfect manuscript;--in the former, he prints
               from a book that has already obtained the European verdict of English criticism; in
               the latter, he has this criticism to encounter, and may be purchasing and
               publishing an inferior production, when his earnest wish is for the very best. This
               statement beiefly displays the several difficulties under which the business of the domestic publisher labors; and, in his case, as in that of the author,
               demands all the indulgence that the patriotism of the citizen, solicitous of the establishment of a native literature, should be ready to accord. Influenced necessarily by these considerations, and by reasonable apprehensions of loss, the publisher hesitates to pay largely for any
               native manuscript. Suppose a work offered him by an author, hitherto unknown, but one of the most unquestionable excellence and originality,
               he has been engaged upon this work, without intermission. He has elaborated it
               with care. The labor limae has not been withheld; and when he conceives it perfect
               he presents it to the publisher, from whom he demands one thousand dollars for the
               copyright. This sum, stated as the charge for one year of clerk hire, would not
               perhaps be considered extravagant in the instance of a clerk of first rate ability;
               yet such a charge for a book, the preparation of which consumed all that time, would stagger the liberality even of the most patriotic publisher,
               particularly in the case of an experiment, undertaken purely for love of country,
               and with funds that might otherwise be invested with equal safety and much greater
               profit in English publications. This is a simple statement of the case to
               which we solicit the attention of the citizen. We trust that there will be a class
               of the American people, sufficiently large, who will propose it to themselves, as a
               duty which they owe the country, to second the attempt of these publishers, in behalf of a native literature, by buying regularly the volumes of this series, as they severally make their appearance. They may sometimes
               buy an inferior book, but we guarantee that they will never get a bad one. The works generally may be of less value than the picked publications of
               the British series, but they will be native, they will possess a character of their
               own, and they may be at the foundation of future publications which shall vie with
               the best of foreign origin. Thus far the issue of the "Library of American Books,"
               will scarcely shrink from comparison with the other. The letters of 
               <span class="person" id="jtheadley">Headley</span> from
               Italy, form a fresh and delightful volume, worthy of the same shelves with
               "Eothen" and "The Crescent and the Cross." The "Journal of an African
               Cruiser," and the Tales of 
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">Edgar A. Poe</span>, forming the second and third works in this
               series, shall receive our notice hereafter. We rejoice to learn that these publications find a ready sale and circulation, and sincerely trust that the praiseworthy scheme of the publishrs will be sustained by the
               people.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p33">
            <div class="biblTitle">Samuel Colman</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="scolman">Samuel Colman</span>, of Boston, has in preparation a Selection from the works of
               American Poets. The book, we believe, is to be somewhat on the plan of 
               <span class="person" id="skettell">Kettel</span>'s
               "Specimens."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p34">
            <div class="biblTitle">The King of Prussia</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>The King of Prussia has again tendered the well-known Lieber a desirable
               Professorship at Berlin.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p35">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Medici Series of Italian Prose</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>In our notice, last week, of "The Medici Series of Italian Prose" we
               spoke, inadvertently, thus:--"The present enterprise extends, we believe, no farther
               than to the Italian Romance." Here we were mistaken. The design is far more
               comprehensive. It will include many historical and other works of value.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p36">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Southern Literary Messenger Published in Georgia</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>We find it stated, that "The Southern Literary Messenger" published
               in Morgan county, Georgia, bears aloft the flag:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">For President in 1848, 
               <br></br>Henry Clay."
            </div>
            
            <p>Is there such a paper as "The Southern Literary Messenger" published in Georgia? If so, is not the title a shameful spoliation?</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p37">
            <div class="biblTitle">Revival of the American Poetical World</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>There is quite a revival in the American poetical world. Besides the collection of
               Specimens of which we have already spoken, we shall have in the fall, from Clark
               and Austen, a volume by Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="fsosgood">Osgood</span>, one by 
               <span class="person" id="abstreet">Alfred B. Street</span>, and one by 
               <span class="person" id="httuckerman">H. T.
                  Tuckerman
               </span>--from J. S. Redfield a volume by Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="eosmith">Seba Smith</span>--and from
               some other publisher a volume by 
               <span class="person" id="rwemerson">Emerson</span>. One or two other collections
               are in posse--by poets whose names we have no authority to mention.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p38">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Tribune</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>The Tribune says:</p>
            
            <p>We learn from a private letter that Miss Martineau is building a cottage at
               Faxhow, a mile from 
               <span class="person" id="wwordsworth">Wordsworth</span>'s residence. Our Bryant was about visiting her.
               
               <span class="person" id="wwordsworth">Wordsworth</span>, hearing of 
               <span class="person" id="wcbryant">Bryant</span>'s arrival, welcomed him to his home with great
               hospitality. 
               <span class="person" id="wwordsworth">Wordsworth</span>, though 76 years old, is hale and vigorous. Miss Martineau
               continues perfectly well, and is extending the benefit of Magnetic treatment to
               other sufferers.
            </p>
            
            <p>We refer our readers to the "London Lancet" (for June we believe) for a very
               interesting expose of the circumstances attending Miss Martineau's Magnetics. We
               have firm faith in Mesmerism--but not in all that Miss Martineau dreams of
               it.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p39">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Albany Evening Journal</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>The "Albany Evening Journal" states on the faith of a private letter from Dublin,
               that Henry Russell the vocalist, is there passing himself oft as an American. Why
               not? The Americans should feel flattered--and no doubt they do.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p40">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Aristidean</div>
            <div class="biblPage">94</div>
            
            <p>"The Aristidean," suspended for a brief period for political reasons, will be immediately resumed--under the conduct, of course, of its
               spirited editor, 
               <span class="person" id="tdenglish">Thomas Dunn English</span>.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p41">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mrs. Sigourney</div>
            <div class="biblPage">95</div>
            
            <p>Mrs. Sigourney, we regret to learn, is still seriously ill at Hartford.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p42">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mr. T. S. Arthur</div>
            <div class="biblPage">95</div>
            
            <p>We announced in our last, that Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="tsarthur">T. S. Arthur</span> was preparing an Annual to be
               published by E. Ferret &amp; Co.--but were not then informed of its title. It is to
               be called "The Snow-Flake and Gift for Innocence and Beauty."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p43">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mr. Lowell's "Conversations"</div>
            <div class="biblPage">95</div>
            
            <p>The proof-reader of the August number of Godey has made us say of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span>'s
               "Conversations" what indeed we should be very sorry to say, viz:
            </p>
            
            <p>The farce of this big book is equalled only by the farce of the ragtag-and-bobtail embassy from the whole earth, introduced by the crazy Prussian into the Hall of the French National Assembly. The author is the Anacharsis Clootz of American Letters.</p>
            
            <p>By the omission of a dash, this paragraph was made part and parcel of our
               commentary on Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span>--to whom it had no reference whatever.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p44">
            <div class="biblTitle">To Correspondents</div>
            <div class="biblPage">95</div>
            
            <p>To Correspondents.--Mr. Thomas W. Field will find a letter for him at the office of
               the "Broadway Journal."
            </p>
            
            <p>Many thanks to X or *. She shall speak in our next. "A New York Ghost" shall
               appear.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are forced to decline "Margarette"; "Cave Sirenis"; "Isabel, a Love-Lay''; and
               a
               "Song to Caroline."
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p45">
            <div class="biblTitle">Our First Volume</div>
            <div class="biblPage">95</div>
            
            <p>Our First Volume.--A few copies of the first volume of the Broadway Journal are for
               sale at the office, either in numbers or handsomely bound.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p46">
         <div class="biblTitle">A Rare Opportunity</div>
         <div class="biblPage">95</div>
         <div class="head">A RARE OPPORTUNITY.</div>
         
         <p>ANY gentleman of enterprise and respectable educa-tion, who has at
            command a cash capital of 700 or 1000 dollars, may hear of an excellent opportunity for its investment, by addressing a note to E. .S T. G., office of the
            "Broadway Journal."
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">95</div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">MUSIC.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">A Rare Opportunity of Acquiring a Thorough Musical Education.</div>
            
            <p>G.H. DERWORT, Professor of Singing, Guitar and Piano Forte, has opened a class for
               Young Ladies, from 7 to 10 years of age, among whom are three of his own daughters,
               whom he proposes to thoroughly instruct in the art of Singing.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Derwort's system is the result of many years' observation and experience, during which he has successfully taught in Germany, London, and New
               York. His method cannot fail to impart to his pupils a clear perception, and a
               thorough knowledge of the grammatical principles of music, with the ability to
               harmonize any simple given melody.
            </p>
            
            <p>Parents and Guardians are invited to call at his Rooms, 427 Broadway,
               when every inquiry will be answered.
            </p>
            
            <p>Terms $20 per annum, payable quarterly in advance. Lessons three times a week.</p>
            
            <p>Private instruction as heretofore.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THIS DAY IS PUBLISHED,</div>
            
            <p>VERSE AND PROSE, by 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Thomas Hood</span>--Part 1, forming No. 16 of the Library of Choice
               Reading, beautifully printed. Price 50 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Of all the humorists, 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Hood</span> was the most poetical. When dealing with the most familiar subjects, whether it might be a sweep bewailing the
               suppression of his cry, or a mother searching through St. Giles's for her lost
               infant, or a Miss Kilmansegg's golden childhood-- there was hardly a verse in which
               some touches of heart, or some play of fancy, did not beckon the laughing reader
               away into far other worlds than the jester's."--London Athenaeum.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The smile and the sigh were ever blended together; the laugh at the grotesque
               idea and whimsical imagination, (rarely seeing objects as others saw them,) and the
               tear which must now on such pathetic narratives as Eugene Aram or the Old Elm Tree.
               Without a parallel and original as 
               <span class="person" id="thood">Hood</span> was in the ludicrous, his more enduring
               fame will rest on the exquisitely humane and simply compassionate."--Literary Gazette.
            </p>
            
            <p>"He was the inventer of a new sort of guano to fertilize men's minds, and to make them produce larger crops of good actions: or rather it was an
               intellectual compost that he invented, and the materials of which were satire
               softened by kindness, and ridicule tempered with good feeling."--Hood's Magazine for
               June. Published and for sale by
            </p>	
            
            <div class="ab">WlLEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">HARPER &amp; BROTHERS' LAST PUBLICATIONS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">1. 
               <br></br>HARPER'S ILLUMINATED BIBLE. No. 34. 
               <br></br>Price Twenty-Five Cents,
            </div>
            
            <p>Comprising portions of the minor prophets to the 9th chapter of Amos. The embellishments to this number include some of unsurpassed beau-ty.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">II. 
               <br></br>HARPER'S ILLUMINATED SHAKSPEARE, 
               <br></br>Nos. 61 and 62. Price Twenty-Five
               Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes "Measure for Measure" and the commencement of the "Tempest"--with the eqquisite designs after Kenny Meadows, Weir,
               and others. It should be recollected that this edition of 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> combines the best features of the two best London editions, by 
               <span class="person" id="cknight">Charles Knight</span> and
               Tyas--rendering it the most perfect ever presented to the public.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">III. 
               <br></br>TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO,
            </div>
            
            <p>Newly collected from valuable MSS. in the Geographical Societies of France and Italy, with copious notes and illustrations by Hugh Murray, with Maps,
               &amp;c. 16mo. muslin. Price 50 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>This well-known production, which forms No. 173 of "The Family Library," has long
               been regarded as unique in geographical science. Marco Polo has justly been styled
               the "Herodotus of the Middle Ages." and the discoverer of the Asiatic continent;
               his explorations in the Chinese empire alone have never been exceeded, even to the
               present day.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IV. 
               <br></br>THE SEERESS OF PREVORST. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>"A work replete with startling new facts on Mesmerism: the most remarkable on the
               subject we have yet seen."--Post.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">V. 
               <br></br>JOHN RONGE AND THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES. 
               <br></br>Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>"A subject of the most absorbing interest throughout the whole whole European
               Continent."
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VI. 
               <br></br>DR. LEVER'S LATEST WORK--THE NEVILLES OF 
               <br></br>GARRETSTOWN. Complete, price 12
               1-2 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>"Equal to the best works of the favourite author of Charles O'Malley."</p>
            
            <div class="ab">VII. 
               <br></br>JAMES'S NEW WORK--THE SMUGGLER. 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new production of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="gprjames">James</span> is founded on on some stirring incidents of past times on the Southern Coast of England; it is characterised by all the author's peculiarities of style, the story being intersected by many
               episodical involutions, which impart to it additional interest.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VIII. 
               <br></br>DE ROHAN. BY 
               <span class="person" id="esue">EUGENE SUE</span>. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>"Picturesque, bold, and highly dramatic--equal to any of his previous
               works."--Sun.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IX. 
               <br></br>PRAISE AND PRINCIPLE--Or, For What shall I Live?
            </div>
            
            <p>By the author of "Conquest and Self-Conquest,' "Woman an Enigma,"
               &amp;c. 18mo. cloth gilt. Price 48 1-2 Cents. A charming volume, elegantly written,
               well sustained in its interest, and rife with excellent moral leaching.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">X. 
               <br></br>CYCLOPEDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY. No. 8. Pr. 26 Cts.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">XI. 
               <br></br>MISS 
               <span class="person" id="fbremer">BREMER</span>'S NEW WORK--THE PARSONAGE OF MO- 
               <br></br>-RA, OR LIFE IN
               DALECARLIA. Price One Shilling.
            </div>
            
            <p>In this new work 
               <span class="person" id="fbremer">Frederika Bremer</span> presents many of her pretty and picturesque scenes, add introduces many of her high minded and romantic
               characters, with their spirit stirring colloquies; the story also includes
               interesting sketches of those Northern subterranean worlds-- the copper mines of
               Fahlua.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XII. 
               <br></br>EVELINA, by Miss 
               <span class="person" id="fburney">Burney</span> (since 
               <span class="person" id="fburney">Madame D'Arblay</span>). New 
               <br></br>edition, 18mo.
               Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This renowned production has long been considered as a classic of our language.
               The work appeared anonymously, the disclosure of the authorship of which, it will be remembered, led to the deeply interesting scene which ensued
               between the father and daughter--their mingled surprise and delight.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XIII. 
               <br></br>DR. 
               <span class="person" id="jcopland">COPLAND</span>'S MEDICAL DICTIONARY. No. 10. 60 Cts.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes a series of topics of vital interest to the Medical faculty of the country. The design and execution of this popular production, evince the most censummate skill and research; every
               person who desires a thorough digest of Medical Science, must ap preciate its high value.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XV. 
               <br></br>PROF. 
               <span class="person" id="tlewis">LEWIS</span>'S PLATO ON ATHEISTS. Price $1 50.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
            
            <p>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANOFORTE, ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed
               to No. 22 Bank street, where his terms for giving instruction can be ascertained.
               my17
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER.</div>
            <p>--JAMES PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near Elm.
               A Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms moderate. FOR SALE--A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a great bargain for
               cash.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">--V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal 
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron Frames, &amp;c.,
               with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials, and highly
               finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in
               the busines
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ.</p>
            
            <p>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>--JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy &amp; Pelhick,) invites the attention of the musical public to the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, corner of
               Cottage Place and Bleecker street, which he will sell at prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business tor the last twenty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two of the
               largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that his instruments
               will bear a favorable comparison with those of the best makers in this country or
               Europe, and that they contain all the real improvements of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and Repaired.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, April 23d, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>The Subscribers, while returning thanks to their
               numerous friends and to the public, would, at the same time call attention to their
               Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood
               and mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department of the business,
               have been enabled to add several important improvements to the action, so that
               their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, upon examination, equal to any in
               the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway. 
               <br></br>Manufactory, 13th St., between 3d and 4th
               Avenues.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>--THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart),
               No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the latest approved Grand
               Action Piano Fortes, of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
               guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, and to
               endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes
               Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <p>PHILIP ERSNT, Teacher of the Flute and Guitar, would inform the
               lovers of Music that he has now for sale several of the above celebrated instruments, constructed in every respect in accordance with those now
               in use at the Paris and London Royal Academies. To be seen at PHILIP ERNST'S Music
               Saloon, 395 Broadway, near Walker.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JUST PUBLISHED.</div>
            <div class="ab">By Paine &amp; Burgers, 62 John St., 
               <br></br>No. 1 of the Medici
               series of Italian Prose.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE CHALLENGE OF BARLETTA, AN HIStorical Romance of the Times of the
               Medici, by 
               <span class="person" id="mdazeglio">Azeglio</span>. Translated by 
               <span class="person" id="celester">C. Edwards Lester</span>, U. S. Consul at
               Genoa. Author of "The Glory and Shame of England," &amp;c. &amp;c. This work is
               founded on the most thrilling aud romantic incidents in the chivalric history of
               Italy. Chevalier Bayaul, the mirror of chivalry, Ca'sar Borgia, the Colloni,
               Gonsalvo of Cordova, &amp;c., are the principal characters. Price 50
               cents.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IN PRESS.</div>
            
            <p>2 and 3, The Florentine Histories, by 
               <span class="person" id="nmachiavelli">Machiavelli</span>. 2 vols.
            </p>
            
            <p>4. The Citizen of a Republic.</p>
            
            <p>6. The Autobiography of Alfieri.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">IN PREPARATION.</div>
            
            <p>The Artist, The Merchant and The Statesman. 2 vols. By 
               <span class="person" id="celester">C. Edwards Lester</span>.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published monthly, at Richmond. Fa. Price Five Dollars per year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835, has a large subscription list, and
               is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by 
               <span class="person" id="jbisco">John Bisco</span>, at the office of the "Broadway
               Journal," 135 Nassau streeet.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. B. CAREY &amp;. CO., ARTISTS,</div>
            
            <p>MANUFACTURERS OF ORNAMENTAL SHOW CARDS adapted for Utility, as well Adornment, for
               stores in all kinds of business. Specimens may be seen in the leading stores of the
               principal cities of the Union.
            </p>
            
            <p>Agents for Boston: Messrs. Sowle &amp; Shaw. Mr. J. L. Lazarus is now visiting the
               Eastern States, all orders received by him will meet with prompt attention. 34
               Beekman-Street, (late 323 Broadway.)
            </p>
            
            <p>Observe! Our names are printed at the foot of each card, and we caution the public
               that
               imitators are in the field. Jy 26
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE. THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE YEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.</div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div> 
            
            <div class="ab"> No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH'S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing,
               guaranteed to all (old and young) in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Stationery. Payable
               at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours--9 A. M.. 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M., daily, for gentlemen, and from 11 to 1
               o'clock, for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale "Goldsmith's Gems of Penmanship," elegantly bound. Price Five
               Dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A. G. BAGLEY'S CELEBRATED IMPROVED EVER-POINTED GOLD PEN.</div>
            
            <p>THIS PEN RECEIVED THE HIGHEST PREmium at the last Fair of the American Institute, and has been pronounced by the First Teachers of
               Penmanship in the country, to be infinitely superior to any Gold Pen ever before introduced to the American public. The lasting properties of this Pen
               are undoubted, owing to the total absence of corrosibility from any of the inks in
               use; and the peculiar shape of the nibs--which was first introduced by Bagley--
               makes it more pleasant to use, renders it less liable to damage, more easy to
               repair, and prevents the necessity of the great care that other articles of the
               kind require.
            </p>
            
            <p>MANUFACTORY, 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">BERTINI</span>'S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method, the most rapid
               advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies are given in such
               progressive order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and carry them almost
               imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often
               made irksome in other instruction books. The time has arrived when a
               superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is only by the
               study of such methods as 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s that pupils will be enabled to read
               music with facility, and at the same time become good musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the rudiments of music
               being given and illustrated at the same lime, and each lesson is fully explained by
               marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations from professional
               gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s Method over all others yet
               published in this country, most of them hiving used the foreign copies previously.
               It will only bo necessary to give a few of the names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Boston. New-York. 
               <br></br>Messr. G. J. Webb, Messrs. H. C Timm, 
               <br></br>J.G. Maeder, W.
               Alpers, 
               <br></br>H.T. Haeh U. C. Hill, 
               <br></br>E. L. White, F. H. Brown, 
               <br></br>David Paine,
               Philadelphia. 
               <br></br>A. Kurek, B.C. Cross, 
               <br></br>T. B. Moses. Joseph Duggan. 
               <br></br>Albany--O.
               J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work. American
               edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p47">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">96</div>
         <div class="note" type="headnote">James C. Blake, Esq., having taken a permanent interest in the publication of the Broadway Journal, will proceed on a tour through the Union, for the purpose of establishing agencies and otherwise promoting the general
            interests of the paper.
         </div>
         
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass. | Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia. 
            <br></br>R. G. H.
            Huntington, Hartford, Ct. | Thos. H. Pease, New-Haven, Ct. 
            <br></br>M. Baullemet, Mobile,
            Ala. | J. C. Morgan, New-Orleans. 
            <br></br>Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O. | W.W.
            Kingsley, New-London, Ct. 
            <br></br>D.M. Dewey, Rochester, N Y. | G. N. Beesley, Utica, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y. | H. B. Strang, Peekskill, N. Y. 
            <br></br>W. E. Russell,
            Schedectady, N. Y. | Haliburton &amp; Dudley, Boston, Mass. 
            <br></br>Levi Willard, Troy, N.
            Y. | S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass. 
            <br></br>G. Jones, Albany, N. Y. | Peter Cooke, Hartford,
            Ct. 
            <br></br>S. F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y. | H. Esten, Providence, R. I. 
            <br></br>Shurtz &amp;
            Wilde, Baltimore, Md. | Safford &amp; Park, Norwich, Ct.
         </div>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>