<div>
   <div class="front">
          
        </div>
   <div class="body">
              <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
VOL. 2.	EDGAR A. POE,
editor and proprietor,	NO. 20.
NEW-YORK, SATURDAY, NOVEMBER 22, 1845.
Sister Mine.
Sister mine—Sister mine!
Why art so dear?
Why throbs this heart of mine,
</p>
         <p>Like the strong-tendrilled vine,
<br/>Clinging so close to thine
<br/>When thou art near,</p>
         <p>Sister mine?
Sister mine—Sister mine!
Why art so dear?
Chill is this heart of mine,
Till that sweet smile of thine
Wakes it to life divine,
When thou art near,
Sister mine.
</p>
         <p>Sister mine—Sister mine I
<br/>Why art so dear?
<br/>Light is this heart of mine,</p>
         <p>As is the sparkling wine
Bright in its crimson-shine,
When thou art near,
Sister mine.
Sister mine—Sister mine!
Thou art so dear
By that wierd spell of thine,
</p>
         <p>Wreathed round this heart of mine
<br/>Till our twin spirits twine
<br/>When thou art near,</p>
         <p>Sister mine !	R. H. DANA
The Spectacles.
</p>
         <p>Many years ago, it was the fashion to ridicule the
<br/>idea of “ love at first sight;" but those who think, not
<br/>less than those who feel deeply, have always advocated
<br/>its existence. Modern discoveries, indeed, in what may
<br/>be termed ethical magnetism or magnetœsthetics, render
<br/>it probable that the most natural, and, consequently the
<br/>truest and most intense of the human affections, are
<br/>those which arise in the heart as if by electric sympathy
<br/>—in a word, that the brightest and most enduring of the
<br/>psychal fetters are those which are riveted by a glance.
<br/>The confession I am about to make will add another to
<br/>the already almost innumerable instances of the truth of
<br/>the position.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>My story requires that I should be somewhat minute.
<br/>I am still a very young man—not yet twenty-two years
<br/>of age. My name, at present, is a very usual and rather
<br/>plebeian one—Simpson. I say “at present;" for it is
<br/>only lately that I have been so called—having legisla-
<br/>tively adopted this surname within the last year, in order
<br/>to receive a large inheritance left me by a distant male
<br/>relative, Adolphus Simpson, Esq. The bequest was con-
<br/>ditioned upon my taking the name of the testator;—the</p>
         <p/>
         <p>family, not the Christian name ; my Christian name is
<br/>Napoleon Buonaparte—or, more properly, these are my
<br/>first and middle appellations.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I assumed the name, Simpson, with some reluctance,
<br/>as in my true patronym, Froissart, I felt a very pardon-
<br/>able pride; beleiving that I could trace a descent from
<br/>the immortal author of the “ Chronicles.” While on
<br/>the subject of names, by the bye, I may mention a singu-
<br/>lar coincidence of sound attending the names of some of
<br/>my immediate predecessors. My father was a Monsieur
<br/>Froissart, of Paris. His wife, my mother, whom he mar-
<br/>ried at fifteen, was a Mademoiselle Croissart, eldest
<br/>daughter of Croissart the banker ; whose wife, again,
<br/>being only sixteen when married, was the eldest daughter
<br/>of one Victor Voissart. Monsieur Voissart, very singu-
<br/>larly, had married a lady of similar name—a Mademoi-
<br/>selle Moissart. She, too, was quite a child when mar-
<br/>ried ; and her mother, also, Madame Moissart, was only
<br/>fourteen when led to the altar. These early marriages
<br/>are usual in France. Here, however, are Moissart, Vois-
<br/>sart, Croissart, and Froissart, all in the direct line of des-
<br/>cent. My own name, though, as I say, became Simpson,
<br/>by act of Legislature, and with so much repugnance on
<br/>my part that, at one period, I actually hesitated about
<br/>accepting the legacy with the useless and annoying pro-
<br/>viso attached.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>As to personal endowments I am by no means deficient.
<br/>On the contrary, I believe that I am well made, and pos-
<br/>sess what nine tenths of the world would call a handsome
<br/>face. In height I am five feet eleven. My hair is black
<br/>and curling. My nose is sufficiently good. My eyes are
<br/>large and gray ; and although, in fact, they are weak to
<br/>a very inconvenient degree, still no defect in this regard
<br/>would be suspected from their appearance. The weak-
<br/>ness, itself, however, has always much annoyed me, and
<br/>I have resorted to every remedy—short of wearing
<br/>glasses. Being youthful and good-looking, I naturally
<br/>dislike these, and have resolutely refused to employ them.
<br/>I know nothing, indeed, which so disfigures the counte-
<br/>nance of a young person, or so impresses every feature
<br/>with an air of demureness, if not altogether of sancti-
<br/>moniousness and of age. An eye-glass, on the other
<br/>hand, has a savor of downright foppery and affectation.
<br/>I have hitherto managed as well as I could without
<br/>either. But something too much of these merely person-
<br/>al details, which, after all, are of little importance. I
<br/>will content myself with saying, in addition, that my
<br/>temperament is sanguine, rash, ardent, enthusiastic—and
<br/>that all my life I have been a devoted admirer of the
<br/>women.</p>
         <p>One night, last winter, I entered a box at the P——
</p>
         <p>theatre, in company with a friend, Mr. Talbot. It was
<br/>an opera night, and the bills presented a very rare at-
<br/>traction, so that the house was excessively crowded.
<br/>We were in time, however, to obtain the front seats</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p300"/>
which had been reserved for us, and into which, with
some little difficulty, we elbowed our way.
</p>
         <p>For two hours, my companion, who was a musical
<br/>fanatico, gave his undivided attention to the stage ; and,
<br/>in the meantime, I amused myself by observing the au-
<br/>dience, which consisted, in chief part, of the very élite of
<br/>the city. Having satisfied myself upon this point, I was
<br/>about turning my eyes to the prima donna, when they
<br/>were arrested and riveted by a figure in one of the pri-
<br/>vate boxes which had escaped my observation.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>If I live a thousand years, I can never forget the in-
<br/>tense emotion with which I regarded this figure. It
<br/>was that of a female, the most exquisite I had ever be-
<br/>held. The face was so far turned towards the stage that,
<br/>for some minutes, I could not obtain a view of it but
<br/>the form was divine—no other word can sufficiently ex-
<br/>press its magnificent proportion, and even the term “di-
<br/>vine” seems ridiculously feeble as I write it.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The magic of a lovely form in woman—the necroman-
<br/>cy of female gracefulness—was always a power which
<br/>I had found it impossible to resist; but here was grace per-
<br/>sonified, incarnate, the beau ideal of my wildest and most
<br/>enthusiastic visions. The figure, almost all of which the
<br/>construction of the box permitted to be seen, was some-
<br/>what above the medium height, and nearly approached,
<br/>without positively reaching, the majestic. Its perfect
<br/>fulness and tournure were delicious. The head, of
<br/>which only the back was visible, rivalled in outline that
<br/>of the Greek Psyche, and was rather displayed than con-
<br/>cealed by an elegant cap of gaze äerienne, which put me
<br/>in mind of the ventum textilem of Apuleius. The right
<br/>arm hung over the balustrade of the box, and thrilled
<br/>every nerve of my frame with its exquisite symmetry.
<br/>Its upper portion was draperied by one of the loose open
<br/>sleeves now in fashion. This extended but little below
<br/>the elbow. Beneath it was worn an under one of some
<br/>frail material, close-fitting, and terminated by a cuff of
<br/>rich lace which fell gracefully over the top of the hand,
<br/>revealing only the delicate lingers, upon one of which
<br/>sparkled a diamond ring which I at once saw was of ex-
<br/>traordinary value. The admirable roundness of the wrist
<br/>was well set off by a bracelet which encircled it, and
<br/>which also was ornamented and clasped by a magnificent
<br/>aigrette of jewels—telling, in words that could not be
<br/>mistaken, at once of the wealth and fastidious taste of the
<br/>wearer.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I gazed at this queenly apparition for at least half an
<br/>hour, as if I had been suddenly converted to stone; and,
<br/>during this period, I felt the full force and truth of all
<br/>that has been said or sung concerning “love at first
<br/>sight.” My feelings were totally different from any
<br/>which I had hitherto experienced, in the presence of even
<br/>the most celebrated specimens of female loveliness. An
<br/>unaccountable, and what I am compelled to consider a
<br/>magnetic sympathy of soul for soul, seemed to rivet, not
<br/>only my vision, but my whole powers of thought and
<br/>feeling upon the admirable object before me. I saw—I
<br/>felt—I knew that I was deeply, madly, irrevocably in
<br/>love—and this even before seeing the face of the person
<br/>beloved. So intense, indeed, was the passion that con-
<br/>sumed me, that I really believe it would have received
<br/>little if any abatement had the features, yet unseen,
<br/>proved of merely ordinary character; so anomalous is
<br/>the nature of the only true love—of the love at first sight
<br/>—and so little really dependent is it upon the external
<br/>conditions which only seem to create and control it.</p>
         <p>While I was thus wrapped in admiration of this lovely
vision, a sudden disturbance among the audience caused
</p>
         <p>her to turn her head partially towards me, so that I be-
<br/>held the entire profile of the face. Its beauty even ex-
<br/>ceeded my anticipations—and yet there was something
<br/>about it which disappointed me without my being able
<br/>to tell exactly what it was. I said “disappointed,” but
<br/>this is not altogether the word. My sentiments were at
<br/>once quieted and exalted. They partook less of transport
<br/>and more of calm enthusiasm—of enthusiastic repose.
<br/>This state of feeling arose, perhaps, front the Madonna-
<br/>like and matronly air of the face ; and yet I at once un-
<br/>derstood that it could not have arisen entirely from this.
<br/>There was something else—some mystery which I could
<br/>not develope—some expression about the countenance
<br/>which slightly disturbed me while it greatly heightened
<br/>my interest. In fact, I was just in that condition of
<br/>mind which prepares a young and susceptible man for
<br/>any act of extravagance. Had the lady been alone, I
<br/>should undoubtedly have entered her box and accosted
<br/>her at all hazards; but, fortunately, she was attended by
<br/>two companions—a gentleman, and a strikingly beauti-
<br/>ful woman, to all appearance a few years younger than
<br/>herself.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I revolved in my mind a thousand schemes by which
<br/>I might obtain, hereafter, an introduction to the elder
<br/>lady, or, for the present, at all events, a more distinct
<br/>view of her beauty. I would have removed my position
<br/>to one nearer her own : but the crowded state of the
<br/>theatre rendered this impossible, and the stern decrees of
<br/>Fashion, had, of late, imperatively prohibited the use of
<br/>the opera-glass, in a case such as this, even had I been
<br/>so fortunate as to have one with me—but I had not, and
<br/>was thus in despair.</p>
         <p>At length I bethought me of applying to my compan-
ion.
“ Talbot,” I said, “ you have an opera-glass. Let me
have it.”
</p>
         <p>“An opera-glass! no! what do you suppose I would
<br/>be doing with an opera-glass ?" Here he turned im-
<br/>patiently towards the stage.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“But, Talbot,” I continued, pulling him by the shoul-
<br/>der, “ listen to me. will you ? Do you see the stage-box?
<br/>—there! no, the next—did you ever behold as lovely a
<br/>woman ?"</p>
         <p>“ She is very beautiful, no doubt,” he said.
"I wonder who she can be ?”
</p>
         <p>“Why, in the name of all that is angelic, don’t you
<br/>know who she is? 'Not to know her argues yourself
<br/>unknown.’ She is the celebrated Madame Lalande—the
<br/>beauty of the day par excellence, and the talk of the
<br/>whole town. Immensely wealthy, too—a widow and a
<br/>great match—has just arrived from Paris.”</p>
         <p>“ Do you know her ?”
“Yes: I have the honor.”
“ Will you introduce me ?”
“Assuredly; with the greatest pleasure; when shall
it be?”
“To-morrow, at one, I will call upon you at B——’s."
“ Very good: and now do hold your tongue, if you
can.”
</p>
         <p>In this latter respect I was forced to take Talbot's ad-
<br/>vice; for he remained obstinately deaf to every further
<br/>question or suggestion, and occupied himself exclusively
<br/>for the rest of the evening, with what was transacting
<br/>upon the stage.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In the mean time I kept my eyes riveted on Madame
<br/>Lalande, and at length had the good fortune to obtain a
<br/>full front view of her face. It was exquisitely lovely—
<br/>this, of course, my heart had told me before, even had</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p301"/>
         </p>
         <p>not Talbot fully satisfied me upon the point—but still the
<br/>unintelligible something disturbed me. I finally conclu-
<br/>ded that my senses were impressed by a certain air of
<br/>gravity, sadness, or still more properly, of weariness,
<br/>which took something from the youth and freshness of
<br/>the countenance, only to endow it with a seraphic tender-
<br/>ness and majesty, and thus, of course, to my enthusiastic
<br/>and romantic temperament, with an interest tenfold.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>While I thus feasted my eyes, I perceived, at last, to
<br/>my great trepidation, by an almost imperceptible start on
<br/>the part of the lady, that she had become suddenly aware
<br/>of the intensity of my gaze. Still, I was absolutely fas-
<br/>cinated, and could not withdraw it, even for an instant.
<br/>She turned aside her face, and again I saw only the chis-
<br/>selled contour of the back portion of the head. After
<br/>some minutes, as if urged by curiosity to see if I was
<br/>still looking, she gradually brought her face again around
<br/>and again encountered my burning gaze. Her large dark
<br/>eves fell instantly, and a deep blush mantled her cheek.
<br/>But what was my astonishment at perceiving that she not
<br/>only did not a second time avert her head, but that she ac-
<br/>tually took from her girdle a double eye-glass—elevated it
<br/>—adjusted it—and then regarded me through it, intently
<br/>and deliberately, for the space of several minutes.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Had a thunderbolt fallen at my feet I could not have
<br/>been more thoroughly astounded—astounded only—not
<br/>offended or disgusted in the slightest degree ; although
<br/>an action so bold in any other woman, would have been
<br/>likely to offend or disgust. But the whole thing was done
<br/>with so much quietude—so much nonchalance—so much
<br/>repose—with so evident an air of the highest breeding, in
<br/>short—that nothing of mere effrontery was perceptible,
<br/>and my sole sentiments were those of admiration and sur-
<br/>prise.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I observed that, upon her first elevation of the glass,
<br/>she had seemed satisfied with a momentary inspection of
<br/>my person, and was withdrawing the instrument, when,
<br/>as if struck by a second thought, she resumed it, and so
<br/>continued to regard me with fixed attention for the space
<br/>of several minutes--for five minutes, at the very least, I
<br/>am sure.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This action, so remarkable in an American theatre, at-
<br/>tracted very general observation, and gave rise to an in-
<br/>definite movement, or buzz, among the audience, which
<br/>lor a moment filled me with confusion, but produced no
<br/>visible effect upon the countenance of Madame Lalande.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Having satisfied her curiosity—if such it was she
<br/>dropped the glass, and quietly gave her attention again
<br/>to the stage ; her profile now being turned toward my-
<br/>self, as before. I continued to watch her unremittingly,
<br/>although I was fully conscious of my rudeness in so doing.
<br/>Presently I saw the head slowly and slightly change its
<br/>position ; and soon I became convinced that the lady,
<br/>while pretending to look at the stage was, in fact, atten-
<br/>tively regarding myself. It is needless to say what effect
<br/>this conduct, on the part of so fascinating a woman, had
<br/>upon my excitable mind.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Having thus scrutinized me for perhaps a quarter of an
<br/>hour, the fair object of my passion addressed the gentle-
<br/>man who attended her, and, while she spoke, I saw dis-
<br/>tinctly, by the glances of both, that the conversation had
<br/>reference to myself.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Upon its conclusion, Madame Lalande again turned to-
<br/>wards the stage, and, for a few minutes, seemed absorbed
<br/>in the performances. At the expiration of this period,
<br/>however, I was thrown into an extremity of agitation by-
<br/>seeing her unfold, for the second time, the eye-glass</p>
         <p/>
         <p>which hung at her side, fully confront me as before, and,
<br/>disregarding the renewed buzz of the audience, survey
<br/>me, from head to foot, with the same miraculous compo-
<br/>sure which had previously so delighted and confounded
<br/>my soul.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This extraordinary behaviour, by throwing me into a
<br/>perfect fever of excitement—into an absolute delirium
<br/>of love—served rather to embolden than disconcert me.
<br/>In the mad intensity of my devotion, I forgot everything
<br/>but the presence and the majestic loveliness of the vision
<br/>which confronted my gaze. Watching my opportunity,
<br/>when I thought the audience were fully engaged with
<br/>the opera, I at length caught the eyes of Madame La-
<br/>lande, and, upon the instant, made a slight but unmistake-
<br/>able bow.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>She blushed very deeply—then averted her eyes—then
<br/>slowly and cautiously looked around, apparently to see if
<br/>my rash action had been noticed—then leaned over to-
<br/>wards the gentleman who sat by her side.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I now felt a burning sense of the impropriety I had
<br/>committed, and expected nothing less than instant expo-
<br/>sure; while a vision of pistols upon the morrow floated
<br/>rapidly and uncomfortably through my brain. I was
<br/>greatly and immediately relieved, however, when I saw
<br/>the lady merely hand the gentleman a playbill, without
<br/>speaking ; but the reader may form some feeble concep-
<br/>tion of my astonishment—of my profound amazement—
<br/>my delirious bewilderment of heart and soul—when, in-
<br/>stantly afterwards, having again glanced furtively around,
<br/>she allowed her bright eyes to settle fully and steadily
<br/>upon my own, and then, with a faint smile, disclosing a
<br/>bright line of her pearly teeth, made two distinct, pointed
<br/>and unequivocal affirmative inclinations of the head.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>It is useless, of course, to dwell upon my joy—upon my
<br/>transport—upon my illimitable ecstasy of heart. If ever
<br/>man was mad with excess of happiness, it was myself at
<br/>that moment. I loved. This was my first love—so I felt
<br/>it to be. It was love supreme—indescribable. It was
<br/>“love at first sight;" and at first sight too, it had been
<br/>appreciated and—returned.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Yes, returned. How and why should I doubt it for an
<br/>instant ? What other construction could I possibly put
<br/>upon such conduct, on the part of a lady so beautiful—so
<br/>wealthy—evidently so accomplished—of so high breed-
<br/>ing—of so lofty a position in society—in every regard so
<br/>entirely respectable as I felt assured was Madame La-
<br/>lande ? Yes, she loved me—she returned the enthusiasm
<br/>of my love, with an enthusiasm as blind—as uncompro-
<br/>misins—as uncalculating—as abandoned—and as utterly
<br/>unbounded as my own ! These delicious fancies and in-
<br/>flections, however, were now interrupted by the falling of
<br/>the drop-curtain. The audience arose ; and the usual tu-
<br/>mult immediately supervened. Quitting Talbot abruptly,
<br/>I made every effort to force my way into closer proximity
<br/>with Madame Lalande. Having failed in this, on ac
<br/>count of the crowd, I at length gave up the chase, and
<br/>bent my steps homewards ; consoling myself for my dis-
<br/>appointment in not having been able to touch even the
<br/>hem of her robe, by the reflection that I should be intro-
<br/>duced by Talbot, in due form, upon the morrow.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This morrow at last came ; that is to say, a day finally
<br/>dawned upon a long and weary night of impatience ; and
<br/>then the hours until “ one” were snail-paced, dreary and
<br/>innumerable. But even Stamboul, it is said, shall have
<br/>an end, and there came an end to this long delay. The
<br/>clock struck. As the last echo ceased, I stepped into
<br/>B——'s and enquired for Talbot.</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p302"/>
“ Out,” said the footman—Talbot’s own.
</p>
         <p>“ Out!” I replied, staggering back half a dozen paces—
<br/>"let me tell you, my fine fellow, that this thing is tho-
<br/>roughly impossible and impracticable ; Mr. Talbot is not
<br/>out. What do you mean ?”</p>
         <p>“Nothing, sir ; only Mr. Talbot is not in. That’s all.
He rode over to S——, immediately after breakfast, and
left word that he would not be in town again for a week.”
</p>
         <p>I stood petrified with horror and rage. I endeavored
<br/>to reply, but my tongue refused its office. At length I
<br/>turned on my heel, livid with wrath, and inwardly con-
<br/>signing the whole tribe of the Talbots to the innermost
<br/>regions of Erebus. It was evident that my consider-
<br/>ate friend, il fanatico, had quite forgotten his appoint-
<br/>ment with myself—had forgotten it as soon as it was
<br/>made. At no time was he a very scrupulous man of his
<br/>word. There was no help for it; so smothering my vexa-
<br/>tion as well as I could, I strolled moodily up the street,
<br/>propounding futile inquiries about Madame Lalande to
<br/>every male acquaintance I met. By report she was known,
<br/>I found, to all—to many by sight—but she had been in
<br/>town only a few weeks, and there were very few, there-
<br/>fore, who claimed her personal acquaintance. These
<br/>few, being still comparatively strangers, could not, or
<br/>would not, lake the liberty of introducing me through the
<br/>formality of a morning call. While I stood thus, in des-
<br/>pair, conversing with a trio of friends upon the all absorb-
<br/>ing subject of my heart, it so happened that the subject
<br/>itself passed by.</p>
         <p>“ As I live, there she is!” cried one.
“Surpassingly beautiful!’’ exclaimed a second.
“ An angel upon earth !” ejaculated a third.
</p>
         <p>I looked ; and, in an open carriage which approached
<br/>us, passing slowly down the street, sat the enchanting
<br/>vision of the opera, accompanied by the younger lady
<br/>who had occupied a portion of her box.</p>
         <p>“ Her companion also wears remarkably well,” said the
one of my trio who had spoken first.
</p>
         <p>“Astonishingly,” said the second ; “still quite a bril-
<br/>liant air; but art will do wonders. Upon my word, she
<br/>looks better than she did at Paris five years ago. A beau-
<br/>tiful woman still;—don’t you think so, Froissart?—Simp-
<br/>son, I mean.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>"Still!” said I, “ and why shouldn’t she be ? But
<br/>compared with her friend she is as a rushlight to the
<br/>evening star—a glow-worm to Antares.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Ha! ha ! ha !—why, Simpson, you have an astonish-
<br/>ing tact at making discoveries—original ones, I mean.”
<br/>And here we separated, while one of the trio began hum-
<br/>ming a gay vaudeville, of which I caught only the lines—</p>
         <p>Ninon, Ninon, Ninon à bas—
A bas Ninon De L’Enclos!
</p>
         <p>During this little scene, however, one thing had served
<br/>greatly to console me, although it fed the passion by
<br/>which I was consumed. As the carriage of Madame La-
<br/>lande rolled by our group, I had observed that she recog-
<br/>nized me; and more than this, she had blessed me, by
<br/>the most seraphic of all imaginable smiles, with no equi-
<br/>vocal mark of the recognition.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>As for an introduction, I was obliged to abandon all
<br/>hope of it, until such time as Talbot should think proper
<br/>to return from the country. In the meantime I persever-
<br/>ingly frequented every reputable place of public amuse-
<br/>ment ; and, at length, at the theatre, where I first saw
<br/>her, I had the supreme bliss of meeting her, and of ex-
<br/>changing glances with her once again. This did not oc-
<br/>cur, however, until the lapse of a fortnight. Every day,</p>
         <p/>
         <p>in the interim, I had enquired for Talbot at his hotel, and
<br/>every day had been thrown into a spasm of wrath by the
<br/>everlasting “ Not come home yet” of his footman.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Upon the evening in question, therefore, I was in a
<br/>condition little short of madness. Madame Lalande, I
<br/>had been told, was a Parisian—had lately arrived from
<br/>Paris—might she not suddenly return ?—return before
<br/>Talbot came back—and might she not be thus lost to me
<br/>forever? The thought was too terrible to bear. Since
<br/>my future happiness was at issue, I resolved to act with
<br/>a manly decision. In a word, upon the breaking up of
<br/>the play, I traced the lady to her residence, noted the ad-
<br/>dress, and the next morning sent her a full and elaborate
<br/>letter, in which I poured out my whole heart.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I spoke boldly, freely—in a word, I spoke with passion.
<br/>I concealed nothing—nothing even of my weakness. I
<br/>alluded to the romantic circumstance of our first meet-
<br/>ing—even to the glances which had passed between us.
<br/>I went so far as to say that I felt assured of her love ;
<br/>while I offered this assurance, and my own intensity of
<br/>devotion, as two excuses for my otherwise unpardonable
<br/>conduct. As a third, I spoke of my fear that she might
<br/>quit the city before I could have the opportunity of a for-
<br/>mal introduction. I concluded the most wildly enthusi-
<br/>astic epistle ever penned, with a frank declaration of my
<br/>wordly circumstances—of my affluence—and with an offer
<br/>of my heart and of my hand.</p>
         <p>In an agony of expectation I awaited the reply. After
what seemed the lapse of a century it came.
</p>
         <p>Yes, actually came. Romantic as all this may appear,
<br/>I really received a letter from Madame Lalande—the
<br/>beautiful, the wealthy, the idolized Madame Lalande.—
<br/>Her eyes—her magnificent eyes—had not belied her noble
<br/>heart. Like a true Frenchwoman, as she was, she had obey-
<br/>ed the frank dictates of her reason—the generous impul-
<br/>ses of her nature—despising the conventional pruderies
<br/>of the world. She had not scorned my proposals. She
<br/>had not sheltered herself in silence. She had not return-
<br/>ed my letter unopened. She had even sent me, in reply,
<br/>one penned by her own exquisite fingers. It ran thus:</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Monsieur Simpson vill pardonne me for not compose de butefulle
<br/>tong of his contree so vell as might It is only de late dat I am
<br/>arrive, and not yet ave de opportunity for to—l’étudier.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Vid dis apologie for de maniere, I vill now say dat, hélas !—
<br/>Monsieur Simpson ave guess but de too true. Need I say de more?
<br/>Hélas! am I not ready speak de too moshe?</p>
         <p>Eugenie Lalande.
</p>
         <p>This noble-spirited note I kissed a million times, and
<br/>committed, no doubt, on its account, a thousand other ex-
<br/>travagances that have now escaped my memory. Still
<br/>Talbot would not return. Alas! could he have formed
<br/>even the vaguest idea of the suffering his absence occa-
<br/>sioned his friend, would not his sympathizing nature have
<br/>flown immediately to my relief? Still, however, he came
<br/>not. I wrote. He replied. He was detained by urgent
<br/>business—but would shortly return. He begged me not
<br/>to be impatient—to moderate my transports—to read
<br/>soothing books—to drink nothing stronger than Hock—
<br/>and to bring the consolations of philosophy to my aid.
<br/>The fool! if he could not come himself, why, in the
<br/>name of every thing rational, could he not have enclosed
<br/>me a letter of presentation? I wrote again, entreating
<br/>him to forward one forthwith. My letter was returned
<br/>by that footman, with the following endorsement in
<br/>pencil. The scoundrel had joined his master in the coun-
<br/>try:</p>
         <p>Left S——yesterday, for parts unknown—did not say where—
<a href="#p303"/>
         </p>
         <p>or when be back—so thought best to return letter, knowing your
<br/>handwriting, and as how you is always, more or less, in a hurry —
<br/>Yours, sincerely,	Stubbs.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>After this, it is needless to say, that I devoted to the
<br/>infernal deities both master and valet;—but there was
<br/>little use in anger, and no consolation at all in complaint.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>But I had yet a resource left, in my constitutional au-
<br/>dacity. Hitherto it had served me well, and I now re-
<br/>solved to make it avail me to the end. Besides, after the
<br/>correspondence which had passed between us, what act
<br/>of mere informality could I commit, within bounds, that
<br/>ought to be regarded as indecorous by Madame Lalande?
<br/>Since the affair of the letter, I had been in the habit of
<br/>watching her house, and thus discovered that, about twi-
<br/>light, it was her custom to promenade, attended only by
<br/>a negro in livery, in a public square overlooked by her
<br/>windows. Here, amid the luxuriant and shadowing
<br/>groves, in the gray gloom of a sweet midsummer even-
<br/>ing, I observed my opportunity and accosted her.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The better to deceive the servant in attendance, I did
<br/>this with the assured air of an old and familiar acquain-
<br/>tance. With a presence of mind truly Parisian, she took
<br/>the cue at once, and, to greet me, held out the most be-
<br/>witchingly little of hands. The valet at once fell into
<br/>the rear; and now, with hearts full to overflowing, we
<br/>discoursed long and unreservedly of our love.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>As Madame Lalande spoke English even less fluently
<br/>than she wrote it, our conversation was necessarily in
<br/>French. In this sweet tongue, so adapted to passion, I
<br/>gave loose to the impetuous enthusiasm of my nature,
<br/>and with all the eloquence I could command, besought
<br/>her consent to an immediate marriage.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>At this impatience she smiled. She urged the old sto-
<br/>ry of decorum—that bug-bear which deters so many from
<br/>bliss until the opportunity for bliss has forever gone by.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I had most imprudently made it known among my friends,
<br/>she observed, that I desired her acquaintance—thus that
<br/>I did not possess it—thus, again, there was no possibili-
<br/>ty of concealing the date of our first knowledge of each
<br/>other. And then she adverted, with a blush, to the ex-
<br/>treme recency of this date. To wed immediately would
<br/>be improper—would be indecorous—would be outre.—
<br/>All this she said with a charming air of naivete which
<br/>enraptured while it grieved and convinced me. She went
<br/>even so far as to accuse me, laughingly, of rashness—of
<br/>imprudence. She bade me remember that I really even
<br/>knew not who she was—what were her prospects, her
<br/>connexions, her standing in society. She begged me, but
<br/>with a sigh, to reconsider my proposal, and termed my
<br/>love an infatuation—a will ’o the wisp—a fancy or fantasy
<br/>of the moment—a baseless and unstable creation rather of
<br/>the imagination than of the heart. These things she
<br/>uttered as the shadows of the sweet twilight gathered
<br/>darkly and more darkly around us—and then, with a gen-
<br/>tle pressure of her fairy-like hand, overthrew, in a single
<br/>sweet instant, all the argumentative fabric she had reared.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I replied as best I could—as only a true lover can. I
<br/>spoke at length, and perseveringly, of my devotion, of
<br/>my passion—of her exceeding beauty, and of my own en-
<br/>thusiastic admiration. In conclusion, I dwelt, with a
<br/>convincing energy, upon the perils that encompass the
<br/>course of love—that course of true love that never did
<br/>run smooth, and thus deduced the manifest danger of
<br/>rendering that course unnecessarily long.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This latter argument seemed finally to soften the rigor
<br/>of her determination. She relented; but there was yet
<br/>an obstacle, she said, which she felt assured I had not</p>
         <p/>
         <p>properly considered. This was a delicate point—for a
<br/>woman to urge, especially so ; in mentioning it, she saw
<br/>that she must make a sacrifice of her feelings ; still, for
<br/>me, every sacrifice should be made. She alluded to the
<br/>topic of age. Was I aware—was I fully aware of the
<br/>discrepancy between us ? That the age of the husband
<br/>should surpass by a few years—even by fifteen or twenty
<br/>—the age of the wife, was regarded by the world as ad-
<br/>missible, and, indeed, as even proper ; but she had always
<br/>entertained the belief that the years of the wife should
<br/>never exceed in number those of the husband. A dis-
<br/>crepancy of this unnatural kind gave rise, too frequently,
<br/>alas ! to a life of unhappiness. Now she was aware that
<br/>my own age did not exceed two and twenty; and I, on the
<br/>contrary, perhaps, was not aware that the years of my
<br/>Eugenie extended very considerably beyond that sum.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>About all this there was a nobility of soul—a dignity of
<br/>candor—which delighted—which enchanted me—which
<br/>eternally rivetted my chains. I could scarcely restrain
<br/>the excessive transport which possessed me.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“My sweetest Eugenie,” I cried, “what is all this
<br/>about which you are discoursing ? Your years surpass
<br/>in some measure my own. But what then ? The cus-
<br/>toms of the world are so many conventional follies. To
<br/>those who love as ourselves, in what respect differs a
<br/>year from an hour ? I am twenty-two, you say; granted:
<br/>indeed you may as well call me, at once, twenty-three.
<br/>Now you yourself, my dearest Eugenie, can have num-
<br/>bered no more than—can have numbered no more than—-
<br/>no more than—than—than—than—”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Here I paused for an instant, in the expectation that
<br/>Madame Lalande would interrupt me by supplying
<br/>her true age. But a Frenchwoman is seldom direct, and
<br/>has always, by way of answer to an embarrassing query,
<br/>some little practical reply of her own. In the present
<br/>instance Eugenie, who, for a few moments past, had
<br/>seemed to be searching for something in her bosom, at
<br/>length let fall upon the grass a miniature, which I imme-
<br/>diately picked up and presented to her.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“Keep it!” she said, with one of her most ravishing
<br/>smiles. “ Keep it for my sake—for the sake of her whom
<br/>it too flatteringly represents. Besides, upon the back of
<br/>the trinket, you may discover, perhaps, the very informa-
<br/>tion you seem to desire. It is now, to be sure, growing
<br/>rather dark—but you can examine it at your leisure in the
<br/>morning. In the mean time, you shall be my escort home
<br/>to-night. My friends are about holding a little musical
<br/>levée. I can promise you, too, some good singing. We
<br/>French are not nearly so punctilious as you Americans,
<br/>and I shall have no difficulty in smuggling you in, in the
<br/>character of an old acquaintance."</p>
         <p/>
         <p>With this, she took my arm, and I attended her home.
<br/>The mansion was quite a fine one, and, I believe, furnish-
<br/>ed in good taste. Of this latter point, however, I am
<br/>scarcely qualified to judge; for it was just dark as we ar-
<br/>rived ; and in American mansions of the better sort, lights
<br/>seldom, during the heat of summer, make their appear-
<br/>ance at this, the most pleasant period of the day. In
<br/>about an hour after my arrival, to be sure, a single shaded
<br/>solar lamp was lit in the principal drawing-room ; and
<br/>this apartment, I could thus see, was arranged with unu-
<br/>sual good taste and even splendor ; but two other rooms
<br/>of the suite, and in which the company chiefly assembled,
<br/>remained, during the whole evening, in a very agreeable
<br/>shadow. This is a well conceived custom, giving the
<br/>party at least a choice of light or shade, and one which</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p304"/>
our friends over the water could not do better than im-
mediately adopt.
</p>
         <p>The evening thus spent was unquestionably the most
<br/>delicious of my life. Madame Lalande had not over-
<br/>rated the musical abilities of her friends ; and the singing
<br/>I here heard I had never heard excelled in any private
<br/>circle out of Vienna. The instrumental performers were
<br/>many and of superior talents. The vocalists were chiefly
<br/>ladies, and no individual sang less than well. At length,
<br/>upon a peremptory call for “ Madame Lalande,” she arose
<br/>at once, without affectation or demur, from the chaise
<br/>longue upon which she had sate by my side, and, accom-
<br/>panied by one or two gentlemen and her female friend of
<br/>the opera, repaired to the piano in the main drawing-room.
<br/>I would have escorted her myself; but felt that, under
<br/>the circumstances of my introduction to the house, I had
<br/>better remain unobserved where I was. I was thus depri-
<br/>ved of the pleasure of seeing, although not of hearing
<br/>her, sing.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The impression she produced upon the company seemed
<br/>electrical—but the effect upon myself was something even
<br/>more. I know not how adequately to describe it. It arose
<br/>in part, no doubt, from the sentiment of love with which
<br/>I was imbued ; but chiefly from my conviction of the ex-
<br/>treme sensibility of the singer. It is beyond the reach of
<br/>art to endow either air or recitative with more impas-
<br/>sioned expression than was hers. Her utterance of the
<br/>romance in Otello—the tone with which she gave the
<br/>words “Sul mio sasso," in the Capuletti—is ringing in
<br/>my memory yet. Her lower tones were absolutely mirac-
<br/>ulous. Her voice embraced three complete octaves,
<br/>extending from the contralto D to the D upper soprano, and,
<br/>though sufficiently powerful to have filled the San Carlos,
<br/>executed, with the minutest precision, every difficulty of
<br/>vocal composition—ascending and descending scales, ca-
<br/>dences, or fiorituri. In the finale of the Sonnambula, she
<br/>brought about a most remarkable effect at the words—</p>
         <p>Ah ! non guinge uman pensiero
Al contento ond ’io son piena.
</p>
         <p>Here, in imitation of Malibran, she modified the ori-
<br/>ginal phrase of Bellini, so as to let her voice descend to
<br/>the tenor G, when, by a rapid transition, she struck the
<br/>G above the treble stave, springing over an interval of
<br/>two octaves.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Upon rising from the piano after these miracles of vocal
<br/>execution, she resumed her seat by my side ; when I
<br/>expressed to her, in terms of the deepest enthusiasm, my
<br/>delight at her performance. Of my surprise I said no-
<br/>thing, and yet was I most unfeignedly surprised ; for a
<br/>certain feebleness, or rather a certain tremulous indecis-
<br/>ion of voice in ordinary conversation, had prepared me to
<br/>anticipate that, in singing, she would not acquit herself
<br/>with any remarkable ability.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Our conversation was now long, earnest, uninterrupted,
<br/>and totally unreserved. She made me relate many of the
<br/>earlier passages of my life, and listened with breathless
<br/>attention, to every word of the narrative. I concealed
<br/>nothing—I felt that I had a right to conceal nothing from
<br/>her confiding affection. Encouraged by her candor upon
<br/>the delicate point of her age, I entered, with perfect frank-
<br/>ness, not only into a detail of my many minor vices, but
<br/>made full confession of those moral and even of those
<br/>physical infirmities, the disclosure of which, in demand-
<br/>ing so much higher a degree of courage, is so much surer
<br/>an evidence of love. I touched upon my college indiscre-
<br/>tions—upon my extravagances—upon my carousals—upon
<br/>my debts—upon my flirtations. I even went so far as to</p>
         <p/>
         <p>speak of a slightly hectic cough with which, at one time,
<br/>I had been troubled—of a chronic rheumatism—of a
<br/>twinge of hereditary gout—and, in conclusion, of the dis-
<br/>agreeable and inconvenient, but hitherto carefully con-
<br/>cealed, weakness of my eyes.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Upon this latter point,” said Madame Lalande, laugh-
<br/>ingly, “ you have been surely injudicious in coming to
<br/>confession ; for, without the confession, I take it for
<br/>granted that no one would have accused you of the crime.
<br/>By the by’” she continued, “ have you any recollection’’
<br/>—and here I fancied that a blush, even through the gloom
<br/>of the apartment, became distinctly visible upon her cheek
<br/>—“ have you any recollection, mon cher ami, of this little
<br/>ocular assistant which now depends from my neck ?”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>As she spoke she twirled in her fingers the identical
<br/>double eye-glass, which had so overwhelmed me with
<br/>confusion at the opera.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Full well—alas I do I remember it,” I exclaimed,
<br/>pressing passionately the delicate hand which offered the
<br/>glasses for my inspection. They formed a complex and
<br/>magnificent toy, richly chased and filagreed, and gleaming
<br/>with jewels, which, even in the deficient light, I could
<br/>not help perceiving were of high value.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“Eh bien! mon ami," she resumed with a certain em-
<br/>pressement of manner that rather surprised me—“Eh bien,
<br/>mon ami, you have earnestly besought of me a favor
<br/>which you have been pleased to denominate priceless. You
<br/>have demanded of me my hand upon the morrow. Should
<br/>I yield to your entreaties—and, I may add, to the plead-
<br/>ings of my own bosom—would I not be entitled to demand
<br/>of you a very—a very little boon in return ?”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Name it!” I exclaimed with an energy that had
<br/>nearly drawn upon us the observation of the company,
<br/>and restrained by their presence alone from throwing my-
<br/>self impetuously at her feet. “ Name it, my beloved, my
<br/>Eugenie, my own !—name it !— but alas it is already
<br/>yielded ere named.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ You shall conquer then, mon ami," she said, “for the
<br/>sake of the Eugenie whom you love, this little weakness
<br/>which you have last confessed—this weakness more moral
<br/>than physical—and which, let me assure you, is so un-
<br/>becoming the nobility of your real nature—so inconsist-
<br/>ent with the candor of your usual character—and which,
<br/>if permitted farther control, will assuredly involve you,
<br/>sooner or later, in some very disagreeable scrape. You
<br/>shall conquer, for my sake, this affectation which leads
<br/>you, as you yourself acknowledge, to the tacit or implied
<br/>denial of your infirmity of vision. For, this infirmity you
<br/>virtually deny, in refusing to employ the customary means
<br/>for its relief. You will understand me to say, then, that
<br/>I wish you to wear spectacles :—ah, hush —you have
<br/>already consented to wear them, for my sake. You shall
<br/>accept the little toy which I now hold in my hand, and
<br/>which, though admirable as an aid to vision, is really of
<br/>no very immense value as a gem. You perceive that, by
<br/>a trifling modification thus—or thus—it can be adapted to
<br/>the eyes in the form of spectacles, or worn in the waist-
<br/>coat packet as an eye-glass. It is in the former mode,
<br/>however, and habitually, that you have already consented
<br/>to wear it for my sake."</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This request—must I confess it ?—confused me in no
<br/>little degree. But the condition with which it was coupled
<br/>rendered hesitation, of course, a matter altogether out of
<br/>the question.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“It is done !” I cried, with all the enthusiasm that I
<br/>could muster at the moment. “ It is done—it is most
<br/>cheerfully agreed. I sacrifise every feeling for your sake.</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p305"/>
         </p>
         <p>To-night I wear this dear eye-glass, as an eye-glass and
<br/>upon my heart ; but with the earliest dawn of that mor-
<br/>ning which gives me the pleasure of calling you wife, I
<br/>will place it upon my—upon my nose—and there wear it
<br/>ever afterwards, in the less romantic, and less fashionable,
<br/>but certainly in the more serviceable form which you
<br/>desire.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Our conversation now turned upon the details of our
<br/>arrangements for the morrow. Talbot, I learned from my
<br/>betrothed, had just arrived in town. I was to see him at
<br/>once, and procure a carriage. The soiree would scarcely
<br/>break up before two ; and by this hour the vehicle was to
<br/>be at the door ; when, in the confusion occasioned by the
<br/>departure of the company, Madame L. could easily enter
<br/>it unobserved. We were then to call at the house of a
<br/>clergyman who would be in waiting ; there be married,
<br/>drop Talbot, and proceed on a short tour to the East; leav-
<br/>ing the fashionable world at home to make whatever
<br/>comments upon the matter it thought best.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Having planned all this, I immediately took leave, and
<br/>went in search of Talbot, but, on the way, I could, not re-
<br/>frain from stepping into a hotel, for the purpose of in-
<br/>specting the miniature ; and this I did by the powerful
<br/>aid of the glasses. The countenance was a surpassingly
<br/>beautiful one ! Those large luminous eyes !—that proud
<br/>Grecian nose !—those dark luxuriant curls !—“ Ah !” said
<br/>I exultingly to myself, “ this is indeed the speaking im-
<br/>age of my beloved !” I turned the reverse, and discov-
<br/>ered the words—“Eugenie Lalande—aged twenty-seven
<br/>years and seven months.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I found Talbot at home, and proceeded at once to ac-
<br/>quaint nim with my good fortune. He professed exces-
<br/>sive astonishment, of course, but congratulated me most
<br/>cordially, and proffered every assistance in his power. In
<br/>a word, we carried out our arrangement to the letter ;
<br/>and, at two in the morning, just ten minutes after the
<br/>ceremony, I found myself in a close carriage with Ma-
<br/>dame Lalande—with Mrs. Simpson, I should say—and
<br/>driving at a great rate opt of town, in a direction North-
<br/>east and by North, half-North.</p>
         <p>It had been determined, for us by. Talbot, that, as we
were to be up all night, we should make our first stop at
C-----, a village about twenty miles from the city, and
</p>
         <p>there get an early breakfast and some repose, before pro-
<br/>ceeding upon our route. At four precisely, therefore, the
<br/>carriage drew up at the door of the principal inn. I
<br/>handed my adored wife out, and ordered breakfast forth-
<br/>with. In the mean time we were shown into a small
<br/>parlor and sate down,</p>
         <p/>
         <p>It was now nearly if not altogether daylight ; and, as
<br/>I gazed, enraptured, at the angel by my side, the singular
<br/>idea came, all at once, into my head, that this was really
<br/>the very first moment since my acquaintance with the
<br/>celebrated loveliness of Madame Lalande, tha-t I had en-
<br/>joyed a near inspection of that loveliness by daylight,
<br/>at all.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ And now, mon ami," said she taking my hand, and so
<br/>interrupting this train of reflection, “ and now, mon cher
<br/>ami, since we are indissolubly one—since I have yielded
<br/>to your passionate entreaties, and performed my portion of
<br/>our agreement—I presume you have not forgotten that you
<br/>also have a little favor to bestow—a little promise which
<br/>it is your intention to keep. Ah !-—let me see-! Let me
<br/>remember ! Yes , full easily do I call to mind the precise
<br/>words of thee dear promise you made to Eugenie last
<br/>night. Listen! You spoke thus: “It is done!—it is
<br/>most cheerfully agreed ! I sacrifise every feeling for your</p>
         <p/>
         <p>sake. To-night I wear this dear eye-glass as an eye-glass,
<br/>and upon my heart; but with the earliest dawn of that
<br/>morning which gives me the privilege of calling you
<br/>wife, I will place it upon my—upon my nose—and there
<br/>wear it, ever afterwards, in the less romantic, and less
<br/>fashionable, but certainly in the more serviceable form
<br/>which you desire.’ These were the exact words, my be-
<br/>loved husband, were they not?”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ They were,” I said ; “ you have an excellent memory;
<br/>and assuredly, my beautiful Eugenie, there is no disposi-
<br/>tion on my part to evade the performance of the trivial
<br/>promise they imply. See ! Behold ! They are becoming—
<br/>rather—are they not ?” And here, having arranged the
<br/>glasses in the ordinary form of spectacles, I applied them
<br/>gingerly in their proper position; while Madame Simp-
<br/>son, adjusting her cap, and folding her arms, sat bolt up-
<br/>right in her chair, in a somewhat stiff and prim, and in-
<br/>deed in a somewhat undignified position.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“Goodness gracious me !” I exclaimed almost at the
<br/>very, instant that the rim of the spectacles had settled
<br/>upon my nose—“My! goodness gracious me!—why
<br/>what can be the matter with these glasses ?” and taking
<br/>them quickly off, I wiped them carefully with a silk
<br/>handkerchief, and adjusted them again.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>But if, in the first instance, there had occurred some-
<br/>thing which occasioned me surprise, in the second, this
<br/>surprise became elevated into astonishment; and this as-
<br/>tonishment was profound—was extreme—indeed I may-
<br/>say it was horrific. What, in the name of everything
<br/>hideous, did this mean ? Could I believe my eyes ?—
<br/>could I ?—that was the question. Was that—was that—
<br/>was that rouge? And were those—were those—Were
<br/>those wrinkles, upon the visage of Eugenie Lalande ?—
<br/>And, oh, Jupiter ! and every one of the gods and goddes-
<br/>ses, little and big !—what—what—what—what had be-
<br/>come of her teeth ? I dashed the spectacles violently to
<br/>the ground, and, leaping to my feet, stood erect in the
<br/>middle of the floor, confronting Mrs. Simpson, with my
<br/>arms set a-kimbo, and grinning and foaming, but, at the
<br/>same time utterly speechless and helpless with terror and
<br/>with rage.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Now I have already said that Madame Eugenie La-
<br/>lande—that is to say, Simpson—spoke the English lan-
<br/>guage but very little better than she wrote it: and for
<br/>this reason she very properly never attempted to speak it
<br/>upon ordinary occasions. But rage will carry a lady to
<br/>any extreme ; and in the present case it carried Mrs.
<br/>Simpson to the very extraordinary extreme of attempting
<br/>to hold a conversation in a tongue that she did not alto-
<br/>gether understand.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“Veil, Monsieur," said she, after surveying me, in
<br/>great apparent astonishment, for some moments—“ Veil,
<br/>Monsieur!—and vat den ?—vat de matter now ? Is it de
<br/>dance of de Saint Vitusse dat you ave ? If not like me,
<br/>vat for vy buy de pig in de poke ?”</p>
         <p>“You wretch!” said I, catching my breath—“ you—
you—you villainous old hag!”
“Ag?—ole?—me not so ver ole, after all! me not one
single day more dan de eighty-doo.”
</p>
         <p>“ Eighty-two !” I ejaculated, staggering to the wall—
<br/>“eighty-two hundred thousand baboons! The minia-
<br/>ture said twenty-seven years and seven months!”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“To be sure!—dat is so!—ver true ! but den de por-
<br/>trait has been take for dese fifty-five year. Ven I go
<br/>marry my segonde usbande, Monsieur Lalande, at dat time
<br/>I had de portraite take for my daughter by my first us-
<br/>bande, Monsieur Moissart.”</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p306"/>
“Moissart!” said I.
</p>
         <p>“ Yes, Moissart, Moissart;” said she, mimicking my pro-
<br/>nunciation, which, to speak the truth, was none of the
<br/>best; “ and vat den ? Vat you know bout de Moissart ?”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“Nothing, you old fright!—I know nothing about him
<br/>at all only I had an ancestor of that name, once upon a
<br/>time.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“Dat name! and vat you ave for say to dat name ?—
<br/>’T is ver goot name ; and so is Voissart—dat is ver goot
<br/>name, too. My daughter, Madamoiselle Moissart, she
<br/>marry von Monsieur Voissart; and de name is bote ver
<br/>respectaable name.”</p>
         <p>“Moissart!” I exclaimed, “ and Voissart! why what is
it you mean ?”
</p>
         <p>“ Vat I mean ?—I mean Moissart and Voissart; and for
<br/>de matter of dat, I mean Croissart and Froissart, too, if I
<br/>only tink proper to mean it. My daughter’s daughter,
<br/>Madamoiselle Voissart, she marry von Monsieur Crois-
<br/>sart, and, den agin, my daughter’s grande daughter, Ma-
<br/>demoiselle Croissart, she marry von Monsieur Froissart;
<br/>and I suppose you say dat dat is not von ver respecta-
<br/>able name.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Froissart!” said I, beginning to faint, “ why surely
<br/>you don’t say Moissart, and Voissart, and Croissart, and
<br/>Froissart ?”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ Yes,” she replied, leaning fully back in her chair,
<br/>and stretching out her lower limbs at great length ; “ yes,
<br/>Moissart, and Voissart, and Croissart, and Froissart. But
<br/>Monsieur Froissart, he was von ver big vat you call fool—
<br/>he vas von ver great big donee like yourself—for he lef
<br/>la belle France for come to dis stupide Amerique—and
<br/>ven he get here he vent and ave von ver stupide, von ver,
<br/>ver stupide sonn, so I hear, dough I not yet av ad de plai-
<br/>sir to meet vid him—neither me nor my companion, de
<br/>Madame Stephanie Lalande. He is name de Napoleon
<br/>Bonaparte Froissart, and I suppose you say dat dat, too,
<br/>is not von ver respectaable name.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Either the length or the nature of this speech, had the
<br/>effect of working up Mrs. Simpson into a very extraordi-
<br/>nary passion indeed; and as she made an end of it, with
<br/>great labor, she jumped up from her chair like somebody
<br/>bewitched, dropping upon the floor an entire universe of
<br/>bustle as she jumped. Once upon her feet, she gnashed
<br/>her gums, brandished her arms, rolled up her sleeves,
<br/>shook her fist in my face, and concluded the performance
<br/>by tearing the cap from her head, and with it an im-
<br/>mense wig of the most valuable and beautiful black hair,
<br/>the whole of which she dashed upon the ground with a
<br/>yell, and there trampled and danced a fandango upon it,
<br/>in an absolute ecstasy and agony of rage.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Meantime I sank aghast into the chair which she had
<br/>vacated. “ Moissart and Voissart !” I repeated, thought-
<br/>fully, as she cut one of her pigeon-wings, and “ Croissart
<br/>and Froissart!” as she completed another—“Moissart
<br/>and Voissart and Croissart and Napoleon Bonaparte Frois-
<br/>sart !—why, you ineffable old serpent, that’s me—that’s
<br/>me—d’ye hear ?—that's me"—here I screamed at the top
<br/>of my voice—“ that's me e e ! I am Napoleon Bonaparte
<br/>Froissart! and if I hav n’t married my great, great,
<br/>grandmother, I wish I may be everlastingly confounded !”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Madame Eugenie Lalande, quasi Simpson—formerly
<br/>Moissart—was, in sober fact, my great, great, grandmo-
<br/>ther. In her youth she had been beautiful, and even at
<br/>eighty-two, retained the majestic height, the sculptural
<br/>contour of head, the fine eyes and the Grecian nose of her
<br/>girlhood. By the aid of these, of pearl-powder, of rouge,
<br/>of false hair, false teeth, and false tournure, as well as</p>
         <p/>
         <p>of the most skilful modistes of Paris, she contrived to
<br/>hold a respectable footing among the beauties un peu pas-
<br/>sées of the French metropolis. In this respect, indeed,
<br/>she might have been regarded as little less than the equal
<br/>of the celebrated Ninon De L’Enclos.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>She was immensely wealthy, and being left, for the se-
<br/>cond time, a widow without children, she bethought her-
<br/>self of my existence in America, and, for the purpose of
<br/>making me her heir, paid a visit to the United States, in
<br/>company with a distant and exceedingly lovely relative
<br/>of her second husband’s—a Madame Stephanie Lalande.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>At the opera, my great, great, grandmother’s attention
<br/>was arrested by my notice; and, upon surveying me
<br/>through her eye-glass, she was struck with a certain
<br/>family resemblance to herself. Thus interested, and
<br/>knowing that the heir she sought was actually in the
<br/>city, she made inquiries of her party respecting me.—
<br/>The gentleman who attended her knew my person, and
<br/>told her who I was. The information thus obtained in-
<br/>duced her to renew her scrutiny ; and this scrutiny it was
<br/>which so emboldened me that I behaved in the absurd
<br/>manner already detailed. She returned my bow, howev-
<br/>er, under the impression that, by some odd accident, I
<br/>had discovered her identity. When, deceived by my
<br/>weakness of vision, and the arts of the toilet, in respect
<br/>to the age and charms of the strange lady, I demanded
<br/>so enthusiastically of Talbot who she was, he concluded
<br/>that I meant the younger beauty, as a matter of course,
<br/>and so informed me, with perfect truth, that she was
<br/>“ the celebrated widow, Madame Lalande.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In the street next morning, my great, great, grandmo-
<br/>ther encountered Talbot, an old Parisian acquaintance;
<br/>and the conversation, very naturally, turned upon myself.
<br/>My deficiencies of vision were then explained ; for these
<br/>were notorious, although I was entirely ignorant of their
<br/>notoriety ; and my good old relative discovered, much to
<br/>her chagrin, that she had been deceived in supposing me
<br/>aware of her identity, and that I had been merely making
<br/>a fool of myself, in making open love, in a theatre, to an
<br/>old woman unknown. By way of punishing me for this
<br/>imprudence, she concocted with Talbot a plot. He pur-
<br/>posely kept out of my way, to avoid giving me the intro-
<br/>duction. My street inquiries about “ the lovely widow,
<br/>Madame Lalande,” were supposed to refer to the young-
<br/>er lady, of course; and thus the conversation with the
<br/>three gentlemen whom I encountered shortly after leav-
<br/>ing Talbot’s hotel, will be easily explained, as also their
<br/>allusion to Ninon De L’Enclos. I had no opportunity of
<br/>seeing Madame Lalande closely during daylight; and, at
<br/>her musical soiree, my silly weakness in refusing the aid
<br/>of glasses, effectually prevented me from making a dis-
<br/>covery of her age. When “ Madame Lalande” was cal-
<br/>led upon to sing, the younger lady was intended ; and it
<br/>was she who arose to obey the call; my great, great,
<br/>grandmother, to further the deception, arising at the
<br/>same moment, and accompanying her to the piano in the
<br/>main drawing-room. Had I decided upon escorting her
<br/>thither, it had been her design to suggest the propriety
<br/>of my remaining where I was ; but my own prudential
<br/>views rendered this unnecessary. The songs which I so
<br/>much admired, and which so confirmed my impression of
<br/>the youth of my mistress, were executed by Madame
<br/>Stephanie Lalande. The eye-glass was presented by
<br/>way of adding a reproof to the hoax—a sting to the epi-
<br/>gram of the deception. Its presentation afforded an op-
<br/>portunity for the lecture upon affectation with which I
<br/>was so especially edified. It is almost superfluous to add</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p307"/>
         </p>
         <p>that the glasses of the instrument, as worn by the old
<br/>lady, had been exchanged by her for a pair better adapt-
<br/>ed to my years. They suited me, in fact to a t.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The clergyman who merely pretended to tie the fatal
<br/>knot, was a boon companion of Talbot’s, and no priest.—
<br/>He was an excellent “whip,” however ; and having dof-
<br/>fed his cassock to put on a great coat, he drove the hack
<br/>which conveyed the “ happy couple” out of town. Tal-
<br/>bot took a seat at his side. The two scoundrels were
<br/>thus “ in at the death,” and, through a half open window
<br/>of the back parlor of the inn, amused themselves in grin-
<br/>ning at the denouement of the drama. I believe I shall
<br/>be forced to call them both out.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Nevertheless, I am not the husband of my great, great,
<br/>grandmother ; and this is a reflection which affords me
<br/>infinite relief but I am the husband of Madame La-
<br/>lande—of Madame Stephanie Lalande—with whom my
<br/>good old relative, besides making me her sole heir when
<br/>she dies—if she ever does—has been at the trouble of
<br/>concocting me a match. In conclusion: I am done for-
<br/>ever with billets doux, and am never to be met without
<br/>SPECTACLES.	Edgar A. Poe.</p>
         <p>To ---------
Oh! they never can know that heart of thine,
Who dare accuse thee of flirtation!
They might as well say that the stars, which shine
In the light of their joy o’er Creation,—
Are flirting with every wild wave in which lies
One beam of the glory that kindles the skies.
Smile on then undimmed in your beauty and grace!
Too well e’er to doubt, love, we know you;—
And shed, from your heaven, the light of your face,
Where the waves chase each other below you;
For none can e’er deem it your shame or your sin,
That each wave holds your star-image smiling within.
Frances S. Osgood.
Critical Notices.
</p>
         <p>We have again to apologise to our publishing friends
<br/>for the brevity of our Critical Notices. In our next num-
<br/>ber we shall devote more than usual attention to this De-
<br/>partment. There are several important works now lying
<br/>before us, of which it is our intention to speak in detail—
<br/>Mrs. Kirkland’s new book, for example—Von Raumer's
<br/>America—and the Life of Schiller—one of the Appleton
<br/>series. We wish to say much, also, of the Annuals and
<br/>Gift-Books—very especially of “ The Missionary Memo-
<br/>rial,” “ The Diadem,” “ The Rose,” and “ The Mayflow-
<br/>er,”—the best of these works, as far as we have yet had
<br/>an opportunity of judging. For the present (owing to the
<br/>bustle consequent upon removing our office) we must con-
<br/>tent ourselves with a mere announcement of the books
<br/>on hand for notice.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of American Books. No. 7.
<br/>Western Clearings. By Mrs. C. M. Kirkland, Author
<br/>of “ A New Home" etc.</p>
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of American Books. No. 8.
The Raven and Other Poems. By Edgar A. Poe.
</p>
         <p>Appleton's Literary Miscellany—a New Series of Choice
<br/>Books. No.5. The Life of Frederick Schiller: Com-
<br/>prehending an Examination of his Works by Thomas
<br/>Carlyle, Author of “ French Revolution," “ Sartor Re-
<br/>sartus,'' “Past and Present," etc. A new Edition re-
<br/>vised by the Author. New-York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.
<br/>200 Broadway.</p>
         <p>Trifles in Verse: A Collection of Fugitive Poems. By
Lewis J. Cist. Cincinnati: Robinson &amp; Jones.
</p>
         <p>The Oath, a Divine Ordinance and an Element of The
<br/>Social Constitution: its Origin, Nature, Ends, Effica-
<br/>cy, Lawfulness, Obligations, Interpretation, Form and
<br/>Abuses. By D. X. Junkin, A. M. Pastor of the
<br/>Presbyterian Church, Greenwich, N. J. New-York:
<br/>Wiley &amp; Putnam.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Mass and Rubrics of the Roman Catholic Church,
<br/>Translated into English, With Notes and Remarks.
<br/>By the Rev. John Rogerson Cotter, A. M., Rector of
<br/>Inishannon, etc. New-York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Diadem for 1846. A Present for all Seasons.
<br/>With Ten Engravings, after Pictures by Inman,
<br/>Leutze, etc. Philadelphia ; Carey &amp; Hurt.</p>
         <p>The Missionary Memorial: a Literary and Religious
Souvenir. New-York: E Walker, 114 Fulton St.
</p>
         <p>The Rose : or Affection's Gift for 1846. Edited by Em-
<br/>ily Marshall, Illustrated, with Ten highly finished
<br/>steel engravings. New-York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.</p>
         <p>The May-Flower, for 1846. Edited by Robert Hamilton.
Boston: Saxton if Kelt.
</p>
         <p>Harper's Library of Select Novels. No. 62. Amaury.
<br/>Translated from the French of Alexandre Dumas. By
<br/>E. P. New-York: Harper &amp; Brothers.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The O'Donoghue. A Tale of Ireland Fifty years ago.
<br/>By Charles Lever, Author of “ Harry Lorrequer,"
<br/>“ Charles O'Malley," etc. With Illustrations by Phiz.
<br/>To which is added St. Patrick's Eve, or Three Eras
<br/>in the Life of an Irish Peasant. Philadelphia : Carey
<br/>&amp; Hart.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Cosmos: a Survey of the General Physical History of
<br/>The Universe. By Alexander Von Humboldt. Part
<br/>2. New-York: Harper if Brothers.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Harper's Library of Select Novels. No. 64. Only a
<br/>Fiddler ! and O. T. By the Author of “ The Impro-
<br/>visators, or Life in Italy" etc. Translated by Mary
<br/>Howitt.		</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Lucy of Lammermoor: Grand Serious Opera in Three
<br/>Acts ; Founded on Sir Walter Scott's Celebrated
<br/>Novel. The Muzic by Donizetti. Words by Messrs.
<br/>G. Bowes and Rophino Lacy. New-York: George
<br/>Trehern.	</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Morse's Ceorgraphic Maps. No. 4. Contents—Texas,
<br/>Kentucky—Tenessee—Indiana—and South Carolina.
<br/>New-York : Harper &amp; Brothers.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Devotional Family Bible. By the Rev. Alexander
<br/>Fletcher, A. M. Containing The Old and New Tes-
<br/>taments, with Explanatory Notes, Marginal Refer-
<br/>ences, etc. Every Part embellished with a Highly Fin-
<br/>ished Engraving on Steel; Including Views of the
<br/>Principal Places mentioned in Scripture, from Draw-
<br/>ings taken on the Spot. Part 12. New-York: R. Mar-
<br/>tin &amp; Co., 26 John St.</p>
         <p>Thei Edinburgh Review, for October. American Edition.
New-York: Leonard Scott &amp; Co.
A New Edition of Tennyson. Boston : Ticknor &amp; Co.
First Love.
</p>
         <p>Oh! precious is the flow’r that Passion brings
<br/>To his first shrine of beauty, when the heart
<br/>Runs over in devotion, and no art
<br/>Checks the free gush of the wild lay he sings;—</p>
         <p>But the rapt eye, and the impetuous thought
Declare the pure affection; and a speech,
Such as the ever-timed affections teach,
Delivers love’s best confidence unbought;—
And all is glory in the o’er-arching sky,
And all is beauty in the uplifting earth,
And from the wood, and o’er the wave, a mirth,
Such as mocks hope with immortality,
Declares that all the loved ones are at hand,
With still the turtle’s voice the loudest in the land.
W. Gilmore Simms.
<a href="#p308"/>
Musical Department.
</p>
         <p>Mrs. V. Mott's Concert.—One of the most fashionable
<br/>audiences we ever witnessed, crowded the Apollo Saloon
<br/>that evening. The fair debutante was received with loud
<br/>cheers whenever she made her appearance. Thou art
<br/>lovelier, and the Wanderer, were the gems of the per-
<br/>formance. Indeed, no other piece, than the latter, could
<br/>haves shown the beautiful contralto of Mrs. Mott. We
<br/>were not so much pleased with the first of her pieces.—
<br/>Here and there it is said, but only in a whisper—it was a
<br/>failure. We do not think so. Laboring under many dis-
<br/>advantages, Mrs. Mott acquitted herself even better than
<br/>we thought she would. She will sing again at the Phil-
<br/>harmonic Concert. To speak of the other part of the per-
<br/>formance : Mr. P. Mayer is becoming quite a favorite —
<br/>He sang the Exile, a German composition, most beauti-
<br/>fully, and his rich baritone voice was never displayed to
<br/>better advantage. Messrs. Kyle and Timm played the
<br/>duett for Flute and Piano exquisitely ; Mr. K„ particular-
<br/>ly, was better than on any other occasion. The duett of
<br/>Messrs. Loder and Timm, however well played, did not
<br/>please much. A like fate had the first concerted piece.
<br/>But altogether, we. think a repetition of the Concert in
<br/>the Tabernacle, would not be amiss.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Mr. Leopold De Meyer, the Lion-pianist; as they will
<br/>have it, had a crowded house on the night of his second
<br/>concert. He was encored several times. It seems, that
<br/>of all the pianists in this city, Mr. Perabeau alone can
<br/>muster courage enough to wrestle with him for the
<br/>wreath of laurels. But we have mentioned already, that
<br/>whatever gestures he makes, in whatever position, he
<br/>forces himself, or however he thumps on the piano, he
<br/>can never make the public believe that he is as great as
<br/>De Meyer; though he has this advantage, that whenever
<br/>Dantan wishes to make a caricature of the great pianist,
<br/>Perabeau, he need not trouble himself to invent one.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Miss Northall did not sing as well as usual, owing,
<br/>perhaps, to the hasty travelling from Philadelphia, where
<br/>she sang but the night before,'to this city. Madame La-
<br/>zare and Mr. Mayer acquitted themselves well. . De
<br/>Meyer is now in Boston, but no accounts of his triumph,
<br/>for such we expect, certainly, have reached us as yet.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Oratorio of Sampson will be performed under the
<br/>direction of Mr. LL C. Hill, at the Tabernacle. We
<br/>think, that, substituting another for this, would do us no
<br/>harm; however, we have no doubt it will be well per-
<br/>formed. Mr. Paige will make his first appearance as a
<br/>public singer, so the papers say. We wonder that the
<br/>New-York Sacred Music Society employs Boston artists
<br/>for the different solo parts ? Is there any want of good
<br/>vocalists here ?</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Paulus, Mendelsjohn Barsholdy’s chef d’oeuvre, is in
<br/>preparation; and will be brought out soon, with Mr. Geo.
<br/>Loder as conductor.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>A German Opera Troupe will occupy Palmo’s Thea-
<br/>tre for a season. Per Freicthutz, with Madame Otto as
<br/>Prima Donna, will be brought out. Then we are to have
<br/>the Magic Flute, Don Juan, Czaar and Zimmerman, to-
<br/>gether with the best Italian Operas with German text.—
<br/>Mr. P. Mayer and Meyer, also Miss Windmuller will
<br/>form part of the troupe. How far. is will succeed, we
<br/>know not, but we wish them success from the bottom of
<br/>our heart.</p>
         <p>The following publications have been sent us by either
publisher or composer:
“Poor Tom,” composed by George P. Manouvrier, and
published by John F. Nunns, 240 Broadway.
Phillips’ Quick Step.
L’Alliance, Brilliant Waltz; and
</p>
         <p>Echo Song, the words by Mrs. Frances S. Osgood.—All
<br/>of them composed by Mr. Saroni, and. published by Geo.
<br/>Willig, Philadelphia.</p>
         <p>“It is the Chime,’’ composed by Benjamin S. Hart,
and published by Atwill.
</p>
         <p>“Kind Friends we Meet Again,” words selected and
<br/>melody composed by Henry Stone, and respectfully dedi-
<br/>cated to his friend, E. Thompson, Esq., of Michigan. Ar-
<br/>ranged for the Piano-forte by H. A. Osborne. Published
<br/>by Ampler.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>‘‘Poor Tom," is a beautiful composition, most admi-
<br/>rably got up by Mr. Nunns ; and the name of Saroni will
<br/>be a guarantee for the other three. But it is of the two
<br/>latter that we wish to speak more particularly. We
<br/>have perused them again and again, and have found
<br/>nothing worth noticing save the titles : the one for its
<br/>miserable lithography, the other for its length. The
<br/>composers of both are amateurs.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The amateurs’ object of publishing compositions is like
<br/>that of a great many brothers of the profession—to satis-
<br/>fy a little vanity—to be thought a genius and prodigy by
<br/>the uninitiated, and to be thought a fool by the knowing
<br/>ones. If it would serve at all to advance the cause of
<br/>music, not a word would we have to say ; but it is just
<br/>the very thing which corrupts musical taste. Publishers
<br/>who are secured from loss, by sufficient exchange with
<br/>other publishers, print anything they can get hold of, pro-
<br/>vided no remuneration, save a few copies, of the piece, is
<br/>asked for it. People will have new music, and not find-
<br/>ing anything good, they get indifferent at last, and take
<br/>whatever the publisher recommends them, as long as a
<br/>showy title adorns the composition. No wonder that
<br/>musicians do not publish their pieces here, when they
<br/>can get, at least, a fair price for them at other places, and
<br/>have no competition with badly lithographed titles and
<br/>and yard-long dedications. Messrs. Hart and Stone’s
<br/>pieces are no better nor worse than hundreds of others ;
<br/>and we are almost sorry that they should be the ones we
<br/>have to vent our spleen at. But let it be a good lesson to
<br/>all amateur composers. We shall not spare them as long
<br/>as we are able to hold a pen, or as long as they do not re-
<br/>form, and study the rules of composition and thorough-
<br/>bass, before publishing anything.</p>
         <p>The Drama.
</p>
         <p>Reports from all parts of the country show a most pros-
<br/>perous condition of affairs throughout the American thea-
<br/>trical world.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In every place, where attraction is even expected,
<br/>houses are crowded ; and new candidates for popular fa-
<br/>vor are constantly pressing forward. During the past
<br/>week the question of the merit and praiseworthiness of
<br/>various foreign performers, has come up in different quar-
<br/>ters.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In the opinion of a portion of the press, a regular de-
<br/>ception is practised on the pockets of the public, by art-
<br/>ists from the old world past their prime or who have
<br/>never attained a prime, from sheer want of faculty. On
<br/>the other hand a claim to supernatural gifts in musical
<br/>and dramatic execution, is claimed by partizans equally
<br/>violent. On all these points we have our own opinion,
<br/>which we shall take occasion to spread at length before
<br/>our readers, hereafter. Among those who have been sub-
<br/>ject of discussion, we find named Mr. Leopold De Meyer</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p309"/>
         </p>
         <p>pianist, Mr. Ole Bull, violinist, Mr. Charles Kean, tra-
<br/>gedian, Mr. Templeton, vocalist. The Sequins also at
<br/>Philadelphia, and the Delcy company, have participated
<br/>in these doubts. These things arc ominous, and when we
<br/>come to consider them, we shall do so without unfair na-
<br/>tional bias, and with reference only to the general stand-
<br/>ards of art and merit. Among the incidents of the past
<br/>week, one of the most striking has been the presentation
<br/>to Mr. Murdoch at Philadelphia, of an elegant copy of
<br/>Shakspeare. It occurred on Friday evening, the night
<br/>of his benefit, before a most brilliant audience, after his
<br/>performance of Hamlet.</p>
         <p>We present the speeches, which embody the purpose
and sentiment of the occasion.
Col. Page, in presenting the volume to Mr. Murdoch,
said:—
</p>
         <p>Mr. Murdoch ,—At the request of numerous friends and some of
<br/>your schoolmates, I am here to-night in the discharge of a pleasing
<br/>duty—that of presenting you with a testimonial of the regard they
<br/>feel for you as a man, and the favorable opinion which they enter-
<br/>tain of your abilities as an Actor.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>It comes in the shape of this superbly bound and approved edition
<br/>of the works of the Immortal Bard, to whose varied and delightful
<br/>creations, in your recent round of performances in this city and
<br/>elsewhere, you have imparted new beauties, and given increased
<br/>interest.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>It is intended by this offering, appropriate as I regard it to be, to
<br/>stimulate you in the highly praiseworthy but arduous task you have
<br/>undertaken, and show that your townsmen, ready as they have ever
<br/>been to patronize merit from abroad, (for mind, Heaven's priceless
<br/>gift to man belongs to no country and is bound by no clime,) can
<br/>never be indifferent to Native Talent, but will always foster and en-
<br/>courage and cheer it onward to a bright and brilliant future.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Allow me then to hand you these beautiful volumes, a deserved
<br/>tribute to personal worth and professional skill. Such a combina-
<br/>tion, aided and guided by Industry and Genius, must command suc-
<br/>cess; they will win for you the proudest chaplet of Histrionic
<br/>Fame, and add another name to the already glorious list of the dis-
<br/>tinguished sons of the Land of the Free and the Home of the Brave.</p>
         <p>To which, Mr. Murdoch replied :—
</p>
         <p>Co... Page:—In accepting this valuable and beautiful copy of
<br/>the works of the great master of the human heart, permit me to ex-
<br/>press my deep sense of gratitude to the kind donors for the gift, and
<br/>to yourself for the generous feelings which prompted you in becom-
<br/>ing the presenter. We are told, sir, that life is a sandy desert, with
<br/>but few green spots in it to cheer the weary traveller. The many
<br/>acts of kindness I have received at the hands of the citizens of Phi-
<br/>ladelphia, from my first appearance before them till the present mo-
<br/>ment, have truly, however, made my desert smile with continued
<br/>verdure, and abound with flowers—sweet and lasting.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This present is doubly dear to mb—first, as it is the page of truth
<br/>and nature, and the field in which I labor; and next, as coming
<br/>from the hands of those who were boys with me, and who now, as
<br/>men. step forward to cheer on an old co-mate through the rugged
<br/>paths which lead to public honors. Their deeds of friendship “are
<br/>registered, where every day I turn the leaf to read them.” May
<br/>heaven bless them, one and all.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>And now, ladies and gentlemen, please accept my thanks for
<br/>your kindness this evening, and during the evenings of the past
<br/>fortnight. Should I ever grow regardless of the deep debt I owe
<br/>my native city, the sight of these volumes, and one glance thrown
<br/>back by memory to this memorable night, and the brilliant array
<br/>befere me, will suffice to awaken all those feelings of gratitude
<br/>and affection with which my heart is now eating, and to the ut-
<br/>terance of which my tongue struggles in vain for expressions of
<br/>deep-seated and heart-felt thankfulness.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>I shall have the pleasure of making .my bow to you, once more,
<br/>tomorrow night, after which I shall leave you for the present,for
<br/>other scenes. Most respectfully, Adieu—tendered, on my part,
<br/>with a full determination to deserve a continuance of your favors.
<br/>Adieu! Adieu!</p>
         <p>Editorial Miscellany.
</p>
         <p>We have to apologize for the insufficient variety of the
<br/>present number. We were not aware of the great length
<br/>of'“ The Spectacles” until too late to remedy the evil.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>As we very confidently expected, our friends in the
<br/>Southern and Western country (true friends, and tried,)
<br/>are taking up arms in our cause—and more especially in
<br/>the cause of a national as distinguished from a sectional
<br/>literature. They cannot see (it appears) any farther ne-
<br/>cessity for being ridden to death by New-England. Hear
<br/>the “Charleston Patriot” :</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Poe’s Poetry.—Mr. Edgar A. Poe is one of the most remarka-
<br/>ble, in many respects, among our men of letters. With singular
<br/>endowments of imagination, he is at the same time largely pos-
<br/>sessed of many of the qualities that go to make an admirable cri-
<br/>tic;—he is methodical, lucid, forcible,—well-read, thoughtful, and
<br/>capable, at all times, of rising from the mere consideration of the
<br/>individual subject, to the principles, in literature and art, by which
<br/>it should be governed. Add to these qualities, as a critic, that he
<br/>is not a person to be overborne and silenced by a reputation;—
<br/>that mere names do not control his judgment;—that he is bold, in-
<br/>dependent, and stubbornly analytical, in the formation of his opin-
<br/>ions. He has his defects also;—he is sometimes the victim of ca-
<br/>pricious moods;—his temper is variable—his nervous organiza-
<br/>tion being such, evidently, as to subject his judgments, sometimes,
<br/>to influences that may be traced to the weather and the winds.—
<br/>He takes his colour from the clouds; and his sympathies are not
<br/>unfrequently chilled and rendered ungenial, by the pressure of the
<br/>atmosphere—the cold and the vapors of a climate affecting his mo-
<br/>ral nature, through his physical, in greater degree than is usual
<br/>among literary men,—who, by the way, are generally far more
<br/>susceptible to these influences, than is the case with the multitude.
<br/>Such are the causes which occasionally operate to impair the value
<br/>and the consistency of his judgments as a Critic.—As a Poet, Mr.
<br/>Poe’s imagination becomes remarkably conspicuous, and to sur-
<br/>render himself freely to his own moods, would be to make all his
<br/>writings in verse, efforts of pure imagination only. He seems to
<br/>dislike the merely practical, and to shrink from the concrete. His
<br/>fancy takes the ascendant in his Poetry, and wings his thoughts to
<br/>such superior elevations, as to render it too intensely spiritual for
<br/>the ordinary reader. With a genius thus endowed and constituted,
<br/>it was a blunder with Mr. Poe to accept the appointment, which
<br/>called him to deliver himself in poetry before the Boston Lyceum.
<br/>Highly imaginative men can scarcely succeed in such exhibitions.
<br/>The sort of poetry called for on such occasions, is the very reverse
<br/>of the spiritual, the fanciful or the metaphysical. To win the ears
<br/>of a mixed audience, nothing more is required than moral or pa-
<br/>triotic common places in rhyming heroics. The verses of Pope are
<br/>just the things for such occasions. You must not pitch your flight
<br/>higher than the penny-whistle elevation of</p>
         <p>“ Know then this truth, enough for man to know,
Virtue alone is happiness below.’’
</p>
         <p>Either this, or declamatory verse,—or something patriotic, or some,
<br/>thing satirical, or something comical. At all events, you must
<br/>not be mystical. You must not task the audience to study. Your
<br/>song must be such as they can read running, and comprehend
<br/>while munching pea-nuts. Mr. Poe is not the writer-for this sort
<br/>of thing. He is too original, too fanciful, too speculative, too any-
<br/>thing in verse, for the comprehension of any but audience fit though
<br/>few' In obeying this call to Boston, Mr. Poe committed another
<br/>mistake. He had been mercilessly exercising himself as a critic
<br/>at the expense of some of their favorite writers. The swans of
<br/>New England, under his delineation, had been described as mere
<br/>geese, and those, too, of none of the whitest. He had been expos-
<br/>ing the short comings and the plagiarisms of Mr. Longfellow,
<br/>who is supposed, along the banks of the Penobscot, to be about the
<br/>comliest bird that ever dipped his bill in Pieria. Poe had dealt
<br/>with the favorites of Boston unsparingly, and they hankered after
<br/>their revenges. In an evil hour, then, did he consent to commit
<br/>himself, in verse to their tender mercies. It is positively amusing</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p310"/>
         </p>
         <p>to see how eagerly all the little witlings of the press, in the old
<br/>purlieus of the Puritan, flourish the cirtical tomahawk about the
<br/>head of their critic. In their eagerness for retribution, one of the
<br/>papers before us actually congratulates itself and readers on the
<br/>(asserted) failure of the poet. The good editor himself was not
<br/>present, but he hammers away not the less lustily at the
<br/>victim, because his objections are to be made at second hand.—
<br/>Mr. Poe committed another error in consenting to address an au-
<br/>dience in verse, who, for three mortal hours, had been compelled to
<br/>sit and hear Mr. Caleb Cushing in prose. The attempt to speak
<br/>after this, in poetry, and fanciful poetry, too, was sheer madness.
<br/>The most patient audience in the world, must have been utterly
<br/>exhausted by the previous infliction. But it is denied that Mr.
<br/>Poe failed at all. He had been summoned to recite poetry. It is
<br/>asserted that he did so. The Boston Courier, one of the most
<br/>thoughtful of the journals of that city, gives us a very favorable
<br/>opinion of the performance which has been so harshly treated.—
<br/>'The Poem,” says that journal, “called ‘ The Messenger Star,’
<br/>was an eloquent and classic production, based on the right princi-
<br/>ples, containing the essence of true poetry, mingled with a gorgeous
<br/>imagination, exquisite painting, every charm of metre, and a
<br/>graceful delivery. It strongly reminded us of Mr. Horne’s
<br/>‘Orion,’ and resembled it in the majesty of its design, the noble-
<br/>ness of its incidents, and its freedom from the trammels of produc-
<br/>tions usual on these occasions. The delicious word-painting of
<br/>some of its scenes brought vividly to our recollection, Keats’
<br/>' Eve of St. Agnes,’ and parts of ‘ Paradise Lost.’</p>
         <p/>
         <p>That it was malapropos to the occasion, we take the liberty to
<br/>deny. What is the use of repeating the ‘ mumbling farce’ of
<br/>having invited a poet to deliver a poem We (too often) find a
<br/>person get up and repeat a hundred or two indifferent couplets of
<br/>words, with jingling rhymes and stale witticisms, with scarcely a
<br/>line of poetry in the whole, and which will admit of no superlative
<br/>to describe it. If we are to have a poem, why not have the ‘ true
<br/>thing,’ that will be recognize! as such,—for poems being written
<br/>for people that can appreciate them, it would be as well to cater
<br/>lor their tastes as for individuals who cannot distinguish between
<br/>the true and the false.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The good sense of this extract should do much towards enforc-
<br/>ing the opinion which it conveys; and it confirms our own, pre-
<br/>viously entertained and expressed, in regard to the affair in ques-
<br/>tion. Mr. Poe’s error was not, perhaps, in making verses, nor
<br/>making them after a fashion of his own; but in delivering them
<br/>before an audience of mixed elements, and just after a discourse
<br/>of three mortal hours by a prosing orator. That any of his hear-
<br/>ers should have survived the two-fold infliction, is one of those in-
<br/>stances of good fortune which should bring every person present
<br/>to his kness in profound acknowledgement to a protecting provi-
<br/>dence.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We thank our friend of "The Patriot” and agree with
<br/>him fully, of course, in all points except his disparage-
<br/>ment of Mr. Cushing, who read us a very admirable dis-
<br/>course. “ The Patriot,” it will be understood, has not
<br/>yet seen our reply of week before last.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Were the question demanded of us—‘‘What is the
<br/>most exquisite of sublunary pleasures ?” we should reply,
<br/>without hesitation, the making a fuss, or, in the classical
<br/>words of a western friend, the “ kicking up a bobbery.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Never was a “bobbery” more delightful than that
<br/>which we have just succeeded in “ kicking up” all around
<br/>about Boston Common. We never saw the Frog-Pond-
<br/>ians so lively in our lives. They seem absolutely to be
<br/>upon the point of waking up. In about nine days the
<br/>puppies may get open their eyes.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>That is to say they may get open their eyes to certain
<br/>facts which have long been obvious to all the world ex-
<br/>cept themselves—the facts that there exist other cities
<br/>than Boston—other men of letters than Professor Long-
<br/>fellow—other vehicles of literary information than the
<br/>“ Down-East Review.”</p>
         <p>As regards our late poem.—Hear the “St, Louis Re-
veille.”
</p>
         <p>“ The Broadway Journal is edited and owned solely by Mr. Ed-
<br/>gar A. Poe. If he had as much tact as talent, he would make suc-
<br/>cess for half a dozen papers.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>So says an exchange paper. Poe, reliant upon his talent, has
<br/>too much contempt for tact; he is wrong, but his error makes his
<br/>career the more remarkable. He is full of eccentricity. Does he
<br/>mean, by the following, that his late Boston Poem, was intended by
<br/>him as a hoax ?</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“We have been quizzing the Bostonians, and one or two of the
<br/>more stupid of their editors and editresses have taken it in high dud-
<br/>geon. We will attend to them all in good time.”</p>
         <p/>
         <p>To our friend Field we thus reply: We had tact
<br/>enough not to be “ taken in and done for” by the Bostoni-
<br/>ans. Timeo Danaos et dona ferentes—(for timeo sub-
<br/>stitute contemno or turn-up-our-nose-o). We knew very
<br/>well that, among a certain clique of the Frogpondians,
<br/>there existed a predetermination to abuse us under any
<br/>circumstances. We knew that, write what we would,
<br/>they would swear it to be worthless. We knew that
<br/>were we to compose for them a “ Paradise Lost,” they
<br/>would pronounce it an indifferent poem. It would have
<br/>been very weak in us, then, to put ourselves to the trou-
<br/>ble of attempting to please these people. We preferred
<br/>pleasing ourselves. We read before them a “juvenile”
<br/>—a very “juvenile” poem—and thus the Frogpondians
<br/>were had—were delivered up to the enemy bound hand
<br/>and foot. Never were a set of people more completely
<br/>demolished. They have blustered and flustered—but
<br/>what have they done or said that has not made them
<br/>more thoroughly ridiculous?—what, in the name of Mo-
<br/>mus, is it possible for them to do or to say ?</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We “ delivered” them the “juvenile poem” and they
<br/>received it with applause. This is accounted for by the
<br/>fact that the clique (contemptible in numbers as in every
<br/>thing else) were overruled by the rest of the assembly.
<br/>These malignants did not dare to interrupt by their pre-
<br/>concerted hisses, the respectful and profound attention of
<br/>the majority. We have been told, indeed, that as many
<br/>as three or four of the personal friends of the little old
<br/>lady entitled Miss Walters, did actually leave the hall
<br/>during the recitation—but, upon the whole, this was the
<br/>very best thing they could do. We have been told this,
<br/>we say—we did not see them take their departure :—the
<br/>fact is they belong to a class of people that we make it a
<br/>point never to see.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The poem being thus well received, in spite of this
<br/>ridiculous little cabal—the next thing to be done was to
<br/>abuse it in the papers. Here, they imagined, they were
<br/>sure of their game. But what have they accomplished ?
<br/>The poem, they say, is bad. We admit it. We insisted
<br/>upon this fact in our prefatory remarks, and we insist
<br/>upon it now, over and over again. It is bad—it is wre'ch-
<br/>ed—and what then ? We wrote it at ten years of age'—
<br/>had it been worth even a pumpkin-pie undoubtedly we
<br/>should not have “delivered” it to them.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>To demonstrate its utter worthlessness, “The Boston
<br/>Star” (a journal which, we presume, is to be considered
<br/>as a fair representative of the Frogpondian genius) has
<br/>copied the poem in full, with two or three columns of
<br/>criticism (we suppose) by way of explaining that we
<br/>should have been hanged for its perpetration. There is
<br/>no doubt of it whatever—we should. “ The Star,” how-
<br/>ever, (a dull luminary) has done us more honor than it
<br/>intended ; it has copied our third edition of the poem,
<br/>revised and improved. We considered this too good for
<br/>the occasion by one half, and so “ delivered” the first
<br/>edition with all its imperfections on its head. It is the
<br/>first—the original edition—the delivered edition—which
<br/>we now republish in our collection of Poems.</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p311"/>
         </p>
         <p>Repelled at these points, the Frogpondian faction hire a
<br/>thing they call the “ Washingtonian Reformer” (or some-
<br/>thing of that kind) to insinuate that we must have been
<br/>“intoxicated” to have become possessed of sufficient au-
<br/>dacity to “ deliver” such a poem to the Frogpondians.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In the first place, why cannot these miserable hypo-
<br/>crites say “ drunk” at once and be done with it ? In the
<br/>second place we are perfectly willing to admit that we
<br/>were drunk—in the face of at least eleven or twelve hun-
<br/>dred Frogpondians who will be willing to take oath that
<br/>we were not. We are willing to admit either that we
<br/>were drunk, or that we set fire to the Frog-pond, or that
<br/>once upon a time we cut the throat of our grandmother.
<br/>The fact is we are perfectly ready to admit any thing at
<br/>all—but what has cutting the throat of our grandmother
<br/>to do with our poem, or the Frogpondian stupidity?
<br/>We shall get drunk when we please. As for the
<br/>editor of the “Jeffersonian Teetotaler” (or whatever
<br/>it is) we advise her to get drunk, too, as soon as possi-
<br/>ble—for when sober she is a disgrace to the sex—on ac-
<br/>count of being so awfully stupid.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>N. B. The “ Washingtonian Teetotaler” is edited by a
<br/>little old lady in a mob-cap and spectacles—at least, we
<br/>presume so, for every second paper in Boston is.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>P. S. Miss Walters (the Syren!) has seen cause, we
<br/>find, to recant all the ill-natured little insinuations she
<br/>has been making against us (mere white lies—she
<br/>need not take them so much to heart) and is now over-
<br/>whelming us with apologies—things which we have
<br/>never yet been able to withstand. She defends our poem
<br/>on the ground of its being “juvenile,” and we think the
<br/>more of her defence because she herself has been juvenile
<br/>so long as to be a judge of juvenility. Well, upon the
<br/>whole we must forgive her—and do. Say no more about
<br/>it, you little darling ! You are a delightful creature and
<br/>your heart is in the right place—would to Heaven that
<br/>we could always say the same thing of your wig !</p>
         <p/>
         <p>In conclusion:—The Frogpondians may as well spare
<br/>us their abuse. If we cared a fig for their wrath we
<br/>should not first have insulted them to their teeth, and
<br/>then subjected to their tender mercies a volume of our
<br/>Poems:—that, we think, is sufficiently clear. The fact is,
<br/>we despise them and defy them (the transcendental vaga-
<br/>bonds !) and they may all go to the devil together.</p>
         <p>To Correspondents.—Many thanks to W. W.—also to
R. S. R.
THIS DAY IS PUHLISHED,
THE 12th NUMBER OF ALEX’R FLETCHER’S
DEVOTIONAL FAMILY BIBLE.
</p>
         <p>Up HIS edition of the Holy Scriptures has already received the ap-
<br/>probation of the American clergy of all denominations. Mr.
<br/>Fletcher’s abilities for the task he has undertaken are well known. 
<br/>The notes, like the engravings, are so contrived as not to interrupt 
<br/>the sacred text. The examination of the work is its best advertise- 
<br/>ment. No. 12 has a beautiful engraving of “ Jepthah’s return.”—
<br/>The 12 numbers already issued show good evidence that the pub-
<br/>lisher’s department will not vary, except for the better. Single
<br/>numbers 25 cents.</p>
         <p>Nov. 21—It.	GEORGE VIRTUE, 26 John street.
G. B. CLARKE,
MERCHANT TAILOR, (from Brundage, Broadway)
No 132 William Street, 3 doors from Fulton, N. Y.
Dress Coat, from $12 to $20 00
Pants,	“	2 50 to 8 00
Vest,	“	1 50 to 4 50
</p>
         <p>Making and Trimming
<br/>Dress Coat, from $6 00 to 9 00
<br/>Pants,	“	1 50 to 2 00</p>
         <p>Vests,	“	1 50 to 2 00
N. B. Seasonable SACK COATS, VESTS, &amp;c. always on
hand, from $1 50 upwards.	nov8—3m
JOHN N.  GENIN,
FASHIONABLE HAT AND CAP ESTABLISHMENT,
211 Broadway.
PIANO FORTES.
</p>
         <p>CHEAP FOR CASH.—The Subscribers have on hand a
<br/>handsome assortment, 6, 61/2, and 7 octave mahogany and rose-
<br/>wood Pianos, which they will warrant and sell low for cash or ap-
<br/>proved paper.	GLENN, ROGERS &amp; CO.,</p>
         <p>Manufacturers, 152 Fulton street, east of Broadway.
General Furnishing Hardware, Cutlery, Tools, &amp;c.
OSBORN &amp; LITTLE,
Importers and General Dealers in English, German and
American
HARDWARE, CUTLERY, &amp;C.,
No. 33 FULTON STREET,
BETWEEN PEARL AND WATER STREETS,
[Where the business has been carried on lor Eighty years past,]
CHARLES OSBORN. )	
CHARLES S. LITTLE. )	NEW YORK.
</p>
         <p>Hardware, Cutlery, Nails, Locks, Latches, Butts, Screws, An-
<br/>vils, Vices, Saws, Files, Shovels and Spades, Hollow Ware, Corn
<br/>and Coffee Mills, Rivets, Pumps, Curriers’ Hones, Crucibles,
<br/>Black Lead, Pots, &amp;c. &amp;c. Also Genuine Haarlem Oil. Ameri-
<br/>can Coopers and Carpenters Edge Tools, of Albertson’s Conger’s
<br/>Barton’s, Horton’s, Gifford’s, and other makers. Also, Cooper’s
<br/>Truss Hoops.	nov8—3m</p>
         <p>GURNEY’S
PREMIUM DAGUERRIAN GALLERY,
189 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.
</p>
         <p>PITCURES taken at this Establishment are not excelled in this
<br/>country—so say his numerous patrons. The public are in-
<br/>vited to call and judge for themselves.	02</p>
         <p>JOHN ANDERSON &amp;. CO.
IMPORTERS AND DEALERS IN
</p>
         <p>CHOICE SEGARS, and Manufacturers of Premium
<br/>Tobacco and Snuffs—a Wall, and 13 and 15 Duane streets
<br/>New-York.	nov8—3m </p>
         <p/>
         <p>WEDDING, VISITING, &amp; PROFESSIONAL CARDS
<br/>Engraved and Printed at VALENTINE’S, 1 Beekman-st,
<br/>Lovejoy’s Hotel.</p>
         <p>CARD OF REMOVAL
</p>
         <p>"MR. W. A. KING PROFESSOR OF MUSIC, AND
<br/>I'l- Teacher of the Piano Forte and Organ, has removed to the
<br/>First House above Twenty-fifth street, on the Railroad, (4th
<br/>Avenue.)</p>
         <p>PENMANSHIP.
Re-opening of goldsmith’s writing academy,
289 Broadway—La Farge Buildings, corner of Reade street!
Terms reduced to three dollars, and.no extra charge.
</p>
         <p>Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the citizens of New
<br/>York and Brooklyn, that his rooms are now open, during the day
<br/>and evening, tor Pupils and Visitors. Mr. G’s. specimens of</p>
         <p/>
         <p>PENMANSHIP
<br/>have received the First Premium Five Years, from (he American
<br/>j Institute, and he guarantees to all in TEN EASY AND INTER-
<br/>ESTING EXERCISES, a free and elegant style of writing, that
<br/>the pupils cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice.</p>
         <p>For sale at the Academy GOLDSMITH’S GEMS OF PEN-
MANSHIP.
Ladies’ Class meets daily at 11 o’clock. Gentleman’s day and
l evening. See circular.	sl8
Parlor ORGAN.
A FINE toned Parlor Organ lor sale or in exchange for a Pia-
no-Forte. Apply to
3w___________EZRA COLLIER, 103 Fulton st.
JAMES PIRSSON,
</p>
         <p>PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER, 88, 90, and 92
<br/>A Walker street, near Elm. A large stock of the finest instru-
<br/>ments always on hand. Terms moderate. For Sale—A splendid
<br/>Harp, nearly new—to be sold at a great bargain lor cash.</p>
         <p>J. Ballard,
PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR, SINGING AND FLUTE.
No. 135 Spring-street.
JOHN BURFORD, 
PORTRAIT AND LANDSCAPE PAINTER,
27 Dey Street.
<a href="#p312"/>
HARPER &amp; BROTHERS’ RECENT PUBLICATIONS,
In one splendidly printed volume, with above 1000 engravings.
Sheep Extra.—Price $3 75.
I.
ENCYCLOPÆDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY.
</p>
         <p>The wide range of topics comprised in this valuable publication,
<br/>commends it to the attention of an unusually extended class of read-
<br/>ers;—to the family circle primarily, the architect, the horticultu-
<br/>rist, the cabinet-maker, and others to whom the work addresses
<br/>itself. It is undoubtedly by far the best work of reference ever pre-
<br/>sented for the use of families. Every housekeeper would find the
<br/>work a real treasure.— Globe.</p>
         <p>PROFESSOR WHEWELL’S ELEMENTS OF MO-
RALITY.
Two volumes 12mo. extra muslin gilt, $1-Forming the com-
mencement of
HARPER’S NEW MISCELLANY,
</p>
         <p>A work of extraordinary merit. It is a thorough discussion of
<br/>the fundamental principles of morals, by one of the profoundest
<br/>thinkers of the age: and whether his conclusions are adopted or
<br/>not, no reader can fail to perceive in any page, the traces of discri-
<br/>mination, thought, and a high moral aim. Its classic purity and
<br/>precision of style is also a strong commendation of the work.—Ob-
<br/>server.</p>
         <p>III.
MORRELL’S AMERICAN SHEPHERD,
</p>
         <p>Being a complete history of the sheep, with their breeds, man-
<br/>agement, dis"ases, &amp;c. Illustrated by numerous engravings, 1
<br/>vol. 12mo., cloth binding, $1—paper covers 75 cents.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ The above named volume, which is issued under the immedi-
<br/>ate sanction of the New Fork State Agricultural Society, is a work
<br/>of great practical importance, and contains a prodigious amount of
<br/>instructive matter, suited to the farmer, the cattle fattener, the agri-
<br/>culturist and the wool-grower. Everyone interested in these de-
<br/>partments of commerce would find the work invaluable.”—Evening
<br/>Gazette.</p>
         <p>IV.
ILLUSTRATED WANDERING JEW.
In numbers; price 25 cents each. Profusely embellished.
</p>
         <p>‘‘We think these illustrations evince more vigor, brilliancy, and
<br/>effect, than almost any thing of the kind we have yet seen. As the
<br/>Harpers publish this revised and elegant edition at such Very tri-
<br/>fling charge, we doubt not a prodigious demand will await it from
<br/>the public; and it richly merits the largest popularity.”—Evening
<br/>Post.</p>
         <p>v.
GEN. GREEN’S
TEXAN EXPEDITION AGAINST MIER,
</p>
         <p>Including the subsequent imprisonment of the author; his suffer-
<br/>ings and final escape from the Castle of Perote; with reflections
<br/>upon the present political and probable future relations of Texas,
<br/>Mexico and the United States, &amp;c. Illustrated by thirteen line en-
<br/>gravings. One volume, 8vo. $2.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This stirring narrative of the perilous and heroic exploits of a
<br/>small band of patriotic Texans, who won not only laurels by their
<br/>prowess, but liberty, is so rife with thrilling interest that it will win
<br/>the attention of the public with the fascination of a romance—
<br/>Com. Adv.</p>
         <p>VI.
CURIOUS AND UNIQUE WORK.
Now ready, in one beautiful octavo volume, with many Engra-
vings on steel, price $2,
NARRATIVE OF A MISSION TO BOKHARA.
In the year 1843-45, to ascertain the fate of Col. Stoddart and
Capt. Conolly.
By the Rev. Joseph Wolff. LL.D.
</p>
         <p>“This work has created a prodigious excitement throughout
<br/>England: it is unique in its character, as a literary production. It
<br/>seems to partake of the features of an autobiography; the narrative
<br/>being full of personal detail, description of the perilous adventure
<br/>and imminent hazard of the author, in his expedition through the
<br/>East. No man living, perhaps, has travelled so extensively as this
<br/>celebrated individual, and few could have contributed a more in
<br/>tensely interesting narrative of his experience.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“It will thus be seen that this extraordinary and eccentric man
<br/>is admirably qualified to present a transcript of Asiatic Character-
<br/>istics,—supplying much that is novel and exceedingly curious
<br/>about tribes and nations of which we know so little. To say that
<br/>the work is an acceptable addition to the library of travel, is affirm-
<br/>ing lar too little of so striking a production: it is a book that ought
<br/>to be read and deliberately enjoyed by every intelligent person, for
<br/>its quaintness, freshness, and superabounding interest. The work
<br/>is elegantly printed as a library book, and adorned by some dozen
<br/>curious fac-similes of oriental drawings.”—Courier and Enquirer.</p>
         <p>IMPORTANT WORKS,
RECENTLY PUBLISHED BY
J. &amp; H. G. LANGLEY, 8 ASTOR HOUSE.
I.
Von- Raumer’s New Work.
</p>
         <p>America and the American People: being the result of the au-
<br/>thor’s recent travels through the United States. Translated from
<br/>the German of Frederick Von Raumer, by Professor Wm. W.
<br/>Turner. 1 vol. 8 vo. 530 pp. Price $2.</p>
         <p>II.
Eliza Cook’s Poetical Works.
</p>
         <p>New Edition, containing all her recent productions. Edited by
<br/>Rufus W. Griswold. 1 vol. 12 mo., illustrated with a Portrait and
<br/>twelve exquisite English engravings. Conies in Morocco, super
<br/>$3 50—Cloth Gilt, $2 50.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“This is a beautiful volume, splendidly bound, and still more
<br/>elegantly illustrated, and combining some of the choicest poems in
<br/>the language. The “ Old Arm Chair,” is one of the most popular
<br/>poems, and has touched the hearts of thousands who never knew
<br/>even the name of the author. She writes for the heart, and her
<br/>beautiful songs always reach it. The book forms one of the most
<br/>elegant holiday presents yet offered.”—Cour. &amp; Enq.</p>
         <p>III.
MISS Barrett’s Poems.
The Drama of Exile, and other Poems, by Elizabeth B. Barrett.
2 vols. 12 mo., elegantly printed.—$2 00.
</p>
         <p>“Miss Barrett is worth a dozen of Tennyson, and six of Mother-
<br/>well—equal perhaps in orignial genius to Keats and Shelley.—
<br/>There are beauties enough in one of her poems to have made a
<br/>fame in Waller’s time.”—Willis’ Evening Mirror.</p>
         <p>IV.
Gregg’s Santa Fe and the Prairies.
</p>
         <p>Commerce of the Prairies, or the Journal of a Santa Fe Trader,
<br/>the personal observation of a trader, made on eight several ex
<br/>ditions across the Great Western Prairies, and during an aim
<br/>uninterrupted residence of nine years in Northern Mexico.—Illus-
<br/>trated with numerous engravings. New Edition, revised by
<br/>Author. By Josiah Gregg. 2 vols. 12 mo. $2 00.</p>
         <p>V.
M. DE TOCQUEVILLE’S GREAT WORK.
</p>
         <p>Democracy in America, by Alexis De Tocqueville. Third edi-
<br/>tion, in 2 vols. 8vo. Corrected and Enlarged, with an Original In-
<br/>dex. Translated by Henry Reeve, Esq., with Introductory Pre-
<br/>faces, by. the Hon. John C. Spencer. Price $4 00 in muslin or
<br/>sheep.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“ This work is one of the most profound and philosophical ever
<br/>written upon the character and institutions of our country.”—
<br/>Boston Traveller.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“As a study of political science, this book stands unrivalled in
<br/>our times; equally remarkable for lucidity of style, acuteness and
<br/>delicacy of reasoning, and lor the moral and intellectual vigor with
<br/>which it has been conceived and completed.”—London Times.</p>
         <p>VI.
DE TOCQUEVILLE ABRIDGED.
</p>
         <p>Designed for District School Libraries, Colleges, &amp;c. In accor-
<br/>dance with the recommendation of several superintendents of Dis-
<br/>trict Schools, the Publishers beg to announce that they have just
<br/>issued a condensed edition of the above standard work, adapted ex-
<br/>pressly for the use of District Schools, Colleges, &amp;c., to form 1 vol.
<br/>12mo. Price $1 00.</p>
         <p>VII.
The Life of General Francis Marion.
</p>
         <p>By W. Gilmore Simms, author of “Guy Rivers.” &amp;c. &amp;c.
<br/>Seventh edition, revised by the author, with numerous engravings,
<br/>1 vol. 12mo.—$1. “Few characters have stood out more boldly
<br/>on our Revolutionary Annals, or have supplied more interesting
<br/>and exciting materials for the historian, than that of Gen. Marion ;
<br/>and it is not saying too much to claim for the work before us no
<br/>less the merit of accredited historical truth, than the most stirring
<br/>and absorbing attributes of high-wrought fiction.”—Democratic
<br/>Review.</p>
         <p>VIII.
The Poetical Works of Praed.
</p>
         <p>Lillian, and other Poems, Fanciful and Facetious. By William
<br/>Mackworth Praed. First collected edition: Edited by R. W.
<br/>Griswold, 1 vol. 12mo muslin. $1 25.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>“Praed was the Poet of Society, ‘a fellow of infinite humor,’
<br/>and in scholarship and art, surpassed by none of the English poets
<br/>of the age. Though many of his pieces have been almost univer-
<br/>sally read in this country, they have never yet been printed col-
<br/>lectively, either here or in England.”—Democratic Review.</p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
</p>
         <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to Du-
<br/>bois and Stodart,) No. 385 Broadway, will keep a compute
<br/>assortment of the latest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of
<br/>the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for
<br/>their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, and to en-
<br/>dure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices.
<br/>Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on hire.</p>
         <p>
            <a href="#p313"/>
DENTISTRY.
</p>
         <p>DOCT. H. E. SCHOONMAKER, Dental Surgeon, Office 446
<br/>Houston St., two doors from Broadway—opposite St. Thomas’
<br/>Church.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Doct. S’s experience and skill in his profession, give him con-
<br/>fidence in asserting that his operations are unsurpassed by any
<br/>Dentist in this city. Dr. S.’s manner of inserting artificial teeth
<br/>varies in many essential points from the usual mode ; and his suc-
<br/>cess in pleasing all, he is happy to say, has brought him many
<br/>difficult cases, which had been unsuccessfully treated by Dentists
<br/>of established professional reputation, and whose prices for the
<br/>same operation were double his own. The object in inserting
<br/>artificial teeth is to supply the deficiency occasioned by the loss of
<br/>natural teeth, both in regard to utility, comfort in wearing, and
<br/>natural appearance. In all these points, Doct S.’s manner is pre-
<br/>eminent. His mechanical tact and ingenuity have enabled him to
<br/>surmount many obstacles, which have long, with the profession
<br/>generally, impeded the path to success in every operation. He
<br/>makes use of the best materials in all his operations—and in cases
<br/>where the gum has fallen away by absorption, (which is always
<br/>the case, more or less, when teeth have been extracted,) which
<br/>causes a contraction of the lips and cheeks, the disfigurement of
<br/>which cannot be fully obviated without adopting the artificial gums,
<br/>which will supply the deficiency, and give to the mouth its usual
<br/>redundancy—besides, their beauty and natural appearance, ren-
<br/>der detection impossible.</p>
         <p>Dr. S. would be happy to refer those who require it, to many of
the best families in this City, in which he has practised.
Ladies who desire it, can have their teeth examined at their re-
sidences, by sending their address as above.	nov. 8—9t
PAINE &amp; BURGESS,
6 2 John Street,
WILL PUBLISH - IN A FEW DAYS,
</p>
         <p>THE ARTIST, MERCHANT, AND STATESMAN,
<br/> Part I. This work is made up of the choicest and most ori-
<br/>ginal material on Fine Arts, Commerce, and Political Economy,
<br/>by C. Edwards Lester.</p>
         <p>PRAIRIEDOM; Rambles and Scrambles in Texas or
</p>
         <p>New Estremadura, by a Southron. 1 vol. l2 mo. with a map. “ It
<br/>is light and vivacious—filled with incident—easy and flowing in
<br/>style, and brilliant in imagery.”—Evening Mirror</p>
         <p>THEY ARE PREPARING FOR PUBLICATION,
Sorgs and Ballads by Gen. G. P. Morris, 32 mo. gilt.
</p>
         <p>Rambles by Land and Water, or Notes of Travel in Cuba and
<br/>Mexico, including a canoe voyage up the river ,Panuco, and Re-
<br/>searches among the Antiquaries of Taumelipas, by B M. Norma,
<br/>1 vol. I2 mo. illustrated.</p>
         <p>The Greece of the Greeks, by G. A. Perdicaris, U. S. Consul at
Athens, 2 vols. 12mo. illustrated.
Trippings in Authorland, by Fanny Forrester.
Montezuma, the Last of the Aztecs, an Historical Romance, on
the Conquest of Mexico, by Edward Maturin, 2 vols. 12mo.
“ This is an original American work.”
The Prince, by Machiavelli, l vol. l2mo.
Man in the Republic, by C. Mathews, l vol. 32mo. gilt.
The Old Continental, or the Prince of Liberty—an historical
romance, by the author of the ‘Dutchman’s Fireside, 2 vols. 12mo.
—NOW READY—
The Medici Series of Italian Prose.
The Autobiography of Alfieri, 1 vol. 12mo Price 50 cents.
T he Secret Thoughts and Actions of Genius, blended with the
wildest adventures and strongest caprices.
The Citizen of a Republic; what are his rights and duties, by
Ansaldo Ceba, 1 vol. l2mo. Price 50 cents.
“ A book of condensed and rare thoughts, like diamonds finely
polished and richly set.”
Tne Challenge of Barletta, a romance of the Times of the Me-
dici, l vol. I2mo.
“ A gem gathered from the jewelled mine of Italian romance.'’
The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli, 2 vols. 12mo.
" The charmed records of the classic city of the Arno, by the
master spirit of his age.”	nov 8
TO MEDICAL MEN.
This day published, the London lancet
</p>
         <p>for November, a Journal ol British, Foreign, Medical and
<br/>Chemical Science, Criticism and News—edited by Thomas Wake-
<br/>ly, M. P. Surgeon, and Henry Bennett, M. D.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>This is the fifth number of the second volume, containing, be-
<br/>sides its usual quantity of valuable matter, the 2d Lecture of a se-
<br/>ries of Lectures on Organic Chemistry, by Justus Liebig.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Also, lour additional Lectures on the Mechanism and Manage-
<br/>ment of Natural and Difficult Labors, by Edward W. Murphy, 
<br/>A.M. M.D.</p>
         <p>Terms—$5 per annum, in advance; single numbers 50 cents,
mailed to any part of the United States, by
BURGESS, STRINGER &amp; CO.
222 Broadway, cor. Ann st.
P. S.—The postage to any distance on the Lancet is 6 1/2 cts.
CHEAP MUSIC.
HOMANS &amp; ELLIS have published the first No. of
THE MUSICAL WORLD,
</p>
         <p>A Semi-monthly Magazine, containing sixteen pages of beauti-
<br/>fully printed Music, and a Journal of Musical Biography, Criti-
<br/>cism, and News.</p>
         <p>Edited by Henry C. Watson.—-Contents of No. 1.
I'll be there,—-words by Fitzball—music by Herbert Rodwell.
Let no thought of care oppress thee,—words by Charles Jeffreys—
music by Bellini.
Far away in my own bright land,—	“	« Bellini.
O cast that shadow from thy brow—a beautiful ballad.
The sunny hours of childhood,—words by J. L. Carpenter—music
by J. Hanoway, R. A.
The melodies of many lands,—words by Charles Jeffreys—music
by C. W. Glover.
Price 25 Cents.
The second number of the Musical World will be published on
the 15th inst.
In Press—Grand Galop, by Leopold De Meyer, with a portrait
and critical biography, will be ready early next week.
WILEY &amp; PUTNAM
</p>
         <p>PROPOSE to supply, if there is sufficient patronage,
<br/>the original London editions of the following Periodicals at
<br/>the prices annexed, to be mailed in London.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Periodicals will be put in strong wrappers with printed ad-
<br/>dress, and can be sent to any part of the United States ; so that they
<br/>may be received as soon as the letters per Boston Steamers.</p>
         <p>All persons wishing to subscribe will please address Wiley &amp;
Putnam before the first of December next.
Subscriptions must be paid in all cases in advance.
</p>
         <p>Edinburgh Review, $3 50
<br/>Foreign Quarterly Review, 3 50
<br/>Westminster Review, 3 50
<br/>Forbes’ Medical Review, 4 00
<br/>Frazer’s Magazine,	5	00</p>
         <p>dec 13—3t
Quarterly Review, $3 50
North British Review, 	3	50
</p>
         <p>For. &amp; Colonial Review, 3 50
<br/>Blackwood’s Magazine, 5 00
<br/>Presbyterian Review, 3 50</p>
         <p>NEW WORKS,
TO BE PUBLISHED BY
MESSRS. WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 BROADWAY,
IN THE MONTH OF NOVEMBER
I.
Western Clearings, by Mrs. C. M. Kirkland, author of “ A New
Home." &amp;c. 1 vol. l6mo. 50 cents.
II.
The Raven and other Poems, by Edgar A. Poe, 1 vol.l6mo. 31 cts.
III.
Views and Reviews in American History, Literature, and Fiction
by W. Gilmore Simms 1 vol. 16 mo.
IV.
Life of the Great Condé, by Lord Mahon, 2 vols. 16mo. 37J
cents each.
V.
Charles Lamb's Specimens of English Dramatic Poets, 2 vols.
16mo. 50 cents each.
VI.
The Rhine, by Victor Hugo.
VII.
Father Ripa's Residence in China, 1 vol. 16mo. 37 cts.
VIII.
The Fall of the Jesuits, 1 vol. 16 mo. 37 1/2 cts.
IX.
Lectures on the English Poets, by Wm. Hazlitt. l6mo. 1 vol.
KNOX’S HATS.
</p>
         <p>THE FALL STYLE OF GENTLEMEN’S HATS are now
<br/>ready for the season, 1845, which for lightness and superiority
<br/>of color cannot be surpassed, which is a very important part of the
<br/>hat, retaining the color till it is worn out. Any article sold in this
<br/>establishment is never misrepresented but sold for what it is. Al-
<br/>so the (all style of boy’s and children’s Caps, of various patterns.
<br/>Gentlemen can have their hats made lo order in any shape or style
<br/>they wish. A full assortment of ladies’ Muffs, of all kinds.</p>
         <p>C KNOX, No. 110 Fulton st.,
Nov. 8—3m	between William and Nassau sis.
UNITED STATES HOTEL.
</p>
         <p>THE PROPRIETOR Of THIS HOTEL, desires to return his
<br/>thanks to his (rends, and the travelling portion of the commu-
<br/>nity generally, for the favors which they have bestowed upon him
<br/>since he opened his Establishment, and to assure them that he will
<br/>spare no exertions to render his House worthy of the patronage of
<br/>which he has already received so liberal a share.</p>
         <p>		H. JOHNSON.
Nov. 8th, 1845.	6m
<a href="#p314"/>
CATALOGUE OF TEAS,
ON SALE AT THE TEA WAREHOUSE OF THE
PEKIN TEA COMPANY,
Importers of fine Green and Black Teas, No. 75 Fulton-st.
New York.
</p>
         <p>[The Teas mentioned in this Catalogue are done up in quarter,
<br/>half pound, and pound packages—the first, or inside wrapper is lead,
<br/>the second wrapper is water proof paper, and the third or outside
<br/>wrapper is of Chinese Rice paper. The Company sell none but
<br/>good Teas, done up in this superior manner, all of them grown in
<br/>the most luxurious districts in China, Country dealers can select
<br/>as small a quantity of each kind as they like and have them packed
<br/>in one chest. These Teas also come in five pound Chinese pack-
<br/>ages, called quattoons, a very convenient, fanciful and portable
<br/>shape.]</p>
         <p>Green Teas:
Young Hyson, sweet cargo, 50
do.	do.	do. do.	finer	62 1/2
do.	do.	finer cargo,	75
do.	do.	extra fii:e,	87	 1/2
do. do. Silver Leaf,	1 00
</p>
         <p>Si ver Leaf—Seldom sold even
<br/>by large dealers, because of the
<br/>very small profits made on its
<br/>sale. This is a very superior
<br/>tea.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>do. do. Golden Chop, Plantation
<br/>or Garden growth, 1 50
<br/>Golden Chop—This is the finest
<br/>(»ree« Ten cultivated in China.
<br/>It is of the first pickings, and ex
<br/>cels all other Green teas for its
<br/>delicacy of flavor, strength and
<br/>aroma. Heretofore this tea has
<br/>never reached this country, ex-
<br/>cept in small lots, as presents to
<br/>importers.</p>
         <p>Hyson,* very fine,	75
do. Plantation growth, 1	00
GUNPOWDER, good,	—
</p>
         <p>do.  superior, (Read "Mon-
<br/>strous fraud” below.) 1 00
<br/>do. small leaf, plantation</p>
         <p>growth,	1	25
Imperial, good,	—
</p>
         <p>do. brisk and fragrant,[read
<br/>“monstrous fraud” be-
<br/>low,}	1	00</p>
         <p>do. curious leaf, very supe-
rior,	1 	25
Hyson Skin, good, fine flavor,	38
do. do. extra fine,	62 1/2
Black Teas.
Pouchong, good, full flavor,	38
do.	fine,	50
do.	very superior,	75
Souchong, good,	38
do.	extra fine,	50
Oolong, strong, flavor fine,	50
</p>
         <p>Oolong—This tea is a great favor-
<br/>ite, and gives universal satisfac
<br/>tion.</p>
         <p>do.	very fine,	62 1/2
do.	in one pound	and half
pound cattys, extra fine, 75
Ne Plus Ultra,	l 50
</p>
         <p>Ne Plus Ultra—This tea is as
<br/>fragrant and sweet as a nosegay.
<br/>It yields a perfume that is truly
<br/>delightful. It is of garden growth,
<br/>and superior to any thing of the
<br/>kind ever sold in this country.</p>
         <p>English Breakfast Tea, very
hue,	50
</p>
         <p>do. dy. do. in one
<br/>pound and half pound cat-
<br/>tys,	62 1/2</p>
         <p>Howqua’s Mixture, a strong and
rich black tea, Pekoe flavor, 75
Congo, good,	37 1/2
do. very fine,	50
vekkoe Flowers, good,	87 1/2
do. do. garden growth, 1 50
</p>
         <p>*Caution. —Large quantities of Hyson Skin are retailed in
<br/>this market as being a Hyson Tea. It is well worth while to com-
<br/>pare the Hyson tea usually sold at 75 cents with the genuine arti-
<br/>cle that the Company offer at the same price. The difference is so
<br/>perceptible on trial as to render any further comment unnecessary.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Monstrous Fraud.—Gunpowder and Imperial Teas cannot be
<br/>retailed by small dealers,'in this country, at 75 cents per pound,
<br/>because they frequently cost that money in China, and no Importer
<br/>in this city can sell good Gunpowder or Imperial Tea at a less
<br/>price than 75 cents per pound by the hundred packages. T. F.
<br/>Davies, Esq., in his interesting work on China, details the manner
<br/>in which he saw the lowest grades of Black Teas manufactured
<br/>and colored with Prussian Blue, so as to closely imitate Gunpow-
<br/>der and Imperial Teas, and adds, the Prussian Blue being a com-
<br/>bination of Prussic Acid with Iron, is of course a dangerous poi-
<br/>son. Let purchasers therefore beware of adulterated teas, and
<br/>deal with those venders whose characters and resources raise them
<br/>above suspicion. Beware of the Gunpowder and Imperial Teas
<br/>retailed at 75 cents per pound, and compare them with the genuine
<br/>article sold by the Pekin Tea Company No one, it is presumed,
<br/>wishes to drink poison. The Company have published a book,
<br/>giving full details on this subject, which may be had at their
<br/>Warehouse, 75 Fulton street, free of charge.</p>
         <p>RECOMMENDATIONS.
</p>
         <p>W3 drink Green Ten, and for many years have been paying one dollar per
<br/>pound for it. But thinks to the Pekin Tea Company, we now get a better tea
<br/>from them at 75 cents per pound. We drink one pound per week, by which
<br/>we are now saving thirteen dollars per year, and enjoying better tea in the
<br/>bargain. Commend us to the Pekin Tea Company, say we.—Mirror.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street, are performing a great and good
<br/>work, and will, in a few years, beyond all doubt, drive all the poor teas which
<br/>have deluged this country, pud defrauded consumers of the article, out of the
<br/>market. They import none but pure and fragrant teas, and detail them by the
<br/>single pound at wholesale prices. Families are always sure of obtaining good
<br/>teas at this great tea warehouse, in quantities to suit their convenience, and at
<br/>the same price that the merchant pays who buys to sell it gain.—Daily True
<br/>Sun.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>You may be sure of obtaining at all times, ppure and highly flavored teas, by
<br/>the single pound, at wholesale prices, of the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton
<br/>street.—They have probably the largest stock, and greatest variety of fine
<br/>green and black teas, of any one establishment in the United States. They
<br/>are doing a large business, and a great benefit to consumers of tea.—Atlas.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Heretofore it has been very difficult, indeed impossible, to always obtain
<br/>good green and black teas. But now you have only to visit the ware rooms of
<br/>the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street, to obtain as delicious and fragrant
<br/>teas as you could wish for.—Daily Sun.</p>
         <p>If any of our readers desire to have good tea, they can obtain it of the Pekin
Tea Company, 75 Fulton street.—Mercury.
A Word to Tea Drinkers.—The Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street,
</p>
         <p>have imported into this market some five hundred thousand dollars worth of
<br/>the finest grades of Green and Black Teas grown in the Celestial Empire, done
<br/>up in all the various fancy packages that Chinese ingenuity can invent. It is
<br/>a privilege to buy teas at this great establishment, and a luxury and comfort
<br/>to drink them They sell good teas only, and retail them at wholesale prices.
<br/>Country met chants who wish to always sell good teas can always obtain them
<br/>at this place, on reasonable terms.—Emporium.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>The Pekin Tea Company—We very cheerfully call the attention of all
<br/>lovers of pure and fragrant Teas, both in town and country, to the great Tea
<br/>warehouse of this Company. Our long acquaintance with the proprietors en-
<br/>ables us to bespeak for them the entire confidence of the public. We know
<br/>that their Teas, both in quality and price, are all that is stated of them. Many
<br/>a lover of the fragrant herb has been compelled to eschew the drinking of Tea
<br/>in consequence of its injurious effects, until at length he has become hopeless
<br/>of finding, among any of the imported varieties of Tea in our market, a kind
<br/>which had not such an effect. Xu this, however, such persons will be agree-
<br/>ably disappointed. The Pekin Tea Company have commenced the importation
<br/>of choice varieties of Garden Teas, of most delicious flavor-cultivated and
<br/>picked with great care, which have heretofore never been introduced into this
<br/>country, except as presents to importers. Among these they have, an Oolong,
<br/>mild as zephyr, and fragrant as a rose, which we especially recommend to all
<br/>nervous persons. Its effect upon many of those who have tried it, has been
<br/>to make them confirmed tea-drinkers. Ladies who have used it, say they
<br/>never before drank such tea. But all testes can here be suited, with the great
<br/>advantage over other stores of getting a pure article at wholesale price, how-
<br/>ever small the quantity. The Company's Warehouse is at 75 Fulton street.—
<br/>New World.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>Tea.—The Pekin Tea Company, No 75 Fulton street, unquestionably sell
<br/>the best teas imported into this market. That they sell them cheaper than any
<br/>other establishment, is a fact proven in a thousand instances since they have
<br/>opened their store.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We would advise our friends to call at this place, and if they don’t wish to
<br/>buy at least to obtain a little pamphlet, kept on their counter, entitled “ Hints
<br/>to Tea Drinkers,” and therefrom learn a little useful information on the subject.</p>
         <p>The pamphlet is given gratis.—Anglo American.
</p>
         <p>The finest specimens of green and black teas ever sold in this country, are
<br/>imported by the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street. Those who want good
<br/>teas at reasonable prices, can always get them there.—Tribune.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>We have tried the teas imported by the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street,
<br/>and if we live will try them often. They are selling the most delicious teas
<br/>we ever drank, and retail them at wholesale prices.—Evening Post. oct8</p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
</p>
         <p>V. F. HARRISON, 23 CANAL STREET, N. Y.—In-
<br/>struments made with the most recent improvement, such as
<br/>Iron Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are
<br/>made from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most
<br/>faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the busi-
<br/>ness.</p>
         <p>N. B.—Wanted a second hand Parlor Organ.
Piano Fortes hired by the month.
ÆOLIAN ATTACHMENT.
</p>
         <p>HERMANN S. SARONI, PROFESSOR OF MUSIC,
<br/>116 Leonard street, New-York, teaches the Piano-Forte, with
<br/>or without Coleman’s celebrated Attachment.</p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
</p>
         <p>H. WORCESTER, No. 139 THIRD AVENUE, COR-
<br/>ner of 14th Street, respectfully informs his friends and the
<br/>public, that he has a good assortment of Piano-Fortes, in Rose-
<br/>wood and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons wishing
<br/>to purchase will find it to their advantage to call and examine be-
<br/>fore purchasing elsewhere.</p>
         <p/>
         <p>To the Public.—Edgar A. Poe, Esq. having purcha-
<br/>sed my interest in “ The Broadway Journal,” is now sole
<br/>proprietor of the same. All persons indebted to the pa-
<br/>per will please make settlement with him.</p>
         <p>John Bisco.
New-York, Oct. 24, 1845.
THE BROADWAY JOURNAL:
Edgar A. Poe,	 Editor and Proprietor,
IS PUBLISHED EVERY SATURDAY.—OFFICE 135 NASSAU ST.
TERMS THREE DOLLARS PER ANNUM—SINGLE NUMBERS SIX AND A QUARTER CTS.
</p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal is, in its general character, a literary pa-
<br/>per; occupying itself with original, and more especially with critical
<br/>articles, in every department of Literature, properly so called—with
<br/>a preference, nevertheless, for the Belles L e t t r e s and the
<br/>Fine Arts. There is no better medium in the country for
<br/>literary or artistical advertisements.</p>
         <p>AGENTS :
Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass.
</p>
         <p>R. G. H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct.
<br/>M. Baulleinet, Mobile, Ala.
<br/>Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O.</p>
         <p>D. M. Dewey, Rochester, N Y.
J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.
W. B. Russell, Schentectady, N. Y.
Levi Willard, Troy, N. Y.
G. Jones, Albany. N. Y.
</p>
         <p>S. F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y.
<br/>Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore, Md.
<br/>Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.</p>
         <p>Thos. H. Pease, New-Haven, Ct.
J C. Morgan, New-Orleans.
W. W. Kingsley, New-London, Ct.
G.	N. Beesley, Utica, N. Y.
H.	B. Strang, Peekskill, N. Y.
</p>
         <p>Ha iburton &amp; Dudley Boston, Maas.
<br/>S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass.
<br/>Peter Cooke, Hartford, Ct.</p>
         <p>H. Esten, Providence, R. I.
Safford &amp; Park, Norwich. Ct.
John Tomlin, P. M. Jackson. Tenn.
S. Hart, Sen., Charleston, S. C.
PRINTED AT THE OFFICE OP THE PARMER AND MECHANIC.
</p>
      </div>
        </div>
   <div class="back">
          
        </div>
</div>
