<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            VOL. I. NO. 12.
            Three Dollars per Annum.
            Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
            NEW YORK, SATURDAY, MARCH 22, 1845.
            C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.
            
         </p>
         <p>Published at
            153 BROADWAY, by
            John Bisco.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding , whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</p>
         <p>Locke.
            REVIEWS.
            Eӧthen, or Traces of Travel brought Home from the East. No. 1, of Wiley
            &amp; Putnam’s Library of Choice Reading.
            
         </p>
         <p>If the days of “ cheap and nasty” literature are not ended,
            we have proof before us that the day of cheap and elegant
            literature has at least dawned. Eӧthen is the first of a series of reprints and original works, commenced by Wiley &amp;
            Putnam, which is recommended by a novel elegance of form,
            and a tempting lowness of price. It argues little for the intelligence of our cheap publishers, that they should have allowed so attractive a work as Eӧthen to escape their hands
            so long. Some of them have deluged the market with two
            shilling novels of every variety, Swedish, French, and English, since it appeared in England, but they have not thought
            it worth their while to offer it to the reading public; it shows
            very plainly their own want of intelligence or their want ol
            faith in the intelligence of the people, the Native Americans,
            for whose benefit they publish their Countess Faustinas and
            Wandering Jews. The greater part of our publishers appear to have a singular taste in books: Scotch philosophy and
            French romance, watered with a pretty constant stream from
            Mr. James’s pump, form the grand staple of their trade,
            good English works, excepting in the shape of historical novels, or novel-like histories, they carefully eschew, and were
            it not for the enterprise, or liberal daring of some ofl our publishers in Broadway, we should know nothing of many of
            the best books which are issued from the British press.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A gentleman asked one of the great publishers a few
            months since why they did not publish Dr. Arnold s life and
            correspondence ? " Would you ruin us?” replied the sagacious book-dealer with a stare. But the Appletons have
            since done the public the service to publish this excellent
            Work, and have risked the chance of ruin. Legally speaking, book-publishers have an unquestionable right to put
            forth only such books as they like, as a baker has an unquestionable right to sell nothing but sour bread, and we have no
            doubt that there are people all ready to snub us up, for pretending to insinuate that anybody, but especially publishers
            of books, should be called to account fordoing what the law
            allows. We submit to the snub, merely begging the privilege of hinting that there are two kinds of law, the law of
            God, and the law of man, and that it is possible to break one
            while you observe the other.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Eӧthen is a reprint of the most brilliant book of travels that
            has appeared in England since the time of Childe Harold.
            Teeming, as the English press does, with works on the
            East, the superior brilliancy of Eӧthen has eclipsed them all.
            The author's name is not given, but he is known, as a matter of course, at home. The great marvel of his book is that 
            it should hare remained so long unpublished, and that the,
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>master of so fine a style and so lively an imagination should
            have kept his peace until now. It was nine years after his
            return from the East before his book was published ; our
            travellers begin to publish the day after they leave home,
            and give us their sketches as they proceed.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Eӧthen begins at Emlin. If the author did not speak as a
            man, we should think from the ease, the grace, the rapidity
            of the style, that Eӧthen was the work of a woman, a better
            sort of Mrs. Gore or George Sand.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There is a vein of infidelity running through the book, but
            it is infidelity to conventionalisms and not to pure faith ; it
            may frighten the timid or offend straight-laced moralists, but
            it will do no harm to the innocent and pure minded. It is
            just the work required to put into the hands of those who
            have overburdened their memories with the lifeless statistics
            of other travellers in the East. It puts life into the mummies that have been brought to us from the Orient, and puts
            words into the mouths of the mummies from whom we have
            been trying to gather knowledge of a country that we cannot visit. It is, indeed, what its name implies, the East, and
            we lay down the book half persuaded that we have in reality been mingling with the Osmanli and the Arab of the desert.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Our limits will permit us to make but a few short extracts
            which will give an idea of the author’s liveliness of fancy and
            elegance of style.
         </p>
         <p>THE DELIGHTS OF FREEDOM.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ The course of the Jordan is from the north to the south and in
            that direction, with very little of devious winding, it carries the shining waters of Galilee straight down into the solitudes of the Dead Sea"
            Speaking roughly; the river in that meridian, is a boundary between
            the people living under roofs, and the tented tribes that wander on the
            farther side. And so, as I went down in my way from Tiberias towards Jerusalem, along the western bank of the stream, my thinking
            all propended to the ancient world of herdsmen, and warriors that
            lay so close over my bridle arm.
         </p>
         <p>	“ If a man, and an Englishman, be not bom of his mother with a
            
         </p>
         <p>natural Chiffney-bit in his mouth, there comes to him a time for loathing the wearisome ways of society—a time for not liking tamed people—a time for not dancing quadrilles—not sitting in pews—a time
            for pretending that Milton, and Shelley, and all sorts of mere dead
            people, w re greater in death than the first Lord of the Treasury—a
            time in short for scoffing and railing—for speaking lightly of the very
            opera, and all our most cherished institutions. It is from nineteen to
            two or three and twenty perhaps, that this war of the man against
            men is like to be waged most sullenly. You are yet in this smiling
            England, but you find yourself wending away to the dark sides of her
            mountains,—climbing the dizzy crags,—exulting in the fellowship of
            mists and clouds, and watching the storms how they gather, or prov.
            ing the mettle of your mare upon the broad and dreary downs, because"
            that you feel congenially with the yet unparcelled earth. A little
            while you are free, and unlabelled, like the ground that you compass
            but Civilisation Is coming, and coming r you, and your much loved
            waste lands will be surely enclosed, and sooner, or later, you will be
            brought down to a state of utter usefulness—the ground will be curiously sliced into acres, and roods, and perches, and you, for all you sit so
            smartly in your saddle, you will be caught—you will be taken up from
            travel as a colt from grass, to be trained, and tired, and matched and
            run. All this in time, but first come continental tours, and the moody
            longing for Eastern travel; the downs and moors of England can hold
            you no longer; with larger stride you burst away from these slips and
            patches of free land—you thread your path through the crowds of
            Europe, and at last on the banks of the Jordan, you joyfully know that
            you are upon the frontier of all accustomed respectabilities. There on
            the other side of the river (you can swim it with one arm), there reigns
            the people that will be like to put you to death for not being a vagrant
            for not being a robber, for not being armed, and houseless. There is
            comfort in that—health, comfort, and strength to one who is dying
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page178"></div>
            from very weariness of that poor, dear, middle-aged, deserving, ac-
            complished, pedantic, and pains-taking governess Europe.
            • •••••••
            
         </p>
         <p>“ The Jordan is not a perfectly accurate boundary betwixt roofs
            and tents, for soon after passing the bridge I came upon a cluster of
            huts. Some time afterwards the guide, upon being closely questioned
            by my servants, confessed that the village which we had left behind
            was the last that we should see, but he declared that he knew a spot
            at which we should find an encampment of friendly Bedouins, who
            would receive me with all hospitality. I had long determined not to
            leave the East without seeing something of the wandering tribes, but I
            had looked forward to this as a pleasure to be found in the Desert between El Arish and Egypt—I had no idea that the Bedouins on the
            East of Jordan were accessible. My delight was so great at the near
            prospect of bread and salt in the tent of an Arab warrior, that I
            wilfully allowed my guide to mislead me; I saw that he was taking
            me out of the straight route towards Jerusalem, and was drawing
            me into the midst of the Bedouins, but the idea of his betraying me
            seemed (I know not why) so utterly absurd, that I could not entertain it for a moment: 1 fancied it possible that the fellow had taken
            me out of my route in order to attempt some little mercantile enterprise with the tribe for which he was seeking, and I was glad of
            the opportunity which 1 might thus gain of coming in contact with the
            wanderers.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ For the rest of the day we saw no human being ; we pushed on eagerly with the hope of coming up with the Bedouins before nightfall.
            Night came, and still we went on our way till about ten o’clock. Then
            came the thorough darkness of the night, and the weariness of our
            beasts (which had already done two good days’ journey in one) forced
            us to determine on coming to a stand-still. Upon the heights to the
            eastward we saw lights ; these shone from the caves on the mountainside, inhabited, as the Nazarene told us, by rascals of a low sort—not
            real Bedouins—men whom we might frighten into harmlessness, but
            from whom there was no willing hospitality to be expected.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ We heard at a little distance the brawling of a rivulet, and on the
            banks of this it was determined to establish our bivouac ; we soon
            found the stream, and following its course for a few yards, came to a
            spot which was thought to be fit for our purpose. It was a sharply
            cold night in February, and when I dismounted, I found myself standing upon some wet rank herbage, that promised ill for the comfort of
            our resting-place. I had bad hopes of a fire, for the pitchy darkness
            of the night was a great obstacle to a successful search for fuel, and
            besides, the boughs of trees or bushes would be so full of sap in this
            early spring, that they would not be easily persuaded to burn. However, we were not likely to submit to a dark and cold bivouac without
            an effort, and my fellows groped forward through the darkness, till
            after advancing a few paces, they were happily stopped by a complete
            barrier of dead prickly bushes. Before our swords could be drawn to
            reap this glorious harvest, it was found, to our surprise, that the precious fuel was already hewn, and strewed along the ground in a thick
            mass. A spot fit for the fire was found with some difficulty, for the
            earth was moist, and the grass high and rank. At last there was a
            clicking of flint and steely and presently there stood out from darkness
            one of the tawny faces of my muleteers, bent down to near the ground,
            and suddenly lit up by the glowing of the spark, which he courted
            with a careful breath. Before long there was a particle of dry fibre,
            or leaf, that kindled to a tiny flame ; then another was lit from that,
            and then another. Then small, crisp twigs, little bigger than bodkins,
            were laid athwart the growing fire. The swelling checks of the muleteer laid level with the earth, blew tenderly at first, and then more
            boldly upon the young flame, which was daintily nursed and fed,
            and fed more plentifully when it gained good strength. At last a
            whole armful of dry bushes was piled up over the fire, and presently
            with loud, cheery cracking and crackling, a royal tall blaze shot up
            from the earth, and showed me once more the shapes and faces of my
            men, and the dim outlines of the horses and mules that stood grazing
            hard by.”
         </p>
         <p>A TEMPTATION TO COMMIT MURDER.
            
         </p>
         <p>" And now it was, if I remember rightly, that Dthemetri submitted
            to me a plan for putting to death the Nazarene, whose misguidance had
            been the cause of our difficulties. There was something fascinating
            in the suggestion, for the slaying of the guide was of course easy
            enough, and would look like an act of what politicians call “ vigor. ’
            If it were only to become known to my friends in England that 1 had
            calmly killed a fellow creature for taking me out of my way, I might
            remain perfectly quiet and tranquil for all the rest of my days, quite
            free from the danger of being considered “ slow;" I might ever alter
            live upon my reputation like “ single-speech Hamilton ’’ in the last
            century, or “ single-sin--” in this, without being obliged to take
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>the trouble of doing any more harm in the world. This was a great
            temptation to an indolent person, but the motive was not strengthened
            by any sincere feeling of auger with the Nazarene : whilst the question of his life and death was being debated, he was riding in front of
            our party, and there was something in the anxious writhing of his supple limbs that seemed to express a sense of bis false position, and
            struck me as highly comic; I had no crotchet at that lime against the
            punishment of the death, but I was unused to blood, and the proposed
            victim looked so thoroughly capable of enjoying life (if he could only
            get to the other side of the river), that I thought it would be hard for
            him to die, merely in order to give me a character for energy. Acting on the result of these considerations, and reserving to mysell a
            free and unfettered discretion to have the poor villain shot at any future moment, I magnanimously decided that for the present he should
            live and not die.”
         </p>
         <p>FLEAS IN JERUSALEM.
            “ Except at Jersusalem, never think of attempting to sleep in a
            ‘ holy city.’ Old Jews from all parts of the world go to lay their
            
         </p>
         <p>bones upon the sacred soil, and as these people never return to their
            homes, it follows that any domestic vermin which they may bring
            with them are likely to become permanently resident, so that the
            population is continually increasing. No recent census had been taken when I was at Tiberias, but I know that the congregation of fleas
            which attended at my church alone, must have been something enormous. It was a carnal, self-seeking congregation, wholly inattentive
            to the service which was going on, and devoted to the one object of
            having my blood. The fleas of all nations were there. The snug,
            steady, importunate flea from Holywell street—the pert, jumping
            ‘ puce’ from hungry France—the wary, watchful 'pulse’ with his poisoned stiletto—the vengeful ‘ pulga’ of Castile with his ugly knife—
            the German ‘ floh’ with his knife and fork—insatiate—not rising from
            table—whole swarms from all the Russias, and Asiatic hordes unnumbered—all these were there, and all rejoiced in one great international
            feast. I could no more defend myself against my enemies, than if I
            had been ‘ pain a discretion’ in the hands of a French patriot, or English gold in the claws of a Pennsylvania Quaker. After passing a
            night like this, you are glad to pick up the wretched remains of your
            body, long, long before morning dawns. Your skin is scorched—your
            temples throb—your lips feel withered and dried—your burning eyeballs are screwed inwards against the brain. You have no hope but
            only in the saddle, and the freshness of the morning air.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>More of the Voluminous History of the Little Longfellow
            War—Mr. Poe’s Third Chapter or Reply to the Letter of
            Outis.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Pray,” inquires Outis of Mr. Willis, “did you ever
            think the worse of Dana because your friend John Neal
            charged him with pirating upon Paul Allen, and Bryant, too
            in his poem of The Dying Raven?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I am sincerely disposed to give Outis his due, and will not
            pretend to deny his happy facility in asking irrelevant questions. In the present case, we can only imagine Mr. Willis’
            reply:—“ My dear Sir,” he might say, “ I certainly do not
            think much the worse of Mr. Dana, because Mr. Neal charged him with the piracy, hut be so kind as not to inquire
            what might have been my opinion had there been any substantiation of the charge.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I quote Outis’ inquiry, however, not so much to insist upon
            its singular luminousness, as to call attention to the argument embodied in the capital letters of “ The Dying Raven.”
            Now, were I, in any spasm of perversity, to direct Outis’
            catechetical artillery against himself, and demand of him
            explicitly his reasons for causing those three words to be
            printed in capitals, what in the world would he do for a
            reply ? As a matter of course, for some moments, he would
            be profoundly embarrassed—but, being a true man, and a
            chivalrous one, as all defenders of Mr. Longfellow must be,
            he could not fail, in the end, to admit that they were so
            printed for the purpose of safely insinuating a charge which
            not even an Outis had the impudence openly to utter. Let
            us imagine his thoughts while carefully twice underscoring the words. Is it impossible that they ran thus?—“ I am
            perfectly well aware, to be sure, that the only conceivable
            resemblance between Mr. Bryant’s poem and Mr. Poe’s poem,
            lies in their common reference to a raven ; but then, what I
            am writing will be seen by some who have not read Mr.
            Bryant’s poem, and by many who have never heard of Mr.
            Poe’s, and among these classes I shall be able to do Mr. Poe
            a serious injustice and injury, by conveying the idea that
            there is really sufficient similarity to warrant that charge of
            plagiarism, which I, Outis, the ‘acquaintance of Mr. Longfellow,’ am too high-minded and too merciful to prefer.”
            Now, I do not pretend to be positive that any such thoughts
            as these ever entered 'he brain of Outis. Nor will I venture
            to designate the whole insinuation, as a specimen of “carping littleness, too paltry for any man who values bis reputation as a gentleman;" for in the first place, the whole matter, as I have put it, is purely supposititious, and in the second,
            I should furnish ground for a new insinuation of the same
            character, inasmuch as I should be employing Outis’ identical words.
         </p>
         <p>The fact is, Outis has happened upon the idea that the
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page179"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>most direct method of rebutting one accusation, is to get up
            another. By showing that I have committed a sin, he proposes to show that Mr. Aldrich and Mr. Longfellow have
            not. Leaving the underscored Dying Raven to argue its own
            case, he proceeds, therefore, as follows:—
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Who, for example, would wish to be guilty of the littleness of detracting from the uncommon merit of that remarkable poem of this
            same Mr. Poe’s, recently published in the Mirror, from the American
            Review, entitled ‘ The Raven,’ by charging him with the paltriness
            of imitation ? And yet, some snarling critic, who might envy the reputation he had not the genius to secure for himself, might refer to
            the frequent, very forcible, but rather quaint repetition, in the last two
            lines of many of the stanzas, as a palpable imitation of the manner of
            Coleridge, in several stanzas of the Ancient Mariner. Let me put
            them together.
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Poe says—
            “ Let me see, then, what thereat is, and this mystery explore,
            Let my heart be still a moment, and this mystery explore.
            And again—
            “ It shall clasp a sainted maiden whom the angels name Lenore—
            Clasp a rare and radiant maiden whom the angels name Lenore.
            Mr. Coleridge says, (running two lines into one) ;
            “ For all averred I had kiUed the bird, that made the breeze to blow.
            'Ah, wretch!’ said they, ' the bird to slay, that made the breeze to blow.'"
            And again—
            “ They all averred I had killed the bird, that brought the fog and mist
            ‘ Twas right,’ said they, ' such birds to slay, that bring the fog and mist.
            
         </p>
         <p>The “ rather quaint” is ingenious. Fully one-third of
            whatever effect “ The Raven” has, is wrought by the quaint
            ness in question—a point elaborately introduced, to accomplish a well-considered purpose. What idea would Outis
            entertain of me, were I to speak of his defence of his friends
            as very decent, very respectable, but rather meritorious ?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the passages collated there are two points upon which
            the “ snarling critic” might base his insinuation—if ever so
            weak a “ snarling critic” existed. Of these two points one is
            purely hypothetical—that is to say, it is disingenuously manufactured by Mr. Longfellow's acquaintance to suit his own
            purposes—or perhaps the purposes of the imaginary snarling
            critic. The argument of the second point is demolished by
            my not only admitting it, but insisting upon it. Perhaps the
            least tedious mode of refuting Outis, is to acknowledge nine
            tenths of every thing he may think proper to say.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But, in the present instance what am I called upon to acknowledge ? I am charged with imitating the repetition of
            phrase in the two concluding lines of a stanza, and of imitating this from Coleridge. But why not extend the accusation,
            and insinuate that I imitate it from every body else ? for certainly there is no poet living or dead who has not put in
            practice the identical effect—the well-understood effect of the
            refrain. Is Outis’ argument to the end that I have no right
            to this thing for the reason that all the world has ? If this
            is not his argument, will he be kind enough to inform me
            (at his leisure) what it is ? Or is he prepared to confess himself so absurdly uninformed as not to know that whatever a
            poet claims on the score of original versification, is claimed
            not on account of any individual rhythmical or metrical effects (for none are individually original) but solely on account
            of the novelty of his combinations of old effects?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The hypothesis, or manufacture, consists in the alteration
            of Coleridge’s metre, with the view of forcing it into a merely ocular similarity with my own, and thus of imposing upon
            some one or two grossly ignorant readers. I give the verses
            of Coleridge as they are :
         </p>
         <p>For all averred. I had killed the bird
            That nude the breeze to blow.
            Ah wretch, said they, the bird to slay,
            That made the breeze to blow.
            
         </p>
         <p>The verses beginning, “ They all averred,” etc., are arranged
            in the same manner. Now I have taken it for granted that it
            is Outis’ design to impose the idea of similarity between my
            lines and those of Coleridge, upon some one or two grossly
            ignorant individuals: at the same time, whoever attempts
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>such an imposition is rendered liable at least to the suspicion
            of very gross ignorance himself. The ignorance or the knavery are the two uncomfortable horns of his dilemma.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Let us see. Coleridge’s lines are arranged in quatrains—
            mine in couplets. His first and third lines rhyme at the closes
            of the second and fourth feet—mine flow continuously, without rhyme. His metre, briefly defined, is alternately tetrameter acatalectic, and trimeter acatalectic—mine is uniformly
            octameter catalectic. It might be expected, however, that
            at least the rhythm would prove to be identical—but not so.
            Coleridge’s is iambic (varied in the third foot of the first line
            with an anapaest)—mine is the exact converse, trochaic. The
            fact is, that neither in rhythm, metre, stanza, or rhyme, is
            there even a single point of approximation throughout; the
            only similarity being the wickedly or sillily manufactured
            one of Outis himself, appealing from the ears to the eyes of
            the most uncultivated classes of the rabble. The ingenuity
            and validity of the manufacture might be approached, although certainly not paralleled, by an attempt to show that
            blue and yellow pigments standing unmixed at separate ends
            of a studio, were equivalent to green. I say “ not paralleled,”
            for even the mixing of the pigments, in the case of Outis,
            would be very far, as I have shown, from producing the supposititious effect. Coleridge’s lines, written together, would
            result in rhymed iambic heptameter acatalectic, while mine
            are unrhymed trochaic octameter catalectic—differing in
            every conceivable circumstance. A closer parallel than the
            one I have imagined, would be the demonstration that two
            axe equal to four, on the ground that, possessing two dollars,
            a man will have four when he gets an additional couple—
            for that the additional couple is somewhere, no one, after due
            consideration, will deny.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If Outis will now take a seat upon one of the horns of his
            dilemma, I will proceed to transcribe the third variation of
            the charges insinuated through the medium of the “ snarling
            critic.”
         </p>
         <p>I have before me an anonymous poem, which I first saw some five
            
         </p>
         <p>years ago entitled “ The Bird of the Dream.” I should like to transcribe the whole—but it is too long. The author was awakened from
            sleep by the song of a beautiful bird, sitting on the sill of his window
            —the sweet notes had mingled with his dreams, and brought to his
            remembrance, the sweeter voice of his lost “ Clare.” He says—
            " And thou wert in my dream—a spirit thou didst seem—
         </p>
         <p>The spirit of a friend long since departed;
            Oh she was fair and bright, but she left me one dark night-- 
            She left me all alone, and broken-hearted.
            .................................................
            My dream went on, and thou went a warbling too,
            Mingling the harmonies of earth and heaven ;
            Till away—away—away—beyond the realms of day—
            My angel Clare to my embrace was given.
            .................................................
            Sweet bird from realms of light, oh! come again to night,
            come to my window-perch upon my chair—
            Give me back again that deep impassioned strain
            That tells me thou hast seen and loved my Clare.
            
         </p>
         <p>Now I shall not charge Mr. Poe with Plagiarism—for, as I have
            said, such charges are perfectly absurd. Ten to one, he never saw
            this before But let us look at the “ identities'’ that may be made out
            between this and “ The Raven.” First, in each case, the poet is a
            broken-hearted lover. Second, that lover longs for some hereafter
            communion with the departed. Third, there is a bird. Fourth, the
            bird is at the poet’s window. Fifth, the bird being at the poet’s win
            dow, makes a noise. Sixth, making a noise attracts the attention of
         </p>
         <p>the poet; who, Seventh, was half asleep dosing, dreaming. Eighth,
            the poet invites the bird to come in. Ninth, a confabulation ensues.
            
         </p>
         <p>Tenth, the bird is supposed to be a visitor from the land of spirits.
            Eleventh, allusion is made to the departed. Twelfth intimation is
            given that the bird knew something of the departed. Thirteenth, that
            he knew her worth and loveliness. Fourteenth, the bird seems willing
            to linger with the poet. Fifteenth, there is a repetition, in the second
            and fourth lines of a part, and that the emphatic part, of the first and
            third. Here is a round baker’s dozen (and one to spare) of identities,
            to offset the dozen found between Aldrich and Hood, and that too,
            without a word of rhythm, metre or stanza, which should never form a
            part of such a comparison.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The first point to be attended to here is the "ten to one
            that I never saw it before.” Ten to one that I never did—
            but Outis might have remembered that twenty to one I
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page180"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>should like to see it. In accusing either Mr. Aldrich or Mr.
            Hood, I printed their poems together and in full. But an
            anonymous gentleman rebuts my accusation by telling me
            that there is a certain similarity between a poem of my own
            and an anonymous poem which he has before him, and which
            he would like to transcribe if it were not too long. He contents himself, therefore, with giving me, from this too long
            poem, three stanzas which are shown, by a series of intervening asterisks, to have been culled, to suit his own purpoes, from different portions of the poem, but which, (again
            to suit his own purposes) he places before the public in consecutive connexion ! The least that can be said of the whole
            statement is that it is deliciously frank—but, upon the whole,
            the poem will look quite as well before me, as before Outis,
            whose time is too much occupied to transcribe it. I, on the
            other hand, am entirely at leisure, and will transcribe and
            print the whole of it with the greatest pleasure in the world
            —provided always that it is not too long to refer to—too long
            to have its whereabouts pointed out—as I half suspect, from
            Outis’ silence on the subject, that it is.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p> One thing I will take it upon myself to say, in the spirit
            of prophecy :—whether the poem in question is or is not in
            existence (and we have only Nobody’s word that it is) the
            passages as quoted, are not in existence, except as quoted by
            Outis, who in some particulars, I maintain, has falsified the
            text, for the purpose of forcing a similarity, as in the case of
            the verses of Coleridge.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>All this I assert in the spirit of prophecy, while we await
            the forthcoming of the poem. In the meantime, we will estimate the “identities" with reference to the “Raven” as
            collated with the passages culled by Outis—granting him
            every thing he is weak enough to imagine I am in duty
            bound to grant—admitting that the poem as a whole exists—
            that the words and lines are ingenuously written—that the
            stanzas have the connexion and sequence he gives them—
            and that although he has been already found guilty of chicanery in one instance, he is at least entirely innocent in
            this.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>He has established, he says, fifteen identities, “ and that,
            too, without a word of rhythm, metre, or stanza, which
            should never form a part of such comparison”—by which of
            course we are to understand that with the rhythm, metre,
            and stanza (omitted only because they should never form a
            part of such comparison) he would have succeeded in establishing eighteen. Now I insist that rhythm, metre and stanza should form and must form a part of the comparison, and
            I will presently demonstrate what I say. I also insist therefore, since he could find me guilty if he would upon these
            points, that guilty he must and shall find me upon the spot.
            He then, distinctly, has established eighteen identities—and
            I proceed to examine them one by one.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ First,’’ he says “ in each case the poet is a broken-hearted lover.” Not so:—my poet has no indication of a broken
            heart. On the contrary he lives triumphantly in the expectation of meeting his Lenore in Aidenn, and is so indignant
            with the raven for maintaining that the meeting will never
            take place, as to call him a liar and order him out of the
            house. Not only is my lover not a broken-hearted one—but
            I have been at some pains to show that broken hearts and
            matters of that kind are improperly made the subject of poems. I refer to the last chapter of an article entitled “ Marginalia” and published, in the last December number, I believe,
            of the “ Democratic Review."
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Second,” says Outis, “ that lover longs for some hereafter communion with the bird." In my poem there is no expression of any such longing—the nearest approach to it is</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>the triumphant consciousness which forms the thesis and staple of the whole. In Outis’ poem the nearest approach to
            the “ longing” is contained in the lover’s request to the bird
            to repeat a strain that assures him (the lover) that it (the
            bird) has known the lost mistress.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Third—there is a bird, “ says Outis. So there is. Mine
            however is a raven, and we may take it for granted that Outis’ is either a nightingale or a cockatoo.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Fourth, the bird is at the poet’s window.” As regards
            my poem, true; as regards Outis’, not:—the poet only requests the bird to come to the window.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Fifth, the bird being at the poet’s window, makes a
            noise.” The fourth specification failing, the fifth, which depends upon it, as a matter of course fails too.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Sixth, making a noise attracts the attention of the poet.”
            The fifth specification failing, the sixth, which depends upon it, fails likewise, and as a matter of course, as before.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Seventh, [the poet] was half asleep, dozing, dreaming.”
            False altogether: only my poet was “napping,” and this in
            the commencement of the poem, which is occupied with realities and waking action. Outis’ poet is fast asleep and
            dreams every thing.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Eighth, the poet invites the bird to come in." Another
            palpable failure. Outis’ poet indeed asked his bird in; but
            my raven walked in without any invitation.
         </p>
         <p>“ Ninth—a confabulation ensues." As regards my poem,
            true; but there is not a word of any confabulation in Outis'.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Tenth—the bird is supposed to be a visiter from the land
            of spirits.” As regards Outis’ poem, this is true only if we
            give a wide interpretation to the phrase “ realms of light.”
            In my poem the bird is not only not from the world of spirits,
            but I have specifically conveyed the idea of his having escaped from “ some unhappy master”, of whom he had caught
            the word “ Nevermore”—in the concluding stanza, it is true,
            I suddenly convert him into an allegorical emblem or personification of Mournful Remembrance, out of the shadow of
            which the poet is “ lifted nevermore."
         </p>
         <p>“ Eleventh—allusion is made to the departed.” Admit-
            ted.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Twelfth—intimation is given that the bird knew something of the departed.” True as regards Outis’ poem only.
            No such intimation is given in mine.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Thirteenth—that he knew her worth and loveliness.”
            Again—true only as regards Outis’ poem. It should be observed here that I have disproved the twelfth and thirteenth
            specifications purely for form’s sake:—they are nothing more
            than disingenuous repetitions of the eleventh. The “ allusion to the departed” is the “ intimation,” and the intimation
            is that he knew her worth and loveliness.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Fourteenth—the bird seems willing to linger with the
            poet.” True only as regards my poem—in Outis’ (as quoted)
            there is nothing of the kind.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Fifteenth—there is a repetition, in the second and fourth
            lines, of a part, and that the emphatic part, of the first and
            third." What is here asserted is true only of the first stanza
            quoted by Outis, and of the commencement of the third.
            There is nothing of it in the second, In my poem there is
            nothing of it at all, with the exception of the repetition in
            the refrain, occurring at the fifth line of my stanza of six. I
            quote a stanza—by way of rendering every thing perfectly
            intelligible, and affording Outis his much coveted “ fair
            play”:
         </p>
         <p>“ Be that word our sign of parting, bird or fiend !” I shrieked,
            upstarting—
            “ Get thee back into the tempest and the Night’s Plutonian
            shore !
            Leave no black plume as a token of that lie thy soul hath spoken '
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page181"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>Leave my loneliness unbroken !—quit the bust above my door!
            Take thy beak from out my heart, and take thy form from off
            my door!”
         </p>
         <p>Quoth the raven “ Nevermore.”
            Sixteenth—concerns the rhythm. Outis’ is iambic—mine
            the exact converse, trochaic.
            
         </p>
         <p>Seventeenth—regards the metre. Outis’ is hexameter alternating with pentameter, both acatalectic.* Mine is octameter acatalectic, alternating with heptameter catalectic repeated in the refrain of the fifth verse, and terminating with
            tetrameter catalectic.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Eighteenth and last has respect to the stanza—that is to
            say, to the general arrangement of the metre into masses.
            Of Outis’ I need only say that it is a very common and certainly a very stupid one. My own has at least the merit of
            being my own. No writer living or dead has ever employed
            anything resembling it. The innumerable specific differences
            between it and that of Outis it would be a tedious matter to
            point out—but a far less difficult matter than to designate
            one individual point of similarity.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>And now what are we to think of the eighteen identities of
            Outis—the fifteen that he establishes and the three that he
            could establish if he would—that is to say, if he could only
            bring himself to be so unmerciful ?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Of the whole eighteen, sixteen have shown themselves to
            be lamentable failures—having no more substantial basis
            than sheer misrepresentation “ too paltry for any man who
            values his reputation as a gentleman and a scholar,” and
            depending altogether for effect upon the chances that nobody
            would take the trouble to investigate their falsehood or their
            truth.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Two—the third and the eleventh—are sustained : and these
            two show that in both poems there is “ an allusion to the departed,” and that in both poems there is ‘‘a bird.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The first idea which suggests itself at this point is, whether not to have a bird and not to have an allusion to a deceased mistress, would not be the truer features of distinctiveness after all—whether two poems which have not these
            items might not be more rationally charged with similarity
            than any two poems which have.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But having thus disproved all the identities of Outis (for
            any one comprehending the principle of proof in such cases
            will admit that two only, are in effect just nothing at all) I
            am quite ready, by way again of affording him “ fair play,”
            to expunge every thing that has been said on the subject, and
            proceed as if every one of these eighteen identities were in
            the first bloom and deepest blush of a demonstration.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I might grant them as demonstrated, to be sure, on the
            ground which I have already touched—that to prove me or
            any body else an imitator is no mode of showing that Mr. Aldrich or Mr. Longfellow is not. But I might safely admit
            them on another and equally substantial consideration which
            seems to have been overlooked by the zeal of Outis altogether. He has clearly forgotten that the mere number of such
            coincidences proves nothing, because at any moment we can
            oblige it to prove too much. It is the easiest thing imaginable to suggest—and even to do that which Outis has failed
            to doing—to demonstrate a practically infinite series of identities between any two compositions in the world—but it by
            no means follows that all compositions in the world have a
            similarity one with the other, in any comprehensible sense
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This it as accurate a description at can be given of the alternating (of the second and fourth) lines in few words. The fact is, they
            are indescribable without more trouble than they art worth—and
            seem to me either to hare been written by some one ignorant of the
            principles of verse, or to be misquoted. The line, however,
         </p>
         <p>"That tells me thou hast seen and loved my Clare,"
            answers the description I have given of the alternating verses, and
            was no doubt the general intention for all of them.
            
         </p>
         <p>of the term. I mean to say that regard must be had not only
            to the number of the coincidences, but to the peculiarity of
            each—this peculiarity growing less and less necessary, and
            the effect of number more and more important, in a ratio
            prodigiously accumulative, as the investigation progresses.
            And again—regard must be had not only to the number and
            peculiarity of the coincidences, but to the antagonistic differences, if any, which surround them—and very especially to
            the space over which the coincidences are spread, and the
            number or paucity of the events, or incidents, from among
            which the coincidences are selected. When Outis, for example, picks out his eighteen coincidences (which I am now
            granting as sustained) from a poem so long as The Raven,
            in collation with a poem not forthcoming, and which may
            therefore, for anything anybody knows to the contrary, be as
            long as an infinite flock of ravens, he is merely putting himself to unnecessary trouble in getting together phantoms of
            arguments that can have no substance wherewith to aid his
            demonstration, until the ascertained extent of the unknown
            poem from which they are culled, affords them a purpose and
            a palpability. Can any man doubt that between The Iliad
            and the Paradise Lost there might be established even a
            thousand very idiosyncratic identities ?—and yet is any man
            fool enough to maintain that the Iliad is the original of the
            Paradise Lost ?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But how is it in the case of Messieurs Aldrich and Hood ?
            The poems here are both remarkably brief—and as I have
            every intention to do justice, and no other intention in the
            world, I shall be pardoned for collating them once again.
            Mr. Hood’s poem runs thus:
         </p>
         <p>THE DEATH-BED.
            We watched her breathing through the night,
            Her breathing soft and low,
            As in her breast the ware of life
            Kept heaving to and fro.
            So silently we seemed to speak,
            So slowly moved about,
            As we had lent her half our powers
            To eke her being out.
            Our very hope belied our fears;
            Our fears our hope belied ;
            We thought her dying when she slept,
            And sleeping when she died.
            But when the morn came dim and sad,
            And chill with early showers,
            Her quiet eyelids closed—she had
            Another mom than ours.
            Mr. Aldrich’s poem is as follows:
            a death-bed.
            Her sufferings ended with the day,
            Yet lived she at its close,
            And breathed the long, long night away,
            In statue-like repose;
            Bul when the sun in all its state
            Illumed the eastern skies,
            She passed through Glory’s morning gate,
            And walked in Paradise.
            
         </p>
         <p>Now, let it be understood that I am entirely uninformed
            as to which of these two poems was first published. And so
            little has the question of priority to do with my thesis, that
            I shall not put myself to the trouble of inquiring. What I
            maintain is, that there are sufficient grounds for belief that
            the one is plagiarised from the other :—who is the original
            and who is the plagiarist, are points 1 leave to be settled by
            any one who thinks the matter of sufficient consequence to
            give it his attention.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But the man who shall deny the plagiarism abstractly
            —what is it that he calls upon us to believe ? First—that
            two poets, in remote parts of the world, conceived the idea
            of composing a poem on the subject of Death. Of course,
            there is nothing remarkable in this. Death is a naturally
            poetic theme, and suggests itself by a seeming spontaneity
            to every poet in the world. But had the subject chosen by
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page182"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>the two widely separated poets, been even strikingly peculiar—had it been, for example, a porcupine, a piece of gingerbread, or anything unlikely to be made the subject of a poem,
            still no sensible person would have insisted upon the single
            coincidence as any thing beyond a single coincidence. We
            have no difficulty, therefore, in believing what, so far, we
            are called upon to believe.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Secondly, we must credit that the two poets concluded to
            write not only on death, but on the death of a woman. Here
            the mind, observing the two identities, reverts to their peculiarity or non-peculiarity, and finding no peculiarity—admitting that the death of a woman is a naturally suggested poetic subject—has no difficulty also in admitting the two coincidences—as such and nothing beyond.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Thirdly, we are called upon to believe that the two poets
            not only concluded to write upon death and upon the death
            of a woman, but that, from the innumerable phases of death,
            the phase of tranquility was happened upon by each. Here
            the intellect commences a slight rebellion, but it is quieted
            by the admission partly of the spontaneity with which such
            an idea might arise, and partly of the possibility of the coincidences, independently of the consideration of spontaneity.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Fourthly—we are required to believe that the two poets
            happened not only upon death—the death of a woman—and
            the tranquil death of a woman—but upon the idea of representing this woman as lying tranquilly throughout the whole
            night, in spite of the infinity of different durations which
            might have been imagined for her trance of tranquility. At
            this point the reason perceives the evidence against these
            coincidences, (as such and nothing more), to be increasing
            in geometrical ratio. It discards all idea of spontaneity, and
            if it yield credence at all, yields it altogether on the ground
            of the indisputable possibility.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Fifthly—we are requested to believe that our poets happened not only upon death—upon the death of a woman—upon the
            tranquil death of a woman—and upon the lying of this woman tranquilly throughout the night—but, also, upon the idea
            of selecting, from the innumerable phases which characterise
            a tranquil death-bed, the identical one of soft breathing—employing also the identical word. Here the reason gives up the
            endeavour to believe that one poem has not been suggested
            by the other:—if it be a reason accustomed to deal with the
            mathematical Calculus of Probabilities it has abandoned this
            endeavour at the preceding stage of the investigation. The
            evidence of suggestion has now become prodigiously accumulate. Each succeeding coincidence (however slight) is proof
            not merely added, but multiplied by hundreds, and hundreds
            of thousands.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Sixthly, we are called upon to believe not only that the
            two poets happened upon all this, together with the idea of
            the soft breathing, but also of employing the identical word
            breathing, in the same line with the identical word, night.
            This proposition the reason receives with a smile.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Seventhly, however, we are required to admit not only all
            that has been already found inadmissible, but in addition,
            that the two poets conceived the idea of representing the
            death of the woman as occurring precisely at the same instant, out of all the infinite instants of all time. This proposition the reason receives only with a sneer.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Eighthly—we are called upon to acquiesce in the assertion that not only all these improbabilities are probable, but
            that in addition again, the two poets happened upon the idea
            of representing the woman as stepping immediately into
            Paradise:--and, ninthly, that both should not only happen
            upon all this, but upon the idea of writing a peculiarly brief
            poem, on so admirably suggestive a thesis :—and, tenthly,
            that out of the various rhythms, that is to say variations of
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>poetic feet, they should have both happened upon the iambus:—and, eleventhly, that out of the absolutely infinite metres
            that may be contrived from this rhythm, they should both
            have hit upon the tetrameter acatalectic for the first and third
            lines of a stanza:—and, twelfthly, upon the trimeter acatalectic for the second and fourth ; and, thirteenthly, upon an ab: solute identity of phrase at, fourteenthly, an absolutely
            identical position, viz: upon the phrases, “But when the
            mom,” &amp;c., and, “ But when the sun, &amp;c.,” occurring in
            the beginning of the first line in the last stanza of each poem:
            —and, fifteenthly and lastly, that out of the vast multitude of appropriate titles, they should both have happened
            upon one whose identity is interfered with at all, only by
            the difference between the definite and indefinite article.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Now the chances that these fifteen coincidences, so peculiar in character, and all occuring within the compass of
            eight short lines on the one part, and sixteen on the other—
            the chances, I say, that these coincidences are merely accidental, may be estimated, possibly, as about one to one hundred millions; and any man who reasons at all, is of course
            grossly insulted in being called upon to credit them as accidental.
         </p>
         <p>In the next number of the Journal, I shall endeavour to bring
            this subject to an end.	E. A. P.
            WOMAN IN THE NINETEENTH CENTURY.
            
         </p>
         <p>We have encountered, during the past week, some half a
            dozen notices of our review of Miss Fuller’s book, which
            strangely misrepresent the opinions we expressed of that lady.
            A writer in the Charleston Mercury, says that we snub Miss
            Fuller because she is neither a wife nor a mother, and has,
            therefore, no right to say what a woman should be, “ forgetting that nature has so arranged it, that many women cannot
            be mothers, and that others prefer a single life.” We have
            the best reasons in the world for not forgetting either of these
            facts. But we spoke of woman, not women. Man, in the
            same way, is nothing, but as a husband and a father. But
            there may be good citizens who are neither; who yet, as
            Lord Bacon says, “ in affection and means have married and
            endowed the public.” Miss Fuller’s theme is “woman,”
            not any particular classes of women, and she argues that
            woman may, and should fill any of the duties which properly
            belong to man, and which are wholly incompatible with the
            duties of a wife and mother. Miss Fuller suggests nothing,
            proposes nothing, hints at nothing, for bettering the condition
            of those of her own sex, who by accident may be placed in
            the unnatural condition of laborers for their own, or even
            their husband’s bread. There are thousands of women in
            this city, married and unmarried, mothers and childless, who
            are compelled to assume the duties of man, and who do. with
            feminine patience, manfully contend with their destiny, and
            rule, where they should serve ; and protect those who should
            protect them. But these are unfortunate, not privileged
            women, who would, like Zenobia, resign the sceptre of power, and gladly become matrons, rather than remain monarchs.
            The true position of woman is not a disputable point; the
            universal sentiment of mankind has determined it; God himself has said “her desire shall be unto her husband, and he
            shall rule over her.” Miss Fuller says “ no,” in very plain
            terms, “ let the desire and rule be the other way,” and she instances the case of the woman, who contentedly resided on a
            mountain with her husband, because he found it for his interest to do so,—and with sufficient distinctness, declares,
            “ I would not have it so.” We did not snub Miss Fuller for
            this, as the writer in the Charleston Mercury asserts, but we
            are sorry for not doing so, and we repair our neglect, by tell-
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page183"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>ing Miss Fuller that no unmarried woman has any right to
            say any thing on the subject. Let any wife, if one can be
            found to say it, declare that she would not have it so. But
            Miss Fuller is not a competent oracle. The writer in the
            Charleston Courier is not correct in saying that Mrs. Sigourney has no children. She has a son and a daughter.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There is an immense deal of nonsense afloat on the subject
            of “ femality,” which can never do any harm to society at
            large, because the instincts of nature and imperative necessity will keep men and women in their true spheres , but it
            may, and we have no doubt does produce a good deal of harm
            in particular cases, by creating improper desires, and unsettling the quiet and content of many a well ordered family. t
            is not denied that there are Abby Kellys and Lucretia Motts,
            who have preached with seemingly good effect, to quiet au
            diences, but it is by no means certain that these women cou
            not have done greater good by an unobtrusive observance of
            their duties in a different manner. We remember hearing
            one of them speak at a public meeting once, where the
            greater part of the assembly was composed of rather rude
            men, and once or twice while she was speaking, her face
            and neck blushed scarlet red ; it was nature that spoke eloquently in her blood, and should have urged her to desist.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Miss Fuller names Mrs. Siddons as an instance of what a
            woman may effect in public; but Mrs. Siddons came before
            the public only as a woman, representing always a woman,
            either as a wife, a mother, or a betrothed wife.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>During the past week, a meeting of young women was
            held in the Superior Court room of the City Hall, at which a
            Miss Gray presided, and a Miss Graham acted as Secretary.
            The object of the meeting appears to have been the consideration of the means by which women may be enable to
            earn their bread. We doubt the propriety of such meetings,
            but they are certainly excusable, and reflect disgrace upon the
            society which makes it necessary that woman should have
            to resort to such means to secure an honest support.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There is one kind of employment, particularly adapted to
            the habits of women, which we hope to see introduced
            among them—wood engraving. It has already been one
            in England and France, and we have now before us some
            specimens of wood-cutting by a young woman, which would
            not only compare favorably with the best specimens of this
            kind of art that we have seen, but which possesses a peculiar character of freedom, which we have never seen in the
            work of any man. A class of young women should be immediately formed, for instruction in elementary drawing,
            with a view to their becoming wood engravers. It might
            easily be done at a trifling expense, and we can hardly fear
            that the city authorities would hesitate to lend their countenance to such an undertaking. Many women, who now
            support themselves with difficulty by their needle, might earn
            a handsome competence as wood engravers. It is an art
            which is daily growing in importance among us, and would
            be employed to a much greater extent, if we had a greater
            number of good artists.
         </p>
         <p>The American Review. No. 3. March, 1845.
            
         </p>
         <p>This political journal contains but one political article, a very
            candid and well written sketch of the twenty-eighth congress,
            by Horace Greeley; it will probably be quite as acceptable
            to the majority of its readers as though it contained more.
            But a very small part of our individual happiness is affected
            by our national politics. The majority of the people, in spite
            of mass meetings and daily papers, care hardly more about
            the characters of their rulers than do the subjects of the sultan,
            The last election of our President is sufficient proof of this.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Those who knew Mr. Polk best gave him the fewest votes ;
            at the most distant points from his own home he mustered
            the greatest number of adherents. Our politics then, being
            purely personal, rather than considerations of principle, can
            never be made the pervading feature of a monthly or quarterly, or even a weekly magazine. The Democratic Review
            contains just enough of partisan writing to swear by ; it is
            read solely for its literary articles. The same may be said
            of the American Review, which calls itself a whig journal.
            The number before us contains 108 pages, ten of which are
            devoted to politics, the remainder to subjects of general interest. Among the papers is a review of the History of the
            Empire, by Thiers, from Dr. Lardner ; an agreeable essay on
            single speech poets by Wm. A. Jones; and a very able article
            on our light-house system, from H. I. Raymond, which we regard as the most important one in the magazine. The subject is very justly handled, and the improprieties of our system forcibly exposed. There are several agreeable papers besides these, and altogether the magazine takes rank among
            the very first of the kind that the country has produced.
         </p>
         <p>The Southern Literary Messenger.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Messenger was founded in the beginning of the year
            1835, by Thomas W. White, a very worthy and energetic
            printer and publisher of Richmond Va., at a period when no
            journal of the kind had ever taken root south of the Potomac,
            and amid loud warnings from the publisher’s friends not to
            engage in the undertaking. He persevered, however, and, by
            dint of much personal exertion, obtained, in the first six
            months, about six or seven hundred subscribers. During this
            period, no editor was regularly engaged—the proprietor depending upon occasional aid from his friends. Mr. James E.
            Heath and Mr. E. V. Sparhawk aided him very materially.
            At the beginning of the seventh month one of the present editors of the “ Broadway Journal” made an arrangement to edit
            the “ Messenger,” and by systematic exertion on the ''part of
            both publisher and editor the circulation was increased by the
            end of the subsequent year to nearly five thousand—a success
            quite unparalleled in the history of our five dollar Magazines.
            After the secession of Mr. Poe, Mr. White took the editorial
            conduct upon his own shoulders and sustained it remarkably
            well. At his death, about three years since, Mr. B. B. Minor, of Va., became editor and proprietor, and is still so. In
            his hands the work maintains its old fame.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Messenger has always been a favorite with the people of the South and West, who take a singular pride in its
            support. Its subscribers are almost without exception the
            èlite both as regards wealth and intellectual culture, of the
            Southern aristocracy, and its corps of contributors are generally men who control the public opinion of the Southerners
            on all topics. The influence of the work is, therefore, prodigious—and it has always been exerted, we sincerely believe, in behalf of the chivalrous, the tasteful and the true.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It subscription-list is by no means confined, however, to
            the South and West. A great many of the most distinguished persons in the North and East are among its warmest supporters Indeed there are comparatively few illustrious
            American names that are not to be found upon its list. In
            the aristocracy of its friends it is quite an anomaly in the literary world.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr Minor is about to make some important improvements
            in the work, with a view of extending the circulation among
            ourselves here in the North and East, and we shall not fail
            to do our part in this endeavour. The New-York agent is
            Mr John Bisco, publisher of the " Broadway Journal,"  153
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page184"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>Broadway. Any communications or subscriptions for the
            Messenger, may be forwarded either to him or to Edgar A.
            Poe, at the same office. The March number is just issued
            and is unusually good. We shall notice it more fully hereafter.	_______
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Stable Economy : A Treatise on the Management of Horses, in relation to stabling, grooming, feeding, watering and working. By
            John Stewart, Veterinary Surgeon, author of “ Advice to Purchasers
            of Horses,” and lately Professor of Veterinary Medicine in the Andersonian University, Glasgow. From the third English Edition,
            with notes and additions, adapting it to American food and climate,
            by A. B. Allen, Editor of the American Agriculturist. New York;
            D. Appleton &amp; Co., 200 Broadway. 1845.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The value of this well-known work, by Stewart, on the
            Management of Horses, is greatly increased for the use of
            Americans, by additions from A. B. Allen. Esq., the accomplished editor of the American Agriculturist. Mr. Allen has
            been engaged in the business of rearing and breeding horses
            on his own farm for the past ten years, and in his recent trip
            to England he had abundant opportunities, by personal inspection, of gaining much valuable information on every subject relating to the horse. He has also availed himself of all
            the discoveries made by the eminent philosophers whose labors in the department of agricultural chemistry during the
            last five years, have thrown so much light on the properties
            of food for man and beast, a subject of which Stewart had
            but little knowledge.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The work is very well printed and copiously illustrated
            with exceedingly neat wood cuts. Altogether it is a work of
            great value, which every owner of a horse should possess.
         </p>
         <p>The Treasury or History, No. 3. Daniel Adee, 109 Fulton street.
            Price 25 cents.
            
         </p>
         <p>This number of this popular work includes the History of
            England from the reign of Richard Cœur de Lion to that of
            Henry IV. It is well printed on good paper with clear type,
            and contains more than one hundred pages.
         </p>
         <p>The Monthly Rose, No 3, a periodical sustained by the present and
            former members of the Albany Female Academy.
            
         </p>
         <p>A very neatly printed little Magazine of 16 pages, of the
            precise quality that might be expected from its contributors ;
            gentle, romantic and purely written. When the spirit of Romance shall have left every other place in the world, she will
            still be found in the atmosphere of a Female Academy. The
            Monthly Rose contains a pretty poem, “ The Wail of the Winter Wind,” and a tale, “ the Knight Heartless," from which
            we give a characteristic passage.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Hear me ! Sir Everard Martinsley ! Let the sound of thy horses’
            hoofs be never more heard in Larmont Castle ! Go, I bid thee, for
            thou wilt see my face no more !”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Charming days of youth and innocence, when young ladies can find amusement in writing and reading romantic
            tales about Knights and Castles! How it is managed in the
            bustling city of Albany with the scream of Steam Engines
            all the time tearing away at one’s ears, we do not comprehend. But every thing is possible with the young and innocent.	_______
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Richmond’s Pamphlet reviewed, or the Priest of Cedar Grove called to order. By a South Carolinian. Jones &amp; Welsh. 104 Nassaustreet.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mary Schweidler, the Amber Witch, forming No. 2 of Wiley &amp;
            Putnam’s new series of cheap and elegant books, “ Library of Choice
            Reading,” has just been issued. We shall notice it at length next
            week.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Columbian Magazine for April, contains the usual quantity of
            readable matter, and two exceedingly fine articles ; The Children of
            Mount Ida, by L. Maria Child, and a flight of fancy by Mrs. F. S.
            Osgood. It also contains two engravings, and a flower piece, of that
            peculiar order of merit which distinguishes the embellishments of this
            magazine.
         </p>
         <p>THOUGHTS OF A SILENT MAN.
            No. 3.
            
         </p>
         <p>I had been amusing an idle moment with Elia’s delightful
            essay on “ Imperfect Sympathies,” when, as I laid down the
            book, my eye fell upon the “ Correspondence between Burns
            and Clarinda.” This gave rise to a train of thought respecting those instructive antipathies which the mass of mankind
            so readily allow, and those innate assimilations about which
            they are so sceptical. Every body has some idiosyncracy
            with regard to likings and dislikings. The “ non amo te Sabide" of the Latin poet, in its English doggrelism of
         </p>
         <p>“ I do not love thee, Dr. Fell,
            The reason why I cannot tell,
            But only this I know full well,
            I do not love thee, Dr. Fell,”
            
         </p>
         <p>has come home to the experience of the coarsest as well as
            of the finest minds. There are persons who inspire us with
            an instant repugnance—persons with whom we, if pugnacious
            would like to pick a quarrel; or, if in gracious mood, we
            would at least like to see kicked by our next neighbour. There
            are people whose souls inhabit an atmosphere so uncongenial
            to our own, that we feel in their presence as if we were
            breathing a sort of mephitic air, benumbing every faculty,
            and smothering every impulse.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The refinements of education and cultivated society may
            render this sense more painfully delicate, but it is universal
            in its existence. Look at any ship’s company, for instance,
            meeting perhaps for the first time in their lives, on the forecastle, which is to be their home during months to come, and
            you will perceive sudden antipathies exhibited between certain individuals, and sudden assimilations between others for
            no outward cause. It is an instinct of the soul, a recognition
            of kindred or a perception of antagonistic nature.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Why is it, then, that while every body is willing to acknowledge a faith in instructive dislikes, few are found as
            ready to believe in instructive attachments ? If the one part
            of the proposition be true, the other must be not less so. People seriously say, “ I don’t like Mr. such-a-one—I can’t tell
            why, but I took a dislike to him the first time I ever saw
            him:" and yet these same people will sneer at the notion of
            “ love at first sight.” Now I do not believe that love in its
            full perfectness and grand developments—love wearing the
            proof-armor of friendship and fidelity—is bom thus instantaneously. But that there may be a sudden recognition of soul,
            an instant sense of kindred affinities, a secret sympathy exerting magnetic influence over two individuals, without any
            decided volition on the part of either, is most undoubtedly
            true. Under favorable circumstances, this instructive preference grows into the full stature of true love; under others, it
            may attain the size of friendship; and if there exist uncongenialities around, it may be chilled and frozen into the semblance of indifference. Who that ever overcame one of these
            instinctive dislikes, did not find reason at some after period,
            to lament their having done so? Who that ever conquered
            an instinctive preference, did not find its spectre haunting the
            silent chambers of the heart, long after more reasonable
            likings had left no trace of their existence.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>One of the falsest of all false theories is that which denies
            the existence of friendship between the sexes. “ Platonic
            love," as it is called, has been so often the object of ridicule,
            that one dares not now utter its name, except with a half
            sneer. Yet what can be more beautiful, more elevating, than
            the true doctrine of the divine Plato—of him who was the
            purest and noblest of that glorious company of truth seekers,
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page185"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>the ancient philosophers—of him who taught that “ Beauty
            is but the reflected glory of Virtue, and Love only the yearning of the Soul after that perfection of which Deity is the
            ideal type.” In love, as it ordinarily exists, there is jealousy,
            and exactingness, or at least, the taint, slight though it may
            be, of sexual emotion. In Platonic love, or friendship, uniting as it does warmth and purity, claiming mutual recognition, while it denies not separate affinities, the cravings of the
            soul are fully satisfied. The terrible sense of human nature’s
            degradation, which always attends the success of mere passion, and often waits upon the tenderest affection with which
            passion mingles, is unknown in such a union. There can be
            no enduring affection which has not among its primordial
            elements much of this holy friendship, but on the contrary,
            such friendship may exist, and go on advancing in fervor and
            strength, without adopting a single constituent of what the
            world calls Love.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Yet it is only the higher order of minds which can recognise this beautiful form of human tenderness. To a low nature, physical laws seem so much stronger than spiritual
            bonds, that a love which rises superior to all grosser modes
            of expression, is as far beyond their comprehension as it is
            above their consciousness. Not that I would assert “ there
            is no sex in genius;" there is sex as strongly marked in
            mental as in physical organization ; but its existence refines
            instead of profaning the worship of truth and love. The
            happiness of men and women of genius has rarely been found
            in the sentiment of love, but it has often grown up quietly
            and surely beneath the fostering care of friendship. Genius
            rarely chooses wisely for itself in the first outgoings of its affections. It seeks the qualities which are wanting in its own
            being—and, finding these, it fancies that all other qualities
            essential to harmonious combination exist with them.
         </p>
         <p>“ Oh ask not, hope not thou too much
            Of sympathy below;
            Few are the hearts whence kindred streams
            At the same touch will flow.”
            
         </p>
         <p>This is the usual result of its experience. It clothes some
            mere human creature with its own beautiful ideality, and
            when
         </p>
         <p>“ Charm by charm unwinds
            That robes its idol,”
            
         </p>
         <p>it feels that not only the object of its worship was a false
            divinity, but that even the religion of its own deep heart is a
            weakness and an error. Of poets this is precisely true. Few
            or none have found peace in the sanctuary of their hearts
            while the altar blazed before the image of love. Yet how
            many have been blessed when they have learned to weave
            their votive garlands only for the shrine of friendship.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Whenever any exposition of the real heart of man is
            brought before the public eye, there is invariably a cry raised
            of the “ wickedness of human nature,” “ innate depravity,”
            "immoral tendencies,” and the thousand watchwords which
            people whose consciences are apt to slumber, think it necessary to repeat for the awakening of their neighbors, who in
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>all probability need no such rousing. The Correspondence
            between Burns and Clarinda, was precisely one of those expositions ; nine-tenths of its readers turned up their eyes in
            holy horror, and looked upon the man as a scapegrace and
            the woman as a “very naughty woman.” Yet why ? There
            Was earnestness of feeling and fervid expression, such as only
            a poet could utter, or a congenial nature understand ; but
            where was a single passage which could justify the charge
            of immorality ? Clarinda was a woman of refined mind, delicate tastes, and strong affections; her husband had ill-treated
            and abandoned her. Full of unappreciated tenderness of nature and unappropriated sympathies, she bad been for years
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>worse than widowed in heart, when she accidentally met
            with Burns. What was more natural than that he—a being
            whose heart, like a full cup, held by an unsteady hand, always trembled over at a breath—should have recognised a
            kindred nature? What more likely than that the woman,
            whose power of loving, even cruelty could not crush out,
            should have found a passing joy in this pure poetic sympathy. Bums had been wild and wayward.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ His pulse’s maddening play
            Wild sent him pleasure’s devious way
            By passion driven,
         </p>
         <p>And yet the light that led astray
            Was light from heaven.”
            
         </p>
         <p>He was his own true interpreter in these lines. The struggle
            of his soul after something more true than the coarseness of
            peasant life, or the cold conventionalism of high society, together with the fierce strivings of a strong physical nature,
            led him into many an error. But who that reads his exquisite
            songs can doubt his many glimpses of that higher life after
            which genius so vainly soars. He who cannot see in Bums’s
            intercourse with Clarinda, one of those “ better moments” in
            his life, is, I think, to be pitied for his obtuseness of perception.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Shame on the man who believes that a feeling like this
            could not exist without wrong! Does he believe that only
            the marriage tie can sanctify such an affection ? Alas! seldom does such an affection sanctify the church’s bond. Passion, prudence, pride, and a thousand similar motives may
            make men marry, and then the power of habit and a strong
            sense of duty assimilate them to their companions through
            life. But rarely indeed does this mystic recognition of soul
            precede or accompany the outward and visible of marriage.
            Men look not enough into their own natures. They know
            not the necessity of such a recognition, until perhaps in after
            life, when the mysteries of life have been revealed to them
            through suffering. Like Alciphron, the Epicurean, they go
            through the Egyptian darkness and mysteries of sorrow and
            sin, in search of that truth whose symbol is light.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>That this mystic recognition exists, I can no more doubt
            than I can disbelieve the existence of the subtle power of
            magnetism. But it cannot be theorised upon even by such a
            mind as Swedenborg’s. There will never be a system of
            sympathetic emotions which will satisfy those who are susceptible of their influence; and to those who are insensible
            to them, all attempts to classify such impalpabilities must
            seem absurd. Neither can it be materialized, as the mesme
            risers of the present day would fain assert. It is purely a
            spiritualism—a link in the chain which binds the soul to its
            dim remembrances of pre-existence.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Society has made certain wise and good laws for the maintenance of order. A high nature will not offend against these
            laws; but neither will it allow a narrow interpretation of
            them to destroy all the elemental purity of the soul. God
            has given us wiser and better laws, which find a ready acceptance in the souls of his true children. The laws uttered
         </p>
         <p>amid the thunders of Sinai are sufficiently comprehensive_
            
         </p>
         <p>they denounce every sin which can make man blush before
            his Maker, and he who breaks none of these, will Certainly
            never offend against society.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I am no believer in perfect sympathy—that is reserved to
            be one of the joys of heaven—but I believe in approaches to
            it, as firmly as I do in decided antipathies. And, therefore,
            as I can understand how Burns might have hated an enemy
            without seeking to murder him, so I can easily comprehend
            how he might have loved Clarinda, deeply and fondly, without degrading her by illicit passion.
         </p>
         <p>RUDOLPH HERTZMAN.
            186
            THE BROADWAY JOUkNAL.
            Original Poetry
            THE DYING ONE.
            TRANSLATED FROM THE GERMAN OF MATTHISON.
            Welcome ! Thou art the only tear
            My tired eyes shall know ;
            Clearly is shadowed in thy sphere
            This earth my home below.
            Swiftly as mist of spring-tide flies
            My dream of Life is flown,
            While of the buds of Paradise
            The Seraphs weave my crown.
            Thou, with thy toiling, dusty crowds,
            Oh Earth, afar dost flee,
            While Heaven opens through the clouds
            The Weary One to free;
            And clearly streams the Morning Light,
            A new day doth outflow,
            Oh, Land ! in thee no heavy blight
            My heart shall ever know.
            Hark ! in the Holy Grove of Palms
            The stream of Life doth roll,—
            I hear the sound of angels’ psalms
            Greeting a sister soul;
            Upward, as with strong eagle’s wings,
            To Light’s Great Source I fly;
            Death ! where is now thy bitter sting !
            Grave ! where thy victory ?
            MARIA LOWELL.
            A TALE OF LUZON.
            Sits the old man in his dwelling, ’neath the lowly roof of reeds,
            To himself his sorrows telling, as a hermit tells his beads,—
            ’Mid the hush of glowing noontide scarce a leaf stirs in the breeze,
            Where it floateth, perfume-laden, lightly o’er the citron trees,
            And a silver fount is flashing in the sunlight near the door,
            Making music with its plashing, rippling o’er the pebbly floor.
            But the old man, all unheeding, sits in loneliness apart,
            Still the page of memory reading deeply traced upon his heart.
            Lo, he weepeth! No one seeth where the tear adown his vest
            Trickles o’er the scapulary hanging low upon his breast.
            But anon he reverent bending crosses thrice his furrowed brow,
            And his voice is utterance lending to his plaintive spirit now—
            " Holy Mother ! Mother ! hear me !
            Hear a sorrowing heart complain—
            Earthly sorrow once came near thee,
            Thou hast suffered mortal pain.
            To the World’s polluted altars
            I from holier temples turned,
            And my heart, as ’twere a censer,
            There before mine idol burned,
            As the tree her odorous incense
            Poureth ever to the sun—
            I have found the God I worshipped
            But a base parhelion !
            Life’s bright visions all have left me
            Where my hopes lie crushed and strown ;
            Time of all I loved hath reft me,
            And I am alone—alone !
            Yet my soul, amid the ashes
            Where I sit with memory,
            Through the tears that cloud my lashes,
            Star of Heaven ! looks up to thee !"
            Now, a bird swan-white, and shaking drops like diamonds from his
            plumes,
            
         </p>
         <p>Springs from out the glancing fountain, and across the garden blooms,
            Bright as ’twere a heavenly sunbeam, darteth through the open
            door—
         </p>
         <p>Swan-white, enters like a spirit from the far Elysian shore.
            Thrice the old man round he circles in a viewless, airy ring,
            Then upon the rude stone table, folding down each snowy wing,
            
         </p>
         <p>Silently the white bird perches close beside the old man’s place,
            And with eyes clear, soft, and luminous, looketh in his sorrowing
            face.
         </p>
         <p>Lo ! the sun, long past its zenith, hasteth on to other lands,
            And no more the old man leaneth down his brow upon his hands,
            But beneath the glowing sunset in his cottage door he stands.
            None may know what words of comfort the swan-white bird could
            impart,
            But joy lights the old man’s visage, and sweet peace is in his heart.
            MARY E. HEWITT.
            NATIONAL NOMENCLATURE.
            
         </p>
         <p>OUR attention has been called to the following resolution,
            which was presented and acted upon at a late meeting of the
            New York Historical Society:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Resolved, That a committee be appointed to inquire and report
            whether it be not expedient that some effort, and if so, what should be
            made, to give a proper name to the country.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We are glad to see from this, that intelligent minds are at
            length roused to the importance of giving our country a title,
            which shall distinguish it from the vast continent of which it
            forms only a portion. A few individuals have long felt its
            want of a proper name, but we do not recollect that any direct
            effort to obtain one has been made until now.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>When thought is once given to this subject, it seems
            strange that our anomalous deficiency has not been more generally observed. But at home it gives little or no inconvenience. We are understood when we speak of “ this country”
            and “ our country.” A sense of our want is not forced upon
            us until intercourse with other nations commences. Then
            we discover how general an idea is attached to the words
            America and American. They call up no distinct associations of locality. Speak of an American belonging to any
            other part of this continent, and he is so fortunate as to have
            a distinguishing appellation. He is a Canadian, a Mexican, a Brazilian, a Peruvian, a Chilian,—a man that bears
            his country in his name. But what are the people of our
            confederacy ? To be known we must be described! We are
            “ inhabitants of the United States of North America,”—a ridiculous, but unavoidable circumlocution, which, after all,
            strictly implies only that we live in this particular portion of
            the world, and not that we are native to its soil, and can, by
            birthright, claim it as our country. When we think of a
            Greek or Roman, it is with associations of country and history, that at once give him character and interest. And why
            should not we, too, link to our history and destiny some
            word that shall be our fitting representative ? Surely there
            is enough to suggest one in our land of beauty and promise,
            in what we have been, and are, and hope to be.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Were a suitable name once chosen, we cannot imagine any
            serious difficulty in bringing it into general use. It is our
            national boast that the greatest obstacle cannot daunt us.
            Here they are few and trifling. We have not to conquer any
            strong attachment to an old title, nor to soothe a popular dislike to needed change. Let it be authorized by government,
            and a year or two would suffice to carry the chosen name,
            through teachers, into our numerous academies and common
            schools, and into new editions of all our popular geographies.
            While children would be catching it at their studies, their
            parents would soon become familiar with it, through newspapers and public documents.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The obvious want of a proper name for our country, and
            the ease with which an attractive one might be brought into
            general use, suggest an inquiry as to the word which we
            shall adopt Columbia is a name that has often been applied
            to us by poets and fourth of July orators, but is not one that
            has caught the public fancy. Nor can we see any appropriateness in giving the name of the great discoverer, to only a
            portion of the mighty continent which he made known to the
            civilized world. His fame is a common heritage, and his
            name properly belongs to the whole. Another objection to
            adopting it for ourselves exclusively, is that it has been already applied to a republic now unfortunately in fragments.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Washington Irving proposes the fine old Indian word Appalachia. This has the great merit of significance. It brings
            to mind not only that extinct race beyond whom even no Indian tradition can go, but also the great natural features of
            our country upon which they have left the record of their
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page187"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>names and labors. The interest which would attach to it is
            common to the Union. We have scarcely a State or Territory
            in which some vestiges of the lost race do not appear.
            Their expressive names cling to our mountain peaks, and
            theirs are the most wonderful monuments of human skill
            that rise in the midst of our prairies and valleys.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Field, the mover of the resolution in the Historical
            Society, has heretofore proposed that, as a nation, we take
            the name of America, and bestow Columbia upon the continent. The history of the last century is sufficient proof
            that greater changes than this have been effected in the
            names of kingdoms and republics. Custom would not, therefore, present an insurmountable obstacle. A little confusion
            would naturally arise from it at first, though it could neither
            be of great extent nor long continuance. The words North
            and South Columbia, would express all that we now mean
            by North and South America. As every country contained
            in them beside our own, has its distinct appellation, they
            could not long feel any inconvenience from the change. It
            would scarcely be felt in any but public transactions. We
            have to choose between a name for ourselves or one for the
            continent. In discontinuing the present name of the continent, we change the word which is least frequently used.
            Were common consent once obtained, it would evidently be
            easy to accomplish this.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>America is a name most obviously appropriate to our
            country. In our early existence as a people, it was virtually
            given to us. We were called the American colonies; our
            national legislature was the American Congress; and we
            achieved our independence as Americans. It is the name
            naturally applied to us in all but our foreign and official relations.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>One important consideration in this change, would be the
            appropriate act of justice it would render to the great navigator who has been so unworthily robbed of this slight reward for his years of patient and persevering toil. It has
            long been felt proper that his name should belong to at least
            some portion of his discovery, but it would be far more fitting
            and just, that the common land he found should in common
            bear his name.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>For ourselves, we care little whether Apalachia or America become our national title, or what other is chosen in their
            Place, if neither of these will suit the public taste, so that it
            be only one that shall fall pleasantly on our ears, while it becomes a watchword to awaken high thoughts and purposes.
            Let it be one that we shall love to see linked with that national literature which is even now springing up in our midst,
            and which will become more characteristic with every successful effort to make our country true to itself, and less imitative even in so small a thing as its names.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>So far as the Committee appointed by the Historical Society under the resolution we have quoted, are concerned,
            we are sure of the faithful and competent discharge of the
            duty assigned them. All bring to it a hearty love of country,
            a deep sense of our great want as a people, and a warm admiration of those beautiful Indian names which are passing
            from our hills and waters with every successive year.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The above well-written article is furnished by a correspondent whose opinions we highly value. In this case, however,
            We give our vote for Apalachia—first, because it is distinctive;
            America is not, and can never be made so. We may legislate as much as we please, and assume for our country whatever name we think right—but to us it will be no name,
            properly so called, unless we can take it away from the regions which employ it at present. Now South America is
            America, and will insist on remaining so. We give our vote
            for Apalachia, secondly, because it is indigenous, springing
            from the country itself, or from one of its most magnificent
            and distinctive features—thirdly, because in employing it, we
            do honor to the Aborigines, whom, hitherto, we have at all
            points unmercifully despoiled, assassinated, and dishonored—
            fourthly, because in itself it is musical, and of sufficient length
            to have dignity and force—fifthly and lastly, because it is the
            suggestion of the most deservedly eminent among all the
            pioneers of American literature. It is but just that Mr. Irving should name the land, for which in Letters he first established a name.
         </p>
         <p>NEW YORK GALLERY OF THE FINE ARTS.
            Gentlemen—
            
         </p>
         <p>In your article under this head, you have done some injustice (unintentional, no doubt) to those who have been instrumental in procuring the gallery for the public. The pictures of which you complain, were in the collection while it
            was private; those by Mr. Flagg were painted by him when
            quite young, and while he was under Mr. Reed’s patronage.
            They were not placed in his gallery on account of their intrinsic merit, but because he wished to encourage one in whom
            he thought he saw talent of a high order. The family of
            Mr. Reed declined selling a part of the Gallery, nor would
            they sell it, except with the stipulation that it should remain
            entire.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The first movers in the matter discovered that there was a
            feeling among Mr. Reed’s old friends, and business associates,
            which would secure the purchase of the collection, and they
            thought it a favorable opportunity to form the nucleus of a
            permanent gallery. They have not been disappointed ; you
            will admit that such a beginning is better than none—you
             could not have had the Coles and Mounts, without the Flaggs.
            That there should be no picture in the collection by Inman or
            Page, is to be regretted, but may we not hope that some of
            their liberal friends will give each an order for a picture, to
            be presented to the gallery ? this is the way in which it must
            increase, if at all. Most of our eminent artists, Cole, Mount,
            Durand, Shegogue, Chapman, Ingham, Edmonds, have promised to paint a picture and present it to the Institution. Several gentlemen have also engaged to give orders for the
            same purpose. If a gentleman presents a picture, he will, of
            course, make his own election as to who shall paint it. The
            writer does not agree with you that no copy should ever be
            in the gallery. Good copies may be of great service to young
            artists who cannot go abroad to see the originals.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>You have made honorable mention of one gentleman, as
            being the most active in securing the collection. He would,
            no doubt, appreciate such an honor, but the facts are otherwise; the plan did not originate with him. Where so many
            have been active and liberal, it is invidious to mention names.
            It is not important who has the most. The gallery is commenced, and all that is now needed to secure its extension is
            liberality in purse and feeling.	S. J.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We give place to the above communication very cheerfully but it
            does not allude to the chief cause of our remarks on the gallery, which
            was, the absence of any regulation in the Constitution or By-Laws in
            regard to the kind of works of Art to be added to it-seeing that once
            the gallery becomes possessed of a work, it can never in any manner
            be alienated. And the fact of there being some pictures in it of a character which, our correspondent admits, would not entitle them to a
            place in a public gallery of Art, suggested the necessity of some definite principle being fixed upon to prevent the admission of improper
            works hereafter. We intended to make no invidious distinction in
            naming any of the gentlemen who had been instrumental in founding
            the gallery, but mentioned those to whose exertions we believed the
            public to be most indebted. The paintings now belonging to the gallery are hardly proper subjects for criticism, owing to the peculiar
            circumstances which led to their purchase—but they are now public
            property; and being called “ The New York Gallery of the Fine Arts "
            strangers who are ignorant of the causes that occasioned their collection, might look upon them as a singular collection of works of Art for
            the purpose at forming the nucleus of a gallery.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The artists who have volunteered to present pictures to the infant
            institution, deserve the thanks of the community; and it is hoped that
            there will not be wanting liberal-minded men of wealth to repay their
            generosity, by giving them orders for other pictures to be placed by
            their side. In this manner a gallery of American Art might be formed
            which would confer renown upon our city.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In regard to copies, we differ from our correspondent. All the principal galleries in Europe do contain copies, it is true, but a gallery of
            Art, to be really valuable, should be unique. We doubt whether an
            artist can benefit himself by studying any other than original works.
            What we hoped to see, when the New York gallery was first projected, was the foundation of a gallery of American Art; one that we
            could point to with pride, as the product of our own soil Our country
            is so belittled by imitation and copyism, that we cannot bat think that
            a collection of Original American works would have a beneficial effect
            in other departments, and lead to self-dependence in other things of
            seemingly greater importance than paintings and statues.
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page188"></div>
            THE FINE ARTS.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. A. L. Dick, of this city, has nearly ready for publication a steel engraving of the last supper by Leonardo da Vinci,
            copied from a proof impression of the engraving by Raffaelle
            Morghen, which was purchased by Mr. Allen, son-in-law of
            the late Luman Reed, of the widow of this celebrated engraver in Italy. The engraving cost Mr. Allen two hundred
            dollars. It is probably as fine an impression of this celebrated work as exists, and Mr. Dick has succeeded in producing a copy which can hardly be distinguished from the original.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The fate of this celebrated picture, the first great work of
            its immortal author, and the greatest of all his productions,
            forms the most curious episode in the history of Art. It was
            painted in the refectory of the Convent St. Maria della
            Grazia, on a wall twenty-eight feet in length ; the figures being larger than life. Sixteen years after it was finished,
            Francis the First wanted to take it to Paris by removing the
            wall, but of course, he could not do it, which has always
            been regretted, for if he had done so the painting would have
            been preserved. In 1500 an inundation happened at Milan
            which overflowed the Convent and nearly effaced the colors
            of the picture, and by the middle of the century they had entirely faded. In 1652 a door was cut through the wall under the figure of Christ which destroyed the feet. In 1726 a
            bungling artist named Belotti, completed the work of destruction by painting over it entirely ; and in 1770 another
            bungler named Mazza retouched it, leaving only three heads.
            In 1796 the French army occupied the convent and used the
            refectory for a stable, filling the consecrated place with hay.
            Something of the painting on the wall, though not of Leonardo’s work, still remains and is religiously preserved. But the
            cartoons of the heads, which he sketched before he executed them in the large size, still exist, as well as many other
            parts of the picture which were copied by his scholars partly
            under his own supervision. The Cartoons are executed in
            black chalk and slightly colored ; many of them are in England, and others in different parts of Italy. There is a Cartoon, the original size of the picture in the Leuchtenberg
            gallery at Munich, made by the Italian painter Bossi; and
            there have been many attempts to reproduce the picture, the
            most successful of which is the engraving of Raffaelle Morghen, which has served as a model for nearly all the copies
            that have been seen in this country, and is the one which
            Mr. Dick has used in producing his engraving. The picture
            is too well known to need any comments, but the artist, the
            great Leonardo, is not as well known as his merits should
            make him. Whenever painting is alluded to the names of
            Michel Angelo, Raffaelle, Titian and Correggio slip from the
            tongue as if by instinct, but the name of Leonardo should
            stand at the head of all painters. He was the greatest man
            of his century, at least, and he combined the largest variety
            of accomplishments, and the most brilliant genius, of any artist that ever lived. Any work from the mind of such a man
            must always be of enduring interest, and Mr. Dick has rendered the public a service by placing at their command for a
            comparatively trifling consideration, a reproduction of the
            greatest of all his works in the plastic arts.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Painters are now content to be only painters, or rather they
            are content to be hardly that, but Leonardo was a poet, a musician, an architect, an astronomer, a sculptor, a mathematition and a natural philosopher; and he excelled in all. We
            have, to be sure, in our own days a painter and a financier,
            which, perhaps, is as marvelous a combination as has even
            been known of opposite qualities; and in the case of Mr.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Morse we have a very ordinary painter and a very extraordinary philosopher, but these cases are rare. In Boston again
            they can boast of a painter, a poet, a sculptor, a musician and
            a lawyer, which is doubtless the strangest combination of
            all. Leonardo, Alberti, Michael Angelo and Raffaelle, were
            all painters and architects. But we have produced no painter-architect in modem times; although we have in our
            city a most promising painter who first distinguished himself
            by his architectural genius. We may have a painter-architect yet. Every architect should, indeed, be a painter, although every painter need not be an architect.
         </p>
         <p>ARCHITECTURE.
            
         </p>
         <p>We have lately had the pleasure of examining the plan
            for Stewart’s new Store to be erected on the site of Washington Hall, in Broadway. It will occupy the whole ground,
            and be devoted entirely to the business of that establishment.
            In point of architectural embellishment it will form the finest and most remarkable feature of this noble street, unless
            some other building of finer proportions should be put up before it is completed. The front in Broadway will be white
            marble. The account given in the Mirror, some time since,
            of the court yard for carriages and so forth, of course never
            had an existence excepting in some Chateau en Espagne belonging to the Editor of that lively paper. The style of Architecture resembles somewhat the Palladian, and makes a
            nearer approach to some of the faҫades of the London Club
            houses than that of any building in the city. The store will
            be an ornament to the city when it is finished, and as a place
            of business we believe without a parallel in the world. The
            Architect is Mr. Trench, who has erected some of the finest
            street fronts in the country.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We should be glad to give an engraving of this beautiful
            front, but we cannot gain the consent of the Architect. There
            appears to be a strange feeling of jealousy among the profession which we can hardly account for, but which we believe
            to be the direct cause of the many disgraceful architectural
            follies that bring reproach upon our city. Instead of that
            mutual interchange of thought and commerce of opinion
            which in every profession lead to improvement and discoveries, the Architects of our city labor with as much secrecy
            as the old chemists did when they were seeking the transmutation of metals; and the design for a door or a cornice is locked up as carefully as though it were some new invention subject to a patent. One of the evil effects of this
            secrecy may be seen in the fronts of two houses now
            in the course of erection in Union Square: although of
            the same proportions, built of the same materials, and nearly of the same style, the effect of the buildings is entirely
            destroyed by a want of correspondence in the enrichments. The owners of the houses were desirous of building
            them alike, but the architects refused to exhibit their drawings and they were compelled to work regardless of each other. The two houses appear to be biting their thumbs at
            each other like the houses of Capulet and Montague.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The National Academy should institute an Architectural
            Department, and give a course of lectures on architectural
            experience, as well as in other departments of the fine arts. If
            any of our architects were men of genius they could not be
            guilty of this littleness of feeling, but would do something to
            infuse a proper sentiment into the whole body. Judging from
            the bitterness of spirit with which architects generally assail each other, we should say that they were the most jealous tribe in the world, and much more worthy of being called the genus irritabile than authors, who are as insensible to
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page189"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>reproof as cast iron when compared with them. The correspondents and essayists of the Architects’ Journal, the Candiduses and Dr. Fultons, are the most waspish tribe that we
            have met in print. It was the most amusing thing conceivable to read the trenchant attacks on Dickens which they used
            to keep up on account of Mr. Pecksniff: though they might
            quarrel among themselves, and fling brick bats and mortar at
            each other’s heads, yet they all joined in the onslaught upon
            Mr. Pecksniff. Every hod carrier in the United Kingdom felt
            himself insulted by Dickens in making Pecksniff an architect.
            And in truth we did not much blame them. They had need.
            Every botch in the profession is now called a Pecksniff, and
            the Pecksniffian style of architecture is as common an expression as the Palladian or any other. It was a name the profession needed, and they have it.
         </p>
         <p>THE CONCERT ROOM.
            COMPLIMENTARY CONCERTS.
            
         </p>
         <p>This innocent and easy method of “ raising the wind,” is
            becoming quite popular. We hear of quite a number of
            these charity concerts yet to come off We are not informed of the names of the lucky individuals to be so honored,
            but we have no doubt that they will be found in every way
            worthy of public commiseration. We are truly at a loss to
            understand how any one possessing delicacy or refinement of
            feeling, can accept even at the hands of his friends so very
            equivocal a compliment. There is certainly no disgrace in
            being poor, but there certainly is disgrace in being as poor in
            heart as in pocket.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We do not mean to reflect upon any individual in these
            our remarks, but we wish to impress upon our professional
            brethren how much beneath, how derogatory to the general
            character and standing of musicians it is, to appeal to the
            public in the position of mendicants. Do we see the other
            learned professions in this degrading position ? Does the
            lawyer, the artist, the physician, the divine, supplicate the
            commiseration of the public? No! they start in life to
            struggle with the world manfully—to watch and wait, to
            suffer and endure, but they scorn to blazon to the world
            their wants or necessities. The like respectable and honorable feeling should guide the conduct of those who follow a
            profession only less honorable than those above mentioned,
            because its followers, deficient in self-respect, strive not in
            the least to either elevate or sustain its character. It ceases
            to be a matter of wonder that society holds the musical profession in such light esteem, when we reflect upon the character of but too many who follow it. A recklessness of public opinion, a contempt for the wholesome forms and usages
            of society, a general intemperateness of conduct, and a laxity
            of principle in worldly concerns, are, we regret to say, distinguishing traits in but too many of the musical profession.
            There are, of course, many bright exceptions among our musicians, but these, alas! only serve to prove the rule.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>For the failings of musicians, the public is in a measure to
            blame. There is a large class of persons who make theatres and music their hobbies; who glory in the society of
            these artists ; who boast of their acquaintance ; who hang
            round them, toady them, treat them, and in a measure force
            them into habits of dissipation. This custom exists in every
            degree of the profession, and if self-respect, and independent
            Pride be not strong, the temptation proves too powerful to
            resist. By many of the profession this society is cultivated
            lor what ? why, for the sake of making a benefit! For this
            paltry end, they sell character, standing, public respect and
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>private esteem. By many writers, the first benefit is considered the first step to degradation of character, and fully
            agreeing in the opinion, we would gladly see the system
            abolished altogether.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>What is a complimentary concert, but a benefit in disguise ?
            A few personal friends of the individual meet together (unknown to said individual, of course) and form themselves into a committee for the purpose of getting up a complimentary
            concert to said individual. What is their next step ? Do
            they immediately subscribe for tickets to fill the room for
            their friend, out of their own pockets ? O no! they issue advertisements and large posting bills, to allure the public, so
            that in plain truth, they (the friends) give him the compliment, leaving the public to give him the benefit. Faugh ! the
            whole system is rotten, and smacks of commission, agency
            and connivance; and every right-minded person should discountenance and condemn it!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Madame Otto and the German Society.—We have been waiting in the expectation that some member of the committee of the
            above Society would give a satisfactory explanation of the slur cast
            upon Madame Otto, and of the reason of Signora Pico’s engagement.
            Our attention was particularly called to this matter, by an able and
            truthful article in the Emporium a week or two since, in which the
            writer puts the question in every possible light. He remarks:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Contrary to our expectation, we heard of no cause, no reason, why
            such a course was pursued, and why German artists, who are popular
            and are held in high estimation by our citizens generally, should be
            put aside; why their gratuitous services should be dispensed with, or
            why the funds of the Society, or rather the funds of the poor, should
            be deprived of a heavy sum of money, (at least $200 or more) which
            must be paid for the services of Signora Pico.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The writer then clearly sets forth the claims of Madame Otto, to at
            least, the polite consideration of her countrymen, and remarks, that
            the committee were bound to ask her to give her aid, even if they did
            not intend to offer her a consideration for her services. We think so
            too, but we also maintain, that they were bound not only to ask her,
            but to pay her, at the least, glove and carriage money.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ But if we look upon the subject in another light, what right had
            these gentlemen to slight the lady in the manner they have done ?
            Dared they to urge their preference against public opinion, popular
            favor, and the interest of the poor ? They will tell us that Signora
            Pico will draw a larger audience to the Tabernacle ! We doubt it.
            The great mass of persons who will visit that Concert, will be the
            German and American friends of the Society, and others who go from
            motives of charity. These world go, to benefit the fund, no matter
            what attraction might be offered.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>All this is perfectly just and quite unexceptionableWe do not believe that Signora Pico drew twenty persons to the Concert of the Society. We do not believe in the extensive popularity of this lady; we
            do not believe either in its extent or in its stability, from the simple
            reason that there is not sufficient evidence of genius to warrant the
            immense expenditure of literary gas which has been let off upon various occasions of this lady’s appearance. The systematic puffing was,
            however, ingeniously conceived, and ably executed. But this said gas
            is expensive to manufacture, and should the material fail, the supply
            will cease, and the inflated reputation collapses into nothing, leaving
            only the odor that “ stinks in the nostrils,” of the judicious and right
            thinking. Signora Pico needed none of this, for she is a talented and
            careful artiste, and would infallibly have won the public favor unheralded and unpuffed.
         </p>
         <p>The writer in the Emporium, further on, very justly observes, that
            
         </p>
         <p>"The same principle which should have induced them to engage Madame Otto should also have induced them to have had no other than a
            German Director for this German Concert, as long at least as one could
            be found fully capable for the task. We have every respect for Mr.
            U. C. Hill both as a man and an artist, but we could have found some
            Germans at least as capable as conductors, and as popular as men. Mr.
            Timm a German, talented as an artist, a great favorite with every
            body and ever ready to respond to the calls of charity; Mr. Wiegers,
            who, at the late Philharmonic Concert proved himself one of the best
            conductors we have, and a number of others. There would have been
            a show of justice and nationality in patronizing their own countrymen."
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We fully coincide with the opinions here expressed. It is disgrace,
            ful in the committee to have chosen any other than a German Director,
            and it shows a littleness of spirit and want of national feeling in the
            Germans composing the orchestra, that they did not resist the implied
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page190"></div>
            imputation that the city could boast of no German professor capable
            of conducting such a concert.
            
         </p>
         <p>We hear that the fact of Signora Pico being engaged, was taken as
            a precedent, by many of the German instrumentalists. They naturally
            said—if Signora Pico, a foreigner, in no way connected with the objects of the Society, is engaged at an expense of some hundreds of dollars, to the exclusion of German vocalists, why should we be made the
            catspaw of the committee, who, by the means af our gratuitous services,
            can afford to remunerate an alien to our name ? And thus arguing, we
            are told, that many insisted upon being paid for their assistance.
         </p>
         <p>MUSICAL REVIEW.
            “ My Bark which o’er the tide.’’ Barcarole, from the new Opera of
            the Daughter of St. Mark, composed by M. W. Balfe.
            “ Erin’s Land my Home." Words by Henry Russell; Music by N.
            J. Sporle.
            “ Once upon a time," written by R. H. Taylor, dedicated to Mrs. J.
            E. Lodge, composed by Miss Augusta Browne.
            “ Tubal Cain." Written by Charles Mackay, Esq.; composed by
            Henry Russell.
            The above are published by W. H. Oakes, and sold by E.H. Wade,
            197 Washington street, Boston.
            
         </p>
         <p>The first on the list is one of the most popular songs from the last
            new Opera by Balfe. This composer is so prolific in his powers of
            production, that we scarcely feel safe in saying that such and such a
            piece is from the last work by Balfe, for there may be yet another.
            The Barcarole before us is a very pretty and flowing melody in G, 6-8
            time. It is not for its originality—it is not for the science, that it
            charms the ear, but it cannot fail to be popular with every one.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The second song is by N. J. Sporle. This is a pretty ballad, and
            somewhat above the usual run of this gentleman’s compositions. The
            air is easy and familiar, and the words breathe a noble and elevated
            sentiment.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The next song, by Miss Augusta Browne, would be a very pretty
            and pleasing song if the last twelve bars of each verse were left out.
            The six bars marked con Multo Sentimento, bear no relation to those
            which go before, or to those which follow after. They interrupt the
            movement of the song, and offer no point of consequence sufficient to
            warrant the interruption. The accompaniments show a marked improvement in Miss Browne’s writing, but we advise her to abolish the
            arpeggio mark with which all her writings abound, for it is a vulgarity
            in style, and is rarely used, except for some very visible effect, by writers of any reputation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Tubal Cain ! The only merit which Mr. Russell can claim for this
            song, is the evidence of good taste in selecting such bold and pithy
            words, to make his music bearable. There is not one atom of originality, nor the slightest evidence of thought in the music, but the accompaniments show more than usual care, and are doubtless the work
            of one of the many poor and unemployed men of talent with which
            London abounds.	
         </p>
         <p>These songs are all got out in that elegant style for which Mr.
            Oakes is so justly celebrated.
            MUSICAL ITEMS.
            We hear that Mr. Perabeau intends producing the Lobge-
            sang, of Mendelssohn, at a concert shortly.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. J. A. Kyle, the talented flutist, gave a concert at Newark, assisted by Madame Pico and Signor Sanquirico, Miss De Luce,
            and Mr. W. A. King. We regret to hear, that in spite of the liberality displayed by the Beneficiary, the room was not half filled. What
            becomes of the immensely attractive power of Pico’s name?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A large number of German instrumentalists gave a concert
            at Niblo’s last week. We are not acquainted with the result, as we
            did not receive any tickets at our office.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Ole Bui has left New Orleans, where his success has been
            doubtful. Wherever this artist goes he always squabbles with those
            he engages. The chief cause of his want of success, has been laid at
            the door of the poor orchestrians. His Niagara and the 8olitude of
            the Prairie, have been severely handled by the New Orleans press.
         </p>
         <p>We expect a whole host of wandering nightingales to visit
            us from the south, in the course of the next two months.
            
         </p>
         <p>We hear nothing of the new opera house ; nor of the short
            season at Palmo's with the Italians now in this city; nor of the proposed managerial speculation of Signor De Begnis.
         </p>
         <p>The first soirée of the New York Vocal Society comes off
            at the Minerva Rooms this evening.
            The last Philharmonic concert takes place early in the en-
            suing month.
            The Misses Bramson have been very successful in Balti-
            more.
            
         </p>
         <p>The choirs of the Catholic churches in New York, have
            been in a most unquiet state for the past month. Changes have taken
            place in nearly all of them. St. Peter’s, St. James’, St. Joseph’s, the
            Cathedral, and others, have changed organists, singers, &amp;c. &amp;c. One
            or two Episcopal churches have been in the same state.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We call the attention of our readers to the advertisement of Mr.
            Warner, who is, without doubt, the most successful class teacher in
            the city. He has had many years’ experience, and has instructed a
            vast number in this city. We can conscientiously recommend all
            those anxious to study music by this system, to place themselves under Mr. Warner’s instruction.
         </p>
         <p>MISCELLANY.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mrs. R. S. Nichols.—Mrs. Nichols, of Cincinnati, is one of our
            most imaginative and vigorous poets. We have lately fallen upon a
            copy of “ An Address of the Carriers of the Cincinnati Daily American Republican to its Patrons, for January, 1845.” This is the composition of Mrs. Nichols; and although we should scarcely look for
            anything very original in a New-Year’s Address, still there is a great
            deal both of originality and of other high merit here. We quote at
            random a stanza or two, not hoping, of course, to convey any just idea
            of the skill manifested in the general conduct of the poem—that point
            which is so severe a test of the artist:
         </p>
         <p>Bride of my youthful days, gentle and fair,
            Low lies thy grave at the portals of Time !
            Wrapt in thy shroud of long sunshiny air,
            The hours upborne by the wings of the air,
            Entombed thee in love, singing dirges sublime !
            *****
            Thin grew my whitened beard—moistened my eye ;
            Faint was my voice’s tone—languished my heart;
            Then, in my dreary age, Autumn drew nigh,
            Like a sweet angel of love from the sky,
            Ready to act the Samaritan’s part!
            *****
            Oft, when the glowing stars—footprints of God !—
            Lit up the earth with a holier light,
            We o’er each pleasant place falteringly trod,
            Wailing the fate of the brown-fading sod
            That shrunk from our steps, as if tearing a blight,
            Down by a flashing rill, winding in shade,
            Leaping to sunlight in gladness and mirth,
            We, in a softened mood, pleasantly made
            A couch, where the streamlet a monody played—
            A death-song for one of the brightest of Earth !
            Pale grew the berries red, close at our feet;
            Wan looked the waning Moon over our head ;
            Then moaned the hollow winds, winged and fleet,
            And Autumn folded her white winding-sheet,
            While Winter approached, and enshrouded the dead !
            
         </p>
         <p>The rhythm here is anapӕstic—by no means an usual one with us,
            and requiring much art in the handling. There are some lapses, to be
            sure, in all the stanzas except the second one quoted, which is rhythmically perfect. Even the lapses, however, or variations, are strictly
            defensible, and show that Mrs. Nichols has, at all events, a well cultivated ear.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Hudson.—We are rejoiced to learn that this new lecturer on
            Shakspeare, has met with sufficient encouragement to induce him to
            commence another course of lectures in New York. Not that we think
            the public greatly needs enlightening on this subject, or that Mr. Hudson will be likely to create a new interest in Shakspeare, but because
            it is encouraging to know that there is a sufficient number of people in
            our community willing to patronise genius, when genius will take the
            pains to make itself known. We have no doubt of there being at least
            a thousand young men in our city, as fully competent to instruct, or
            amuse the public, as Mr. Hudson, who will never be heard of, simply
            because they have not energy enough to force themselves out of
            their studies and dusty offices into the world; or because they fear
            there is not intelligence enough to appreciate their talents. It
            may be thought that Mr. Hudson’s very peculiar manner attracts a
            great part of his audiences, but we believe that his manner keeps away
            many more than it attracts. For ourselves, we wonder that anybody
            can be induced to listen to him a second time; perhaps, if we had survived the first lecture that we attended, we could have gone again, but
            that was impossible. Such was the peculiar effect of his drawling
            enunciation upon our nerves, that after sitting fifteen minutes in the
            sound of his voice, the marrow in our bones began to dissolve, our
            teeth were set on edge as by the filing of a saw, and chills crept
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page191"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>over us like an ague-fit; to have listened a moment longer would
            have induced a paralysis, or something worse; and we did not begin
            to resume our usual serenity until we had beeu jolted in an omnibus
            from the Stuyvesant Institute to Bowling-green. There is a member of Congress from Massachusetts, of the same name as Mr. Hudson,
            to whom he bears a very strong resemblance in his speech and countenance. We remember having heard the Hon. Mr. Hudson make
            a speech in Congress, in which he repeated two or three dozens of
            times, the phrase "yallar com from Virginny,” and every time that
            any body laughed, he laughed with them. His speech was a sensible
            speech enough, notwithstanding the “ yallar com,” and the lectures of
            his name-sake are not a whit the less valuable to those who can listen
            to them, for being delivered in the worst provincial drawl that ever
            wounded a human ear.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have heard Mr. Hudson (Shakspeare Hudson) called a humbug,
            but a humbug he is not. He is a quack, without question ; such a
            quack as Shakspeare himself was, and such a quack as every man of
            genius must be, who is not a regular practitioner. It is not likely that
            there is a professor of elocution in the world who would consent that
            Mr. Hudson should open his mouth in public. But what are professors
            of elocution to him ? he is a professor himself.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Newspaper Courtesies.—There is no class of public servants, who
            owe their success to the aid of each other, more than newspaper editors ; none, who have it in their power to do each other so much harm,
            or so much good. A certain editor holds the daily control of the opinions of a certain circle, who look to him for information on all subjects
            which they lack opportunities of becoming personally acquainted with,
            themselves, and he may, by a good word, or an ill one, make or mar
            the fortunes of his brethren of the press with his own readers. It is
            this sense of general dependence which has led to a certain degree
            of conventional courtesy among our newspaper editors, which is often
            carried to the extreme of amenity, almost ridiculous, and has rendered
            downright malicious abuse, sometimes called spicy writing, acceptable
            in its place. We are as yet too young to regard our own censure or
            applause of any particular consequence to any of our elder brethren,
            but it shall be our aim, as it has been, to speak candidly of the merits
            and demerits of those with whom we come in contact, and we ask for
            nothing more in return. Much harm, it is confessed on all sides, has
            been done to every kind of art, newspaper writing included, by the indiscriminate puffs of the press. The public have been often grossly
            wronged, and real merit insulted by such a course, which is beginning
            generally to be abandoned. For ourselves, we set our faces against
            all puffs, unless paid for as advertisements, and then they deceive nobody. The time has nearly gone by, when editors were presented
            with remarkable gooseberries, and baskets of very red strawberries,
            as an inducement to write an article worth a dozen limes the thing presented, in glorification of the donor.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Saturday Emporium.—There is an excellent weekly paper
            with this title published in New York, by Ward &amp; Co., of Ann street.
            It so happens we have never seen more than three numbers of it, the
            last of which contained an imputation upon our editorial honesty,
            which we felt bound to answer; and being struck with the generally
            agreeable tone of its articles, its enormous size, and neat appearance,
            we took that occasion to stale the same to our friend, the public. It
            so happened also that we had just read a paragraph which has been
            pretty generally circulated the last three months, informing the poor
            that a sheet of brown paper would make a warmer coverlid for a be
            than an ordinary rosa blanket; and it seemed to us that a poor family
            could not do a better thing this cold weather, than to provide themselves with a paper for a sixpence, which would answer the double
            purpose of a “ quilt by night, a library by day,” which we said.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It appears that the Emporium regards this as a doubtful compliment,
            but it appears to us that we could not have paid it a more unequivocal
            one. However, the Emporium says it prefers the calumet of peace,
            to the tomahawk of war. Very good. Then put this in your pipe
            and smoke it; and when you copy any thing from our columns again,
            have the kindness to give us credit for it.
         </p>
         <p>To Readers and Correspondents.--We again thank R. H.
            Shall we not soon hear from P. P. C., of Va.?
            We return our warmest acknowledgments to the author of the "Tale of
            Luzon"—also to our esteemed friend, M L. L.
            
         </p>
         <p>Is there no hope of our hearing from “ Ellen” of the C. M. ?
            The Communication from "M. of Albany," is received. It will appear
            at the first convenient opportunity.
         </p>
         <p>THE
            SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
            Published Monthly at Richmond, Va.; price Five Dollars per Year.
            THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835,
            has a large subscription list among the e1ite of the Southern Aristocracy,
            and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the “ Broadway Jour-
            nal,” 153 Broadway.
            REPUBLICATION OF THE FOREIGN MAGAZINES.
            LONDON, EDINBURGH, FOREIGN, and WEST-
            MINSTER QUARTERLY REVIEWS, and BLACKWOOD’S MAGA-
            ZINE.
            
         </p>
         <p>The above Periodicals are reprinted in New-York, immediately on their
            arrival by the British steamers, in a beautiful clear type, on fine white paper
            and are faithful copies of the originals—Blackwood’s Magazine being an exact fac-simile of the Edinburgh Edition.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The wide spread fame of these splendid Periodicals renders it needless to
            say much to their praise. As literary organs, they stand far in advance of
            any works of a similar stamp now uublished, while their political complexion
            is marked by a dignity, candor, and forbearance not often found in works of
            a party character.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>They embrace the views of the three great parties in England, Whig, Tory,
            and Radical. “ Blackwood” and the " London Quarterly” are Tory; the
            “ Edinburgh Review” Whig ; and the “ Westminster” Radical. The “Foreign Quarterly” is purely literary, being devoted principally to criticisms on
            foreign Continental Works.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The prices of the Re-Prints are less than one third of those of the foreign
            copies ; and while they are equally well got up, they afford all that advantage to the American over the English reader.
         </p>
         <p>TERMS.—Payment to be made in Advance.
            For the four Quarterly Reviews, $8.00 per annum,
            For any three	“	“	7.00	“
            For any two	“	“	5.00	“
            For any one	“	“	3.00	“
            For Blackwood, Monthly,	3.00	“
            For 4 Reviews Sc Blackwood,	10.00	•*
            CLUBBING.
            Four copies of any or all the above works will be sent to one address, on
            payment of the regular subscription for three—the fourth copy being gratis.
            Remittances ana communications (post-paid or franked), should be made to
            LEONARD SCOTT &amp; CO., Pub’s, 112 Fulton st., N. Y.
            KEIGHTLEY’S HISTORICAL WORKS.
            THE HISTORY OF GREECE.—By Thomas Keight-
            
         </p>
         <p>i-v with notes and additions by G. Toulman Smith, in one volume.
            THE HISTORY OF ROMEBy the same author, with notes and addition. in the same manner, in one volume.
         </p>
         <p>HISTORY OF THE ROMAN EMPIRE—Being a continuation of
            the History of Rome. By the same author. In one volume.
            THE HISTORY OF ENGLAND-From the Invasion of Julius Cӕsar to
            the close of the reign of George IV. By the same author, with note.
            additions as above. In two volumes. Published by
            	TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John St.
            PIANO FORTES.—V. S. HARRISON, 23 Canal
            Street, N. Y.
            
         </p>
         <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as iron frames,
            &amp;c., with a compass of 6 1/2 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of
            23 years experience in the business.
         </p>
         <p>STODART &amp; DUNHAM,
            PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURERS,
            361 BROADWAY.
            JAMES PIRSSON,
            PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER,
            88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.
            A large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
            TERMS MODERATE.
            SINGING AT SIGHT.
            MR. WARNER, translator of Weber s theoretical
            
         </p>
         <p>work &amp;c., continues his course of Vocal Instruction at his rooms, 411
            Broad-Way. Mr. Warner’, new Illustrating Apparatus will also furnish
            very great facilities for a ready and full understanding of the subject preparatory to the study of Instrumental Music.
         </p>
         <p>MITCHELL’S OLYMPIC THEATRE.
            PERFORMANCES EVERY EVENING. DOORS
            open at Seven ; Curtain rises at half-past Seven. ’
            Dress Circle, SO Cents. Upper Boxes, 25 cents. Pit, 12 1-2 cents. Private
            Boxes, $3. Box Office open every day.
            JOHN DOUGLAS,
            BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            
         </p>
         <p>NO 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every description of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
            with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, on terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
         </p>
         <p>January 16, 1846.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page192"></div>
            THIS DAY PUBLISHED,
            No. 1 of
            WILEY &amp; PUTNAM’S LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING,
            CONTAINING
            EOTHEN, OR TRACES OF TRAVEL BROUGHT HOME FROM THE EAST. 1 Vol. very beauti-
            fully printed on fine paper, in large clear type. 60 Cents.
            
         </p>
         <p>"This is a real book—not a sham. It displays a varied and comprehensive power of mind,
            and a genuine mastery over the first and strongest of modern languages. The author has caught the character and humor of the eastern mind
            as completely as Anastasius, while in his gorgeous descriptions and
            power of sarcasm, he rivals Vathek. His terseness, vigor, and hold imagery, remind
            us of the brave old style of Fuller and of South, to which he adds a
            spirit, freshness, and delicacy all his own.”—Quarterly Review.
         </p>
         <p>No. 2.
            MARY SCHWEIDLER, THE AMBER WITCH. A Trial for Witchcraft. 1 vol. very beautifully
            printed
            on fine paper, in large clear type. 38 Cents.
            “We have read nothing in Fiction or in History which has so completely rivetted and
            absorbed our interest as tills little volume. If it be a fiction, it
            a worthy—we can give no higher praise—of De Foe.”—Quarterly Review.
            Published and for sale by
            WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            PIANO FORTES.
            THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, late Practical partner of
            
         </p>
         <p>the old established firm of 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the larest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most superior
            quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone.
            Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano
            Fortes aw ays on hire.
         </p>
         <p>BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
            
         </p>
         <p>work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method
            the moat rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies, are
            given in such PROGRESSIVE order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
            carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
            otherwise, are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
            has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,
            and it is only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will be en
            abled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good musicians.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ; the rudments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each lesson
            is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest reccommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of Bertini’s Method
            over all others yet published in this country, most of them having used the
            foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
            names in the principal cities.
         </p>
         <p>Boston.
            Messrs, G. J. Webb.
            
         </p>
         <p>J. G Maedar,
            H. T, Hach.
            E. L. White.
            David Paine,
            A. Kurek.
         </p>
         <p>T, B. Moses.
            
         </p>
         <p>New York.
            Messrs. H. C. Timm.
            W. Alpers,
         </p>
         <p>U. C. Hill.
            F. H. Brown.
            Philadelphia.
            B. C. Cross.
            Joseph Duggan.
            Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            
         </p>
         <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
            American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston.
         </p>
         <p>M. DUMSDAY’S IMPROVED ACCORDEON.
            ADDITIONAL MODULATIONS.
            THE ACCOMPANIMENT OF ALL ACCORDE-
            
         </p>
         <p>ons heretofore has been confined to one key, in music. By applying the
            above improvement, (on the bottom of the instrument,) we are enabled to
            play accompaniments in various major and minor keys. The above improvement added to any Accordeon, having the large and small keys, on
            reasonable terms. Mr. D., professor of music, continues to teach ladies and
            gentlemen of New York, at their residences, the following instruments, in a
            scientific and modern style, in a very short tune, by his new system of teaching : Guitar and Singing, Accordeon, Violin, Trombone and Cornopean,
            Terms moderate. Satisfactory city and other references given, on application at No. 56 Chrystie st., above Walker.
         </p>
         <p>DISBROW'S RIDING SCHOOL,
            NO. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette
            Places. New York.	
            Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Even-
            ing, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.
            TERMS:
            Lecture Lessons.
            16 Lessons..................$15	00
            10 “ ........................10 00
            4	“	 5	00
            Single Lessons...................2	00
            Road “		 2 50
            Exercise Riding.
            1 Month.......................$12	00
            20 Rides.......................l0 	00
            10 ** ........................6 00
            Single Rides.....................0	75
            N. B.—Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let.
            Evening Class.
            12 Lessons. . , . ...........$9 00
            Single “ ......................l 00
            20 Rides.....................$10 00
            Single Ride.............• ... 0 75
            RULES :
            1.	All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.
            2.	One hour allowed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.
            3.	One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.
            4.	Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 8 P. M.
            5. Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.
            6. No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladies.
            A card of address is requested previous to commencing.
            N. B. Gentlemen keeping their horses at this establishment, will have the
            privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
            The first Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for the
            best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
            NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
            
         </p>
         <p> tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
            in 10 lessons ol one hour each. Terms Reduced to TWO DOLLARS
            AND A HALF.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
            course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
            Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
         </p>
         <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen
            and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
            Price Five Dollars.
            
         </p>
         <p>From the Courier and Enquirer. July 27, 1844.
            Goldsmith’s Gems or Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
            much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
            Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
            volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
            of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
         </p>
         <p>From the New York Express.
            
         </p>
         <p>Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship.—We have seen the original, as
            executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
            wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
            to be “ more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
         </p>
         <p>PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY
            AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
            
         </p>
         <p>Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
            the Medal, four first Premiums, and two” Highest Houors," at the
            Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
            the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced lo that of ordinary ones
            at other places, so that no one need now ait for an inferior likeness on
            the score of economy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American In
            struments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polish
            ing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders receive
            promptly attended to.
         </p>
         <p>John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      
   </div>
</div>