<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            
            <br></br>VOL. I. NO. 10. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, MARCH 8, 1845.
            
            <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.
            
            <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
            
            <br></br>C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.
            
            <br></br>Published at
            
            <br></br>153 BROADWAY, by
            
            <br></br>JOHN BlSCO.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="cit">
         
         <span class="quote">Truth, whether in or out of fashion, it the measure of knowledge and the butiness of the understanding ; whatsoever to beside that, however authorised by content or recommended by variety, it nothing but ignorance, or something
            worse. 
         </span>
         
         
         <div class="bibl">
            <span class="person">Locke</span>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p1">
            
            <div class="head">Woman in the Nineteenth Century.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">(Second Notice.)</div>
            
            <p>The great defect of Miss Fuller’s book is a want of distinctness. We can easily discover that her chief concern is
               to help remove the evils which afflict society ; but we cannot discover any hints of the means by which they may be
               removed. She is sufficiently learned, sufficiently vigorous,
               and sufficiently earnest, but not sufficiently plain and direct.
               We have too much of the Scandinavian mythology and the
               Greek tragedy, and too little of what the book professes to
               deal with—woman in the nineteenth century. The most direct writing is on a topic that no virtuous woman can treat
               justly, because she must of necessity be imperfectly informed; it is exceedingly painful to read a portion of her work,
               which we feel must have been painfully produced; and
               though we cannot but respect her for her courage in printing
               it, we regret that she should have felt herself bound to do so,
               since no good can possibly result from it. There are a thousand existing evils in society which a woman may freely censure, and a thousand topics of pervading interest which she
               may freely discuss, with profit to her sex, without verging
               towards those that the innocent had better not know the existence of. We wish that Miss Fuller had loosened the fibula
               of her arrows, and let them fly at the practices which are, indeed, the direct causes of the lewdness which she deplores,
               instead of treating of the lewdness itself, which she can only
               know by hearsay, and of course but imperfectly comprehend.
            </p>
            
            <p>The only way in which any good can be rendered to society, is by making woman more womanly and man more
               manly. To make sailors of women and milliners of men, is
               to have imperfect sailors and imperfect milliners. The advocates of woman’s rights who are for putting men and women on a level, point to France as a proof that women are
               capable of performing all the duties of men; but they would
               hardly be willing to accept of the morals or the politics of
               France, which they must do if they adopt her practices.
               The difference between the sexes in this country is all in
               favor of the women : the law of courtesy grants them every
               thing, and the law of the land gives them more than they
               could ask. The privilege of voting is one which they could
               not exercise if it were granted, and it is the only privilege
               that is withheld from them. No change can bring them any
               good, or at least no greater privileges than what they enjoy
               at present. Men labor for little else than to make women
               happy ; the cream of every enjoyment is skimmed for their
               express use, while the sour milk is drank by their lords: the
               instincts of the mass can be trusted more safely than the speculations of any individual. Men and women fall naturally
               into their proper spheres when let alone, and there can be no
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>need of any violent revolutions to displace them from their
               true positions. The restraints which Miss Fuller complains
               of as hindering women from becoming blacksmiths, sailors,
               and soldiers, are the restraints which Nature has imposed,
               and which can never be overcome. As we have already said,
               the mind of woman is not endowed with the elements of
               command, because she cannot originate. There are no other
               restraints to her doing so, but her own weaknesses. Miss
               Fuller glories in the “triumphs of female authorship”; but
               we know of no woman who can claim the merit of originality. And we have no peculiar “signs of the times” in any
               work which has appeared from a woman’s hand. In the
               Arts, where the creative faculties are tested, women have
               done nothing. Drawing and painting are considered a necessary part of every woman’s education, but the world has
               produced no famous woman-artist of any kind; yet their
               way of life peculiarly fits them for artistic employment.
               There are no restraints upon woman in any civilised country,
               to prevent her becoming an architect; yet we have never
               heard of but one architectural work, and that a very recent
               one, produced by a female. All women are instructed in
               the rudiments of music, yet we have no female composers.
            </p>
            
            <p>The employments of women are distinct from those of
               men, and the more perfect that society becomes, the more
               distinct they will grow. Therefore, instead of its being a
               cause of complaint that women are compelled to be women,
               it should be hailed as a sign, indeed, of the incoming of better times.
            </p>
            
            <p>We believe that Miss Fuller admits the truth of our argument in the following passage, although we are not sure that
               we comprehend her meaning:
            </p>
            
            <p>" The especial genius of woman I believe to be electrical in movement, imitative in function, spiritual in tendency. She excels not so
               easily in classification, or recreation, as in an instinctive seizure of
               causes, and a simple breathing out of what she receives that has the
               singleness of life, rather than the selecting and energizing of art.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Among all the “signs of the times” which Miss Fuller
               takes note of, there is none so encouraging as the following:
            </p>
            
            <p>" A woman of excellent sense said it might seem childish, but to her
               one of the most favorable signs of the times was, that ladies had been
               persuaded to give up corsets.”
            </p>
            
            <p>It is a most favorable sign indeed, and the next generation
               of men will be all the better for it. But we should be glad
               to see the candy saloons and worsted warehouses of Broadway disappear along with the corset stores.
            </p>
            
            <p>Miss Fuller has a great passion for heroines. Among all
               the females that she has selected for emulation, not one has
               been taken from the pure feminine creations of Walter Scott.
               To combat a postulate of Spinoza, she has extracted a long
               poem from W. E. Channing, a character of a woman from
               the tragedy of Festus, and a monstrosity—Mother Perpetua,
               from Eugene Sue. We see no need of a resort to fiction,
               while there are Catherines, Elizabeths, and Isabellas in abundance.
            </p>
            
            <p>There are many admirable little episodes in the book, which ever and anon appear,
               like
               springs of tweet water
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page146"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>bubbling out of a sterile soil, and charm us by their sparkles and music.
               There are too few of passages like the following:
            </p>
            
            <p>"Only in a clean body can the soul do its message fitly. The praises of cold water seem to me an excellent sign of the age. They denote a tendency to the true in life. We are now to have, as a remedy
               for ills, not orvietan, or opium, or any quack medicine, but plenty of
               air and water, with due attention to warmth and freedom in dress, and
               simplicity in diet. Every day we observe signs that the natural feelings on these subjects are about to be reinstated, and the body to
               claim care as the abode and organ of the soul.”
            </p>
            
            <p>These passages are of greater import than Miss Fulller
               seems to be aware of, or she would dwell longer upon them,
               and draw more profitable reflections from them than she has
               done. The well-being of the body is the great end of all
               moral leaching, and if this truth were most distinctly comprehended, the moral preacher would not so often preach to
               so little purpose. It is the too frequent way with moral philosophers and religious teachers, to exalt the dignity of the
               soul, by treating its habitation, the body, with contemptuous
               neglect, and it is a very rare thing to find a healthy soul
               shrined in a gaudy tabernacle. God has affixed the several
               penalties against any abuse of the body, not only in the natural laws, but in his revealed laws; yet in the days of ignorance and superstition, as well as in these days of knowledge
               and refinement, men have thought they were doing God a
               service by mortifying and lacerating the form which He
               had created in his own image. The most pale, unhealthy,
               decerpit, and consumptive men in the country, are the denizens of theological seminaries, who waste their vital energies in the vain illusion of studying God’s will. They should
               be, if they rightly interpreted His will, the rosiest, healthiest,
               happiest men in the world. Man’s first offence, which brought
               death into the world, was a wrong done to his own body ; he
               ate forbidden fruit. Whether the Mosaic cause of the fall
               be typical or literal, the lesson which it teaches is the same.
               It was a violence done to his own body that brought suffering
               upon man. and caused his expulsion from Eden. If we are
               to be restored to Paradise, the body must be restored to its
               pristine dignity and beauty, by abstaining from the forbidden
               fruit which destroys it. Shall we neglect the study of God’s
               law, then, for the laws of health? By no means: the law
               of God is the law of health. Paul preached nothing to
               Agrippa, but righteousness, temperance, and judgment.
            </p>
            
            <p>There are some things in Miss Fuller’s book, which startle
               us by their strange sound, and set us a-thinking what they
               can possibly mean ; for instance: “if there were more Marys
               there would be more virgin mothers;" and some others,
               equally enigmatical. Miss Fuller is of opinion that the ideal
               of woman is expressed to a greater height and depth in German literature, than elsewhere, and gives the themes of three
               ballads, as instances; one of which is as follows, a legend
               of Drachenfels.
            </p>
            
            <p>"A youth is sitting with the maid he loves on the shore of an isle,
               her fairy kingdom, then perfumed by the blossoming grape vines,
               which draped its bowers. They are happy; all blossoms with them,
               and life promises its richest wine. A boat approaches on the tide; it
               pauses at their feet. It brings, perhaps, some joyous message, fresh
               dew for their flowers, fresh light on the wave. No! it is the usual
               check on such great happiness. The father of the Count departs for
               the crusade ; will his sou join with him, or remain to rule their domain, and wed her whom he loves t Neither of the affianced pair
               hesitate a moment. ‘ I must go with my father.’ ‘ Thou must go
               with thy father.’ It was one thought, one word. ' I will be here
               again,’ he said, ‘ when these blossoms have turned to purple grapes.
               ' I hope so,’ she said, while the prophetic sense said ' no.’ And there
               she waited, and the grapes ripened and were gathered into the vintage,
               and he came not. Year after year passed thus, and no tidings; yet
               still she waited. He, meanwhile, was in a Moslem prison. Long he
               languished there without hope, till at last, his patron saint appeared
               in a vision and announced his release, but only on condition of his
               joining the monastic order for the service of the saint. And so his
               release was effected, and a safe voyage home given. And once more
               he sets sail upon the Rhine. The maiden still watching beneath the
               vines, sees at last the object of all this partial love approach. Approach, but not to touch the strand, to which she with outstretched
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>arms had rushed. He dares not trust himself to land; but in low heart
               and broken tones, tells her of Heavens will; and that he, in obedience to his vision, is now on the way to a convent, on the river bank,
               there to pass the rest of his earthly life, in the service of the shrine.
               And then he turns his boat, and floats away from her and hope of any
               happiness in this world, but urged, as he believes, by the breath of
               Heaven. The maiden stands appalled, but she dares not murmur, and
               cannot hesitate long. She also bids them prepare her boat. She follows her lost love to the convent gate, requests an interview with the
               abbot, and devotes her Elysian isle, where vines had ripened their
               ruby fruit in vain for her, to the service of the monastery, where her
               love was to serve. Then, passing over to the nunnery opposite, she
               takes the veil, and meets her betrothed at the altar ; and for a lifelong union, if not the one they had hoped in earlier years.”
            </p>
            
            <p>We have marked several passages for quotation, which
               our limits which will not allow us to make. Miss Fuller
               writes vigorously, but womanly; she has gathered together
               the materials for a very profitable book ; but they are so
               loosely arranged, and so pervaded with threads of error, that
               as a whole we doubt whether the work will be productive of
               much either of good or of evil. It will, however, have one
               good effect. It will cause her to be more generally known
               than she has been; for although the reading public have
               been familiar with her name since the first appearance of
               the “Dial,” they have had but an imperfect conception of
               the exact quality of her mind.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p2">
            
            <p>Glossary or Ecclesiastical Ornament and Costume. Compiled and illustra-
               ted from ancient authorities and examples, by A. Welby Puyin, architect.
               London, 1844. Imported by Wiley and Putnam, New York.
            </p>
            
            <p>The art of book-making has been carried to the highest
               reach of elegance in the superbly illuminated volume before
               us. Gold and color can do no more, with the aid of manipulative skill alone, in making a beautiful book. Invention,
               of course, is not looked for in a work like this, which, brilliant as it appears, derives its main value from its sober
               truthfulness. It reflects, as in a mirror, the best specimens
               of mediӕval ecclesiastical ornament to be found in Europe,
               explained and illustrated by the pen of the accomplished author, and by extracts from the works of Deorandus, Georgius,
               Bona, Catalani, Gerbert, Martene, Molaenus, Thiers, Mabillon, Ducange, etc.
            </p>
            
            <p>The plates are 73 in number, and are altogether the most
               brilliant examples of this style of illustration that we have
               ever seen ; the letter-press forms over 200 pages, which are
               copiously illustrated with wood cuts, worthy to accompany
               the other ornaments of this superb volume.
            </p>
            
            <p>Welby Pugin has done more to revive a love of mediӕval
               art, than any other man of his time ; he is a devout Catholic,
               as every genuine enthusiast in ecclesiastical architecture
               must be, and is sustained in his labors to revive the dead
               forms of a departed age, by an ardent religious faith. He is
               the true apostle of Gothic architecture, and his churches are
               the only specimens of religious structures that seem to be
               invested with that feeling of sincerity, which so charms us in
               the old cathedrals, that have been erected in Europe or
               America during the last two centuries. But even his churches do not preserve the genuine character of the ecclesiastical
               buildings of the fourteenth and fifteenth centuries, when the,
               so called, Gothic style reached its highest point of expression. Rudeness of execution and a poverty of invention, or
               a meagreness of details in imitation, distinguished the Gothic style as much as profuseness of ornament, and grandeur
               of feeling; we cannot in a refined age imitate the barbarisms
               of a semi-civilized one, and our attempts at Gothic architecture must therefore be tame and lifeless when compared with
               the examples of this religious enthusiasm which still remains. When religious zeal burnt heretics at the stake, and
               girded a sword upon the thigh of a bishop, it was unavoidable that the same violent feeling should lavish the wealth
               of an empire upon the decorations of a house of worship, and
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page147"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>that more thought should be given to the nimbus of a saint
               than to the glory of God. But in these days of colporteurs
               and Bible Societies, when Christians go to Jerusalem to convert the Musselman and not to slay him, it is a feeling closely verging upon the ludicrous, which animates men, in striving to revive the forms and symbols of worship which belonged to an age whose enlightenment was thick darkness,
               when compared with ours. But if these things appear absurd, even among Papists and Episcopalians, who do at least
               preserve the creeds, though they have long since abandoned
               the practices of their fathers, how doubly absurd must they
               appear in the dissenters who repudiate all creeds, practices,
               forms, ceremonies and vestments, which they do not invent
               themselves. Man, however, is an imitative animal, at best,
               but in the present age he is pre-eminently so, and he can do
               nothing, not even build a church, without a precedent. Some
               potent voice seems to have arrested us in our march by a command of “about, face !” and we all stand looking backwards,
               as though we were nothing of ourselves or had nothing to
               look forward to. The last twenty years has been elaborately
               wasted in attempts to revive dead things. Even in the
               drawing rooms of our humblest citizens, we are startled by the
               appearance of fauleuils, copied after examples brought from
               the boudoirs of Louis Quartorze’s Mistresses, and there is
               scarce a house in town which has not an article of furniture
               imitated from some portion ofa Gothic cathedral; the tunacle
               of a priest of the fourteenth century is faithfully copied in a
               dandy’s robe de chambre ; and a fire poker is fashioned after
               the pastoral staff of a bishop. Were it not for the terrible
               necessities which compel mankind in ail ages to be true to
               themselves in some things, we should have nothing to show
               as evidence that we had not dwindled into apes who had no
               power to originate or invent; but we have railroads, canals
               and stores; and comfortable houses for day laborers, monstrous hotels and snug little chapels of ease, where pious
               ladies may exhibit their elegant dresses, and their wearied
               husbands enjoy a quiet nap of a warm Sunday afternoon,
               as proof that we do not depend upon the past for everything.
            </p>
            
            <p>The rage for Gothic architecture and ornament we think
               must have reached its calenture in this country at this time,
               and we shall look for its cooling off when the cross shall be
               affixed to the spire of Trinity Church in Broadway. There
               are now in the course of erection in Brooklyn four churches
               in the Gothic style, so close together, that the preacher’s
               voice may be heard from each at the same time, dedicated to
               four different religions, and neither of them claiming to have
               any affinity with the religion whose outside expression they
               have endeavored to copy. One of them is a Baptist, another
               a Unitarian, a third an Episcopalian, and the fourth, shade
               of Cotton Mather defend us! the church of the Pilgrims.
               Without any reference to the religious principle involved in
               Mr. Pugin’s introduction on “Symbolism in Art,” we make
               a short extract for the sake of the sound philosophy in respect to ornamental art which it contains. We would advise
               the genius who furnishes the ornaments of a certain “illuminated" work, to procure the book and study it, not only the
               letter press, but the magnificent scroll work and diapering of
               the plates.
            </p>
            
            <p>" That Art has its fixed principles, any departure from which leads
               to inconsistency and unmeaning effect, is a truth never to be lost sight
               of. And if all art is subject to fixed laws, which define her province
               and inform her purpose ; least of all is Christian Art to be regarded
               as exempt from rule, not merely of ecclesiastical precedent, but of
               philosophical and scientific principle.—Ornament, in the true and proper meaning of the word, signifies the embellishment of that which is
               in itself useful, in an appropriate manner. Vet bjr a perversion of the
               term, it is frequently applied to mere enrichment, which deserves no
               other name than that of unmeaning detail, dictated by no rule but
               that of individual fancy and caprice. Every ornament to deserve the
               name must form an appropriate meaning, and be introduced with an
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>intelligent purpose, and on reasonable grounds. The symbolical associations of each ornament must be understood and considered : otherwise things beautiful in themselves will be rendered absurd in their
               application. It is to the neglect of these principles that we may trace
               half the blunders and monstrosities that disgrace modern Art. Ornaments have been regarded as mere matters of whim and caprice. Accordingly, the most opposite styles have been mixed: and emblems
               of characters the most distinct, Christian and Pagan, ecclesiastic and
               civil, have been jumbled together in unutterable confusion. Only for
               ornament is the usual reply to an enquiry respecting the intention of
               views, detail and combinations, frequent in modem designs, although
               it is not possible for any forms or enrichments to be ornamental which
               are not appropriate and significant, if their utility extends no further.
               It has been said poetically, that, ' where use is exiled, beauty scorns
               to dwell,' and the sentiment is founded in truth and reason."
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p3">
            
            <p>IMITATION—PLAGIARISM—MR. POE’S REPLY TO THE LETTER OF
               OUTIS—A LARGE ACCOUNT OF A SMALL MATTER—A VOLUMINOUS HISTORY OF THE LITTLE LONGFELLOW WAR.
            </p>
            
            <p>In replying to the letter signed “Outis,” which appears in
               last Saturday’s “Weekly Mirror”, I find it advisable, for reasons which will be obvious as I proceed, to dismiss for the
               present the editorial “we.”
            </p>
            
            <p>For the “Evening Mirror” of January 14, before my editorial connection with the “Broadway Journal,” I furnished a
               brief criticism on Professor Longfellow’s “Waif.”
            </p>
            
            <p>In the course of my observations, I collated a poem called
               “The Death-Bed,” and written by Hood, with one by Mr. Aidrich, entitled “A Death-Bed.” The criticism ended thus :
            </p>
            
            <p>We conclude our notes on the “Waif,” with the observation that,
               although full of beauties, it is infected with a moral taint—or is this a
               mere freak of our own fancy? We shall be pleased if it be so;-but
               there does appear, in this little volume, a very careful avoidance of all
               American poets who may be supposed especially to interfere with the
               claims of Mr. Longfellow. These men Mr. Longfellow can continuously imitate (is that the word?) and yet never even incidentally
               commend.
            </p>
            
            <p>Much discussion ensued. A friend of Mr. Longfellow’s penned a defence which had at least the merit of being thoroughly impartial; for it defended Mr. L., not only from the onetenth of very moderate disapproval in which I had indulged,
               but from the nine-tenths of my enthusiastic admiration into
               the bargain. The fact is, if I was not convinced that in
               ninety-nine hundredths of all that I had written about Mr.
               Longfellow I was decidedly in the wrong, at least it was no
               fault of Mr. Longfellow’s very luminous friend.
            </p>
            
            <p>This well-intended defence was published in the “Mirror”
               with a few words of preface by Mr. Willis, and of postscript
               by myself.
            </p>
            
            <p>Still dissatisfied, Mr. L., through a second friend, addressed to Mr. Willis an expostulatory letter, of which the Mirror
               primed only the following portion :—
            </p>
            
            <p>It has been asked, perhaps, why Lowell was neglected in this collection? Might it not as well be asked why Bryant, Dana and Halleck were neglected? The answer is obvious to any one who candidly considers the character of the collection. It professed to be, according to the Poem, from the humbler poets; and it was intended to
               embrace pieces that were anonymous, or which were easily accessible
               to the general reader—the waifs and estrays of literature. To put anything of Lowell’s, for example, into a collection of waifs would be a
               particular liberty with pieces which arc all collected and christened.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Not yet content, or misunderstanding the tenor of some of
               the wittily-put comments which accompanied the quotation,
               the aggrieved poet, through one of the two friends as before,
               or perhaps through a third, finally prevailed on the good
               nature of Mr. Willis to publish an explicit declaration of his
               disagreement with “all the disparagement of Longfellow”
               which had appeared in the criticism in question.
            </p>
            
            <p>Now when we consider that many of the points of censure
               made by me in this critique were absolutely as plain as the
               nose upon Mr. Longfellow’s face—that it was impossible to
               gainsay them—that we defied him and his coadjutors to say
               a syllable in reply to them—and that they held their tongues
               and not a syllable said—when we consider all this, I say,
               then the satire of the “all" in Mr. Willis’ manifesto becomes
               apparent at once. Mr. Longfellow did not see it; and I
               presume his friends did not see it. I did. In my mind’s eye
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page148"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>it expanded itself thus ;—“My dear Sir, or Sirs, what will
               you have? You are an insatiable set of cormorants, it is
               true; but if you will only let me know what you desire, I
               will satisfy you, if I die for it. Be quick !—merely say what
               it is you wish me to admit, and (for the sake of getting rid of
               you) I will admit it upon the spot. Come! I will grant at
               once that Mr. Longfellow is Jupiter Tonans, and that his
               three friends are the Graces, or the Furies, whichever you
               please. As for a fault to be found with either of you, that is
               impossible, and I say so. I disagree with all—with every
               syllable of the disparagement that ever has been whispered
               against you up to this date, and (not to stand upon trifles)
               with all that ever shall be whispered against you henceforward, forever and forever. May I hope at length that these
               assurances will be sufficient?”
            </p>
            
            <p>But if Mr. Willis really hoped anything of the kind he was mistaken.</p>
            
            <p>In the meantime Mr. Briggs in this paper—in the “Broadway Journal”—did me the honor of taking me to task for what
               he supposed to be my insinuations against Mr. Aldrich.
            </p>
            
            <p>My reply (in the “Mirror”) prefaced by a few words from
               Mr. Willis, ran as follows:
            </p>
            
            <p>Much interest has been given in our literary circles of late to the
               topic of plagiarism.
            </p>
            
            <p>About a month ago a very eminent critic connected with this paper,
               took occasion to point out a parallelism between certain lines of Thomas Hood, and certain others which appeared in the collection of American poetry edited by Mr. Griswold. Transcribing the passages, he
               ventured the assertion that “somebody is a thief.” (He goes on below to speak for himself.)
            </p>
            
            <p>The matter had been nearly forgotten, if not altogether so, when a
               “good-natured friend” of the American author (whose name had
               by us never been mentioned) considered it advisable to re-collate the
               passages, with the view of convincing the public (and himself) that
               no plagiarism is chargeable to the party of whom he thinks it chivalrous
               to be the “good-natured friend.”
            </p>
            
            <p>For our own part should tee ever be guilty of an indiscretion of this
               kind, we deprecate all aid from our “good natured friends ’’—but in
               the mean time it is rendered necessary that once again we give publicity to the collation of poems in question. Mr. Hood’s lines run thus
               :
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>We watched her breathing through the night,
               
               <br></br>Her breathing soft and low, As in her breast the wave of life
               
               <br></br>Kept heaving to and fro.
               
               <br></br>So silently we seemed to speak,
               
               <br></br>So slowly moved about,
               
               <br></br>As we had lent her half our powers
               
               <br></br>To eke her being out.
               
               <br></br>Our very hope belied our fears;
               
               <br></br>Our fears our hope belied;
               
               <br></br>We thought her dying when she slept.
               
               <br></br>And sleeping when she died.
               
               <br></br>But when the morn came dim and sad.
               
               <br></br>And chill with early showers,
               
               <br></br>Her quiet eyelids dosed ;—she had
               
               <br></br>Another morn than ours.
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Mr. Aldrich’s thus:--</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Her sufferings ended with the day,
               
               <br></br>Yet lived she at its close.
               
               <br></br>And breathed the long, long night away
               
               <br></br>In statue-like repose ;
               
               <br></br>But when the sun in all its state
               
               <br></br>Illumed the eastern skies,
               
               <br></br>She passed through Glory’s morning gate.
               
               <br></br>And walked in paradise.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>And here, to be sure, we might well leave a decision in the ease to
               the verdict of common sense. But since the “Broadway Journal” insists upon the “no resemblance,” we are constrained to point out especially where our supposed similarity lies. In the first place, then,
               the subject in both pieces is death. In the second it is the death of a
               woman. In the third, it is the death of a woman tranquilly dying.
               In the fourth, it is the death of a woman who lies tranquilly throughout the night. In the fifth it is the death of a woman whose " breathing soft and low is watched through the night” in the one instance and
               who “breathed the long long night away in statue-like repose” in the
               other. In the sixth place, in both poems this woman dies just at daybreak. In the seventh place, dying just at daybreak, this woman in
               both cases, steps directly into Paradise. In the eighth place all these
               identities of circumstance are related in identical rhythms. In the
               ninth place these identical rhythms are arranged in identical metres ;
               and, in the tenth place, these identical rhythms and metres are constructed into identical stanzas.
            </p>
            
            <p>At this point the matter rested for a fortnight, when a fourth
               friend of Mr. Longfellow took up the cudgels for him and
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>Mr. Aldrich conjointly, in another communication to the
               “Mirror.” I copy it in full.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">PLAGIARISM.</div>
            
            <p>Dear Willis—Fair play is a jewel, and I hope you will let us have
               it. I have been much amused, by some of the efforts of your critical
               friend, to covict Longfellow of imitation, and Aldrich and others, of
               plagiarism. What is plagiarism? And what constitutes a good
               ground for the charge? Did no two men ever think aiike without
               stealing one from the other? or, thinking alike, did no two men ever
               use the same, or similar words, to convey the thoughts, and that,
               without any communication with each other? To deny it would be
               absurd. It is a thing of every day occurrence.
            </p>
            
            <p>Some years ago, a letter was written from some part of New England, describing one of those scenes, not very common during what is
               called “the January thaw,” when the snow, mingled with rain, and
               freezing as it falls, forms a perfect covering of ice upon every object.
               The storm clears away suddenly, and the moon comes up. The letter
               proceeds—“every tree and shrub, as far as the eye can reach, of pure
               transparent glass—a perfect garden of moving, waving, breathing chrystals. * * * Every tree is a diamond chandelier, with a whole constellation of stars clustering to every socket,” &amp;c. This letter was
               laid
               away where such things usually are, in a private drawer, and did not
               see the light for many years. But the very next autumn brought out,
               among the splendid annuals got up in the country, a beautiful poem
               from Whittier, describing the same, or rather a similar scene, in
               which is this line
               “The trees, like chrystal chandeliers,”
               was put in italics by every reviewer in the land, for the exceeding
               beauty of the imagery. Now the letter was written, probably about
               the same time with the poem, though the poem was not published till
               nearly a year after.—The writers were not, and never have been, acquainted with each other, and neither could possibly have seen the
               work of the other before writing. Now, was there any plagiarism
               here? Yet there are plenty of “identities.” The author of the letter, when urged some years after, to have it published, consented very
               reluctantly, through fear that he should be charged with theft; and,
               very probably, the charge has been made, though I have never
               seen it.
            </p>
            
            <p>May not this often occur? What is more natural? Images are not
               created, but suggested. And why not the same images, when the circumstances are precisely the same, to different minds? Perhaps your
               critic will reply, that the caso is different alter one of the compositions
               is published. How so? Does he, or you, or anybody read everything
               that is published? I am a great admirer, and a general reader of
               poetry. But, by what accident 1 do not know, I had never seen the
               beautiful lines of Hood, till your critical friend brought them to my
               notice in the Mirror. It is certainly possible that Aldrich had not
               seen them several years ago—and more than probable that Hood had
               not seen Aldrich’s. Yet your friend affects great sympathy for both,
               in view of their better compunctions of conscience, for their literary
               piracies.
            </p>
            
            <p>But, after all, wherein does the real resemblance between these two
               compositions consist? Mr.---I had almost named him, finds nearly 
            </p>
            
            <p>a dozen points of resemblance. But when he includes rhythm, metre
               and stanza among the dozen, he only shows u bitter resolution to make
               out a case, and not a disposition to do impartial justice. Surely the
               critic himself who is one of our finest poets, does not mean to deny
               that these mere externals are the common property of all bards. He
               does not feel it necessary to strike out a new stanza, or to invent new
               feet and measures, whenever he would clothe his “breathing thoughts
               in words that bum.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Again, it is not improbable that, within the period of time since
               these two writers, Hood and Aldrich, came on the stage, ten thousand
               females have died, and died tranquilly, and died just at day-break, and
               that after passing a tranquil night, and, so dying, were supposed by
               their friends to have passed at once to a better world, a morning in
               heaven. The poets are both describing an actual, and not an imaginary occurrence. And here—including those before-mentioned, which
               are common property—are nine of the critic’s identities, which go to
               make up the evidence of plagiarism. The last six, it requires no
               stretch of the imagination to suppose, they might each have seen and
               noticed separately. The most of them, one other poet at least, has
               noticed, many years ago, in a beautiful poem on these words of the
               angel to the wrestling Jacob—“Let me go, for the day breaketh.”
               Wonder if Hood ever saw that?
            </p>
            
            <p>The few remaining “identities” are, to my mind, sufficiently disposed of by what I have already said. I confess I was not able, until
               the appearance of the critic’s second paper, in which he brought them
               out specially, “marked, numbered, and labelled,” to perceive the
               resemblance on which the grave charge of literary piracy, and moral
               dishonesty of the meanest kind was baaed. In view of all the glaring
               improbabilities of such a case, a critic should be very slow to make
               such a charge. I say glaring improbabilities, for it seems to me that
               no circumstantial evidence could be sufficient to secure a verdict of
               theft in such a case. Look at it. A man, who aspires to fame, who
               seeks the esteem and praise of the world, and lives upon his reputation, as his vital element, attempts to win his object—how? By
               stealing, In open day, the finest passages, the most beautiful thoughts
               (no others are worth stealing) and the rarest images of another, and
               claiming them as his own ; and that too, when he knows that every
               competitor for fame, and every critical tribunal in the world, as well
               as the real owner, will be ready to identify the borrowed plumes In a
               moment, and cry him down as a thief. A madam, an idiot, If he were
               capable of such an achievement, might do it, but no other. A rogue
               may steal what he can conceal in his pocket, or his chest—but one
               must be utterly non compos, to steal a splendid shawl, or a magnificent plume, which had been admired by thousands for its singular
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page149"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>beauty, for the purpose of sporting it in Broadway. In nine hundred
               and ninety-nine cases of a thousand, such charges are absurd, and indicate rather the carping littleness of the critic, than the delinquency
               of his victim.
            </p>
            
            <p>Pray did you ever think the worse of Dana because your friend,
               John Neal, charged him with pirating upon Paul Allen, and Bryant
               too, in his poem of “the dying raven?” or of yourself, because the
               same friend thought he had detected you in the very act of stealing
               from Pinckney, and Miss Francis, now Mrs. Child? Surely not.
               Every body knows that John Neal wishes to be supposed to have read
               every thing that ever was written, and never have forgotten any thing.
               He delights, therefore, in showing up such resemblances.
            </p>
            
            <p>And now—for the matter of Longfellow’s imitations—In what do
               they consist? The critic is not very specific in this charge. Of what
               kind are they? Are they imitations of thought? Why not call them
               plagiarisms then, and show them up? Or are they only verbal imitations of style? Perhaps this is one of them, in his poem on the “Sea
               Weed.”
               
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>-----“drifting, drifting, drifting
                  
                  <br></br>On the shirting
                  
                  <br></br>Currents of the restless main.”
                  
               </div>
               resembling, in form and collocation only, a line in a beautiful and very
               powerful poem of Mr. Edgar A. Poe. (Write it rather Edgar, a
               Poet, and then it is right to a T.) I have not the poem before me,
               and have forgotten its title. But he is describing a magnificent intellect in ruins, if I remember rightly—and, speaking of the eloquence
               of its better days, represents it as 
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>-----"flowing, flowing, flowing
                  
                  <br></br>Like a river.”
                  
               </div>
               
            </p>
            
            <p>Is this what the critic means? Is it such imitations as this
               that he alludes to? If not, I am at fault, either in my reading of
               Longfellow, or in my general familiarity with the American Poets.
               If this be the kind of imitation referred to, permit me to say, the
               charge is too paltry for any man, who valued his reputation either as
               a gentleman or a scholar, to make. Who, for example, would wish to
               be guilty of the littleness of detracting from the uncommon merit of
               that remarkable poem of this same Mr. Poe’s, recently published in
               the Mirror, from the American Review, entitled “The Raven,” by
               charging him with the paltriness of imitation? And yet, some snarling critic, who might envy the reputation he had not the genius to secure for himself, might refer to the frequent, very forcible, but rather
               quaint repetition, in the last two lines of many of the stanzas, as a palpable imitation of the manner of Coleridge, in several stanzas of the
               Ancient Mariner. Let me put them together.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Poe says— 
               
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>" Let me see, then, what thereat is, and this mystery explore,
                  
                  <br></br>Let my heart be still a moment, and this mystery explore.”
                  
               </div>
               And again— 
               
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>“It shall clasp a sainted maiden, whom the angels name Lenore—
                  
                  <br></br>Clasp a rare and radiant maiden, whom the angels name Lenore.”
                  
               </div>
               Mr. Coleridge says, (running two lines into one): 
               
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>“For all averred I had killed the bird, that made the breeze to blow.
                  
                  <br></br>' Ah, wretch !’ said they, ‘the bird to slay, that made the breeze to blow.” '
                  
               </div>
               And again— 
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>"They all averred I had killed the bird, that brought the fog and mist.
                  
                  <br></br>’ ’Twas right,’ said they, ‘ such birds to slay, that bring the fog and mist.
                  
               </div>
               
            </p>
            
            <p>I have before me an anonymous poem, which I first saw some five
               years ago, entitled “The Bird of the Dream.” I should like to transcribe the whole—but it is too long. The author was awaked from
               sleep by the song of a beautiful bird, sitting on the sill of his window
               —the sweet notes had mingled with his dreams, and brought to his
               remembrance, the sweeter voice of his lost “Clare.” He says—
            </p>
            
            <p>
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>" And thou wert in my dream—a spirit thou didst seem—
                  
                  <br></br>The spirit of a friend long since departed;
                  
                  <br></br>Oh! she was fair and bright, but she left me one dark night—
                  
                  <br></br>She left me all alone, and broken-hearted.
                  
               </div>
               * * * * * * * * 
               
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>My dream went on, and thou went a warbling too, 
                  
                  <br></br>Mingling the harmonies of earth and heaven ; 
                  
                  <br></br>Till away—away—away—beyond the realms of day— 
                  
                  <br></br>My angel Clare to my embrace was given.
                  
               </div>
               * * * * * * * *
               
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>Sweet bird from realms of light, oh! come again to-night,
                  
                  <br></br>Come to my window—perch upon my chair— 
                  
                  <br></br>Come give me back again that deep impassioned strain
                  
                  <br></br>That tells me thou hast seen and loved my Clare.
                  
               </div>
            </p>
            
            <p>Now I shall not charge Mr. Poe with Plagiarism—for, as I have
               said, such charges are perfectly absurd. Ten to one, he never saw
               this before. But let us look at the “identities” that may be made out
               between this and "The Raven.” First, in each case, the poet is a
               broken-hearted lover. Second, that lover longs for some hereafter
               communion with the departed. Third, there is a bird. Fourth, the
               bird is at the poet’s window. Fifth, the bird being at the poet’s window, makes a noise. Sixth, making a noise, attracts the attention of
               the poet: who, Seventh, was half asleep, dosing, dreaming. Eighth,
               the poet invites the bird to come in. Ninth. a confabulation ensues.
               Tenth, the bird is supposed to be a visitor from the land of spirits.
               Eleventh, allusion is made to the departed. Twelfth, intimation is
               given that the bird knew something of the departed. Thirteenth, that
               he knew her worth and loveliness. Fourteenth, the bird seems willing
               to linger with the poet. Fifteenth, there is a repetition, in the second
               and fourth lines, of a part, and that the emphatic part, of the first and
               third. Here is a round baker's-dozen (and one to spare) of identities,
               to offset the dozen found between Aldrich and Hood, and that too,
               without a word of rhythm, metre or stanza, which should never form a
               part of such a comparison. Moreover, this same poem contains an
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>example of that kind of repetition, which I have supposed the critic
               meant to charge upon Longfellow as one of his imitations--
               " Away—away—away,” &amp;c.
            </p>
            
            <p>I might pursue it further. But I will not. Such criticisms only
               make the author of them contemptible, without soiling a plume in the
               cap of his victim. I have selected this poem of Mr. Poe’s, for illustrating my remarks, because it is recent, and must be familiar to all
               the lovers of true poetry hereabouts. It is remarkable for its power,
               beauty, and originality, (out upon the automaton owl that has presumed to croak out a miserable parody—I commend him to the tender mercies of Haynes Bayley,) 
               <span class="anchor" id="a001">
                  <a href="#n001"> Link </a>
               </span> and shows more forcibly than any
               which I can think of, the absurdity and shallowness of this kind of
               criticism.
            </p>
            
            <p>One word more,—though acquainted with Mr. Longfellow, I have
               never seen Mr. Aldrich, nor do I even know in what part of the country he resides ; and I have no acquaintance with Mr. Poe. I have
               written what I have written from no personal motives, but simply because, from my earliest reading of reviews and critical notices, I have
               been disgusted with this wholesale mangling of victims without rhyme
               or reason. I scarcely remember an instance where the resemblances
               detected were not exceedingly far-fetched and shadowy, and only perceptible to a mind pre-disposed to suspicion, and accustomed to splitting hairs.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">OUTIS.</div>
            
            <p>What I admire in this letter is the gentlemanly grace of
               its manner, and the chivalry which has prompted its composition. What I do not admire is all the rest. In especial,
               I do not admire the desperation of the effort to make out a
               case. No gentleman should degrade himself, on any grounds,
               to the paltriness of ex-parte argument; and I shall not insult
               Outis at the outlset, by assuming for a moment that he (Outis)
               is weak enough, to suppose me (Poe) silly enough, to look
               upon all this abominable rigmarole as anything better than a
               very respectable specimen of special pleading.
            </p>
            
            <p>As a general rule in a case of this kind, I should wish to
               begin with the beginning, but as I have been unable, in running my eye over Outis’ remarks, to discover that they have
               any beginning at all, I shall be par.doned for touching them
               in the order which suits me best
            </p>
            
            <p>Outis need not have put himself to the trouble of informing his readers that he has “some acquaintance with Mr.
               Longfellow.”
            </p>
            
            <p>It was needless also to mention that he did not know me.
               I thank him for his many flatteries—but of their inconsistency I complain. To speak of me in one breath as a poet, and
               in the next to insinuate charges of “carping littleness,” is
               simply to put forth a flat paradox.
            </p>
            
            <p>When a plagiarism is committed and detected, the word
               “littleness" and other similar words are immediately brought
               into play. To the words themselves I have no objection
               whatever; but their application might occasionally be improved.
            </p>
            
            <p>Is it altogether impossible that a critic be instigated to the
               exposure of a plagiarism, or still better, of plagiarism generally wherever he meets it, by a strictly honorable and even
               charitable motive? Let us see. A theft of this kind is committed—for the present we will admit the possibility that a
               theft of this character can be committed. The chances of
               course are, that an established author steals from an unknown one, rather than the converse; for in proportion to the
               circulation of the original, is the risk of the plagiarism’s detection. The person about to commit the theft, hopes for impunity altogether on the ground of the reconditeness of the
               source from which he thieves. But this obvious consideration is rarely borne in mind. We read a certain passage in a
               certain book. We meet a passage nearly similar, in another
               book. The first book is not at hand, and we cannot compare
               dates. We decide by what we fancy the probabilities of the
               case. The one author is a distinguished man—our sympathies are always in favor of distinction. “It is not likely,”
               we say in our hearts "that so distinguished a personage
               as A. would be guilty of plagiarism from this B. of whom
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page150"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>nobody in the world has ever heard.” We give judgment,
               therefore, at once against B. of whom nobody in the world
               has ever heard; and it is for the very reason that nobody in
               world has ever heard of him, that, in ninety-nine cases out of
               the hundred, the judgment so precipitously given is erroneous. Now then the plagiarist has not merely committed a
               wrong in itself—a wrong whose incomparable meanness
               would deserve exposure on absolute grounds—but he, the
               guilty, the successful, the eminent, has fastened the degradation of his crime—the retribution which should have overtaken it in his own person—upon the guiltless, the toiling, the unfriended straggler up the mountainous path of Fame.
               Is not sympathy for the plagiarist, then, about as sagacious
               and about as generous as would be sympathy for the murderer whose exultant escape from the noose of the hangman
               should be the cause of an innocent man’s being hung? And
               because I, for one, should wish to throttle the guilty with the
               view of letting the innocent go, could it be considered proper on the part of any “acquaintance of Mr. Longfellow’s”
               who came to witness the execution—could it be thought, I
               say either chivalrous or decorous on the part of this “acquaintance” to get up against me a charge of “carping littleness,”
               while we stood amicably together at the foot of the gallows?
            </p>
            
            <p>In all this I have taken it for granted that such a sin as
               plagiarism exists. We are informed by Outis, however, that
               it does not. “I shall not charge Mr. Poe with plagiarism,”
               he says, “for, as I have said, such charges are perfectly absurd.” An assertion of this kind is certainly funny (I am
               aware of no other epithet which precisely applies to it) ; and I
               have much curiosity to know if Outis is prepared to swear to
               its truth—holding right aloft his band, of course, and kissing
               the back of D’Israeli’s “Curiosities,” or the “Melanges," of
               Suard and André. But if the assertion is funny (and it is) it is
               by no means an original thing. It is precisely, in fact, what
               all the plagiarists and all the “acquaintances” of the plagiarists since the flood, have maintained with a very praiseworthy resolution.
            </p>
            
            <p>The attempt to prove, however, by reasoning à priori, that
               plagiarism cannot exist, is too good an idea on the part of
               Outis not to be a plagiarism in itself. Are we mistaken?—
               or have we seen the following words before in Joseph Miller,
               where that ingenious gentleman is bent upon demonstrating
               that a leg of mutton is and ought to be a turnip?
            </p>
            
            <p>“A man who aspires to fame, etc. attempts to win his object—how? By stealing, in open day, the finest passages,
               the most beautiful thoughts (no others are worth stealing)
               and claiming them as his own ; and that too when he knows
               that every competitor, etc., will be ready to cry him down as
               a thief.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Is it possible?—is it conceivable that Outis does not here
               see the begging of the whole question. Why, of course, if
               the theft had to be committed “in open day" it would not be
               committed; and if the thief “knew" that every one would cry
               him down, he would be too excessive a fool to make even a
               decent thief if he indulged his thieving propensities in any
               respect. But he thieves at night—in the dark—and not in
               the open day (if he suspects it), and he does not know that he
               will be delected at all. Of the class of wilful plagiarists
               nine out of ten are authors of established reputation, who
               plunder recondite, neglected, or forgotten books.
            </p>
            
            <p>I pause for the present, through want of space, but will resume the subject at some length in the next” Journal,” and
               hope to convince our friend Outis that he has made a series
               of very singular mistakes.
            </p>
            
            <div class="byline">E. A. P.</div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         
         <div class="head">THE ART OF THE USE OF COLOR IN IMITATION IN PAINTING.</div>
         
         
         <div class="ab">NO. IV.
            
            <br></br>BY 
            <span class="person">WILLIAM PAGE</span>.
         </div>
         
         <p>No, all the outcry that has been made against imitation,
            and in favor of the ideal, anti-natural, is most unadulterated
            cant, and though propped up by the words of Reynolds, and
            innumerable blind followers, his works, that is, the best of
            them, give his theory the lie direct, being, so far as his means
            or knowledge extended, the merest imitations of the things
            before him, with certainly no exaltation of character. No one
            who remembers the portrait of Baron Heathfield, I think, as
            the defender of Gibraltar, will believe that there is any poetic
            license taken, in the way of elevating the character—it is the
            most upright and downright plain old fellow that you would
            meet in a day’s march. And as for elevation, I have seen
            some of our independent beggars, who presented as much the
            look of tough endurance, and importance, as well as self-dependence, as this celebrated picture conveys, though I judge
            it through such copies as I ha ve seen in print and otherwhere,
            enough generally to enable any intelligent observer to judge
            fairly, or favorably at least, of most English pictures. Though
            Sir Joshua says so much about elevating nature by true art,
            he did not mean in color, and I don’t know that there is a
            line in his discourses that can be construed into such a sense,
            or nonsense rather; but after talking a great deal about it, he
            says that, after all, “in comparison with Nature, the best colored pictures are but faint and feeble.” And indeed, the critics who condemn Titian to the lowest as a designer of form,
            because he has imitated the shape of the model before him,
            laud him to the skies because in the color he has imitated his
            model perfectly. And what do these wiseacres suppose that
            he would choose a model for—for form? Raffaelle might
            have thought about this property, but the great Venetian had
            eye and mind for color, and color was his first thought, form
            was a secondary consideration—all things sang color to him,
            and a grand concert they made of it too, and a scarcely less
            harmonious accompaniment did he play. In fact, the color of
            Nature is so fair, it is so unapproachable by art, so ever
            charming, infinitely varied, yet so gentle and subdued, so
            palpably introduced in the works of God, for beauty, not
            utility, that we say, yes, there is no ideal in color beyond the
            real. This is perfect. All the contrivances of man may not
            attain to even the perfect imitation of this quality. But in
            form and expression, say the same worshippers of themselves,
            we only are perfect. But let them rest for the present; the
            time will come for their dry bones to be shaken into powder,
            and their dryer theories to crumble into dust with them, leaving but a heap of ashes for the winds to scatter as they list.
            If we take a few solid pigments representing the primary
            colors, together with white and black, and mix them together in all possible gradations, straining the sense to divide
            and subdivide them with the greatest subtlety, we may, perhaps, reach to the number of some few thousand tints sufficiently distinct to be distinguished by the eye as being different, and that is all. But if one single compound color, Orange
            for instance, be made by mixing two opaque colors, one Red
            and the other Yellow, together forming an Orange, and this
            be laid aside, then another Orange color be formed by painting a Yellow over a Red, and placed beside the first, a third
            then formed by painting a Red over a Yellow, and disposed
            in like manner as the other two, then another a lighter Red
            over a darker Yellow, and again a lighter Yellow over a
            darker Red, we could go on, on this principle, multiplying
            this one infinitely, and yet always producing a distinctive
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page151"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>character that a nice eye would discern and enjoy. And it is
            by this means that Nature ekes out her unmeasured treasures,
            to make a fuller, richer, more varied bouquet, for the dainty
            eye of man. And yet we painters will do without this: we’ll
            take a shorter way, mixing together our muddy tints, thereby
            making them still muddier, holding up the pallette-knife, and
            match all that Nature herself did, only by her finer Art: we
            have no need of any such niceties—we see deeper than Nature’s laws, and have a short-cut tunnel under them, whereby we reach it much more conveniently. We have no need
            to separate the accidental from the local, and then we will
            cheat all eyes into the belief that no such things exist in nature, more than in our pictures—so we will patch over what
            is to be taken for a piece of white drapery, with all the colors
            of earth and heaven, and make people see that these colors
            have nothing to do with the white drapery, but are only
            made to represent the light and shade, folds, &amp;c.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have repeatedly had young painters—not always young
            men, who have called upon me from the country and more
            inland cities, complain of the want of discrimination in the farmers and others, their patrons or employers, because, forsooth,
            the good old common sense people, when they had been
            plastered on to the threads of a canvass, by these aspirants
            after artistic honors, meekly inquired why Mr. Charcoal, the
            artist, had represented them as snuff-takers, as he had evidently intended to do, because he had made a broad patch of
            that doubtful color, beneath the organ to which that peculiar
            form of the weed is usually addressed. Then, I have said,
            Mr. C., it seems to me that he, the farmer you speak of, has
            decidedly the advantage of you, and that, as a critic, he has
            fairer pretensions than you can claim as an artist, for if you
            had sold your shadow to the evil one, this good critic, who
            never saw such a thing in his life, would never have missed it, but the patch which you introduced beneath his nose
            in your portrait, he didn’t know the meaning of, because it
            did not look like a shadow as intended, but like what he
            mistook it for. So, when what you mean for shadow is mistook lor snuff, be sure that it is not a fair representation.
            Your flesh must be seen with all its qualities, as well in the
            shadows as in the lights. So, when a landscape painter
            would represent a distant mountain, he mixes up together
            all the local colors of things, and the atmosphere which
            makes it look blue, and we have the qualities altogether
            producing such mountains, though intended to appear miles
            away, as cheat no sense but that of the painter. And such
            sky, upright as a wall, and hard enough to tempt an unfortunate, who had resolved on suicide, to rush headlong
            against it as the most solid substance he can find, to rid himself of his brains. He paints in his picture two cloaks, red
            cloaks for instance, such as were once in the same piece of
            cloth, consequently of one color, one of these cloaks is twice
            as far from the eye of the spectator as the other. So be
            mixes his blue color with the red of the cloak—the blue to
            represent the greater distance of this cloak from the eye than
            that of the other, but in reality this blue makes the cloak a
            different color, produced by more light between it and the eye
            of the spectator. The true way to paint it, indubitably is, after
            having by the linear perspective made the necessary difference in the size of the two objects to represent their places in
            the picture, to paint them of the same color, and when it
            has become dry, pass light over them in unequal quantities,
            the one being at double distance from the eye, having a
            double quantity of light over its local color, by which that
            local color will be undisturbed, and the accidental color will
            be kept separate from the thing itself as it should evidently
            he, and a more perfect imitation than can possibly be attain
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            ed by any other means known will follow. No sky ever
            was or can be truly represented, unless some of this using
            the principle existent in the thing itself be adopted, any more
            than the conch shell, the inside of which is by so many supposed to resemble the color of flesh, can be used as a model
            ! from which to represent that substance. The color of this
            shell, if you break and examine its structure, will be found a
            wash or transparent glaze upon a white surface, through
            which glaze the light illuminates the white beneath, and is
            reflected back to the eye, often with great brilliancy, but not
            sufficiently like flesh to make it deserve to be so often compared with it, much less to serve as a lesson of the mode to
            be adopted by the painter to imitate that more complicated
            substance ; and yet this mode is the one most in repute at
            present, as the best for painting flesh, being that of finishing
            it by glazing a color over a white, until the tone desired is
            attained. What we should learn from it (the shell) is how
            to paint that, and how not to paint flesh. When rightly
            painted, the eye sees that there is more under than it can
            reach; it looks into the red beneath the colorless surface of
            the skin, and recognises an intense hue that is actually presented. So in all the works of Nature is this unfathomable
            depth, leading us on to see more and more by increased effort,
            and yet hiding the end ever from our reach. So does true
            Art, and in its smallest product can be seen its highest principles, as in the pebble on the seashore, may be found subjects
            of as high and sublime thought and grand association, as in
            the circling of the planets round their suns, or the going and
            returning of the comets. What art would do is only to fix
            some of those fleeting beauties, that, though numberless, are
            ever passing, and with such rapidity before our eyes, that it
            is long before we learn to see them; but he would stay their
            flight, that the eye may look upon and contemplate them at
            its leisure, and so, when the poor feeble artist has done his
            best, the world wonders at his product, and, because he has
            never seen these things before, it deems it a new creation, and
            a higher one than has before existed. Away with such flattery ; let each fix what each best sees and knows, and the
            garden of art will again blossom with fresh beauties.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         
         <div class="head">THOUGHTS OF A SILENT MAN.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">
            
            <br></br>No. 1.
            
            <br></br>“Nemo est meorum amicorum hodie
            
            <br></br>Apud quem expromere occulta mea audeam.”
         </div>
         
         <p>Of all the various causes which may be assigned for the
            superabundance of inferior authorship, so much complained
            of among readers, perhaps the most frequent may be
            found in that terrible necessity for expression, which in many
            minds is even more powerful than the “strong necessity of
            loving.” Yet the world rarely understands this. Ambition,
            avarice, and above all, vanity, are regarded as propellants
            to literary labor, while a yearning for sympathy, a desire for
            repose, an irrepressible longing to claim kindred with congenial hearts, are feelings which are rarely believed in, or appreciated. The practical part of the world, who live on from
            day to day, governed only by the exigencies of the moment,
            and yielding to the expediencies of the passing hour, can have
            no idea of such needs. They find sufficient utterance in the
            gossip of petty scandal, the discussion of minor political questions, or the detail of every day business. They eat, drink,
            sleep, and read newspapers; while the real energies of their
            nature are all expended in the task of gain. They live for
            bargaining and trading; they feel no vacancy of soul, because
            they have filled that temple of the living God with the tables of the money changers.
         </p>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page152"></div>
         
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>But to those who think deeply, and feel vividly, expression is a necessity of their being ; they must “speak or die.”
            Some find their utterance in the interchange of socialities,
            some in discoursing elegant music, some speak in the wordless tints of painting, some few work out the ideal of their
            souls in the enduring marble, and some send forth their
            thoughts, winged by poesy, to the far winds of heaven.
            Yet there are still left many to whom are denied all these
            resources. There are some who have all the elements of
            power within them, but have never had their lips touched
            with the live coal from the altar, which was to the prophet,
            both inspiration and expression. There are some who seem
            like Zacharias, to be struck dumb by the very power which
            brings the promise of blessing: some to whom self-distrust
            is an incubus upon the mind, exciting it to uneasy activity,
            yet deterring it from utterance.
         </p>
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>Without putting forth any pretension to the possession of
            the higher order of such power, I may yet claim to know
            something of the discomforts attendant upon compulsory
            silence. I have outlived all the associates of very early life,
            and my unconquerable shyness of temper has prevented me
            from forming new ones. I have a large circle of acquaintance,
            and many family friends, but not one to whom I can open
            my inner heart. I have a competent fortune, refined tastes,
            and, I think, warm affections, yet I lead the life of a hermit,
            as far as the social sympathies are concerned. In the opinion
            of the world I have all the means of happiness within my
            reach, but all these gifts are marred by the want of a power
            which is so generally possessed, that, like the blessings of
            light and air, people scarcely value it; I mean the power of
            expressing my overburdened mind in words.
         </p>
         
         
         <div class="ab">(Continued on page 154.)</div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         
         <div class="head">Letter from James Given in New York, to his Cousin Hugh Hughes, of Pool Lane,
            Liverpool.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Globe Hotel, March 3, 1845.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Dear Hughey,</div>
         
         <p>It is a whole year (mercy, how the time has flown !) since I wrote you last. I was
            then
            at “Maple Hill” with the Myrtles, with my
            eyes wide open to see every thing, and my heart as soft, and almost as pure, as a
            lump of virgin wax. It received an impression from every
            thing that touched it, but as I felt it growing harder and harder every day, I was
            resolved not to pen another line until its first impressions
            were either obliterated altogether, or hardened into a durable form.
         </p>
         
         <p>First impressions, you must know, my dear Hughey, are always wrong ; therefore the
            reports of a transient visitor to any country, and to
            this one in particular, should be received with great distrust. Going from one
            country to another is like going from the sunshine into a dar.
            kened room. You think at first that it contains nothing. By degrees you perceive here
            a table, there a chair, a sofa, a mantel clock, a bookcase, a mirror, a picture, and a young lady; until at last you find that
            it is a well furnished room, like any other one. This I must confess,to
            you was exactly my case, when I first landed in New York. I could see nothing the
            first few days, but I soon began to recover my sight, und
            then things wore a familiar look to me, and every morning I got up with changed impressions
            of the country, the people, the laws, the climate, the fruits, the flowers, the habits, the every thing. Every day I
            feel myself less an Englishman; and if not more a Yankee, at least
            more a man of the world. Once I thought that England was the universe, and Pool lane
            the best place in it; but all that is changed, and
            I can now honestly declare, that I believe there are as good places in England as
            Pool lane, and much better places in the universe than
            England. Something has bewitched me—the blue skies, perhaps, or perhaps you will say,
            the blue eyes. But I will not tell you now. But
            I will tell you one thing now : towards you, dear Hughey, I am still unchanged, and
            I
            still think, in truth I know, that there is not another so
            good a fellow, so true a friend, so companionable a companion, in or out of England,
            as yourself. Take my honest word for it, and make no
            doubt of it. This of course you will not tell; but do oblige me and say nothing about
            the rest, for fear that somebody in Bold street, no matter who, should think that I am estranged.
         </p>
         
         <p>I believe that I mentioned in one of my first letters something about Franklin Myrtle,
            a
            young American artist with whom I had
            become intimate, who has half a dozen sisters and to forth. He is a capital good
            fellow and a promising artist; some of his sketches art
            the best I have ever seen, of the kind. I will give you a specimen, or at least he
            shall, for he is at my elbow, and he says that he will add
            something as a tail piece to my letter, if I will spare him a blank inch or two.
         </p>
         
         <p>To-day is the last of the Tyler dynasty. You are probably so ignorant as not to know
            what
            that is, and I have not room to tell you fully,
            but I will another time. You must know that the people of this country, or the Whigs
            rather, four years ago, made themselves a President,
            somewhat after the manner of Frankenstein, who no sooner began to feel hit strength
            than he made use of it to destroy hit makers. Frank,
            you must know, was one of those who helped to make him, and of course he feels very
            sore on the subject. He calls him a Flibbertigibbet
            and tells the most amusing stories of hit pranks and grimaces. But to-day he goes
            out
            of power. The strong hand of Destiny is upon
            him, and Frank says he is boxed for eternity. He says that an idea has struck him,
            and begs that I will let him put it down before it
            escapes him. So I give him the pen.
         </p>
         
         <div class="figure">
            
            <div class="head">THE LAST OF TYLER.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         <p>In my next I will tell you all that I intended to do in this. You may show the specimen
            in Bold street, but nothing more.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Ever yours, JAMES GIVEN.
            
            <br></br>PS. Direct your letters care of F. Myrtle, Now York.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page153"></div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p7">
         
         <p>No person of proper feeling can peruse the works of a distinguished author or authoress
            (the latter is a very absurd word, to be sure, but
            for that very reason the more necessary,) without an instantaneous desire to make
            his
            (or her) personal acquaintance—provided always that
            the said author (or authoress) has not committed himself (or herself) to the extent
            of perpetraying criticisms full of "carping littleness" upon
            the last "Sonnet to the Katy-Did,” or the next to the last “Sonnet to the Katy-Did’nt,”
            composed by the person of proper feeling aforesaid—for, in such a case as we have imagined, the identical "proper
            feeling” of which we speak, would of course induce the person to get
            as far away from the critic as possible. But, as a general rule, we are always inquisitive
            about the physical appearance of a celebrated author; and it is but a sort of corrollary from this proposition, that if
            we are prevented by unhappy circumstances, from beholding the author
            himself, we still entertain a longing to see his portrait. If we cannot see this,
            we
            get his autograph if possible—but if this again is not to be
            discovered, we then regard ourselves as unfortunate beings and subject to an especial
            dispensation on the part of Providence.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is with a view of ministering to this very commendable curiosity that we furnish
            our
            readers, this week, with the subjoined engraving.—
            It either is, or ought to be, an accurate portrait of one of the most distinguished
            of American authoresses. We are not quite sure that we
            have ever seen a more striking likeness, and we presume it will be recognized at once
            by all who have ever met the original. We might pick
            out, perhaps, a few material points of variation, and we would do so upon the spot,
            were it not for fear of offending the artist, who is an exceedingly sensitive person. But for this, we would say, for example, that
            the nose is a little—a very little too Grecian.—That the “fine
            phrenzy” of the eyes has not been preserved so decidedly as it should be—that the
            chin has too shrewish a character—that the little finger
            of the left hand is too straight (or perhaps a little too crooked)—that the table
            is
            too round—the feather of the pen too feathery—and the
            Ink (as far as we can judge of it through a metal ink-stand,) too blue. We forbear
            to
            give the name of the original, because, in the case of
            the ladies, an editor must be cautious how he deals in personalities—and we cannot
            be
            sure of not having an invitation to Hoboken forthwith.
            The name, however, is a point of no consequence. The portrait will be recognised the
            world over—if not, the fault will lie in that rather
            unusual acidity of expression worn at present by the fail lady, who happens to be
            engaged in a perusal of one of our criticisms upon her antepenultimate ode “To the Universe.”
         </p>
         
         <div class="figure">
            
            <div class="head">PORTRAIT OF A DISTINGUISHED AUTHORESS.</div>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">E. Brown</span>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page154"></div>
      
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         
         <div class="ab">(Continued from page 152.)</div>
         
         <p>I cannot talk. An unfortunate impediment in my speech,
            which is always increased by any nervous excitement, is one
            obstacle; but another, and more insuperable one, is my unconquerable shyness and self-distrust. I enjoy society with
            my whole heart. I listen to brilliant conversation, (for I
            number among my friends some of the best talkers I ever
            heard), and within my own mind I take full part in it. Ready
            rejoinders, sparkling repartees, unanswerable arguments,
            profound reflections, high-toned moralizing, and all the varied
            forms of spoken eloquence, are wrought out in the chambers
            of mine imagery. Sometimes I delude myself with the belief that I have really contributed my proportion of amusement to the social circle. My fancies are so vivid that it
            often seems to me as if I had actually uttered all the fine
            things which have been passing through my mind. I have
            often pleased myself with such a belief, and have experienced for a moment, all the satisfaction of a man who has acted
            well his part in society, until some trivial recollection has
            brought me back to the consciousness that mine had been
            only an “imaginary conversation,” a sort of vivification of
            birth-strangled ideas.
         </p>
         
         <p>How can one like me, find expression? My mind is too
            active for continued silence; it hives up stores of knowledge,
            it accumulates masses of facts, it fashions images of beauty,
            it works out conceptions of goodness and greatness. Why
            then must it be ever dumb, when it would utter the oracles
            of nature and truth? I am resolved. I will take my humble pen, and surrounded by my books, those quiet friends,
            whose silence is so suggestive,—I will imprison in written
            words the busy fancies which so disturb my peace. Crude
            and ill arranged as my ideas may seem, they will perhaps
            give out glimpses of something better to come. There is
            more in me than I can now utter, but a true word was never
            yet spoken in vain, and it may be that some one will become
            the happier for having picked up a rough-hewn thought from
            my quarry.
         </p>
         
         <p>I do not flatter myself that mine is an unusual case, or
            that I possess the genius which demands freedom. There is
            no condition of life to which the history of human nature
            does not afford numberless parallels, and one of the grand
            mistakes which make the wretchedness of mortals, is the
            belief in a peculiar destiny of suffering. Therefore I know
            that thousands have felt as I do, and could doubtless have
            expressed their feelings better. As for genius, that is a gift
            of God, vouchsafed, once in an age, to the world. Men of
            talents may be counted by hundreds, men of learning by
            thousands, but men of genius must still be numbered by
            tens, although the world is six thousand years old. Besides,
            Genius comes with a commission from the Most High; it
            cannot be silent even if it would.
         </p>
         
         <p>But I am wearied of ceaseless commune in the shyness of
            my own heart, wearied of perpetual activity and unbroken
            silence. I would fain speak, aye, speak without feeling the
            eye of ridicule scorching my cheek,—without having my ear
            pained by the half inarticulate sounds that fall from my
            stammering lips,—without feeling in every vein the throb of
            that terrible silence which always follows any attempt at
            vocal utterance.
         </p>
         
         <p>It may be that old age is creeping upon me apace, and
            that I grow garrulous as I grow grey. It may be that I am
            mistaken in thinking I have any thing to say. If so, I shall
            soon learn my error, for nothing is so severe a trial of one’s
            crude fancies as the sight of them in print. We all have
            our imaginings, but when the “soul of our thoughts” first
            appears before us in actual form and type, we feel very
            much as if we looked upon an apparition from the world of
            shadows, and like the witch of Endor, we are terrified before
            the spectre we have ourselves called forth.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">RUDOLPH HERTZMAN</span>.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         
         <div class="head">Original Poetry.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            
            <div class="head">THE GHOST-SEER.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               
               <br></br>Ye who, passing graves by night,
               
               <br></br>Glance not to the left nor right
               
               <br></br>Lest a spirit should arise,
               
               <br></br>Cold and white, to freeze your eyes,
               
               <br></br>Some weak phantom, which your doubt
               
               <br></br>Shapes upon the dark without
               
               <br></br>From the dark within, a guess
               
               <br></br>At the spirit’s deathlessness,
               
               <br></br>Which ye entertain with fear
               
               <br></br>In your self-built dungeon here,
               
               <br></br>Where ye dance and shake your chain
               
               <br></br>As if freedom would be pain,—
               
               <br></br>Ye without a shudder meet
               
               <br></br>In the city’s noon-day street,
               
               <br></br>Spirits sadder and more dread
               
               <br></br>Than from out the clay have fled :
               
               <br></br>Spirits buried dark and deep
               
               <br></br>In a grave where never sleep,
               
               <br></br>The cool dew of Paradise,
               
               <br></br>Drops upon their burning eyes,
               
               <br></br>Buried, beyond hope of light,
               
               <br></br>In the body’s haunted night!
               
               <br></br>See ye not that woman pale?
               
               <br></br>Where are bloodhounds on her trail,
               
               <br></br>Bloodhounds two, all gaunt and lean,
               
               <br></br>For the soul their scent is keen,
               
               <br></br>Want and Sin, and Sin is last,
               
               <br></br>They have followed far and fast;
               
               <br></br>Want gave tongue, and, at her howl,
               
               <br></br>Sin awakened with a growl.
               
               <br></br>’Twas the World and the World’s law
               
               <br></br>Let them slip and cried, Hurrah!
               
               <br></br>Ah, poor girl! she had a right
               
               <br></br>To a blessing from the light,
               
               <br></br>Title deeds to sky and earth
               
               <br></br>God gave to her at her birth,
               
               <br></br>But, before they were enjoyed,
               
               <br></br>Poverty had made them void,
               
               <br></br>And had drunk the sunshine up
               
               <br></br>From all nature’s ample cup,
               
               <br></br>Leaving her a firstborn’s share
               
               <br></br>In the dregs of darkness there.
               
               <br></br>Often, on the sidewalk bleak,
               
               <br></br>Hungry, all alone, and weak.
               
               <br></br>She has seen, in night and storm,
               
               <br></br>Rooms o’erflow with firelight warm,
               
               <br></br>Which, outside the window glass
               
               <br></br>Doubled all the cold, alas !
               
               <br></br>Till each ray that on her fell
               
               <br></br>Stabbed her like an icicle,
               
               <br></br>And she almost loved the wail
               
               <br></br>Of the bloodhounds on her trail.
               
               <br></br>Till the floor becomes her bier
               
               <br></br>She shall feel their pantings near.
               
               <br></br>Close upon her very heels,
               
               <br></br>’Spite of all the din of wheels ;
               
               <br></br>Shivering on her pallet floor,
               
               <br></br>She shall hear them at the door
               
               <br></br>Whine and scratch to be let in.
               
               <br></br>Sister bloodhounds, Want and Sin !
               
               <br></br>Hark ! that rustle of a drew
               
               <br></br>Stiff with lavish costliness !
               
               <br></br>Here comes one whose cheek would flush
               
               <br></br>But to have her garment brush
               
               <br></br>’Gainst the girl whose fingers thin
               
               <br></br>Wove the weary broidery in,
               
               <br></br>Who bent backward from her toil
               
               <br></br>Lest her tears the silk might soil,
               
               <br></br>And, in midnight chill and murk,
               
               <br></br>Stitched her life into the work.
               
               <br></br>Little doth the wearer heed
               
               <br></br>Of the heart break in the brede,
               
               <br></br>A hyena by her side
               
               <br></br>Skulks, downlooking—it is Pride.
               
               <br></br>He digs for her in the earth,
               
               <br></br>Where lie all her claims of birth,
               
               <br></br>With his foul paws rooting o’er
               
               <br></br>Some long-buried ancestor
               
               <br></br>Who, most like, a statue won
               
               <br></br>By the ill deeds he had done.
               
               <br></br>Round her heart and round her brain
               
               <br></br>Wealth hath linked a golden chain,
               
               <br></br>Which doth dose and closer press
               
               <br></br>Heart and brain to narrowness.
               
               <br></br>Every morn and every night
               
               <br></br>She must bare that bosom white,
               
               <br></br>Which so thrillingly doth rise
               
               <br></br>’Neath its proud embroideries,
               
               <br></br>What its mere heave lets men know
               
               <br></br>How much whiter 'tis than snow,—
               
               <br></br>She must bare it, and, unseen,
               
               <br></br>Suckle that hyena lean ;—
               
               <br></br>Ah! the fountain’s angel shrinks,
               
               <br></br>And forsakes it while he drinks !
               
               <br></br>There walks Judas, he who sold
               
               <br></br>Yesterday his Lord for gold,
               
               <br></br>Sold God’s presence in his heart
               
               <br></br>For a proud step in the Mart;
               
               <br></br>He hath dealt in flesh and blood,
               
               <br></br>At the Bank his name is good,
               
               <br></br>At the Bank, and only there,
               
               <br></br>’Tis a marketable ware.
               
               <br></br>In his eyes that stealthy gleam
               
               <br></br>Was not learned of sky or stream,
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page155"></div>
               
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               
               <br></br>But it has the cold, hard glint,
               
               <br></br>Of new dollars from the Mint
               
               <br></br>Often now your spirit’s eyes
               
               <br></br>Look through that poor clay disguise
               
               <br></br>Which has thickened, day by day,
               
               <br></br>Till it keeps all life away,
               
               <br></br>And his soul in pitchy gloom
               
               <br></br>Gropes about its narrow tomb,
               
               <br></br>From whose dank and slimy walls,
               
               <br></br>Drop by drop, the horror falls.
               
               <br></br>Look ! a serpent lank and cold
               
               <br></br>Hugs his spirit, fold on fold,
               
               <br></br>From his heart, all day and night,
               
               <br></br>It doth suck God’s blessed light
               
               <br></br>Drink it will, and drink it must,
               
               <br></br>Till the cup holds naught but dust;
               
               <br></br>All day long he hears it hiss,
               
               <br></br>Writhing in its fiendish bliss;
               
               <br></br>All night long he sees its eyes
               
               <br></br>Flicker with strange ecstasies,
               
               <br></br>As the spirit ebbs away
               
               <br></br>Into the absorbing day.
               
               <br></br>Who is he that skulks afraid
               
               <br></br>Of the trust he has betrayed,
               
               <br></br>Shuddering if perchance a gleam
               
               <br></br>Of old nobleness should stream
               
               <br></br>Through the pent, unwholesome room,
               
               <br></br>Where his shrunk soul cowers in gloom,
               
               <br></br>Spirit sad beyond the rest
               
               <br></br>By more instinct for the Best?
               
               <br></br>'Tis a poet, who was sent
               
               <br></br>For a bad world’s punishment,
               
               <br></br>By compelling it to see
               
               <br></br>Golden glimpses of To Be,
               
               <br></br>By compelling it to hear
               
               <br></br>Songs that prove the angels near;
               
               <br></br>Who was sent to be the tongue
               
               <br></br>Of the weak and spirit-wrung,
               
               <br></br>Whence the fiery-winged Despair
               
               <br></br>In men’s shrinking eyes might flare.
               
               <br></br>’Tis our hope doth fashion us
               
               <br></br>To base use or glorious:
               
               <br></br>He who might have been a lark
               
               <br></br>Of Truth’s morning, from the dark
               
               <br></br>Raining down melodious hope
               
               <br></br>Of a freer, broader scope,
               
               <br></br>Aspirations, prophecies,
               
               <br></br>Of the spirit’s full sunrise,—
               
               <br></br>Chose to be a bird of night,
               
               <br></br>Which, with eyes refusing light,
               
               <br></br>Hooted from some hollow tree
               
               <br></br>Of the world’s idolatry.
               
               <br></br>’Tis his punishment to hear
               
               <br></br>Flutterings of pinions near,
               
               <br></br>And his own vain wings to feel
               
               <br></br>Drooping downward to his heel,
               
               <br></br>All their grace and import lost,
               
               <br></br>Burthening his weary ghost:
               
               <br></br>Ever walking by his side
               
               <br></br>He must see his angel guide,
               
               <br></br>Who at intervals doth turn
               
               <br></br>Looks on him so sadly stem,
               
               <br></br>With such ever-new surprise
               
               <br></br>Of hushed anguish in her eyes,
               
               <br></br>That it seems the light of day
               
               <br></br>From around him shrinks away,
               
               <br></br>Or drops blunted from the wall
               
               <br></br>Built around him by his fall.
               
               <br></br>Then the mountains, whose white peaks
               
               <br></br>Catch the morning’s earliest streaks,
               
               <br></br>He must see, where prophets sit,
               
               <br></br>Turning East their faces lit,
               
               <br></br>Whence, with footsteps beautiful,
               
               <br></br>To the earth, yet dim and dull,
               
               <br></br>They the gladsome tidings bring
               
               <br></br>Of the sunlight’s hastening.
               
               <br></br>Never can those hills of bliss
               
               <br></br>Be o’erclimbed by feet of his!
               
               <br></br>But enough! Oh, do not dare
               
               <br></br>From the next its mask to tear,
               
               <br></br>Which, although it moves about
               
               <br></br>Like a human form without.
               
               <br></br>Hath a soul within, I ween,
               
               <br></br>Of the vulture’s shape and mien.
               
            </div>
            
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">JAMES R. LOWELL.</span>
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         
         <div class="head">LITERARY NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            
            <p>A Lecture on the Philosophy of Vegetation. Read at the Organization of
               the American Agricultural Association, at the University in the City of
               New York, on Monday, the 10th February, 1845. By W. A. Seeley, Esq.
               Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Seeley’s lecture is too purely technical for popular reading, and
               we were not surprised to see, in a morning paper that gives a good portion of its columns to agricultural knowledge, some exceedingly disparaging remarks in regard to it. Probably the critic had in his mind
               Milton’s lines in Comus, 
               <div class="lg">
                  
                  <br></br>" How charming is divine philosophy !
                  
                  <br></br>Not harsh and crabbed as vain fools suppose,
                  
                  <br></br>But musical as is Apollo's lute.
                  
                  <br></br>And a perpetual feast of nectared sweets,’'
                  
               </div> was disappointed in not finding the “philosophy of vegetation” as smooth and
               flashy as a review by Macaulay. A purely scientific essay
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>should not read too smoothly, lest it slip over the tongue without
               making any impression upon the mind. A few jagged points may help
               to make a principle stick to the memory. Mr. Seeley’s lecture is not
               written in the pleasing style of Dumas it is true, nor with the copiousness of detail and illustration which we find in the lectures of Davy,
               but he has crowded as many facts into his lecture as we remember to
               have seen in the same space. We extract one sentence, merely to
               show how unacceptable truth itself may be made by conveying it in
               an unseemly shape ; and as a caution to those who would have their
               thoughts disseminated to put them into a vehicle that is not too clumsy to carry them.
            </p>
            
            <p>“While one special energy of electro-chemical force exhibits healthy life
               maintaining literally a successful conflict between its own vital, and its coexistent chemical forces, ruling, nolens volens, its materials to an
               Antiseptic
               condition, yet, by reason of that conflict, dooming it ultimately to assured
               divorce in death; we find another, the independent chemistry of the broad
               and illimitable field of inorganic nature, often, even during the decline of its
               forces by disease, or the infirmities of age, hut ever in death, seizing upon
               those elements, and subjecting them, through septic agencies, to disembodiment, for the purpose of another, and a future, again antiseptic
               existence.”
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            
            <p>Mothers' Lessons for little Girls and Boys. By a Lady of Boston.
               Little Stories for Little Folks. From the German. Boston. Published by W.
               D. Ticknor 4c Co., 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have seldom met with two better books for the hands of children than these beautiful little volumes from the press of Ticknor
               and Co. of Boston. It has been a too frequent fault with childrens'
               books that they have been badly got up, but these volumes are sufficiently elegant for the most fastidious amateur in bibliography. The
               engravings are not quite as good as they should be, but they are free
               from the blotches and distortions which disfigure the majority of
               books of this class.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            
            <p>The Gambler's Mirror, Vol. 1. No. 1. Boston, Redding &amp; Co., 1845.
               Gambling unmasked, or the Reformed Gambler, designed as a warning to the
               young of this country. New-York, Burgess, Stringer, &amp; Co., 1845.
               An Exposè of the Arts and Miseries of Gambling, Second Edition, improved.
               Boston, Redding &amp; Co., 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>These books have already obtained a wide popularity, and we trust
               a profitable circulation. They detail the personal experience of their
               author, Mr. J. H. Green, who is doing essential service to the cause of
               humanity by his labors in a field which has long remained without the
               husbandman, though it has been many years white for the harvest.-There are few besides those who suffer from gambling who know to
               what a fearful extent the vice prevails among us ; at the west, where
               society has not been put into a strait-jacket, it shows itself openly
               and fearlessly, and the mischief it produces may only be faintly imagined from the bare reports of its effects, such as the extempore execution of half a dozen “Sportsmen” at Vicksburg a few years since
               that reach us in the newspapers. Occasionally in New York we hear
               of a defaulting clerk, or a bankrupt merchant, whose ruin has been
               produced by this dreadful vice, but the greater part of the misery and
               crime which arc caused by it are attributed to other causes. Every
               father who has a son just entering upon business should put one of
               Mr. Green’s books in his hand, and every merchant when he first receives a new clerk into his employment should see that he has a copy
               of the “Miseries of Gambling.”
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            
            <p>The Last of the Plantagenets, a Tragic Drama in three acts. By Caroline M. Keteltas.
               Founded on the romance of that name by William Heseltine of Turret house, South Lambeth,
               England. New-York, 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>The gentle author of this " Tragic Drama” has given her book to
               the world from a very amiable motive, namely, a desire to counteract
               the prejudices which Shakspeare’s delineation of Richard the Third
               has created in the minds of mankind. But her intention is better than
               her gift. Horace Walpole labored zealously and learnedly in tho
               same cause, in his “Historic Doubts,” but Shakspeare’s Richard still
               keeps possession of men’s minds, and the world will never forgive him
               for his tyrannies, or forget that he murdered the infants in the Tower
               The blood of the innocent will always make an immortal outcry
               against those who shed it. The author of the “Tragic Drama” has
               taken a great chronological liberty with the last of the Plantagenets
               in making him kneel before the bust of Shakspeare, which we are less
               willing to forgive, since we learn from a note to her epilogue that she is
               descended from a great dramatic poet; no less than “glorious John ”
               She also informs hs that she has a relative who has a monument in
               Westminster Abbey. " A genealogical tree in the author’s family "
               she says, " traces a descent from the Poet Dryden, who married Lady Elizabeth Howard, daughter of the Earl of Berkshire.” How fine
               and natural the allusion to “the Poet Dryden who married ” &amp;c.—
               Whatever doubts may be entertained of the descent from the husband
               of the daughter of the earl of Berkshire, there can be none in the
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page156"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>world that the descent from the Poet Dryden to the author of the
               “Last of the Plantagenets” is not only very real, but very great.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            
            <p>The Knickerbocker, March, 1349. John Allen, 139 Nassau St.</p>
            
            <p>This comfortable old Magazine contains several very capital papers, a beautiful poem from Albert Pike, a quaint one from John Waters which would be beautiful if it were not Quaint; and some amusing bits in the editor’s table. The fun about the Pennsylvanian’s gunfiring on the payment of their State debt interest, is very Punchy. We
               are sure that our good natured friend the editor will pardon us, if not
               thank us, for hinting to him, as gently as a lamb, that he makes use
               of the adjectives forceful and matterful too often for his readers’ pleasure; we like adjectives ending in ful extremely well, as armful,
               mouthful, pocketful, &amp;c.; but matterful sounds less agreeably than
               full of matter.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            
            <p>The Saturday Emporium. March 1st, 1345. Ward A Go., Ann St., New-
               York.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is an admirable paper, one better adapted to the uses of the
               poor wo have never stumbled upon in the course of our Newspaper
               experience, since it can be put to more uses than one; after it has enlightened the intellect, refreshed the spirit and warmed the heart, it
               may be made to warm the body by using it as a counterpane for the
               bed. It is large enough, stout enough, and white enough. Neither
               dogs it contain any of those heavy articles which papers of this class
               often do that would be likely to bruise the limbs if used in the way
               which we have recommended, nor any of the poppyish ones that
               would be likely to cause too deep a slumber, nor any of those grotesque ones which would cause nightmares, nor yet any of those very
               light articles which would keep it from lying gently upon a sleeper.—
               However, it was not our intention to pronounce a panygeric, though we
               hardly know of a case in which wc could do it with a clearer conscience, but to vindicate ourselves from a vile aspersion upon our critical honesty which the paper contained last Saturday, in a notice of
               our review of Bulwer’s Minor Poems published by Farmer and Daggers, and edited by C. Donald Macleod. So far from having any “private pique” to “gratify,” we have no private feelings of any kind, but
               pure good will, towards every person whose name is connected with
               the book, excepting Bulwer, for whom we entertain no very profound
               admiration. Mr. Macleod will acquit us of the smallest tinge of personal unkindness towards himself, for we only know him by his writings which have heretofore impressed us with a very high opinion of
               his abilities ; and for the publisher of the “Minor Poems," we certainly have none but the kindest feelings. Do not, we beseech of you,
               Messieurs of the Emporium, accuse us of making attacks upon people
               when we simply utter our opinions and fortify them with reasons.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            
            <p>The Foreign Quarterly Review. No. LXVIII. for January, 1845. Ameri- can edition,
               Leonard Scott &amp; Co., 112 Fulton st.
            </p>
            
            <p>For American readers the Foreign Quarterly is becoming the most
               popular of all the British Reviews ; it contains few papers of merely a
               local interest, and gives a belter view of continental literature than
               any other work that we are acquainted with. The present number
               contains sound, valuable papers, but the most interesting one is on
               Bettina Brentano.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            
            <p>Blackwood's Magazine. February. New American Edition. New-York.—
               Published by Leonard Scott &amp; Co., 113 Fulton St.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is the sprightliest and most valuable number of Blackwood
               that has been issued the year past. North’s specimens of the British
               Critics is in the true vein of the professor. It is miraculous how he
               preserves the peculiarities of his early years.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         
         <div class="head">The Fine Arts.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            
            <p>A New picture by Chapman has been exhibited at the the rooms of
               the Art Union in Broadway, the last fortnight, representing Rachel,
               mourning for her first bora, and refusing to be comforted. To our perceptions it is the best of Chapman’s paintings ; and we were pleased
               to learn that it found a private purchaser at a liberal price. When
               such works can find purchasers other artists need not despair of finding a market for their paintings. We do not allude to it for the purpose of criticism, for we are not sure that it is within the circumference of propriety to make a public criticism on private property ; but
               to chronicle the fact of a historical painting being bought as soon as
               it was exhibited. A gentleman well known for his liberality to artists
               was the purchaser.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            
            <p>We have recently inspected the portraits of a horse and a Shetland
               poney, painted by Mr. T. Hicks, for John H. Hicks, Esq. of this city,
               which struck us as the finest specimen of animal portraiture that we
               have ever seen from an American artist. The animals, though in
               high keeping, had nothing of that unnatural glossiness of hide which
               is so disagreeable in the majority of pictures of this class. The interior of the stable would do credit to any American artist with whose
               works we are acquainted. Mr. Hicks adheres to the integrity of nature in his portraits, and we should judge from the few pictures of his
               execution that we have seen that he is a hard student and a close observer of nature. If he do not in a few years stand at the head of his
               profession in this country, we shall be disappointed in our expectations.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            
            <p>The granite buildings on the corner of Chambers-street and Broadway, is a huge eccaleiobeon, for hatching artists. On every floor of
               that capacious building may be found a half dozen of painters or sculptors, who are just bursting from the chrysalis of obscurity and preparing to spread their butterfly wings and soar into the summer sky of
               Fame. The best of them will be fouud highest up. There is Elliot,
               the most promising of our young portrait painters, in the room which
               Page used to occupy, and opposite to him are Cropsey, Gignoux and
               Cafferty, the most promising among our landscape painters. They
               are, in truth, more than promising, for they have already fulfilled the
               promises which they gave when they first made themselves known to
               the public.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            
            <p>Mons. Edouart’s Silhouettes —The works of this gentleman deserve to be classed among works of fine-art. His mere profile cuttings,
               perhaps, do not; although even his scissored portraits better deserve
               it than many portraits on canvass, which have that distinction awarded to them. Mons. Edouart has an epic composition in his rooms in
               Broadway, representing the temptation of Saint Anthony, which gave
               a different idea of his genius from what we had found before we saw
               it. He has lately adopted an ingenious plan of grouping his subjects,
               after cutting them, and then re-producing them in miniature by the
               Daguerreotype. So that a gentleman may have his whole family put
               into a convenient shape to carry in his vest pocket. A visit to his
               room is worth more than his charge for a portrait.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p21">
         
         <div class="head">THE CONCERT ROOM.</div>
         
         <p>The New York Philharmonic Society.—The third Concert of
            the third season took place at the Apollo Saloon on Saturday, March
            1st, when, as usual, there was a perfect crowd, an intolerable heat,
            and no ventilation. Since the room has been hung with the bar-room
            drapery, it seems impossible to breathe with freedom or comfort; added to which the sound is entirely destroyed, and the decorations are
            in the worst possible taste. We should be glad to see the room as it
            was.
         </p>
         
         <p>The programme was as follows:</p>
         
         <div class="ab">Part I.
            
            <br></br>Sinfonia Eroica (No. 5.)    -    -    -    Beethoven.
            
            <br></br>Movements 1 Allegro con brio.
            
            <br></br> “ 2 Marcia funebre. Adagio.
            
            <br></br> “ 3 Scherzo. Allegro vivace.
            
            <br></br> “ 4 Finale. Allegro molto.
            
            <br></br>Rondo. Finale del Furioso, -    -    Donizetti.
            
            <br></br>“Che d’AIla Goija.”    -    -    Madame Arnoult.
            
            <br></br>Sinfonia Concertante (No. 2.)    -    -    Lindpaimtner.
            
            <br></br> Flute, oboe, clarionette, horn and bassoon.
            
            <br></br> Messrs Kyle, Weisse, Grceneveldt, Reiff, and Trosji.
            
            <br></br>Part II.
            
            <br></br>Descriptive Overture. The Naiads, (Die Najaden.)
            
            <br></br> First time in America,    -    -    W. Sterndale Bennett.
            
            <br></br>Grand Air—Grace. Robert le Diable. Mad. Arnoult, Meyerbeer.
            
            <br></br> Dialogo Brillante—flute and clarionette.    -    Bochsa.
            
            <br></br> Messrs. J. A. Kyle and T. W. Grceneveldt.
            
            <br></br>Grosse Fest Ouverture und Sieges Marsch (first time.) F. Ries.
            
            <br></br> Componirt fur dot Nitderheinische Musick fest in Colon 1832.
            
            <br></br> Director, Mr. Louis Wiegers.
         </div>
         
         <p>The symphony Eroica, of Beethoven, is so well known to all who
            visit these classical Concerts, that a particular description will not be
            necessary. The design is said to have been conceived in honor of Napoleon, when first Consul, but before it was completed, the first Consul
            bad become Emperor, and Beethoven in the deepest indignation vowed
            that he would never dedicate one of his works to such a renegade from
            his principles. The first movement is supposed to vindicate the indomitable firmness of the conqueror’s mind ; the second movement is a
            dead march ; the third, the. return from the funeral, and the fourth, a
            sort of musical history of the times, being a collection of revolutionary
            airs, worked one into the other.
         </p>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page157"></div>
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>Of the performance of this great work, we can with justice say that
            it was executed with great precision; each point was taken up with
            perfect exactness, and grand effects were frequently produced ; but to
            us the performance appeared hard and mechanical. The conductor
            never deviated from the exact time at which he started—on, on, on!
            without pause, without breath—firm, unyielding, and untiring in its
            motion, his hand seemed a sort of human Metomone that was wound
            up to go, just so. Too strict attention to mere time, may produce correctness in performance, but something more is wanted to delineate
            faithfully the mind of the composer. We believe that Mr. Weigers
            will make an able conductor, but on this occasion he has attended less
            to the intellect than to the mechanism of the art.
         </p>
         
         <p>Madame Arnoult sang one of Donizetti’s mawkish arias, which coming directly after
            Beethoven, was as grateful to the ear as tepid water to the palate after a draught
            of
            Burgundy.
         </p>
         
         <p>We cannot refrain from asking of the Board of Government why such
            an incongruous mixture of style is allowed to appear at such a concert.
            We have asked this question repeatedly before, and have at various
            times received assurances that there would be a change for the better.
            We placed but little faith in such assurances, but even that little was
            thrown away ; for it seems that for the mere chance of catching a few
            dollars in extra tickets from some of the "upper ten thousand,” they
            would insert anything in their programme. After the comparative
            failure of Castellan, and the positive and unmistakeable failures of
            Valtellina and Signora Amalia Ricci, we did think that the " Government” would learn wisdom, and have done with the Donizettis, Marlianis, Riccis, and a host of other i’s. But experience is never considered of importance until it is bought dearly.
         </p>
         
         <p>Madame Arnoult executes most of her passages with exceeding delicacy and precision ; her voice, however, is weak and incapable of producing any great effect. Her style is so evidently that of an amateur,
            that we fear a long time must elapse before she can do herself credit
            before the public.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Instrumental Quintett was a truly admirable performance, in
            every way worthy of its intrinsic beauty. We have really no choice
            among those admirable artists, Messrs. Kyle, Weisse, Grœneveldt,
            Trosji and Reiff. We were kept in a continual round of admiration
            from its commencement to its close, and we can only say now, that so
            perfect an instrumental performance was never before heard in this
            country. The second part commenced with Sterndale Bennett’s descriptive
            overture of the Naiads. It is a remarkable composition in every respect. Its conception indicates a fancy at once brilliantly imaginative
            and highly refined, and the instrumentation displays an intimate knowledge and familiar acquaintance with the particular genius of the different instruments. Bennett was a pupil of Mendelssohn, and his compositions bear somewhat of the impress of that great master’s mind.
            We do not by any means assert that Stemdale Bennett is a coyist,
            but all his works have a tinge of the intellectual beauty which is the
            characteristic of the writings of Mendelssohn. In his instrumentation
            this similarity is singularly striking; he treats passages as Mendelssohn would have treated them; many of his combinations smack of
            bis great model, but his conception is his own, and one of more singular and attractive beauty we have rarely heard. Its reputation in Europe is second only to the Midsummer Night’s Dream and Fingal’s Cave.
            We were by no means pleased with the performance of this work, for
            it was exceedingly unequal. Some passages were given with great
            delicacy, while others were crowded and indistinct. Another rehearsal
            or two would have made both the conductor and the band more familiar with the intention of the composer, and also more at ease with
            each other.
         </p>
         
         <p>Madame Arnoult sang a portion of a scena from les Huguenots, by
            Meyerbeer, we regret to say very badly indeed. Not only was she
            continually out of tune to a painful degree, but she failed in several
            Passages, particularly two chromatic passages, which were very bad
            in taste, but still worse in execution. With every wish to be lenient
            to one who has so recently adopted the profession, we are yet compelled to speak the truth of all alike.
         </p>
         
         <p>The instrumental Dialogo for flute and clarionette, was played in
            most exquisite style by Messrs Kyle and Grœneveldt. Mr. Kyle played with more brilliancy, precision and feeling than upon any former
            “cession within our remembrance. He only requires emulation to render him always equal to that evening’s performance. He has certainly
            few rivals, and no superiors in this country, but he lacks somewhat of
            the true artistic enthusiasm which will lead one always to endeavor
            to excel himself. Mr. Grœneveldt’s solo was spoiled by the band, and
            he showed them their fault with an emphasis that must have astonished them, and which they are not likely toon to forget.
         </p>
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>The concluding overture by Ries, is a brilliant and effective composition, and had it not been so late would doubtless have been encored.
            It was admirably performed ; the wind instruments, as usual, distinguished themselves greatly.
         </p>
         
         <p>We consider Mr. Weiger’s debut as a Philharmonic conductor highly
            successful. It is true that we cannot award all praise, but what we do
            say we say most cordially, and with infinite satisfaction we congratulate him upon his highly creditable wielding of the baton.
         </p>
         
         <p>The next concert will take place on the 15th of April.</p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         
         <div class="head">MUSICAL REVIEW.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            
            <p>From A. Fiot, 196 Chesnut St., Philadelphia, and W. Dubois 315
               Broadway, New York.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Twelve Nouvelles Vocalisées, pour Mezzo-Soprano, dediées á
               S. A. R. Madame La Duchesse de Nemours, par Marco Bordogni.”_____
               In two books.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Abd-El-Kader Quick Step,” for the piano forte, composed bv J
               C. Viereck.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The Reproach” (Il Rimprovero), duettino, words translated from
               Metastasio, by B. S. Barclay. The music by F. Flovino.
               “Le Tremolo, sur un Theme de Bethoven, pour le Piano Forte,
               composée par Henri Herz.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Marco Bordogni has for many years been considered universally
               one of the finest singing masters in the world. He numbers among his
               pupils many of the most distinguished artists of the French capital.
               His consummate skill has gained for him the professorship of singing
               at the Paris Conservatoire, and also the honorable distinction of Chevalier de I’Ordre Royal de la Legion d’Honneur. Every work from his
               pen must be looked upon as a vocal standard and as a gift of price for
               futurity. The one before us is intended for the use of those who possess a mezzo soprano quality of voice. On looking through the books
               it will be perceived that a very extensive range is given to this voice
               a scale of two octaves and a note, from A below to B above. Many
               of our so-called soprano voices do not possess such a compass. The
               exercises are not for beginners ; they are intended to follow, after
               the usual routine of preliminary practice has been gone through. They
               are initiated to form the style, to render the ear firm under the most
               rapid and delicate changes of key; to impart emphasis and expression .
               to perfect the use of the shake, the sforzaudo, the vibrato; to cultivate
               the portamento, but to denude it of its abuses by imparting to it dig
               nity, emphasis and passion.
            </p>
            
            <p>The twelve exercises display several styles, of which we shall discourse in order. No. 1 is a very beautiful larghetto movement in C.»
               semibreve time. The passages are mostly to be sung legato, with
               many parts of marked emphasis. The key changes to its dominant
               and to E flat. The latter change is direct, and requires much steadiness
               of ear, particularly as it returns to the original key. No. 2 is a some
               what pastoral movement in A flat, twelve-eight time. The second part
               of this is in D flat changing to F minor and ending in E flat, from which
               it returns to the original. This is a fine exercise both for the ear and
               for the time. No. 3 is a larghetto movement in B minor, six-eight
               time. This is also calculated to give great delicacy to the ear, for the
               harmonies are always changing. The intervals are often great, and
               always difficult, requiring the utmost precision to render them justly
               No. 4 is an elegant andante in A flat two-four time, changing to an allegro, followed by allegro A tempmeno. This is a very difficult, brilliant, and instructive exercise, partaking of every quality of the grand
               scena excepting the recitation. No. 5 is an allegro spiritoso in G, semibreve time. The movement is almost entirely in triplets, and the concluding cadence is one of great difficulty, requiring the finest ear and
               most delicate intonation to execute it, being a triplet passage in semitones, for an octave and a half. No. 6 is an allegro moderato in G
               common time, of a bold character, containing many passages of difficulty ; tied notes, syncopations, extended intervals, &amp;c., &amp;c.
               Such is
               a description of the first book; and we are sure that the pupil who shall
               have the perseverance to achieve its contents, will be marvellously
               improved in intonation, execution and style, and other difficulties
               which occur in music.
            </p>
            
            <p>Abd-el-Kader Quick Step in B flat two-four time. The first movement
               is brisk and martial, but like ten thousand other marches. In the first
               bar of the fifth line, the second note in the bass should be E natural.
               The trio is in E flat, and quite devoid of originality, but still the piece
               is an inoffensive composition, and likely from its facility of execution,
               to meet with a ready sale. It has a clever vignette title-page, representing the beau ideal of an Arab chief.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Reproach.—Duettino. In F minor, common time. It is an agitato movement, full of passionate energy, and breathing the heart’s
               despair in every phrase. The syncophated passage at ‘‘My Heart beats
               not for thee," is very effective, and the introduction to its relative major, is exceedingly happy. The subject is afterwards repeated in F
               major, and is carried on to the end in perfect unity of design. It is a
               
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page158"></div>
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>very clever composition, and although the accompaniment is here and
               there somewhat heavy and labored, it is as a whole a very musicianlike work, and one which we can very cordially recommend to the
               public.
            </p>
            
            <p>There are a few corrections necessary in a revised edition. The
               seventh note, in fourth bar, third line of accompaniment, should be E
               flat; third bar, third line, in page four, the D in the right hand should
               be E flat. The word or is omitted from the second voice part, bar oue,
               third line, page five. In the first bar of the last symphony the B in
               the right hand should be C.
            </p>
            
            <p>Le Tremolo.—This is one of Herz’s recent pianoforte pieces, and abounds with the
               composer’s peculiarities.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            
            <p>Bertini’s Great Method tor the Piano-Forte.—Every teacher of every grade in the profession, has felt for years the want of a
               Piano-Forte instruction bonk, which should contain in its single compass matter sufficient for many months' consideration and practice;—
               beginning at the beginning, and leading the pupil on by easy stages
               pretty far into the mystery—preserving at the same time a strict and
               pure school. This end has been obtained by Bertini, as far as we can
               judge, from a somewhat hasty glance at its contents. Next week we
               shall present our readers with a review of the whole work as published
               by E. H. Wade and W.H. Oakes, 197 Washington street, Boston.
               Meanwhile let the author speak for himself.
            </p>
            
            <p>“My intention in publishing this new method, has been to facilitate
               the study of the Piano-Forte; snd I have tried as much as is in my
               power to furnish a progressive work, in which the young pianists
               might, asssisted by the experience of their master, find all the elements
               of instruction. 
            </p>
            
            <p>“A great number of elementary works—many of them written, too,
               by men of talent and very good sense in some respects—have the disadvantage that they are rather a collection of popular airs, than a series of lessons connected and graduated so as to develope the musical
               knowledge and mechanism of beginners. I wanted to avoid this fault,
               and have, therefore, written especially for this work a scries of melodies and exercises, instead of resorting to popular melodies, romances,
               waltzes, &amp;c., &amp;c., which are commonly annexed to instruction books.
            </p>
            
            <p>“It has hitherto but loo often been forgotten, that an instruction
               book is intended for a grammar, and not merely for a book of amusement ; and hence the false system which made elementary works consist entirely of little airs which the memory can easily retain. This
               custom perverts the taste of the pupil; it prevents their mind and ear
               from making themselves familiar with the different harmonic combinations, and it fills their heads with musical trivialities, which more
               and more drawing them away from the works of true art, ultimately
               incapacitate them from understanding the works of great masters.
            </p>
            
            <p>“It is very important to have the first studies of children directed
               by a skilful master; for, on the principles imbibed in the first lessons
               always depends the future success of an artist;—faults then acquired
               and confirmed by long practice, will never be lost.
            </p>
            
            <p>“I would therefore make it the duty of parents, and those who have
               the charge of pupils, to act, in this respect, with circumspection, and
               to consult artists before concluding about the choice of a teacher.
            </p>
            
            <p>“I hope I have succeeded in composing a solid work, which will
               force the pupil to exert himself, and familiarise him with all the difficulties of tonalite, lingering and rhythm.
            </p>
            
            <p>“I have graduated all my lessons from the natural key up to those
               most charged with chromatic signs. I have often observed,in pupils
               who had already obtained a certain proficiency, a difficulty in reading
               music with accidentals; and I doubt not this want of readiness is to
               be ascribed to the timidity and excessive reserve of the old instruction
               books.
            </p>
            
            <p>“My course of piano-forte instruction, if followed from the beginning to the end, will offer one advantage, which I hope will be appreciated. It furnishes elements of study for more than a year, without
               making it necessary to have recourse to a multitude of little pieces,
               almost all of them carelessly written and badly fingered.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            
            <p>To Accordion Players.—We call the attention of professional and
               amateur performers on this instrument, to the admirable improvements made upon it by Mr. Dumsday, Professor of Music, 55 Christie
               street. This instrument has hitherto been considered very imperfect
               from the want of the harmonies necessary to enable the performer to
               modulate into various keys—even the simplest melody could only be
               accompanied by the tonic and the dominant. Hut Mr. Dumsday’s invention, by applying keys to the bottom of the instrument, entirely
               remedies this delect and supplies chords sufficient for every ordinary
               purpose. Mr. Dumsday can apply this addition to any accordion
               which has the chronometer scale at a reasonable rate. The importance of this invention will be at once appreciated by every one acquainted with the instrument, and we cordially recommend all who
               are learning it, or wish to learn it, to call on Mr. Dumsday, who will
               give practical evidence of the superior advantages of this invention
               over all others now in use.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         
         <div class="head">MUSICAL ITEMS.</div>
         
         <p>New Orleans.—Mesdames Borghose and Ricci, with Signori Perozzi, Tomasi, and Condi, have, contrary to the reports recently in circulation here, succeeded in securing the American Theatre in
            New Orleans, and were expected to open on the 3d of March.
         </p>
         
         <p>Ole Bul is drawing crowded houses there also. About the magni- tude of his success
            accounts differ greatly.
         </p>
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <p>The Swiss Bell Ringers have surprised the people into an extensive
            enthusiasm. They are very highly spoken of.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Barton, the flutist, arrived here lately; he had a very narrow
            escape from shipwreck, and report says, that to his presence of mind
            and hearty assistance, the captain acknowledges the safe arrival of
            the vessel to be mainly attributed.
         </p>
         
         <p>THE MISSES SLOMAN attracted a large audience at the Philharmonic concert, Philadelphia, last week. These very talented
            young ladies will ere long reap a rich harvest, to which their talents
            and perseverance fully entitle them.
         </p>
         
         <p>HOME NEWS.—The Park Theatre will open on the 10th
            inst. As far as we can learn, the business will begin with Booth, and
            Anderson and the Seguins will follow in succession.
         </p>
         
         <p>Why does not Simpson start with a dash, by bringing out Antigone,
            the tragedy by Sophocles, with Mendelssohn’s music? It would create
            a great sensation.
         </p>
         
         <p>They talk of building an Opera-house up town !! We maintain that
            this is news, for many people will naturally believe that after so much
            talk, something is doing. But we inform them, that they talk.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. George Loder has been very sick, but is fast recovering.</p>
         
         <p>Mr. W. A. King has left Grace Church, and taken the organist’s situation at St. Peter’s Church, in Barclay street. This is a great loss
            to the one, and a great gain to the other.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss Watson is, we understand, to be the first Soprano in St. Pe-
            ter’s choir.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is rumored that Mr. Beams will succeed Mr. King at Grace Church.</p>
         
         <p>Mitchell will produce next week, a new burlesque upon a popular
            Opera. It will, we hear, be admirably produced.
         </p>
         
         <p>A correspondent requests us to offer ten cents reward to any body
            who will give any good public reason why Mr. Brough should nave a
            complimentary benefit? The gentleman has retired from the profession, and has become a merchant. “How then,” writes our correspondent, “do you account for Mr. Brongh, while denying his profession, receiving any paltry engagement which may offer here, besides
            flying round to all the small towns and giving small concerts. If Mr.
            Brough is a musician, let him acknowledge it, and not deny a profession which is an honor to any man who understands it; but if Mr. B.
            is not in the profession, let him cease from thrusting himself into engagements, to the injury of those who arc compelled to live upon their
            professional talents.” A friend at our elbow suggests that the complimentary concert is given as a public and private tribute to his good
            taste in retiring from the profession. If our correspondent is satisfied
            with the guess, we shall be glad to hand from him to our highly talented
            friend, those ten cents.
         </p>
         
         <p>We invite our readers to go this evening to the concert of the German Benevolent Society, at the Tabernacle, and are sure of redeeming
            our word in promising them a delightful treat. We seldom have seen
            a programme richer or happier in its choice. Beethoven, Weber,
            Mendelssohn, by the orchestra of the Philharmonic Society, Pico,
            Grœnfeld, Scharfenberg, and several other eminent artists, will make
            the honors. But the most interesting feature, from its novelty and intrinsic merit, will undoubtedly be the Song-Union, composed of our
            principal German citizens, who have volunteered their services, owing
            to the charitable purposes of the concert. For the introduction of the
            German Manner Chor in America, we are indebted to Mr. Charles Perabeau, whose principal object in leaving an enviable position in Germany, was to attain this object, and we do not doubt in the least of the
            success of his undertaking, as he possesses in an eminent degree, both
            the qualities of the leader and of the professor.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">COM.</div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s6">
         
         <div class="head">CORRESPONDENCE.</div>
         
         <div id="#26">
            
            <div class="head">TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
            
            <p>My Dear Sir:
               The following case, in the opinion of many of your subscribers,
               loudly calls for some censor’s correcting rod.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is in this city a certain young gentleman, who has this winter,
               for the first lime, been introduced to society; or as Seneca would have
               it, “has left the society of boys to enjoy that of philosophers;" or as
               an anxious mamma would say of her bud of ‘ sweet sixteen,’ “just been
               brought out.” He is a young man of fine talents, of good appearance,
               of an easy, agreeable, and manly address, and is very learned for one
               no older; in short, he is a gentleman, and particularly distinguished
               for a straight-forward, independent manner of expressing hit opinions.
               He has been before the town only seven weeks, and yet no man’s
               society was ever more eagerly courted than his, from the half-starved
               author shivering in his fifth-story garret, to the rosy-nosed publisher,
               who, by “turning to commodify” the brains of these same starving
               authors, is enabled to enjoy a luxuriously furnished mansion, and
               “fare sumptuously every day.”
            </p>
            
            <p>But with all my friend’s good and shilling qualities, he has one bad
               failing, that I fear will cause him to fall in the estimation of very
               many of his best friends ;—by friends I do not mean associates who
               eat his meat and drink his wine, but those, who admiring his many
               good qualities, wish well of him, and ever speak well of him behind his back. His failing is this:--he has become so indoctrinated
               with opposition to Texas, that whenever he hears the most distant
               allusion to the subject, or any thing else that by association of ideas,
               brings it to mind, he seizes the opportunity to let the company know
               that he is opposed to the measure. No matter what the company, or
               occasion, or place, if he but hear an allusion to Texas, he must, uncle
               Toby-like, mount his ever-saddled nag, and frisk away for the enter
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page159"></div>
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>tainment of his auditory, though all the laugh I ever saw him raise
               was at him. He takes vast delight in exhibiting this beast of his.
               although to my mind he is one of the most hideously deformed
               animals imaginable.
            </p>
            
            <p>Last Saturday when he made his seventh appearance in public,
               while conversing upon a subject having no connexion with annexation,
               he took occasion to beak on in the middle of a sentence, and abruptly
               tell the company, many of whom were his elders, and far his superiors
               in information and talents, and withal many of them warm friends of
               the measure," that the people declare themselves opposed to the measure,’’ and that “he discerns a glimpse of morning breaking out from
               the darkness,” for the joint resolution will not pass both houses.” A
               few minutes afterwards, when the company were considering the
               literary merits of a young man, who had at some former time said
               something in favor of Texas, he volunteered to tell us—though we
               were not discussing the merits or demerits of annexation, but, as said
               before, speaking of a young man who had sometime, to somebody,
               said something in its favor—“that the measure savored as little of
               justice as any that could be proposed.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Now, Mr. Editor, I do not find fault with his opinions, nor for expressing them at proper times and places; but would it not look better
               of him to let off his extra steam in a political meeting, and give vent
               to his spleen through the columns of some political journal? I pray
               you, my dear sir, to ask him, when he attends a literary meeting, or
               philosophical disquisition, or convivial party, or any mixed company,
               to have sufficient common civility to keep his politics at home. Many
               who are exceedingly fond of his company will feel themselves compelled to forego that pleasure if he always carries in his pocket, and
               at every opportunity offensively thrusts under their noses, a phial of
               this unsavory partizan stuff. I pray you, Mr. Editor, take your pen
               from behind your ear, and shake it at this friend of mine, ana thereby
               perhaps make others flutter who are in a similar predicament.
            </p>
            
            Horace.
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p27">
         
         <p>Mr. Webster and his Friends.—There have been a variety of statements in the newspapers the past month or two, respecting
            a magnificent donation said to have been made to Daniel Webster, to
            induce him to return to the Senate. The facts are ; that certain gentlemen, feeling that the welfare of the country demanded his presence in the Senate, and knowing that his private affairs were not in
            a condition which would admit of his return to public life, without making a greater sacrifice than his duty to his family would permit, opened a subscription, among a very limited number of course, with the
            object of raising a hundred thousand dollars, to be invested for his
            benefit. About sixty thousand dollars were subscribed in Boston, and
            the remainder in New York. This has been, or will be invested so as
            to produce seven per cent. The income to be given to Mr. Webster
            during his life, and continued to Mrs. Webster during hers, after which
            the principal is to revert to the original donors, or their heirs.
            We believe this to be a tribute to genius, without a parallel, in the
            history of our own or any other country. It matters not what the object of the donors may be. As an acknowledgment of the greatness
            of the recipient, it is alike unequivocal and honorable to him, whether
            their motives be mercenary or patriotic. For our own part, we think
            that the transaction reflects the highest honor on all parties concerned,
            and we wish we had more such men, who could command such friends
            we should not care a straw what principles they professed.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p28">
         
         <p>In a late lecture on the "Poets and Poetry of America,” delivered
            before an audience made up chiefly of editors and their connexions, I
            took occasion to speak what I know to be the truth, and I endeavoured so to speak it that there should be no chance of misunderstanding
            what it was I intended to say. I told these gentlemen to their
            teeth that, with a very few noble exceptions, they had been engaged
            for many years in a system of indiscriminate laudation of American
            books—a system which, more than any other one thing in the
            world, had tended to the depression of that American Literature”
            whose elevation it was designed to effect. I said this, and very much
            more of a similar tendency, with as thorough a distinctness as I could
            command. Could I, at the moment, have invented any terms more
            explicit, wherewith to express my contempt of our general editorial
            course of corruption and puffery, I should have employed them beyond
            the shadow of a doubt;—aud should I think of anything more expressive hereafter, I will endeavour either to find or to make an opportunity
            for its introduction to the public.
         </p>
         
         <p>And what, for all this, had I to anticipate? In a very few cases, the
            open, and, in several, the silent approval of the more chivalrous portion of the press ;—but in a majority of instances, I should have been
            weak indeed to look for anything but abuse. To the Willises—the
            O’Sullivans—the Duyckincks—to the choice and magnanimous few
            who spoke promptly in my praise, and who have since taken my hand
            with a more cordial and more impressive grasp than ever—to these I
            return, of course, my acknowledgements, for that they have rendered
            me my due. To my villifiers I return also such thanks as they deserve, inasmuch as without what they have done me the honor to say,
            there would have been much of point wanting in the compliments of
            my friends. Had I, indeed, from the former, received any less equivocal tokens of disapprobation, I should at this moment have been looking about me to discover what sad blunder I had committed.
         </p>
         
         <p>I am most sincere in what I say. I thank these, my opponents, for
            their good will,—manifested, of course, after their own fashion. No
            doubt they mean me well—if they could only he brought to believe it;
            and I shall expect more reasonable things from them hereafter. In the
            mean time, I await patiently the period when they shall have fairly
            made an end of what they have to say—when they shall have sufficiently exalted themselves in their own opinion—and when, especially, they
            shall have brought me over to that precise view of the question which
            it is their endeavor to have me adopt.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">E. A. P.</div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s7">
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">STODDART &amp; DUNHAM,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">
               
               <br></br>PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURERS,
               
               <br></br>361 BROADWAY.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,
               PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">
               <br></br>88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.
               
               <br></br>A large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
               
               <br></br>TERMS MODERATE.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, late Practical partner of
               the old established firm of 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the larest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most
               superior
               quality ; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone.
               Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano
               Fortes a ways on hire.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">SINGING AT SIGHT.</div>
            
            <p>
               MR. WARNER, translator of Webers theoretical
               work, &amp;c., continues his course of Vocal Instruction at his rooms, 411
               Broad-Way. Mr. Warner’s new Illustrating Apparatus will also furnish
               very great facilities for a ready and full understanding of the subject preparatory to the study of Instrumental Music.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
               work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method
               the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and
               studies, are
               given in such progressive order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
               carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
               otherwise, are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
               haa arrived when a superficial know ledge of the Piano is of but little account,
               and it is only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will been
               abled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ; the rudments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each
               lesson
               is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest reccommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of Bertini’s
               Method
               over all others yet published in this country, most of them having used the
               foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
               names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Boston.
               
               <br></br>Messrs. G. J. Webb.
               
               <br></br>J. G Maedar.
               
               <br></br>H. T. Hach.
               
               <br></br>E. L. White.
               
               <br></br>David Paine.
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek.
               
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.
               
               <br></br>New York.
               
               <br></br>Messrs. H. C. Timm.
               
               <br></br>W. Alpers.
               
               <br></br>U. C. Hill.
               
               <br></br>F. H. Brown.
               
               <br></br>Philadelphia.
               
               <br></br>B. C. Cross.
               
               <br></br>Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
               American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">WORKS ON THE FINE ARTS</div>
            
            <div class="ab">
               
               <br></br>RECENTLY IMPORTED.
               
               <br></br>LECTURES ON PAINTING AND DESIGN, by
               
               <br></br>B. R. Haydon. 1 vol. 8vo. with Engravings - - - - $4 00
               
               <br></br>TREATISE ON PAINTING, written by Cennino Cenini in
               
               <br></br>1487. Translated, with Notes, &amp;c. 1 vol. 8vo. with fine Engra-
               
               <br></br>vings - - - - - - - - - - - - 4 50
               
               <br></br>ACKERMANN’S MANUAL OF COLOURS, used in Water-
               
               <br></br>Colour Painting. 1 neat volume - - - - - - - 088
               
               <br></br>THE ANATOMY AND PHILOSOPHY OF EXPRESSION
               
               <br></br>as connected with the Fine Arts. By Sir Charles Bell. Third edi-
               
               <br></br>tion, enlarged - - - - - - - - - - - 6 00
               
               <br></br>A MANUAL OF FRESCO AND ENCAUSTIC PAINTING
               
               <br></br>By W. B. S. Taylor. 1 vol. - - - - - - - - 2 50
               
               <br></br>LECTURES ON SCULPTURE. By John Flaxman. 1 vol
               
               <br></br>8vo. with 52 Engravings - - - - - - - - - 5 50
               
               <br></br>TRAITE COMPLET DE LA PEINTURE. Par M. de
               
               <br></br>Montalbert. Nine large volumes 8vo., with a 4to. volume of En-
               
               <br></br>gravings - - - - - - - - - - - - 28 0
            </div>
            
            <p>
               Imported and for sale by
               WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">JOHN DOUGLAS,
               BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            </div>
            
            <p>No. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every description of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
               with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, ou terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">January 16, 1845.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page160"></div>
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">OLIVER DITSON,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">
               
               <br></br>Dealer in all kinds of
               
               <br></br>SHEET MUSIC, MUSIC BOOKS,
               
               <br></br>and Second-hand Piano-Fortes.
               
               <br></br>NO. 115 WASHINGTON STREET, BOSTON.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">FAMILY GROUPS</div>
            
            <p>TAKEN by Mons. EDOUART in an unique style peculiarly his own, which has been patronized by the Crowned heads of Europe and the most distinguished families of America. Mons. E. begs to observe that his likenesses are true to nature, and that the manner he
               disposes
               of the figures constituting his Family Group has always elicited the highest
               commendation from eminent artists of both hemispheres. The large number of groups in his possession (which are for sale,) evince his natural
               talent.
            </p>
            
            <p>A collection of 150,000 likenesses with autographs api ended, preserved in
               books and large groupings of distinguished characters, are testimonials of his
               unrivalled skill. Those who wish to leave mementos to posterity should not
               lose the present opportunity. A call at his exhibition room (free) will satisfy
               all that these works are entirely unique and capable of resisting the destructive influences of time.—His Fireside Groups, representing the members
               of
               families united, which union must be of short duration, separations occuring by marriage, change of location and demise, can be faithfully
               preserved
               in the works of Mons. Edouart, thus affording mementos to those remaining,
               of time past, and to posterity, of ancestors long since departed.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mons. E. leaves for Europe in a short time. An early visit from patrons
               at No. 285 Broadway, near Granite Buildings, is solicited and will receive
               mmediate attention, or attendance at the family residence if required.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DISBROW’S RIDING SCHOOL,</div>
            
            <p>NO. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette
               Place, New York.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Evening, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS:
               
               <br></br>Lecture Lessons.
               
               <br></br>16 Lessons - - - - - - - - - - - - $15 00
               
               <br></br>10 " - - - - - - - - - - - - 10 00
               
               <br></br>4 " - - - - - - - - - - - - 5 00
               
               <br></br>Single Lessons - - - - - - - - - - 2 00
               
               <br></br>Road “ - - - - - - - - - - 2 50
               
               <br></br>Exercise Riding.
               
               <br></br>1 Month - - - - - - - - - - - - $12 00
               
               <br></br>20 Rides - - - - - - - - - - - - 10 00
               
               <br></br>10 " - - - - - - - - - - - - 6 00
               
               <br></br>Single Rides - - - - - - - - - - 0.75
               
               <br></br>N. B.—Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let.
               
               <br></br>Evening Class.
               
               <br></br>12 Lessons - - - - - - - - - - - - $9 00
               
               <br></br>Single “ - - - - - - - - - - - - 1 00
               
               <br></br>20 Rides - - - - - - - - - - - - $10 00
               
               <br></br>Single Ride - - - - - - - - - - - - 0 75
               
               <br></br>RULES :
               
               <br></br>1. All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.
               
               <br></br>2. One hour allowed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.
               
               <br></br>3. One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.
               
               <br></br>4. Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 3 P. M.
               
               <br></br>5. Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.
               
               <br></br>6. No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladies.
            </div>
            
            <p>A card of address is requested previous to commencing.</p>
            
            <p>N. B. Gentlemen keeping their horses at this establishment, will have the
               privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">M. DUMSDAY’S IMPROVED ACCORDEON.</div>
            
            <div class="figure">
               
               <div class="head">ADDITIONAL MODULATIONS</div>
               
            </div>
            
            <p>THE ACCOMPANIMENT OF ALL ACCORDEons heretofore has been confined to one key, in music. By applying the
               above improvement, (on the bottom of the instrument,) we are enabled to
               play accompaniments in various major and minor keys. The above improvement added to any Accordeon, having the large and small keys, on
               reasonable terms. Mr. D., professor of music, continues to teach ladies and
               gentlemen of New York, at their residences, the following instruments, in a
               scientific and modern style, in a very abort time, by his new system of teaching : Guitar and Singing, Accordeon, Violin, Trombone and Cornopean.
               Terms moderate. Satisfactory city and other references given, on application at No. 55 Chrystie st, above Walker.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
               The first Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for the
               best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons o( one hour each. Terms Reduced to TWO DOLLARS
               AND A HALF.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen
               and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale “Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27. 1844.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith’s Gems or Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
               much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
               Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
               volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
               of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">From the New York Express.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship.—We have seen the original, as
               executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
               wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
               to be “more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by th e most thoughtless.
               The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
               professional 9kiU, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo.
               
               <br></br>Joshua Herrick, Me.
               
               <br></br>ames Irvin, Pa.
               
               <br></br>Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
               
               <br></br>John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               
               <br></br>J. Thompson, Miss.
            </div>
            
            <p>Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.</p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY</div>
            
            <p>AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
               Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
               the Medal, four first Premiums, and two “Highest Honors,” at the
               Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
               the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
            </p>
            
            <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
               at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
               the score of economy.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American In
               struments of the very beat quality, with plates, cases, chemical polish
               ing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders receive
               promptly attended to.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p29">
         
         <div class="head">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">To be Published every Saturday.</div>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely ot
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
            to make it worthy of patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers in the country i but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may “let loose their
            thoughts,” will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate.
            It will be printed on tine paper with clear type, in the Octavo form of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum—Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.</p>
         
         <p>A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.</p>
         
         <p>All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor
            or the Broadway Journal, and all lettera on business to
            JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.</div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      <a href="#a001"> Link </a>
      <div class="note" id="n001">"I would be a Parody, written by a ninny,
         Not worth a penny, and sold for a guinea," &amp;c.
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>