<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450125</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1.     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JANUARY 25, 1845.     N  4.
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      
      
      <div class="cit">
         <span class="quote">
            <p>Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</p>
         </span>
         
         <div class="bibl">
            <span class="person">Locke</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p1">
            <div class="biblTitle">Hints on the Re-organization of the Navy</div>
            <div class="biblPage">49</div>
            <div class="ab">Hints on the Re-organization of the Navy. New York: Wiley
               
               <br></br>and Putnam.
            </div>
            
            <p>A subject of greater importance to the people of the United States, or one about which they appear to care less, than
               the re-organization of the Navy, could hardly be selected to
               form the topic of a pamphlet.
            </p>
            
            <p>"It is admitted very generally by those acquainted with the subject," says the writer before us, "that the Navy of the United States
               is defective in its organization; that the laws, rules, and regulations
               by which it is governed require remodelling, although complaints from
               the Navy may not have reached the public ear in tones sufficiently
               loud to attract attention. Grievances, nevertheless, exist."
            </p>
            
            <p>And from this promising paragraph we hoped to find
               something in the remainder of the "hints," which would
               expose the gross wrongs of our naval system, and suggest
               some means for their removal. But, the author, though
               evidently belonging to the service, seems not to be aware
               that there are any other wrongs in the Navy but such as the
               civil department of it suffer, from inadequate pay and the
               want of a definite rank. This has been the general complaint
               of all the officers in the service, ever since the last war; the
               service is going to kingdom come for the want of a higher
               grade of officers, say those who have reached the highest,
               while those still in the line of promotion complain of insufficient pay, and the slowness with which they go up.
            </p>
            
            <p>But it is not of the slightest consequence to the nation,
               whether an assistant surgeon in the Navy eats his meals in
               the cock-pit with the midshipmen, or in the ward-room with
               the lieutenants and purser; nor whether he receive twelve
               hundred and fifty or fifteen hundred dollars a year; yet, it is
               to reform such abuses as these that the author has published
               his "hints;" he had a right to do so, but he will get nothing
               but his labor for his pains.
            </p>
            
            <p>One of the complaints of the secretary of the Navy, in his
               report to Congress is, that "the Oregon had to proceed to sea
               recently with a citizen surgeon," which our author thinks a
               good reason for reform. There are a good many merchantships leaving our harbor every day, for distant ports, with no
               other surgical aid than such as the captain and his mates
               can render, with the assistance of a few exceedingly brief directions contained on the lid of his medicine chest; yet we
               believe that our merchant-ships lose as few men by disease
               as our national vessels.
            </p>
            
            <p>The only persons of whom our author seems to have any
               knowledge in the Navy, are those that wear epaulettes. He
               does not appear to know that there are such beings as sailors
               on board of our national ships. Not a word is said in their
               behalf, not a whisper breathed, that they have any wrongs
               to be redressed.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Instances can be cited of commanding officers so far forgetting
               their own dignity and what is due to others, as to profanely curse in
               loud tones on the quarter-deck surgeons and other civil officers of the
               Navy. Such instances are rare, it is true; but they have occurred,
               and may occur again."
            </p>
            
            <p>This is very curious. It would be hard to cite an instance
               of a commanding officer who had not so far forgot his own
               dignity as to curse in loud tones the sailors under his command; and we must confess to that degree of simplicity as
               not to perceive any very marked difference between a sailor
               and a surgeon, so far as usefulness on ship board and the dignity of humanity are concerned.
            </p>
            
            <p>The following particulars in regard to midshipmen are
               well worth the consideration of the people, not one in a hundred of whom know, probably what they have to contribute
               towards the education and support of the children and ne-phews of prominent politicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Midshipmen are admitted into the Navy between the ages of fourteen and sixteen. All the qualification required to obtain an appointment, is political influence, or the favor of those in power. By law or
               regulation no degree of primary education is requisite. It is usual,
               however, for those appointed to be more or less instructed in the simple elements, or at least the rudiments of a common English education.
               To remedy this deficiency in some measure, 'twenty-two' professors
               of mathematics are maintained in the Navy, at a salary of $1,200 a
               year each, or in other words, it costs the government $26,400 annually, to instruct 356 midshipmen in those elementary branches of mathematics deemed sufficient to enable them to read 
               <span class="person" id="nbowditch">Bowditch</span>'s system of
               navigation: in round numbers preceptors' fees amount to upwards of
               $74 annually for every midshipman in the Navy, a sum sufficient to
               pay the annual cost of a collegiate course. Besides professors of mathematics, the government provides three teachers of languages. In
               addition to all this, every midshipman receives in pay from $300 to
               $473 yearly, and has little or nothing to offer in return, except the
               promise or prospect of some day being capable of performing the duty
               of a lieutenant; or in other words, he is paid while receiving his professional education at the cost of the government."
            </p>
            
            <p>No sooner does a youngster of sixteen receive an appointment in the service, than his fortune is made; he is booked
               for the highest rank and the highest pay in the service,
               wholly irrespective of merit; by the time he reaches the age
               of forty-five he will receive a better salary than the vice president of the Union, and yet he need never fire a shot, or
               spend a quarter of his time on ship board. Although it is
               requisite that the sea-going officers of the service should enter it at an early age, that they may make themselves perfectly familiar with their duties; yet the chief director of
               the service; the one who holds sole control of the navy, and
               may do what he likes with the ships and officers in it, is
               generally a country attorney, who has never seen blue water,
               and who could not tell a cat-head from a bulk-head to save
               himself from perdition. That there should be errors and
               abuses in a service so governed is a matter of course.
            </p>
            
            <p>To gain employment in any of the civil departments of the
               government, some fitness for the office which you may fill is
               considered necessary; not so with the Navy. Our author
               says, very pertinently,--
            </p>
            
            <p>"Unfortunately for the country, owing to peculiar notions and usages, the highest qualifications are advanced no more rapidly than the
               most marked stolidity; advancement is regulated by the miller's rule. 
               'first come, first served,' as promotions to fill vacancies in the superior
               grades are made from the first on the list of the next grade below.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The career of a military seaman is a glorious career. He surely
               rises, though very slowly, in dignity and consideration, and last,
               though not least, his pecuniary reward increases from $300 to $4500
               annually, as he passes from the foot of the list of midshipmen to the
               head of the list of captains, which he does in from thirty-five to forty
               years."
            </p>
            
            <p>We have known some peculiar cases of unfitness in the service, where the officers went up side by side with the best
               fellows in it. We happened once to witness an instance
               where the commander of one of our national vessels would not
               allow one of his lieutenants to have charge of a vessel in the
               night time, because he was afraid to trust the ship in his
               keeping. Yet this incompetent officer will, in a few years, be
               himself a commander. Such gross favoritism cannot be
               shown in the British service.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Before, an officer obtains a lieutenant's commission in Her Majesty's Navy, he must have passed five examinations; but in the Navy of
               the United States, he is required to pass but one; to prepare for
               which, six months' study is usually enough to ensure success.''
            </p>
            
            <p>"Which method," our author pointedly asks, "is likely to
               produce the most efficient lieutenants, the British or the
               American?" and, "supposing the two systems to be followed
               out as they now exist in the two nations, is it not probable
               that the officers of the British Navy, as a body, will be superior, in professional attainments, to those of the Navy of the
               United States?''
            </p>
            
            <p>There are two important questions to be asked in regard
               to the Navy, and no aims at reform in this department of
               national expenditure can amount to any good, unless they be
               considered. First, is there any necessity for a Navy at all,
               when there is neither a war, nor a prospect of one; and secondly, if a Navy is necessary, why should the citizens of the
               country, who enter the lowest ranks of the service, be debarred from rising in it, by good conduct, bravery, and genius?
            </p>
            
            <p>There are few people, who never been on board of our
               national ships, that have any idea of the degraded condition
               of the seamen that serve in them. For the three years that
               they enlist, they are as much cut off from the privileges of
               freemen, as though they had never stepped foot on American
               soil. Their commander may flog them on their naked backs,
               as often as he may be in humor to do so, which is sometimes
               of very frequent recurrence; and if they should look sour under
               their punishment, they will be in danger of suspension, not
               from duty, but from the yard-arm. The law limits the cruelty
               of a commander to twelve lashes with a cat on the bare back
               of a sailor, for any one offence; but an angry man, with unlimited authority, pays but little regard to law; and we have
               known an officer to inflict three dozen lashes on the back of
               one of his men, under the pretence that he had committed
               three offences. But abuses like these do not appear to have
               come under the notice of the author of this book, for among
               all his hints for re-organizing the Navy, he hints nothing
               about bettering the condition of the right arm of the service,
               or putting the citizens of the union who serve as seamen on
               board of our national ships, on a level with those who enter
               it with a warrant in their pocket.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p2">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Natural Boundaries of the Empires</div>
            <div class="biblPage">50</div>
            <div class="ab">The Natural Boundaries or Empires, and a New View of Colo-
               
               <br></br>nization. By 
               <span class="person" id="jfinch">John Finch</span>, Esq., Corresponding Member of the
               
               <br></br>Literary and Historical Society of Quebec, and of the Natural His-
               
               <br></br>tory Societies of Montreal, New York, New Brunswick, Delaware,
               
               <br></br>etc. London: Longmans, 1844. Imported by Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            </div>
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="ssmith">Sydney Smith</span>, or somebody else, said once that the present was an age of persiflage. We can hardly open a book
               on any subject, which does not contain a dash of satire. The
               gravest lessons are now taught in a vein of humor, and all
               our philosophers are professed jokers. There seems to be
               nothing serious but fun, and nothing funny which is not
               serious. The favorite jest book of the day is the Comic
               Blackstone; and the legitimate successors of 
               <span class="person" id="jaddison">Addison</span> and
               
               <span class="person" id="sjohnson">Johnson</span>, are the contributors to Punch. Upon our own side
               of the water, we have, as yet, no didactic humorists; our
               sermons contain as little humor as they well can; and our
               humorous writers would run little danger of being mistaken
               for preachers. Our jokes are nothing but jokes, and none of
               our political writers have yet aimed at enlightening the people, or enlivening their essays, by witticisms in disguise. We
               certainly had no expectation of meeting anything punchy in
               a philosophical essay on the natural boundaries of empires;
               but the corresponding member of the Natural History Societies of Montreal, New York, New Brunswick, etc., is not
               free from the contagion of the age. There is irony in every
               page of his book; it reads like the papers in Punch, or the
               preface to Martin Chuzzlewit; but it contains more of the
               philosophy of history than we ever before saw compressed
               into so small a space. The author must be an old man, for
               he was a correspondent of Madison's, and he appears to have
               distilled this volume from the studies of a life-time. His
               knowledge of American affairs is very exact and minute, and
               his national prejudices are nothing. He seems to have entirely forgotten the place where he was born, for he shows no
               partiality for any particular part of the globe; and though an
               Englishman, he makes no boast of British glory. He mentions the fact, incidentally, that there are three millions of
               slaves in the United States, but he has no more prejudices
               against the south than Mr. Calhoun, or father Ritchie. His
               book is of great value to America, now, when we are striving
               to change the boundaries of the empire, and we hope that
               some of our publishers will undertake its republication. A
               copy of it should be placed in the hands of every member of
               Congress, and a large one, like a pulpit bible, should be nailed
               to the desk of the Secretary of State, from which he should
               be required to read a chapter every morning.
            </p>
            
            <p>Much of the book is of that scrappy, anecdotical character, which so well suits the taste of a people, whose favorite
               reading is found in magazines.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Many persons," says Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jfinch">Finch</span>, "imagine that walnuts were
               created, because the nut is good to eat, but they are quite mistaken;
               they hang in profusion from the trees because they exhibit the true
               model for the hull of a ship. If you examine attentively the shell of
               a walnut, you perceive that one extremity is sharp, exhibiting all the
               qualities of a beautiful prow, while the other end expands with all the
               dignity and proportions of a Dutch galliot."
            </p>
            
            <p>He is a profound lover of the ocean, like most of his countrymen, whom we never suspected of so strong an attachment
               as he makes them have.
            </p>
            
            <p>"An Englishman who resides in the interior of the country, and is
               not able to visit the ocean or the sea once a year, always expires of
               ennui, although the learned physicians who attend him give the disease a different name."
            </p>
            
            <p>Unlike the majority of British writers, he draws as many
               of his illustrations from the United States, as from the states
               of Europe.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The most philosophical treaty of peace in relation to boundaries
               ever recorded in history, was that between the States of North Carolina and Tennessee. Their boundary being undetermined, they agreed
               that the highest ridge of the Appalachian chain should form the
               boundary line. Commissioners were appointed to take the altitude of
               the several ranges, and the highest being ascertained, both parties
               acquiesced in the result. In other parts of the world, rather than
               have made such a treaty, they would have covered every hill with
               wounded, and they would have filled every valley with slain."
            </p>
            
            <p>Here is a prophecy which cannot be very far from being
               fulfilled. Massachusetts and South Carolina are doing what
               they can to bring it about.
            </p>
            
            <p>"America is arranged almost in natural divisions. It is probable
               that, at some future day, the New England States, throwing off the
               weight of the federal yoke, may once more become free. Thus, on
               the surface of the earth, man finds it impossible to change the decree
               of that Almighty Power, whose will governs the Universe."
            </p>
            
            <p>When Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jfinch">Finch</span> composed his book, we had not raised
               the cry of Polk, Dallas and Texas.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Make room there! make room! come, arrange yourselves in the
               boxes, and take your seats in the pit, and those who cannot find room
               elsewhere, may go into the gallery, and we will see the spectacle
               which the world now exhibits. There are going to pass before us on
               the stage, in triumphal procession, the various conquering nations,
               with their banners displayed, and bearing the insignia of war, and
               with their unhappy captives at their feet. See! the lamps afford a
               brilliant light, the curtain is about to rise. Keep silent, and do not
               speak a word.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Who comes there? see, in the van of conquering nations, comes
               Great Britain, a free representative monarchy, her swords are red
               with blood, her bayonets are bent and twisted in the struggle, her cannon are hot with firing repeated charges of balls. Ten empires, which
               once had independent sovereigns, are crushed beneath her chariot
               wheels; seven republics, anxious to pursue their glorious career of
               enterprise and fame, are chained beneath her feet. She has conquered
               and retains in subjection one hundred millions of people! Pass on.
            </p>
            
            <p>"What see we next? Ah! here is a nation who profess themselves
               republicans, and who believe that if all the liberty which the nations
               of the earth ever possessed was collected and placed in a single pile,
               it would form an insignificant heap in comparison with that which they
               enjoy. These are the United States of America, who call themselves
               the freest of the free. And what are they about? Keep silent. They
               have room in their present territory for two hundred millions of people, but that is not sufficient; and they are fitting out an expedition to
               take possession of Oregon, and are exterminating the unfortunate
               Seminoles because they will not part with the hunting grounds of their
               fathers. Pass on!"
            </p>
            
            <p>His acquaintance with our political affairs is as intimate as
               of our geographical boundaries.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The boundaries of the United States present many phenomena
               that are worthy of being attentively studied. In examining these,
               we must remember that the people have yielded to a central government the distinctive mark, the most important prerogative of sovereign
               power, the right of making peace and declaring war. The frontiers
               of the several states must therefore, under the present form of government, be judged rather as divisional lines of one territory, than as
               rival jealous nations, ready to war with each other on the slightest
               pretexts. It may however be observed, that in most important questions brought before Congress, although every member enjoys and exercises the privilege of speech, only three members are allowed to vote.
               These are representatives of the South, the East, the West. All the
               artificial divisions of territory disappear before the powerful influence
               of natural boundaries."
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jfinch">Finch</span> proposes to erect Long Island into an independent state, and we like his proposition exceedingly. The east
               end of Long Island reaches out towards Connecticut, and
               seems to be striving for a closer neighborhood with New
               England. It is quite impossible that the people of Sag Harbor and Sackett's Harbor should ever think alike in regard to
               politics. They may both vote for the same men, as they
               often do, but they must differ when they come to conclusions.
               We do not know how the project of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jfinch">Finch</span> will suit our
               neighbors, but if they should adopt it, we should be very
               likely to make one amongst them.
            </p>
            
            <p>"We have in a former page, proposed that the island of Nassau,
               contiguous to New York, should form an independent State. It is
               larger in extent than Rhode Island, and nearly as populous as Delaware. A friend here whispered in my ear,  What trouble you are
               going to cause to these unfortunate people. If they are to be free,
               they will require a constitution, and will want a governor. Then only
               consider the caucuses, the political meetings of young and old men,
               the votes, the resolutions, the remonstrances, and counter-resolutions,
               and the opposite meetings of federalists and democrats, and national
               republicans of the old and new school.' Struck with his remark, I
               replied,  I will give them a constitution, and I will be their governor.'
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">CONSTITUTION OF THE ISLAND OF NASSAU.</div>
            
            <p>Any person who expressed a wish to subdue or to purchase any
               neighboring territory, or to found a colony and keep it in subjection,
               should be esteemed an enemy to his countrymen, for he would add to
               their taxes, and take away from their happiness.
            </p>
            
            <p>The community should be entirely agricultural.</p>
            
            <p>He who sowed most wheat, or Indian corn, should be esteemed a
               friend to his country.
            </p>
            
            <p>He who planted a peach orchard should be a senator for life.</p>
            
            <p>He who shot the fattest buck should be captain in his district for a
               year.
            </p>
            
            <p>He who produced the most wine might have the pleasure of sending
               a cask to each of his neighbors.
            </p>
            
            <p>He who caught the largest quantity of fish should have the privilege
               of keeping open-house until all were consumed.
            </p>
            
            <p>He who raised the fattest ox should be at liberty to keep him in
               a beautiful paddock, and to walk round him once a day as long as he
               lived.
            </p>
            
            <p>No lawyers would be necessary, for there would never be any disputes.</p>
            
            <p>No physicians would be requisite, for the human race, exempt from
               care, would be free from disease.
            </p>
            
            <p>There would be no robbers, for no man would attempt to steal a
               barn, or to run away with a cow.
            </p>
            
            <p>All would be good, and therefore all would be happy.</p>
            
            <p>The only misfortune that could possibly happen to these people
               would be when the sun did not ripen the peaches.
            </p>
            
            <p>No penitentiaries should be built, for if they built one, they must
               build two; they must finally cover the whole face of the island with
               penitentiaries, and the foul sight of those receptacles of crime would
               disfigure the fair face of nature. Instead of the care and the money of
               the State being lavished on criminals, it should be bestowed in quite a
               different direction--in the education of the innocent and poor.
            </p>
            
            <p>And then with their seas full of fish, their woods full of game, their
               orchards full of peaches, and their gardens full of roses, they might
               enjoy the happiest life in the world.
            </p>
            
            <p>The chapter on the boundaries of the British Empire is
               very gorgeous; the vastness of English possessions are well
               summed up in the following verses:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Gold is gathered in our stream,
               
               <br></br>Diamonds are found in our rock,
               
               <br></br>Pearls grow in our water,
               
               <br></br>Rubies shine in our mine.
               
               
               <br></br>A Meteor-fire plays with our wave,
               
               <br></br>A Cataract falls in our colony,
               
               <br></br>A Water-spout gathers in our climate,
               
               <br></br>A Sand-storm rages in our province.
               
               
               <br></br>Cotton grows on our bush,
               
               <br></br>Sugar ripens in our canes,
               
               <br></br>Cocoa flourishes in our groves,
               
               <br></br>Coffee is gathered from our plants.
               
               
               <br></br>The Mango falls in our field,
               
               <br></br>The Tamarind grows in our garden,
               
               <br></br>The Plantain clusters in our orchard,
               
               <br></br>The Pomegranate blushes in our wood.
               
               
               <br></br>The Cinnamon grows on our isthmus,
               
               <br></br>The Clove hardens on our peninsula,
               
               <br></br>The Pineapple lives on our island,
               
               <br></br>The Grape ripens on our continent.
               
               
               <br></br>The Cowry lives on our shore,
               
               <br></br>The Conch travels on our beach,
               
               <br></br>The Pholas bores on our rock,
               
               <br></br>The Trumpet-shell sounds on our sand.
               
               
               <br></br>The Lion wars on our plain,
               
               <br></br>The Wolf howls on our hill,
               
               <br></br>The Tiger fights in our jungle,
               
               <br></br>The Leopard hunts in our wood.
               
               
               <br></br>The Beaver builds in our pond,
               
               <br></br>The Moose-deer browses our moss,
               
               <br></br>The Giraffe eats our tender shrubs,
               
               <br></br>The Polar Bear warms himself on our ice.
               
               
               <br></br>The Kangaroo leaps on our plain,
               
               <br></br>The Spring Bok jumps on our valley,
               
               <br></br>The Antelope bounds on our upland,
               
               <br></br>The Gazelle dances on our lowland.
               
               
               <br></br>The Crocodile smiles in our stream,
               
               <br></br>The Brown Bear frowns in our wood,
               
               <br></br>The Hyaena laughs in our cave,
               
               <br></br>The Panther moans in our grove.
               
               
               <br></br>The Sloth climbs on our tree,
               
               <br></br>The Monkey chatters on our rock,
               
               <br></br>The Boa sleeps on our soil,
               
               <br></br>The Baboon lives on our fruit.
               
               
               <br></br>The Condor flies in our province,
               
               <br></br>The Scorpion bites in our kingdom,
               
               <br></br>The Polypus arms in our sea,
               
               <br></br>The Fire-fly shines in our garden.
               
               
               <br></br>The Turtle slumbers on our beach,
               
               <br></br>The Humming Bird flies in our grove,
               
               <br></br>The Ostrich walks on our sand,
               
               <br></br>The Flamingo sentries our land.
               
               
               <br></br>The Whale gambols in our ocean,
               
               <br></br>The Shark preys in our sea,
               
               <br></br>The painted Dolphin strives in vain
               
               <br></br>To rival the color on our flag.
               
               
               <br></br>The Nautilus sails on our sea,
               
               <br></br>The Blue Fish rows in company,
               
               <br></br>The Flying-Fish leaps in our water,
               
               <br></br>The Porpoise plays in our waves.
               
               
               <br></br>The Sturgeon leaps in our river,
               
               <br></br>The White Fish glitters in our lake,
               
               <br></br>The Muscanonge is captain in our water,
               
               <br></br>The Cat Fish lives in our brooks.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>And the salmon swims up our rivers every year as far as he can, to
               inquire whether people who have conquered so many nations are happy and contented at home. But what are all these foreign birds, and
               beasts, and fishes? One little robin redbreast, is worth them all
               combined; the note of the skylark is more pleasing to the ear than
               the roar of the lion; and the chirp of the household sparrow is more
               agreeable than the cry of the flamingo."
            </p>
            
            <p>We fear that there is too much truth in the following:</p>
            
            <p>"The time will never arrive when the human race will cease to
               connect the idea of political happiness with extended dominion; yet
               an empire too extended is unfavorable to the happiness of those over
               whom it is exercised. The farmer, on the Atlantic coast of North
               America, when rejoicing in the extension of the Confederacy to new
               States in the far west, forgets that it deprives him of that self-government for which his ancestors fought so bravely and so well.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Thus the same laws apply to the boundary of nations, under
               whatever form of government they choose to remain.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The liberty of a country depends very much on the same circumstance. A nation is as much deprived of liberty and self-govenment
               by extensive conquests, as the people over whom it exercises an unjust
               sway. Some may say, What is the use of this liberty, whose acquisition demands so much toil, and whose preservation demands such
               constant care?
            </p>
            
            <p>"We reply, Liberty is invaluable. She is the parent of every good
               to man. Without liberty, man is like a horse that is flogged, an ox
               that is goaded, or an ass whose ears have been pulled to an unnatural
               length.
            </p>
            
            <p>"For when the ass was first created, his ears were no longer in proportion to his size, than those of any other animal; but being of a firm
               disposition, which his enemies called obstinacy, and declining on
               some occasions to proceed when he considered himself too heavily
               laden, his enemies began to pull at his ears, until by the lapse of time
               they have become of their present size.
            </p>
            
            <p>The author of this work, we understand, was in this country some twenty years since, searching after cairns and making geological discoveries; which accounts for his intimate
               acquaintance with our geographical distinctions.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p3">
            <div class="biblTitle">St. Ignatius and His First Companions</div>
            <div class="biblPage">52</div>
            <div class="ab">St. Ignatius and his First Companions. By the Rev. 
               <span class="person" id="ccpise">Charles Constantine Pise</span>, D.D. Edward Dunigan, 151 Fulton street, 1845.
            </div>
            
            <p>Among the nine first companions of Ignatius, four preceded
               him to the tomb, namely, Peter Faber, St. Francis Xavier,
               Claudius Jaius, and John Cordurius. The lives of these are
               given to the conclusion; of the others, James Layner, Alphonsus Salmeron, Nicholas Bobadilla, Simon Rodriguez,
               and Paschasius Broetus, the author has only given their lives
               down to the time when their chief was taken from them.
               "The principal object I had in view," says the author, "in
               not carrying out their history after the death of St. Ignatius,
               was, to exhibit the spirit which he, in person, diffused
               throughout the body, and thereby confute, by evidence, the
               vain calumny, that he was a fanatic, and his first disciples
               were intriguers and impostors."
            </p>
            
            <p>The author manifests an unbecoming fear of the term
               "fanatic": it is only another word for earnestness. His patron would never have become a saint, if he had not first
               been a fanatic. We protestants are so much used to speak
               of Ignatius Loyala in no very devout terms, that perhaps
               some will be a little startled to hear him spoken of as Saint
               Ignatius; but Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="ccpise">Pise</span> is, himself, of the order which Loyala
               founded: he was educated by its brethren. His work is, of
               course, the labor of a loving and reverent heart, and will
               commend itself by its sincerity even to those who may dif-fer with its author about the merits of his patron.
            </p>
            
            <p>As an example of the style in which the work is written,
               we give the following extract from the chapter on Saint Ignatius:--
            </p>
            
            <p>"Wearied and much agitated from a strange and recent apparition,
               a noble looking cavalier, robed in the plain guise of a pilgrim, sat
               down to repose him on the banks of a gentle stream, not far from the
               village of Manreza.
               <span class="footnote" id="n001">
                  <span class="footnoteLink">1</span>
                  <span class="footnoteText">*The singular vision here alluded to is thus described by , in
                     his History of the Society of Jesus: "A very comely image appeared to him
                     in the air, the figure of which he could not clearly discern. It was lengthy,
                     like the form of a serpent, bright, and of various hues, and glittering with
                     many eyes, like stars: which, while it appeared rendered him happy, and
                     when it vanished left him sorrowful." Lib. i. 22, p. 7. The conversion of
                     Ignatius happened in 1521. He was in his thirty-first year.
                  </span>
               </span> The deep shadows were now falling from the
               neighboring hills: over the brow of Mount Serat, the dusk of the evening seemed already wreathing its sombre twilight, the waters of the
               lonely river rippled beneath the breath of the solitude's breeze.
               There, in profound contemplation, with his dark-gray eyes fixed intently upon the river, sat that wondrous stranger. His elegant mien,
               his broad, high forehead, his aquiline nose, his beautiful yet manly
               features, bespoke the high rank to which he belonged, and the magnanimous character with which he was adorned. He had recently
               fought, at the head of a chivalrous army, for the liberties of Spain,
               and had been wounded in her glorious cause, on the walls of Pampeluna. He had been confined to his bed, suffering intense pain from the
               extraction of the ball which had entered his leg, and the amputation
               of a bone which protruded from the wound. During this period of
               lingering and solitary illness, he had sought to relieve his tedium, and
               engage his mind with reading. No works of fancy or books of chivalry being within his reach, he had recourse to a volume of the Lives
               of the Saints, in which he beheld depicted, for the imitation of great
               souls, their heroic virtues, and sublime sanctity. The transition, in
               such a mind as his, from one species of chivalry to another, was very
               easy and natural; he had been trained up to that of arms and martial
               enthusiasm; he could without difficulty, appreciate that of peace and
               religious glory. As he read on, his heart opened as it were, to the divine influences of Christian heroism; his soul insensibly began to glow
               with an ardour more ennobling than he had before experienced; a desire to emulate the splendid moral achievements of the examples before him, an irresisitible admiration of their victories over themselves
               and their triumphs over the world, urged forward his generous ambition; and the grace of God co-operating, meanwhile, with his natural
               dispositions, he determined to change the standard of war for the ensign of the cross. He had laid aside from his towering person the insignia of knight, and taken upon himself those of an humble penitent,
               making a pilgrimage from shrine to shrine. Over the altar of the ever-blessed Virgin he had hung the sword which was still gleaming
               with the lustre of valour--a bright, a splendid trophy of the grace of
               God. For that brave spirit that knew not how to cower before the terrors of the cannon, was stricken down in profound subjection--not to
               any human power--and lain prostrate, by the "violence" of the love of
               God. Sweet violence, indeed, that gives no pain but contrition, and
               demands no subjection but a calm submission to the will of Heaven.
               Violence which, it is true, storms the citadel of the heart, but renders
               it, at the same time, a voluntary captive: which sometimes achieves
               its object by forcing the deep and silent tear from the fountains of
               some Magdalen's soul, and, at other times, by casting down headlong
               --blind and terror-stricken--on the sward, some Saul of Tarsus. That
               extraordinary personage, meditating, at this twilight hour, on the
               banks of the Rubricato, is the immortal founder of the Society of Jesus--Ignatius of Loyola.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Between the epoch of the birth of this defender of the ancient faith,
               and that of Martin Luther, its pest and scourge, a space of nine years
               occurred: the former having been born in 1491, the latter in 1482. God,
               whose providence could but prepare a barrier against the calamities
               which he foresaw were about to desolate his Church, raised up Ignatius, as a host in the company which he was destined to establish,
               for her defence and edification. Guipuzcoa, a province in Cantabria,
               was the place of his nativity. His family was noble and renowned.
               His father and mother were both of illustrious origin. His youthful
               disposition tended to the study and the feats of arms: and, having, at a
               maturer age, embraced the military profession, he won the applause
               of his country and reaped no little glory on the field. This soldierlike character he impressed on the company which he instituted. It
               appears in the celerity of obedience on the part of its members, in the
               enduring of labour, and the missionary exercises--all modeled on the
               exemplar of the camp. His soul, from early childhood, burned with
               inextinguishable ardour for renown, and human praise: which natural
               impetuosity, changed and chastened under holier influences, he carried
               with him into the ranks of religion, and infused into the breasts of his
               disciples. He was distinguished by grace, ease, and majesty of manners, and a singular love of elegance of dress; which qualities he afterwards hallowed, and transferred to sacred things, and made auxiliary to the discipline and spirit of his order. He possessed a sublime
               magnanimity in pardoning an offence, as well as in conferring a favour: an innate detestation of avarice, and--the germ of all vices-cupidity. He exhibited a lofty daring in dangerous and difficult exertions; a singular prudence in the transaction of business, and an unwearied and patient perseverance and constancy of character. In the
               flower of youth he displayed the maturity of age; and in the first impulse of his conversion was raised, on a sudden, to the highest grade
               of perfection.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Hence the sublime ascetic character of his book of 'Spiritual Exercises,' written so soon after his retreat to Mount Serat, and his austere and penitential musings at Manreza. Hence his marvellous ecstasy, in which, wrapt in the contemplation of heavenly things, during
               eight days, he seemed dead to those of earth. And hence, too, that solemn vow of chastity by which he devoted himself forever to the service of God, following the Lamb whithersoever he went.' This perfection displayed itself in all his actions. Whether we trace him to the
               isle of Cyprus, on his pilgrimage to the Holy Land; whether we view
               him, entering--an humble palmer--upon the consecrated soil of Palestine, prostrate, in tears, at the tomb of Christ partaking of the Redeemer's agony on the mount of Olives; whether we behold him favoured with celestial visions, or wrecked on the shoals near the coast
               of Cyprus, or, on his return to Europe, seized upon and contumaciously
               treated as a spy in France:--under all circumstances, and in every
               condition, there was a grandeur of soul, a sanctity of motive, and an
               enthusiasm of virtue, which stamped him, at once, with that transcendant character, which was wonderfully developed in the course of his
               subsequent career.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The Company' he established, was destined to labour for the salvation of men, and to propagate the greater glory of Jesus Christ.
               Hence the motive for his styling it the 'Society of Jesus:' deriving its
               name from him, who is the only true salvation of the human race, and
               who promised to be  propitious to him at Rome.'"
            </p>
            
            <p>It is among the handsomest specimens of printing that
               we have seen from the New York press; but the frontispiece of portraits is altogether unworthy, in point of execution, to rank with the other parts of the book.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p4">
            <div class="biblTitle">Vestiges of the Natural History of Creation</div>
            <div class="biblPage">52</div>
            <div class="ab">Vestiges or the Natural History of Creation. Wiley &amp; Put-
               
               <br></br>nam, 1845.	12mo. pp. 291.
            </div>
            
            <p>One of the chief merits of this book is its freedom from
               those patronising and approbatory passages with which popular writers on similar subjects intersperse their speculations.
               Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="dick">Dick</span> is probably the worst of the whole tribe, and the
               author of the work before us, the best. But he is not wholly
               free from this wearisome fault. The only two qualities really
               needed in authors of books of this class, are: first, accuracy
               of information; and second, clearness of style. Every word,
               beyond what is necessary to convey a fact, is felt to be lumber;
               and all reflections upon the goodness and greatness of the
               Creator, are, to speak of them in the mildest terms, insults to
               the understanding of the reader. It must be taken for granted
               that any person who will be likely to read a work on Natural
               History, has already formed an idea that God is both great
               and good, beyond the capacity of man to comprehend. We do
               not see the propriety of taxing the undevout astronomer with
               madness, any more than the undevout husbandman. The
               man who fails to see God in a butter-cup, will hardly discern
               him by looking at the Georgium Sidus through a telescope.
               Whoever can contemplate himself, without being impressed
               with the thought that God is all-wise and all-powerful, will
               never be awe-struck from a contemplation of the Heavens.
               The following extract from the first chapter contains a good
               many of these objectionable passages. What have we to do
               with the "tear that falls from childhood's cheek," in a work
               professedly scientific? The tear that falls from an old man's
               cheek is of precisely the same quality.
            </p>
            
            <p>"It is remarkable of physical laws, that we see them operating on
               every kind of scale as to magnitude, with the same regularity and
               perseverance. The tear that falls from childhood's cheek is globular,
               through the efficacy of that same law of mutual attraction of particles
               which made the sun and planets round. The rapidity of Mercury is
               quicker than that of Saturn, for the same reason that, when we wheel
               a ball round by a string and make the string wind up round our fingers, the ball always flies quicker and quicker as the siring is shortened. Two eddies in a stream, as has been stated, fall into a mutual
               revolution at the distance of a couple of inches, through the same
               cause which makes a pair of suns link in mutual revolution at the distance of millions of miles. There is, we might say, a sublime simplicity in this indifference of the grand regulations to the vastness or minuteness of the field of their operation. Their being uniform, too,
               throughout space, as far as we can scan it, and their being so unfailing in their tendency to operate, so that only the proper conditions
               are presented, afford to our minds matter for the gravest consideration. Nor should it escape our careful notice that the regulations on
               which all the laws of matter operate, are established on a rigidly accurate mathematical basis. Proportions of numbers and geometrical
               figures, rest at the bottom of the whole. All these considerations,
               when the mind is thoroughly prepared for them, tend to raise our
               ideas with respect to the character of physical laws, even though we
               do not go a single step further in the investigation. But it is impossible for an intelligent mind to stop there. We advance from law to the
               cause of law, and ask, what is that? Whence have come all these 
               beautiful regulations? Here science leaves us, but only to conclude,
               from other grounds, that there is a First Cause to which all others are
               secondary and ministrative, a primitive almighty will, of which these 
               laws are merely the mandates. That great Being, who shall say 
               where is his dwelling-place, or what his history? Man pauses breathless at the contemplation of a subject so much above his finite faculties, and only can wonder and adore!"
            </p>
            
            <p>A tolerable purity of style seems almost impossible with 
               writers of this class. They cannot read the Bible to any 
               good purpose, or they would write better. The author before
               us has more to recommend him on this score than many 
               others, but he seems to be impressed with an idea that a 
               great subject requires great swelling words. He should, 
               in the outset, fix upon some term by which to express his idea 
               of the Omnipotent, and dismiss the thought that he is called
               upon, personally, to assert the dignity of his Creator. He 
               seeems to labor under a continual fear that his readers have 
               not a sufficient reverence for their Creator, and he bestows
               upon Him a great variety of high-sounding expletives. The
               August Being, the Deity, the Divine Wisdom, the Divine Author, Almighty Perfection, the Great Creator, Providence,
               Creative Providence, Almighty Conception, Great Father,
               Almighty Wisdom, &amp;c., &amp;c., occur with variations throughout the book.
            </p>
            
            <p>The most interesting chapter in the book is that relating to
               vegetable and animal generation. It is treated here with
               great delicacy, originality, and power, and will prove interesting even to those who differ from the author in his conclusions; as many will. The theory that man sprang from the
               first order of organic life, and that he passes, now, through
               all the conditions of fish, reptile, and bird, is fanciful in the
               extreme. If it were true, men of premature birth, would
               more nearly resemble the simia than the human race.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the chapter on the "Mental Constitution of Animals,"
               we find some curious statistical facts.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Even mistakes and oversights are of regular recurrence, for it is
               found in the post offices of large cities, that the number of letters put
               in without addresses is year by year the same. Statistics has made
               out an equally distinct regularity in a wide range, with regard to many
               other things concerning the mind, and the doctrine founded upon it
               has lately produced a scheme which may well strike the ignorant with
               surprise. It was proposed to establish in London a society for ensuring the integrity of clerks, secretaries, collectors, and all such functionaries as are usually obliged to find security for money passing
               through their hands in the course of business. A gentleman of the
               highest character as an actuary spoke of the plan in the following
               terms: "If a thousand bankers' clerks were to club together to indemnify their securities, by the payment of one pound a year each, and if
               each had given security for 500l., it is obvious that two in each year
               might become defaulters to that amount, and so on, without rendering the guarantee fund insolvent. If it be tolerably well ascertained
               that the instances of dishonesty (yearly) among such persons amount
               to one in five hundred, this club would continue to exist, subject to
               being in debt in a bad year, to an amount which it would be able to
               discharge in good ones. The only question necessary to be asked
               previous to the formation of such a club would be,--may it not be feared that the motive to resist dishonesty would be lessened by the existence of the club, or that ready made rogues, by belonging to it,
               might find the means of obtaining situations which they would otherwise have been kept out of by the impossibility of obtaining security
               among those who know them? Suppose this be sufficiently answered
               by saying, that none but those who could bring satisfactory testimony
               to their previous good character should be allowed to join the club;
               that persons who may now hope that a deficiency on their parts will
               be made up and hushed up by the relative or friend who is security,
               will know very well that the club will have no motive to decline a
               prosecution, or to keep the secret and so on. It then only remains to
               ask, whether the sum demanded for the guarantee is sufficient?" The
               philosophical principle on which the scheme proceeds, seems to be simply this, that, amongst a given (large) number of persons of good
               character, there will be within a year or considerable space of time,
               a determinate number of instances in which moral principle and the
               terror of the consequences of guilt will be overcome by temptations
               of a determinate kind and amount, and thus occasion a periodical
               amount of loss which the association must make up."
            </p>
            
            <p>It appears, from a foot note, that this proposed association
               has been formed in London, and is working well. A society
               of this kind should be immediately formed in Wall street, and
               in Washington.
            </p>
            
            <p>The faults that we have discovered in this book are very
               few, and not of a character to detract in the least from its
               popularity. It is admirably calculated for the million, and
               being sold at a low price, it must, we think, meet with a
               rapid sale.
            </p>
            
            <p>But where did the publishers of this valuable work obtain
               it? Was it produced by their literary dragoman? or did
               some obliging friend give them the manuscript? It has not
               the appearance of a spontaneous production; yet we can find
               in no part of it, any hint of its origin. It cannot have been
               reprinted from a foreign edition, for the publishers have the
               reputation of honest men, and they would, of course, have
               given some intimation of the fact, if such had been the case.
               A work of similar title has gone through two or three editions
               in London, but we have no right to think that this is the same.
               As good books are not published every day, readers have a
               curiosity to know where one comes from, when they meet
               with a new one; who produced it, what language it first made
               its appearance in, how long it has been before the world, and
               what degree of credit to attach to its statements when they
               are of a novel character. Publishers would confer a benefit
               upon the reading world by giving some intimation, when
               they put forth a new work, of the source whence they derived
               it. If Wiley &amp; Putnam had printed in the title-page of this
               work, "Republished from the third London Edition," it would
               have been more to their credit, and not in the slightest degree
               detrimental to their interests. Tradesmen who deal in books,
               should set an example of honesty to the rest of the trading
               world.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            <div class="biblTitle">Conversations on Some of the Old Poets</div>
            <div class="biblPage">53</div>
            <div class="ab">Conversations on Some of the Old Poets. By 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">James Russell
                  Lowell
               </span>. Cambridge. Published by John Owen, 1845.
               
               <br></br>                   (Second Notice.)
            </div>
            
            <p>Passages like these in a conversation on Chaucer, appear
               somewhat incongruous when taken by themselves, but they
               spring up as naturally as flowers do from a seemingly exhausted soil:
            </p>
            
            <p>Philip. The Devil might listen to some preaching I have heard, without getting his appetite spoiled. There is a great deal of time and
               money expended to make men believe that this one or that one will be
               damned, and to scare or wheedle them into good Calvinists or Episcopalians but very little pains is taken to make them good Christians.
            </p>
            
            <p>John. You use plain words.</p>
            
            <p>Philip. Plain words are best. Truth wants no vail; the chastity
               and beauty of her countenance are defence enough against all lewd
               eyes. Falsehood, only, needs to hide her face for, that unseen, she
               has learned so well to mimic the gait and feign the voice of Truth,
               as to counterfeit her with ease and safety. Our tongue has become so
               courtly and polite, as well-nigh to have forgotten that it has also
               words befitting indignation and reproof. Some thoughts demand the
               utmost swell and voluptuousness of language; they should float like
               Aphrodite upborne on a summer ocean. For others, the words should
               be jagged and immitigable and abrupt as the rocks upon the shore.
               Let the feeling of the moment choose. If melody be needed, the
               chance shell of the tortoise shall become a lyre which Apollo might
               sigh for.
            </p>
            
            <p>John. It has never been a safe thing to breathe a whisper against
               the church, least of all in this country, where it has no prop from the
               state, but is founded only on the love, or, if you will have it so, the
               prejudices of the people. Religion has come to be esteemed synonymous with the church; there are few minds clear enough to separate
               it from the building erected for its convenience and its shelter. It is
               this which has made our Christianity external, a task-ceremony to be
               gone through with, and not a principle of life itself. The church has
               been looked on too much in the light of a machine, which only needs
               a little oil, now and then, on its joints and axles, to make it run glibly
               and perform all its functions without grating or creaking. Nothing
               that we can say will be of much service. The reformers must come
               from her own bosom; and there are many devout souls among her
               priests now, who would lay down their lives to purify her. The names
               of infidel and heretic are the San benitos in which we dress offenders
               in the nineteenth century, and a bigoted public opinion furnishes the
               fagots and applies the match! The very cross itself, to which the sacred right of private judgment fled for sanctuary, has been turned into
               a whipping-post. Doubtless, there are nations on the earth so wicked
               as those who profess Christianity; and the blame may be laid in great
               measure at the door of the church, which has always sought temporal
               power, and has chosen to lean rather upon the arm of flesh than upon
               that of God. The church has corrupted Christianity. She has decked
               her person and embroidered her garments with the spoils of pagan
               altars, and has built her temples of blocks which paganism had squared
               ready to her hand. We are still Huns and Vandals, and Saxons and
               Celts, at heart. We have carved a cross upon our altars, but the
               smoke of our sacrifice goes up to Thor and Odin still. Lately I read
               in the newspapers a toast given at a military festival, by one of those
               who claim to be earthly representatives of the Prince of Peace. Eng
               land and France send out the cannon and the bayonet, upon missionary enterprises, to India and Africa, and our modern Elliots and Brainerds among the red men are of the same persuasive metal.
            </p>
            
            <p>Philip. Well, well, let us hope for change. There are signs of it:
               there has been a growling of thunder round the horizon for many days.
               We are like the people in countries subject to earthquakes, who
               crowd into churches for safety, but find that their sacred walls are as
               fragile as other works of human hands. Nay, the very massiveness
               of their architecture makes their destruction more sudden, and their
               fall more dangerous. You and I have become convinced of this. Both
               of us, having certain reforms at heart, and believing them to be of vital interest to mankind, turned first to the church as the nearest helper
               under God. We have been disappointed. Let us not waste our time
               in throwing stones at its insensible doors. As you have said, the reformers must come from within. The prejudice of position is so
               strong, that all her servants will unite against an exoteric assailant,
               melting up, if need be, the holy vessels for bullets, and using the
               leaves of the holy book itself for wadding. But I will never enter a
               church from which a prayer goes up for the prosperous only, or for
               the unfortunate among the oppressors, and not for the oppressed and
               fallen; as if God had ordained our pride of caste and our distinctions
               of color, and as if Christ had forgotten those that are in bonds. We are
               bid to imitate God: let us in this also follow his example, whose only
               revenge upon error is the giving success to truth, and but strive more
               cheerfully for the triumph of what we believe to be right. Let us,
               above all things, imitate him in ascribing what we see of wrongdoing to blindness and error, rather than to wilful sin. The Devil
               loves nothing better than the intolerance of reformers, and dreads nothing so much as their charity and patience. The scourge is better upon
               our backs than in our hands.
            </p>
            
            <p>John. When the air grows thick and heavy, and the clouds gather
               in the moral atmosphere, the tall steeples of the church are apt to
               attract the lightning first. Its pride and love of high places are the
               most fatal of conductors. That small upper room, in which the disciciples were first gathered, would always be safe enough.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have given an extract on the Dignity of Poverty: we
               give one below on the false dignity of Death.
            </p>
            
            <p>John. It is singular what ugly portraits of Death are ordinarily given
               us. There seems to be but little living faith in the immortality of the
               soul--so soon does any idea become formal and external, when diluted
               by the customariness of a creed. Men do not believe in the next world
               as they do in London or Boston; they do not launch upon the ignotum mare with a shadow of that prophetic belief which girded up the
               heart of Columbus. Most religion-mongers have baited their paradises
               with a bit of toasted cheese. They have templed the body with large
               promise of possessions in their transmortal El Dorado. Sancho Panza
               will not quit his chimney corner, but under promise of imaginary
               islands to govern. For my own part, I think it wiser to make the spirit
               a staff for the body, than the body for the spirit. When the vessel
               casts off for the voyage, and the body finds itself left behind, it may well
               cry out and disturb the whole vicinage with the story of its wrong.
            </p>
            
            <p>Philip. I agree with you that the body is treated with quite too
               much ceremony and respect. Even religion has vailed its politic hat
               to it, till, like Christopher Sly, it is metamorphosed, in its own estimation, from a tinker to a duke. Men, who would, without compunction, kick a living beggar, will yet stand in awe of his poor carcass,
               after all that rendered it truly venerable has fled out of it. We agree
               with the old barbarian epitaph, which affirmed that the handful of
               dust had been Ninus; as if that which convicts us of mortality and
               weakness could at the same time endow us with our high prerogative
               of kingship over them. South, in one of his sermons, tells us of certain men whose souls are of no worth, but as salt to keep their bodies
               from putrifying. I fear that the soul is too often regarded in this sutler fashion. Why should men ever be afraid to die, but that they regard the spirit as secondary to that which is but its mere appendage
               and conveniency, its symbol, its word, its means of visibility? If the
               soul lose this poor mansion of hers by the sudden conflagration of disease, or by the slow decay of age, is she therefore houseless and shelterless? If she cast away this soiled and tattered garment, is she
               therefore naked? A child looks forward to his new suit, and dons it
               joyfully; we cling to our rags and foulness. We should welcome
               Death as one who brings us tidings of the finding of long-lost titles to
               a large family estate, and set out gladly to take possession, though, it
               may be, not without a natural tear for the humbler home we are leaving. Death always means us a kindness, though he has often a gruff
               way of offering it. Even if the soul never returned from that chartless
               and unmapped country, which I do not believe, I would take Sir John
               Davies's reason as a good one:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"But, as Noah's pigeon, which returned no more,
               
               <br></br>Did show she footing found, for all the flood;
               
               <br></br>So, when good souls, departed through death's door,
               
               <br></br>Come not again, it shows their dwelling good."
            </div>
            
            
            <p>The realm of Death seems an enemy's country to most men, on
               whose shores they are loathely driven by stress of weather; to the
               wise man it is the desired port where he moors his bark gladly, as in
               some quiet haven of the Fortunate Isles; it is the golden west in which
               his sun sinks, and, sinking, casts back a glory upon the leaden cloudrack which had darkly besieged his day.
            </p>
            
            <p>After all, the body is a more expert dialectician than the soul, and
               buffets it, even to bewilderment, with the empty bladders of logic;
               but the soul can retire, from the dust and turmoil of such conflict, to
               the high tower of instinctive faith, and there, in hushed serenity, take
               comfort of the sympathizing stars. We look at death through the
               cheap-glazed windows of the flesh, and believe him for the monster
               which the flawed and crooked glass presents him. You say truly that
               we have wasted time in trying to coax the body into a faith in what, by
               its very nature, it is incapable of comprehending. Hence, a plethoric,
               short-winded kind of belief, that can walk at an easy pace over the
               smooth plain, but loses breath at the first sharp uphill of life. How
               idle is it to set a sensual bill of fare before the soul, acting over again
               the old story of the Crane and the Fox!
            </p>
            
            <p>These Conversations cannot fail to prove a permanent addition to our national literature. For although their professed subject is one of the most hackneyed that could be chosen; yet they contain as much freshness and beauty as though
               it were now handled for the first time.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         <div class="biblTitle">American Prose Writers, No. 3, John Waters</div>
         <div class="biblPage">55</div>
         <div class="head">AMERICAN PROSE WRITERS.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">        NO. 3.
            
            <br></br>    JOHN WATERS.
         </div>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="hcary">John Waters</span> is well entitled to a place in the catalogue
            of American prose writers. Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="rwgriswold">Griswold</span> has given him a
            niche among our poets, but he will be known better by his
            essays than his poems. In one respect he is like 
            <span class="person" id="clamb">Charles
               Lamb
            </span>; the best part of his life has been devoted to business;
            the Phenix bank, of which he was president many years,
            contains the largest amount of his writings, as the India
            House does of Lamb's. We are not aware that 
            <span class="person" id="hcary">John Waters</span>
            has ever appeared before the public with a book, but his individuality is as well defined, and he stands apart from
            other writers as distinctly as 
            <span class="person" id="clamb">Elia</span> did before his essays were
            published in a separate volume.
         </p>
         
         <p>It would be unjust to compare him with Lamb, as we
            have heard done, for their style and habits of thought are
            quite different. In fastidiousness of tastes, a reverence for
            the past and a delicacy of appetite, there is considerable resemblance between these two authors, but in other respects
            they are widely different. A looseness of religious sentiment
            pervades the writings of 
            <span class="person" id="clamb">Elia</span>, but you discern upon a very
            short acquaintance with 
            <span class="person" id="hcary">John Waters</span>, that his religious faith
            is as sharply defined, and as positive as his taste in fish or
            wine, and that he would frown upon heterodoxy in the
            church as severely as he would upon a blunder in carving,
            whether in marble or mutton. His essays are all short, as
            essays should be, of the Addisonian dimensions and density
            of expression. His sentences are the most perfect in the language; it would be a vain task to hunt through them all for
            a superfluous conjunction. They are too perfect to be peculiar, for writers are distinguished from each other more by
            their faults than their excellencies. He is manifestly an admirer of 
            <span class="person" id="wirving">Geoffrey Crayon</span>, but very far from an imitator of
            his style. He has a finer artistic taste than the author of the
            Sketch Book, but a less genial love of nature, as nature.
            He can endure nothing that wears a slovenly aspect. His
            lawns must be neatly trimmed and his gardens weeded.
            He abhors Scuppernon wine, but can relish port in chowder.
            He has not written much about flowers, but we should think
            that his favorite was a Camelia. He is in some sort a 
            <span class="person" id="srogers">Sam
               Rogers
            </span>, but more particular. In pictures he is an admirer
            of Both and Weir. Probably Gerard Douw and Watteau are
            among his great artists. His humor is of the quiet kind
            which provokes a bland smile, but never a laugh, which
            would be irregular and boisterous. His piety is tender and
            subduing, it may cause a tear, but never a swelling of the
            heart. He is rather fanciful than imaginative, and the pictures
            which he presents to us are exhibited through a stained glass,
            which mellows the outlines without distorting the forms represented. His descriptions have a delicacy of finish like
            the carvings of Grinling Gibbons. They remind you as forcibly of nature as anything short of nature can, but they
            never deceive you; you know all the while that it is not a
            reality that affects you.
         </p>
         
         <p>We are not familiar with any of his writings, but those
            that have appeared in the New York American and in the
            Knickerbocker. They should be collected together in a volume by themselves; for they would make a valuable addition to our national literature. We need them as models of
            style, in these days of rhodomontades and Macaulayisms.
            
            <span class="person" id="hcary">John Waters</span> is a sensualist, rather than a sentimentalist.
            Perhaps he thinks otherwise. But his sensualism is a sentiment. The greater part of his essays are purely sensual,
            although it is not a vulgar sensualism, but rather a spiritual
            appetite of the senses. He elevates a buttered muffin into a
            work of high art; and his fish are such exquisite creatures,
            that you feel while gazing upon them, that Vatel may be
            pardoned for falling upon his sword. There is always something to be tasted, or smelt or listened to in his essays. The
            mouth is more apt to water than the eyes, in his company.
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="hcary">John Waters</span> is only an assumed name, as all the world
            knows, like that of 
            <span class="person" id="jwilson">Christopher North</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="bwprocter">Barry Cornwall</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="wirving">Geoffrey Crayon</span>, and others. The real name of this pure essayist is 
            <span class="person" id="hcary">Henry Cary</span>. He is at present we believe a gentleman
            of wealth and leisure. With a keen relish for elegant literature and refined art, he appears to have had the prudence
            to labor diligently through his early years in acquiring a fortune, that his later life might be spent in the quiet of independent ease. Pity, pity, that many of similar taste were
            not endowed with similar prudence and forethought!
         </p>
         
         <p>We give a short extract from one of his papers in the
            Knickerbocker containing an account of the great Hungarian
            pianist Lizst, who, we have reason to believe, we shall have
            among us during the year.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Our nice travelling chariot, with all its trunks, cases, pockets,
            down-cushions, and delightful appliances, that we had thought such a
            purchase two days before at Frankfort, gave out just as we approached Heidelberg. One of the axletrees heated, the wheel refused to
            turn round, and for two hours we were standing in the road, surrounded
            by peasantry that the postillion had assembled together, endeavoring
            to get the wheel oil, pouring cold water upon it, and talking to us
            and about us in an unknown tongue; for although my friend and myself mustered five modern languages, German unfortunately was not
            one of them, and we knew nothing whatever of the patois of these
            honest people.
         </p>
         
         <p>After consultation with a mechanic at Heidelberg, and finding that
            the defect was not to be remedied there without great delay, we resolved upon a partial repair, and to return as best we might to Frankfort and seek redress from the warranty of the party of whom we had
            bought the vehicle. We paid our visit to the incomparable ruins of
            the castle, and then proceeded to retrace our steps; and examining
            our wheels at every post-house, reached the Hotel d'Angleterre at
            Frankfort at the close of day in August last.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is always depressing to be turned back upon one's path; and
            these reclamations and bargainings for redress are the most uncomfortable things in the world; so that M. and I looked blank at one another as we entered again the streets of that busy mart. We determined
            to say nothing of the matter until mornihg, and I longed heartily for
            some refreshment that should banish it altogether from my mind in
            the mean time.
         </p>
         
         <p> Is there no music in Frankfort to-night?' I inquired.</p>
         
         <p> I beg your pardon,' was the reply;  there is, the finest. Monsieur
            Liszt, the pianist, performs this evening at the theatre.'
         </p>
         
         <p> Is it far from this?'</p>
         
         <p> Quite the contrary, fortunately, for the performances must have
            begun.'
         </p>
         
         <p> Show me the way.'</p>
         
         <p>In a few minutes I had passed through the boxes into the pit of a
            small theatre. It was well filled, and yet the number of performers
            and amateurs on the stage seemed hardly less than that of the audience.
            The entertainment had opened, and was continned for some time with
            alternate instrumental and vocal music. The latter was composed of
            those strong brassy, male voices, that satisfy the ear by their correct-
            ness and force, perhaps, but make no approach toward the heart
         </p>
         
         <p>There was then a pause of some minutes, and a movement of expectation throughout the house; and presently a pale-faced, light-complexioned, loosely-constructed, middle-aged person made his way
            through the artists and assistants, saluted the audience in a shambling
            and gauche manner, and seated himself without notes at a piano that
            was near the front of the stage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Until he reached the side of this instrument, he seemed like part of
            a man, wanting support and confidence; but as he took his place, the
            existence became complete, and joy passed over his countenance as he
            laid his hand upon the keys. It was one of the faces of Thorwaldsen,
            an express indication of the deep interior spirit; and expectation rose
            high when the piano breathed as it were under his touch. He ran
            through a delicious voluntary, that there might be no doubt of the exactness of each note, and we all felt the perfection of his fingering;
            clear, distinct, round, precious, full--a shower of pearls upon a table
            of porphyry.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was now all stillness, the intense stillness of watchfulness,
            throughout the house; for his performance was to commence; and although the moment if measured by a clock might have been short, no
            doubt, we divided time by a different metre; and a wild waste had in
            our imagination extended itself around him, when he calmly raised his
            hands to their utmost height, and with blow after blow upon the instrument with his whole force, successively planted large columnar
            masses of sound over the extended plain, and a scene like that of the
            Giant's Causeway rose like enchantment before our astonished and delighted senses. Hardly had he sketched the vision before us, when a
            storm began such as I have seldom witnessed. The instrument rained,
            hailed, thundered, moaned, whistled, shrieked round those basaltic columns, in every cry that the tempest can utter in its wildest paroxysms
            of wrath. It was almost too powerful and ungoverned at the last; and
            at the instant that this thought entered into the mind, the wind lulled,
            the elements were spent, the calm came; the brooks and water-courses
            took up their song of exultation; the air was refreshed, the birds chirped, the sun put forth, and the 'young leaf lifted its green head.'
         </p>
         
         <p>We now accompanied him through a small valley with precipitous
            banks, such as one finds in Piedmont, where the large leafed tree
            grows beside the mossy rock, and the vine tries vainly to envelope
            both, and shade and light and repose are the glory of the earth. Young
            clouds were forming on the upper heights, destined to paint the skies of
            Italy, and struggled hard in their ascent at every jutting rock and leafy
            buttress to remain adhering to their native cliffs, against the repeated
            bidding of the sun; as if preferring even to the cerulean heaven, a world
            so verdant and so fair! We were thus borne along by the strain
            through countless beauties of rock and sky and foliage to a grotto, by
            the side of which was a fountain that seemed one of the Eyes of the
            Earth, so large and darkly-brilliant was it, so deep and so serene;
            reflecting on its retina with magical distinctness every surrounding object, whether distant or near. Here we listened for some moments to the voices rather than the songs of birds, when the music by
            degrees again diminished, and then fluttered and then ceased.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was not immediately that the audience gave forth their demonstrations of rapturous applause; and as I looked round, I saw on all
            sides that 'eyes, in tears, both smiled and wept' I walked home almost upon air, and every pulsation on the way was a throb of gratitude
            to Him, who for our solace and delight hath 'planted the ear' and
            opened all hearts to the inspiration of the truly gifted master of this
            wonderful art.
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus far, dear editor, is the extract, which world never have been
            offered to your regard, but that being some days afterward in the society of an accomplished lady, herself no mean musician, and describing to her the effect produced on my mind by this remarkable performance, she surprised me by saying that she bad been present at it,
            and that the same imagery had passed with slight variation before her
            as she listened, that I have here endeavored faintly to preserve.
         </p>
         
         <p>I was charmed at the assurance, for it confirmed me in the belief
            that this was not the mere flitting of the rainbow spirit across the
            imagination, rearing in its passage a fabric of happiness--beautiful at
            times as a palace of the Genii, and, alas! as illusory--but a substantive and truthful joy, to be recalled at will; to be remembered in
            solitude; to be dwelt upon for the enrichment of the soul; and--may
            I entertain the hope?--in some degree perhaps even to be imparted."
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">
            <span class="person" id="hcary">John Waters</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Chronology</div>
         <div class="head">CHRONOLOGY.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Origin of Manhattan, Hell Gate, Etc.</div>
            <div class="biblPage">56</div>
            <div class="head">THE ORIGIN OF MANHATTAN, HELL GATE, ETC.</div>
            
            <p>It is characteristic of the American people to look forward,
               and indulge in anticipations of the future--probably because
               the most brilliant prospects attract the mind in contemplating
               the rise and development of the nation. We have nothing
               to allege against so natural a trait. Hope beckons on the
               course of nations, as well as of ambitious and noble-minded
               individuals. But we propose, just now, to cast a moment's
               retrospect, and to look back--it is not a very long vista, at
               most--to the verge of our early history on the continent.
               The time is not very remote, when ships came doubtingly
               out of the Atlantic mists on our coasts, from the leading
               ports of Europe, and, after a furtive recognition of the "wild
               men," found here, dropped anchor in our roadsteads, and the
               mouths of our larger rivers. Wonder sat depicted in the
               countenances of every master and mate of a vessel, who got
               into a pinnace to land, and kept his two eyes on a restless
               stretch for new objects, and he moved his tiller with adroit
               ease, from one side to the other.
            </p>
            
            <p>It may be doubted, indeed, whether 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> did not
               draw the scenes of his "Tempest" from the first narratives of wondering voyagers, who came to America, and who
               were prone to see on every cliff a "Caliban," or something
               worse, or more fantastic, in the shape of an Indian. Bear in
               mind, gentle reader, that the Scandinavians saw here the
               "Unipedes"--that singular race of the human family who
               went, with somewhat of the nervous emphasis of a Kangaroo, on one foot. This was certainly an improvement on the
               ancient notion of the people of Kaethay, as reported by the
               veritable Joseph Barberat and Marco Polo, who affirmed, that
               all other nations besides themselves, had but one eye. To
               have but one leg was the greater wonder of the two.
            </p>
            
            <p>Be these questions as they may, and there is room for historiographers and physiologists to say a great deal on both
               sides, it is just two hundred and thirty-six years--not a
               whit more, since the first ship of the bold and adventurous
               Hollander first cast anchor in the noble bay which is now
               called New York. The area of Broadway, from which we
               issue this sheet, like some other spots hereabout, was then
               occupied by the scattered wigwams of a gaunt, fierce-looking race of men, with piercing black eyes, and black hair,
               who walked about with bows and arrows, and called themselves Manhattans. We humor orthography, by letting the
               word stand, as our Dutch ancestors wrote it, albeit, we could
               easily prove that they retrenched some of the true original,
               and gave it a twist to suit their own notions of the laws of
               recording sound.
            </p>
            
            <p>Manhattan, (with this salvo,) was the name for a noted
               whirlpool in the vicinity, which the Dutch called Hellegat,
               and which we, taking the same right to twist it that the
               Dutch did to twist Man-a-ha-tan-uk, call Hellgate. It is only
               our Eastern neighbors, by the way, who have ever been
               noted, especially in their discussions on theology, for steering
               clear of so hard a place, or eschewing it, at least from a
               choice in their terminology, that call this remarkable pass
               Hurlgate. By the ancient Manhattanese, it was simply described, as a place of violent, or bad whirling waters, just
               indeed, what it is. And as it is by far the most striking
               and characteristic geographical trait in the vicinity of New
               York, they called the island, on its west, Manhattan Island,
               while that on its east, was Metoacs, [Long Island.] These
               sons of the forest were no deep philosophers, and did not set
               themselves down to consider why and wherefore all things
               should be done. They smoked their pipes, and never once
               thought of philology, or ethnography, or any other word, that
               might help men, two hundred and thirty-six years afterwards,
               to trace ties of affinities, physical or moral. They were content to call themselves the people of Manhattan Island--that
               is to say, the people of the whirlpool. Here is both good
               history and sound philology, and should the reader like it, we
               may, perchance, tell him, hereafter, who these ancient Man-hattanese were, and how they danced, and roved, and whoop-ed, and cut all sorts of savage antics, on the very spots where
               theatres, and churches, and exchanges, and great hotels are
               now erected,--aye, they were not afraid to worship the devil
               himself, on the identical place where the most "tried" bishops, now rule or abide.
            </p>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">H. R. S.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">Singular Anecdote of a Cat</div>
            <div class="biblPage">56</div>
            <div class="head">SINGULAR ANECDOTE OF A CAT.</div>
            
            <p>During a hard snow storm last winter, a kitten with a
               broken leg hopped into the hall door of a gentleman's house
               in Brooklyn, and began a piteous mewing. He ordered one
               of the servants to throw the kitten into the street, when his
               little daughter, a lovely child of eight years, caught it in her
               arms and begged to be allowed to keep it and nurse it.
               The father refused, but the child begged so earnestly that
               he at last allowed her to keep it.
            </p>
            
            <p>The child nursed her pet until it got well, and the cat, unlike the majority of its species, returned all the fondness of
               its gentle nurse.
            </p>
            
            <p>A few weeks since the little girl took sick and was confined to her bed, and it was almost impossible to keep the
               cat away from her. As the child grew sicker the cat grew
               more troublesome, by mewing and constantly jumping upon
               the bed where she lay. It was impossible to drive her out
               of the room, until at last, the child being near her end, the
               cat stretched herself out near the bed and appeared to be
               dying; it was taken into an adjoining room and put upon a
               rug. "Take care of my poor kitten," said the little girl, as
               she saw them take it away.
            </p>
            
            <p>In a few hours the child died, and when they went into
               the adjoining room the cat lay dead upon the rug.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p9">
         <div class="biblTitle">"Mi Boy" and "The Brigadier"</div>
         <div class="biblPage">57</div>
         
         <p>We gave last week a column or two to the peculiarities of Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="npwillis">Willis</span> as a prose writer; we present the public this
            week with a full-length portrait of that popular author, together with one of his
            popular coadjutor, which represents
            them at their favorite Mirror. We have represented them in this manner, because their
            names are so identified with the
            Mirror, that, without it, no likeness of them could be considered perfect. The Brigadier,
            for a similar reason, is represented in his epaulettes. For the last twenty years he has been known to the New York
            public, as the Colonel, or the
            General. At his Benefit, the other night, we observed that he was called in the bills,
            
            <span class="person" id="gpmorris">George P. Morris</span>, Esq. It was
            the first time that we ever saw those mysterious letters, E.S.Q. attached to his name.
            We did what we could for his
            benefit then, and we hope that our endeavors now will be in some manner beneficial
            to him.
         </p>
         
         <p>The names of 
            <span class="person" id="gpmorris">Morris</span> and 
            <span class="person" id="npwillis">Willis</span> have been too long associated together to admit of their being parted in an illustration.
         </p>
         
         <div class="figure">
            <div class="head">"MI BOY," AND "THE BRIGADIER."</div>
            
            <div class="ab">"Hereafter both Editors will devote all their time exclusively to the Mirror."
               
               <br></br>                                               Prospectus of the New Mirror.
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Original Poetry</div>
         
         <div class="head">Original Poetry.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">Now is Always Best</div>
            <div class="biblPage">58</div>
            <div class="head">NOW IS ALWAYS BEST.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Dreamy river of the Past,
               
               <br></br>Flowing into darkness slowly,
               
               <br></br>Many a blossom I have cast
               
               <br></br>On thy waters, now made holy
               
               <br></br>By an idle melancholy;
               
               <br></br>Give me but a leaflet back,
               
               <br></br>Though quite wilted, ere thy track
               
               <br></br>Shall be lost in midnight wholly!
               
               <br></br>Give me one, I ask no more,
               
               <br></br>Though it be but from the store
               
               <br></br>Of some childish, by-gone folly!
               
               
               <br></br>Ah me! in a heavy mood,
               
               <br></br>Such as I to-night am bearing,
               
               <br></br>Any thing that's past is good;
               
               <br></br>All the present is but caring,
               
               <br></br>All the future more despairing,
               
               <br></br>And the past is sweet alone,
               
               <br></br>Where, although the sun be gone,
               
               <br></br>Half the sky is warm with wearing
               
               <br></br>His last kiss, and in the East
               
               <br></br>A faint glow, of lights the least,
               
               <br></br>Tells that moon-rise is preparing.
               
               
               <br></br>When was ever joy like thine,
               
               <br></br>Whose memory, even, is juvenescent?
               
               <br></br>Then my blood was more than wine,
               
               <br></br>Then I slumbered like a peasant,
               
               <br></br>Then my hope was like a crescent
               
               <br></br>That could never come to full,
               
               <br></br>Then, if ever, life looked dull,
               
               <br></br>Dulness must for once be pleasant,
               
               <br></br>Then my heart so lightly beat
               
               <br></br>That the sunshine seemed more sweet
               
               <br></br>Even for being evanescent.
               
               
               <br></br>Idle fancies! would I change
               
               <br></br>The hard present, with its swinking,
               
               <br></br>With its hopes of broader range,
               
               <br></br>Past and Future strangely linking
               
               <br></br>By their privilege of thinking,--
               
               <br></br>Would I change it for their Old,
               
               <br></br>Which, for all its cups of gold,
               
               <br></br>Gives us but poor dregs for drinking?
               
               <br></br>Would I change it for the past?
               
               <br></br>Make ease first, and labor last?
               
               <br></br>Out on such unmanly shrinking!
               
               
               <br></br>Mine the Present! That is best,
               
               <br></br>Let what will have gone before it;
               
               <br></br>Here my heart shall build her nest,
               
               <br></br>With green leaves to rustle o'er it;
               
               <br></br>When there's sunshine, she shall store it
               
               <br></br>As the moss does, 'gainst the hour
               
               <br></br>When the clouds come into power,
               
               <br></br>And from her own garners pour it
               
               <br></br>All around, until the sun
               
               <br></br>Come again, ere half's outrun,
               
               <br></br>And with tenfold grace restore it.
               
               
               <br></br>After both are over and gone,
               
               <br></br>What care I for sun or shower?
               
               <br></br>While there's earth to stand upon,
               
               <br></br>Spite of both the heart can flower;
               
               <br></br>In herself is all her power;
               
               <br></br>Fancy, too, can build a home
               
               <br></br>Higher than where change can come,
               
               <br></br>And the soul hath still her dower
               
               <br></br>Of high faith and purpose vast,
               
               <br></br>Where, though earth in night be cast,
               
               <br></br>She waits firm as in a tower.
            </div>
            
            <div class="byline">                      
               <span class="person">JAMES RUSSELL LOWELL</span>.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">An Epigram, On Certain Conservatives</div>
            <div class="biblPage">58</div>
            <div class="head">AN EPIGRAM,
               On Certain Conservatives.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>In olden days men's ears were docked
               
               <br></br>For thinking, and for other crimes;
               
               <br></br>And now, some worthies overstocked
               
               <br></br>With these commodities are shocked
               
               <br></br>At the false mercy of the times,
               
               <br></br>Which spoils their chance of being shortened
               
               <br></br>In their own feature most important.
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="head">The Fine Arts.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">Horace Kneeland</div>
            <div class="biblPage">58</div>
            <p>Horace Kneeland, the sculptor, has in his studio in the
               Granite Building corner of Chambers street and Broadway,
               two remarkably fine busts, which for integrity of expression
               are equal to any that we have seen by Powers. They are
               of Professor Mapes and Captain Ericcson: the first is in marble. Mr. Kneeland only requires to be more extensively
               known to be more fully employed. He should go to Rome,
               for the name of it; for his countrymen cannot bring themselves to believe that an American can attain to anything
               like respectability in Art without breathing the atmosphere
               of Italy. Powers owes much of his reputation to the commendation of the Italians. This is hardly a matter of reproach to his countrymen; for we have so few works of Art
               amongst us, that we are not capable of judging of the relative merit of an artist, when compared with the great masters in Art. It takes a long while for common observers to
               appreciate any work of Art that is merely natural and sim-ple. If the Theseus or Antinous were set up at the corner
               of one of our streets, we doubt whether it would attract
               many admirers.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">The American Art-Union</div>
            <div class="biblPage">58</div>
            <p>The American Art-Union have selected for the subject of
               their next engraving, a picture by Durand, in the possession
               of Mr. Paulding, representing the capture of Major Andre.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p14">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Drama</div>
         <div class="biblPage">58</div>
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>A good natured friend, who seems to labor under a very
            erroneous impression, that we have an idea of setting the
            North River on fire, has entirely misunderstood the meaning
            of our initial remarks on the Theatres. We desire first to
            disabuse his mind in respect to the incendiary motives with
            which he has charged us, and next, to assure him that we
            only meant that our remarks on the Theatre should apply to
            the consideration in which the Theatre has always been held
            by that portion of the community in England and America,
            whom the world call religious. The Theatre has long held
            an anomalous position among Englishmen. There is very
            little difference between Great Britain and America, in this
            respect, and our remarks are meant for both countries. The
            critic of the Mirror, asked the other day, "Are our Theatres
            worthy of support?" But that is not the important question.
            WHY ARE THEY NOT? is the great question. We said that
            the Theatre had not been a reputable profession since the
            time of Queen Elizabeth. This our friend disputes. But we
            cannot fix upon any point when it has been so considered.
            It was not in 
            <span class="person" id="jdryden">Dryden</span>'s time; it was not in 
            <span class="person" id="">Addison</span>'s; it was
            not in 
            <span class="person" id="dgarrick">Garrick</span>'s; it was not in 
            <span class="person" id="rbsheridan">Sheridan</span>'s. Assuredly, it has
            not been since. In 
            <span class="person" id="dgarrick">Garrick</span>'s time, the Church of Scotland
            expelled one of its ministers for writing a tragedy; an earl
            disowned his daughter for marrying a player, who was in
            other respects, an estimable man. There is not a clergyman
            in New York, who would dare to be seen in one of our Theatres, with his family. Yet clergymen go with their families
            to the Concert-room, and other places of purely idle amusement, without fear of reproach. In France, where the Drama
            is a national amusement, and the Theatres are partly supported from the public treasury, actors were long denied
            Christian burial, and even 
            <span class="person" id="jbpoquelin">Moliere</span>, was refused this sacred
            rite by a churlish priest. There is a reason for the odium
            which attaches to the Theatre, and it is worth inquiring into.
            It is a very easy thing, but not always safe, to charge those
            with ignorance who happen to differ with you in opinion; or
            charge one with putting a match to the North River, when
            he only walked down to the shore to bathe his hands. We
            thought that our friend's magazine of mischief was stored
            with harder missiles than these cheap witticisms.
         </p>
         
         <p>We cut the following seemingly just remarks on the drama
            from an essay on Landscape Painting in a late English publication.
         </p>
         
         <p>"It will be acknowledged at once that, of all modes of rendering an
            imitation of an event, the stage possesses the greatest power. It has
            the advantage of uniting the concentrated capabilities of painting,
            poetry, and music. Instead of being limited, like painting, to the
            representation of one moment of time, and those incidents out of the
            many which took place only in such moment, the mind is prepared by
            a continued run of events, for the development of some grand burst
            of tragedy--the poetry uttered by the choicest language of passion,
            the picture formed of living man, under the highest emotion, and relieved upon a back ground of music, rushing in harmonious surges, or
            gliding through thrilling melodies, from one appropriate and sustaining
            character of pathos to another, as the subject may demand."
         </p>
         
         <p>The difficulties of dramatic representation are owing to
            these very causes which the author considers its advantage.
            Poetry, music, and painting are entirely distinct arts, and can
            lend no aid to each other. If Ole Bul had been surrounded by
            a panorama of Niagara Falls in his late performance, wherein
            he aimed at conveying by sound, an idea of the cataract, he
            could never have succeeded in impressing his audience with
            an idea of the real scene--the eye would have been continually
            breaking in upon the abstraction of the ear. But the greatest
            disadvantage in dramatic representation, arises from the necessity of employing real men as actors, while all around
            them is artificial. The incongruity arising from this necessity
            will always prevent a perfect illusion, in a dramatic performance. The Greeks, by giving to the persons of their drama,
            the appearance of artificial men and women by covering their
            faces with masks, and rejecting all attempts at scenic illusion,
            produced effects of terror and mirth, which the modem stage,
            with all its aids, has never been able to accomplish. The
            Greek women were certainly not more effeminate than the
            delicate ladies of our own time; yet we hear of no swoonings
            at our Theatres, such as took place in the time of AEschylus;
            when, as Miss 
            <span class="person" id="ebbrowning">Barrett</span> says,
         </p>
         
         <p>"The women swooned to see so awful."</p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="dgarrick">Garrick</span> played Hamlet in a bob-wig and laced coat, and
            produced an impression which none of his successors have
            been able to do, with all the aids of black velvet and glass
            beads. It would really be less offensive to good taste to see
            Hamlet personated by a player in a coat and pantaloons, than
            in the dress in which he is now presented. This being a
            thinking age, and a searching age, two thirds of any audience mnst feel the absurdity of dressing a Danish prince of
            the supposed time of Hamlet, in the fancy gear which actors
            generally wear. We have seen actresses personate Ophelia
            with tropical flowers in their hair in the mad scene. There
            is no reason why the stage should not be as perfect in its representations of nature and society as any other department
            of art. Macready wears a dress in Macbeth which all the
            wealth of Scotland could not have purchased in the days o
            the Thane of Cawdor. The barbarisms committed by Macbeth and his wife, are utterly repugnant to the refinement of
            their apparel. In the banquet scene the tables are generally
            set out with dishes of pine-apples and oranges; in a climate
            where carraways and pippins have never been heard of.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p15">
         <div class="biblTitle">Operas and Concerts</div>
         <div class="biblPage">59</div>
         <div class="head">OPERAS AND CONCERTS.</div>
         
         <p>After a short, but highly successful, musical season, we
            are likely, it seems, to be left entirely to our own resources
            for our musical entertainments. The English Opera company have left us for the South, after having coined dollars by
            the thousands; and the Italian company, it is currently reported, is bound under engagement to proceed at once to
            New Orleans. This last item, however, we look upon as
            mere hear-say, or probably a lure thrown out by the friends
            of the artists to accelerate the in-coming of subscriptions for
            another season. But, whether it be true or not, there cannot
            be a doubt but that the absence of Pico and Borghese will
            prove a terrible blow to the amusement of the "Upper Ten
            Thousand." Into what channel the intensely concentrated
            enthusiasm of this discriminating class will flow, it is impossible to predict; but we believe that the turning of a hair
            would transfer this variable stream to the Park theatre, now
            that the mere bipeds have been driven forth to seek their
            bread, and are judiciously succeeded by the more sagacious,
            whose wants are carefully attended to, particularly the food.
         </p>
         
         <p>We greatly distrust this violent and sudden excitement
            about the Italian Opera. It is not the expression of a discriminating and healthy public appreciation, but it is rather the
            fussy clamor of a set or clique, with no further end in view
            than the passing away of idle hours, combined with affected
            display of dress and fashion. We are by no means opposed
            to the establishing of an Italian opera here, but we have little faith in it as a means of aiding the cause of music, or of
            musical taste. We shall probably discuss this subject more
            fully in a future number.
         </p>
         
         <p>Borghese and Pico have had their benefits in the fullest
            sense of the word. On each occasion the house was crowded in every part. Hundreds of dollars were expended upon
            bushel baskets of flowers, and Borghese circulated among the
            audience an envious imitation of the Carrier's New Year's
            address, in which her patrons (oh! artistical degradation!)
            were lauded with the usual amount of flummery. We look
            upon this as altogether a very notable piece of absurdity,
            even exceeding the usual limits assigned to a beneficiary.
         </p>
         
         <p>The success of the English Opera at the Park Theatre has
            been more to our satisfaction, for the reason that its efforts
            are more beneficial to the mass. The circle of its influence
            is more extended, and the solace of its charms falls upon a
            class which needs most greatly this softening and refining
            amusement.
         </p>
         
         <p>Music is a necessity to the rich, for custom has made it so,
            and heavy-footed time has strengthened the custom; but
            music is a luxury to the poor--whose luxuries are few--and
            that which will tend however remotely to ameliorate the
            condition, or sweeten the labor of those who struggle with
            the world, should always demand our earliest attention and
            warmest advocacy.
         </p>
         
         <p>Madame Arnoult's Concert.--This lady made her first
            appearance before a New York audience on Friday the 17th
            inst. at the Tabernacle. The weather was very much against
            her: it stormed all the day, and persisted in wearing an appearance of gloom and discomfort, long after the hour appointed for the commencement of the concert. The audience
            assembled, in number eight or nine hundred, was possibly
            the most fashionable ever seen in the Tabernacle. We noticed the heads of most of the sterling families in the city,--
            proving how warm an interest is taken in the best circles, in
            the good cause of this worthy lady.
         </p>
         
         <p>Madame Pico, Signora Borghese, Signori Antognini, Sanquirico, Tomasi, with Messrs. Etienne and J. A. Kyle, assisted on this occasion, and, as the bills state, gave their services to Madame Arnoult.</p>
         
         <p>The fair beneficiary comes before us in a doubtful light-doubtful, we mean, as regards her liability to suffer our criticism. She has hitherto exercised her vocal abilities for the
            amusement of her friends. She now comes before the public
            to redeem the fortunes of her husband, but whether or not
            she has finally adopted music as her profession, we are not
            informed. We will, however, make a few remarks upon her
            capacity, as evidenced upon this occasion. She has a light
            soprano voice of good compass, but of moderate power. Her
            intonation is generally good, her execution is very neat and
            rapid, her voice being very flexible, while her enunciation is
            distinct. Yet with all these good points, she has much to
            learn, ere she can become an efficient public performer.
            There is a want of a decided style, a want of emphasis and
            energy--in short, a want of those essentials which, though
            trifling to name, are of the utmost consequence to a public
            singer. However, with good care and judicious advice, Madame Arnoult will, ere long, have little to fear. May she
            go on and prosper.
         </p>
         
         <p>Most of the other artists are too well known to the public
            to need our comment upon the present occasion. We will
            however say, that Mr. Kyle's solo on the flute, was played
            most charmingly,--with taste, brilliancy and expression.
         </p>
         
         <p>General Morris's Complementary Concert.--This generous testimony to Mr. Morris as a man and worthy citizen,
            fully equalled, in its results, the expectations of the friendly
            projectors. We are told that he netted some two thousand
            dollars. He was called out between the parts, and responded
            to the call in a few words neatly turned;--he would have
            said more, but his heart rose to his throat, and his honeyed
            words were distilled into tears, and he retired.
         </p>
         
         <p>Some of our contemporaries have shown a disposition to
            question the claims of the General to a Complimentary Benefit. But those who gave their services on the occasion
            should be allowed to be the best judges. Those who attended the concert certainly got the worth of their money; and
            let the General's claims have been what they might, he need
            feel under no obligations to his audience. The silly custom
            of throwing bouquets at ladies on the stage, should never be
            practised by an audience pretending to the smallest degree of
            refinement. If the money which these kind of compliments
            cost was enclosed to the beneficiary, it would no doubt be infinitely more acceptable than in the shape of faded camelias.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p16">
         <div class="biblTitle">Places Worth Visiting</div>
         <div class="biblPage">60</div>
         <div class="head">PLACES WORTH VISITING.</div>
         
         <p>The sights best worth seeing in New York, may be visited
            free of cost. This is an important fact, which strangers, in
            particular, are not aware of, and they waste a good deal of
            time and money in sight-seeing, with but little pleasure, or
            profit to themselves, for the lack of a suitable guide to the
            places really worth visiting.
         </p>
         
         <p>The upper part of the city, particularly in the avenues west
            of Broadway, has always something new to attract a stranger, and even a citizen, in the shape of an Italian villa, or a
            Gothic church. These architectural exhalations are continually rising from the earth i this part of the town, and if they
            are not always elegant, they are always novel. It is a well
            known fact in natural history, that where an oak forest is
            cut down, a pine forest springs up in its place. The soil of
            Manhattan Island possesses some peculiarity akin to that on
            which oaken forests grow. Wherever an old Dutch house
            is pulled down, a Gothic church is almost certain to spring
            up in its place. It is our intention to give engravings of all
            these new churches and villas; but our arrangements for that
            purpose are not yet entirely completed to our satisfaction.
         </p>
         
         <p>One of the most enchanting places, at this season, is Thorburn's flower depot, in John street; apart from his picture
            gallery, which alone is worth visiting, his bow-window,
            formed of the purest plate glass, is the great point of attraction. Here may be seen the latest chrysanthemums, and the
            earliest hyacinths; a rare cactus of some kind is always in
            bloom, and the whitest of camelias here open their delicate
            petals; here, too, of a forenoon, may be seen every day, a
            collection of bouquets, which will be exhibited in the evening
            by some young lady, to an exclusive circle only. Mr. Thorburn must be a benevolent hearted man, to make so precious
            an exhibition for the benefit of the public, without charging
            them any thing in return. A churl would not do so good
            natured an act.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Daguerrian galleries are very attractive places, and we
            do not know of a more agreeable room to while away an
            idle hour in, than the Plumbe establishment, on the corner of
            Barclay street. The rooms are well fitted up, the proprietors
            gentlemanly and obliging, and their collection of authentic
            portraits of people whom one would like to know, very extensive. The workmen in this establishment are artists,
            who will not allow an imperfect likeness to leave their hands.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Coleman has a fine collection of curious books, which
            he is always happy to exhibit to the public free of cost. His
            windows have a crowd about them in all weathers, and we
            have seen many a pedestrian forget the rain, while looking
            in at them; but the best things are to be seen inside. In
            the upper part of his establishment he has fitted up a secluded little nook, away from all noise and dust, which seems
            always to be filled with sunshine, where a loiterer may
            spend an entire day for a shilling. Here will be found some
            very curious pictures, and a few very fine ones; among them
            are an original by Hans Holbein, a landscape, by Ruysdael,
            and a dying gladiator, by David. The walls are filled to
            excess with works worth looking at; and there are but a
            few not worthy of a place in a permanent gallery of art.
         </p>
         
         <p>Bartlett &amp; Welford's shop, in the Astor House, is another
            seductive place for the lover of rarities in the shape of books.
            Some of the finest illustrated works ever published, may be
            here inspected free of charge, and purchased at prices greatly
            below their first cost. These gentlemen are among the few
            instances of traders in literature, who know something of the
            articles they deal in. The senior partner is a good scholar,
            and an accomplished ethnologist. Besides the fine collection
            of old books to be found here, may be seen all the late French
            and English publications that have any thing to recommend
            them in the shape of illustrations.
         </p>
         
         <p>The rooms of the American Art-Union, is another cheap
            place of exhibition. Here may be found many works in
            sculpture and painting, the productions of our young artists
            who have not yet become sufficiently well-known to attract
            visitors to their studios; and who avail themselves of the
            opportunities afforded them by this excellent institution, to
            make themselves known to the world. Among the works
            now exhibited there, is an exceedingly fine landscape by
            Cafferty, a young artist who promises to rise very high in his
            profession.
         </p>
         
         <p>We shall resume this subject next week, and point out
            many other places well worth visiting.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Illustrated Magazines</div>
         <div class="head">ILLUSTRATED MAGAZINES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">Godey's Magazine and Lady's Book</div>
            <div class="biblPage">60</div>
            <p>Godey's Magazine and Lady's Book, Edited by Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="sjhale">Sarah J.
                  Hale
               </span>, 
               <span class="person" id="mmcmichael">Morton M'Michael</span> and 
               <span class="person" id="lagodey">Louis A. Godey</span>, presents an imposing
               array of Editors; but when taken in consideration with the list of
               contributors, they are truly formidable. No less than ten ladies and
               six gentlemen, besides the editors, have helped to fill the forty-six
               pages of this magazine. Probably a much greater number of writers
               than was ever employed on a single number of any of the great Reviews. But the great marvel is that so many writers should have been
               able to produce so small an amount of readable matter. The only
               article in the Magazine that will ever be read a second time, except
               by the writers of them, is the New Arabian Nights' Tale by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">Poe</span>.
               The idea of this tale is a very happy one, and it afforded the author a
               wide scope for displaying his exact knowledge and lively imagina
               tion; two qualities that we rarely find united in the same person.
               Scheherazade tells a new story, more wondrous than any that she had
               related before, a continuation of Sinbad's adventures, wherein are related some of the modern discoveries in science, which startle the
               king more than any of the doings of the Genii. At last, when the
               narrator tells of women who wear artificial humps on their backs, he
               grows impatient, and believing that his Queen is imposing upon his
               credulity, orders her to be bow-strung. There are four engravings,
               two in mezzotint, and two in line, one of them an old design of Corbould's from a worn-out plate, and the other a very sweetly tinted
               picture of a sleeping child.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">Graham's Magazine of Literature and Art</div>
            <div class="biblPage">61</div>
            <p>Graham's Magazine of Literature and Art, Edited by the
               proprietor, 
               <span class="person" id="grgraham">Geo. R. Graham</span>, has but five ladies and thirteen gentlemen, for contributors to the February number. It has three engravings, in line, and a something which is called a portrait of 
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">Edgar A.
                  Poe
               </span>. It is poor as a work of art, and something much worse as a
               portrait. It is a gross wrong to Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">Poe</span>, and a fraud upon the purchasers of the Magazine. It bears no more resemblance to that gentleman than to any other of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="grgraham">Graham</span>'s contributors. But if it were
               much worse that it is, which is hardly conceivable, it would be amply
               compensated by the fine sketch of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="eapoe">Poe</span>'s genius, by 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span>, which
               accompanies it. The other engravings, excepting two wretched wood
               cuts, are very commendable specimens of art; that of the Blackfeet
               Indians, is the best that we have ever seen in this Magazine. There
               are some remarks on domestic architecture, which, not being attributed to any Contributor, we suppose are from the Editor's pen; we have
               rarely seen so many mistakes crowded into so small a space. The writer thinks that Gothic Architecture is best adapted to our use, because,
               "its dim religious light accords best with a Christian people." A
               plenty of light we should think accorded best with Christian feelings;
               and a plenty of windows, and large ones too, is one of the marked
               characteristics of the so-called Gothic style of Architecture. It was
               only in Pagan Temples, that a dim religious light was considered
               necessary.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Columbian Lady's and Gentleman's Magazine</div>
            <div class="biblPage">61</div>
            <p>The Columbian Lady's and Gentleman's Magazine, Edited by
               
               <span class="person" id="jinman">John Inman</span> and 
               <span class="person" id="rawest">Robert A. West</span>, contains four engravings of which
               we have already given an opinion. The plate of fashions for February presents some very curious figures, particularly the gentleman in a
               pink cravat, light green coat, dove colored trowsers and yellow kids.
               A fashion plate, to be of any value, should be as exact as a table of
               logarithms. By what process Mr. Post gets his fashions for February
               three months in advance, we do not know, but we think it would be
               rather unsafe for any of the ladies and gentlemen in the upper circles
               to have their dresses made in the style of his plate, without further
               advices from Paris. Trifles light as air, are to the fashionable confirmation strong enough, when coming from Paris; but we have doubts
               whether the firmans of Mr. Post have much weight in the fashionable
               world. The contributors to this number, are seven ladies and seven
               gentlemen. We see many names in both lists of great reputation,
               but it was our sole design in this notice, to speak of these periodicals,
               in reference to their decorations, and we are not therefore prepared to
               pronounce judgment upon the merit of their papers.
            </p>
            
            <p>These three magazines are so nearly alike, that if the covers were
               changed, it would not be easy to distinguish one from the other.
               They all have nearly the same contributors and the same embellishers. There are two of Chapman's designs in the Columbian, and
               one in Graham; and both have engravings from the same hands.
               Magazines of this class are peculiar to the United States. Nothing
               like them can be found in either England or France, saving La Belle
               Assemblee, which, if published now, must have a very limited circulation. They tell a humiliating story for the public taste, and our attainments in art. Illustrated periodicals in England, France and Germany, are very abundant and very cheap. But it would be difficult to
               find one in either country so poor in artistic design as either of these
               magazines. The only method of illustration that has been employed
               for many a year in Europe, in periodicals, has been by wood cuts.
               And it is the only style of art that can be fitly employed with letter
               press. In the infancy of the art, copper plates were employed from
               necessity; but since the art of wood engraving has reached the perfection which has distinguished it for the last twenty years, it has
               gradually superseded all other kinds of illustration; and steel engravings in a printed book are beginning to wear as incongruous an appearance as the gilding in old missals.
            </p>
            
            <p>These three magazines give us twelve plate engravings, without an
               original thought, or a subject of the least interest, excepting the view
               of Dr. Rose's Villa, in Graham. They must have cost a good deal of
               money, and we have no doubt that, the half of it expended in the
               encouragement of wood engraving from original designs, would have
               procured illustrations which would have given double the satisfaction
               that these smooth inanities will do. Once let the public get a taste of
               good wood cuts, and these trifles will soon vanish. We trust that the
               undertaking of our artists, to get out an illustrated edition of 
               <span class="person" id="wcbryant">Bryant</span>'s
               Poems, which we gave a hint of in our last number, will give the
               world an evidence that we can do something worth having in this important department of art.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s6">
         <div class="biblTitle">Literary Notices</div>
         <div class="head">LITERARY NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Life and Correspondence of Thomas Arnold</div>
            <div class="biblPage">61</div>
            <div class="ab">The Life and Correspondence of 
               <span class="person" id="tarnold">Thomas Arnold</span>, D.D. late Head Master of
               
               <br></br>Rugby School, and Regius Professor of Modern History in the University
               
               <br></br>of Oxford. By 
               <span class="person" id="apstanley">Arthur Penrhyn Stanley</span>, M. A. First American from the
               
               <br></br>third London Edition. D. Appleton &amp; Co. 1845. 1 vol. 12mo. pp. 516.
            </div>
            
            <p>Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="tarnold">Arnold</span> was one of the very few men whose death was felt to
               be a loss to the world; and the full record of his life contained in this
               valuable volume, must of course be gratefully received by all who
               have any knowledge of his writings. The work by which he is best
               known in this country, is his Introduction to the Study of Modern
               History. His writings were very numerous, but those most widely 
               known, are the Lectures on Modern History, which are incomplete--
               and a History of Rome in three volumes, ending at the second Punic
               War.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers have done the public a service in reprinting this
               book; and we hope to see the practice followed by other publishers,
               which they have here introduced, of giving the edition from which
               the work is republished.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">Oneota, or the Red Race of America</div>
            <div class="biblPage">61</div>
            <div class="ab">Oneota, or the Red Race of America--their History, Tradition, Customs,
               
               <br></br>Poetry, Picture-Writing, &amp;c., in Extracts from Notes, Journals, and other
               
               <br></br>unpublished writings, by 
               <span class="person" id="hrschoolcraft">Henry R. Schoolcraft</span>. Nos. 1 to 4. Burgess,
               
               <br></br>Stringer &amp; Co. Price 25 cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>The first time that we saw Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hrschoolcraft">Schoolcraft</span> personally, was at Michilimackinac, surrounded by a company of noble looking fellows, of
               the race whose history is so fully elucidated in the work before us.
               His name is so familiarly connected with Indian tradition and customs, that any work on these subjects, bearing his name, must meet
               with a favorable reception from his countrymen. Oneota is a work of
               very miscellaneous character, but all its miscellanies tend to the
               elucidation of one subject. It is well printed and properly illustrated,
               not with unmeaning pictures of effeminate looking Indians, in fancy
               costumes, but with actual transcripts of their picture-writing--which
               prove one thing very clearly--that Art, in her first rugged attempts at
               delineating nature, and in her last effeminate endeavor at the same
               object, stands at about the same distance from the object aimed at.
               There is abundant reading in these numbers tor the mere idler in literature, as well as for the student in Ethnology and Archaeology.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Southern Quarterly Review</div>
            <div class="biblPage">61</div>
            <div class="ab">The Southern Quarterly Review. No. XII. Charleston, S. C.</div>
            
            <p>This is a very respectable looking periodical, hardly if at all infeferior to the North American, or any of the foreign Quarterlies, in its
               externals. It must have been very quietly conducted, for we do not remember ever having heard it spoken of, or of seeing it in any of our
               bookstores or reading rooms. It professes to advocate Southern interests, but it is conducted by a New England man, Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="dkwhitaker">Whitaker</span>, the
               son of a Unitarian clergyman, who preached, once, in New Bedford.
               Any literary publication that narrows itself down to so small a compass as South Carolina prejudices must, of course, be exceedingly
               narrow in its moral dimensions. But we do not find anything very exclusive in this number, excepting an article on Annexation--which,
               being written by a professed admirer of Mr. Calhoun, is, of course,
               strongly impregnated with the flavor of his prejudices. The longest
               article in the Review is devoted to the writings of 
               <span class="person" id="cmathews">Cornelius Matthews</span>.
               While the reviewer complains in no moderate terms of the hardships
               of American authors, arising from lack of sympathy among their own
               countrymen, he does not, himself, appear to be aware that there are
               any other American writers beside the subject of his paper and Judge
               
               <span class="person" id="ablongstreet">Longstreet</span>. He hints at 
               <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span> and 
               <span class="person" id="sebasmith">Jack Downing</span>, but makes no
               mention of any other American author. While talking about home, his
               eyes are stretched across the water. Probably he does not consider
               the Northern States as a part of the Union. He denies the quality of
               humor to any American author, and appears to be profoundly ignorant of the existence of 
               <span class="person" id="wirving">Washington Irving</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="nhawthorne">Hawthorn</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jneal">Joseph Neal</span>,
               
               <span class="person" id="jkpaulding">Paulding</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="owholmes">Holmes</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="sands">Sands</span>, and a score or two more. In speaking of Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="cmathews">Matthews</span>' merits, he makes him run the gauntlet through a host of
               tall men from the time of 
               <span class="person" id="homer">Homer</span> down to 
               <span class="person" id="cdickens">Dickens</span>; as a poet, he
               measures him with the Greeks; as a dramatist, with 
               <span class="person" id="jfletcher">Fletcher</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="wcongreve">Congreve</span>, and 
               <span class="person" id="">Shakspeare</span>; as a humorist, with 
               <span class="person" id="whogarth">Hogarth</span>; as a novelist,
               with 
               <span class="person" id="">Fielding</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="tgsmollett">Smollet</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="wscott">Scott</span>, and 
               <span class="person" id="cdickens">Dickens</span>. This is a rather severe
               trial, but the reviewer entertains a high opinion of the genius of Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="cmathews">Matthews</span>, notwithstanding the cruel test that he tries him by. The
               article is written in a very grave and solemn tone, but it contains two
               witticisms, though they are of a rather ponderous character; he calls
               the English John Ox, and the Irish Sans Potato. Without quarrelling
               with him for emasculating the national emblem of the English, we
               must object to the new name for the Irish--it should be Sans-everything-but-Potato, if sans anything.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Waif</div>
            <div class="biblPage">62</div>
            <div class="ab">The Waif--A Collection of Poems.
               
               <br></br>Poems by 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">James R. Lowell</span>.
               
               <br></br>Voices of the Night, by 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>. Cambridge: Published by James
               
               <br></br>     Owen. 1845.
            </div>
            
            <p>To catch the eye is as desirable and almost as indispensable in
               bookselling as in other branches of trade. Nor do we object to successful experiment of the kind where the fair promise thus volunteered
               is kept "to the hope." Such is the case with the three volumes mentioned above. The are bound in illuminated paper covers, and have
               altogether more tempting exteriors than any specimens of American
               book-making we have seen. Something at once cheeerful and mysterious, radiates from the bright arabesque designs that glow like the
               missals of old. A more dainty and appropriate style for works of elegant literature can scarcely be imagined, and we hope Mr. Owen will
               persevere in furnishing readers of taste with volumes equally delightful. One advantage of this kind of binding is, that it is easily replaced
               by more substantial when defaced; an especial convenience to those
               who adopt uniform covers in arranging their libraries. As regards the
               contents of the volumes, it is almost superfluous to speak. "The
               Waif" is a collection of fugitive pieces, most of which are familiar to
               the lovers of poetry--such as the "Lament of the Irish Emigrant,"
               
               <span class="person" id="hsmith">Horace Smith</span>'s "Ode to the Flowers," and other gems by 
               <span class="person" id="pbshelley">Shelley</span>,
               
               <span class="person" id="thood">Hood</span>, and some of the old poets. 
               <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>, the compiler, has annexed a beautiful poem of his own. This author's "Voices of the
               Night" will be very acceptable to his admirers in its new and elegant
               dress, and Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jrlowell">Lowell</span>'s volume not less so to those who sympathize
               with his muse.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <div class="biblTitle">Dunigan's Illustrated Edition of the Bible</div>
            <div class="biblPage">62</div>
            <div class="ab">Dunigan's Illustrated Edition of the Bible, according to the Douay and 
               
               <br></br>Rheimish Versions--Nos. 15 and 16.
            </div>
            
            <p>The illustration given with these two numbers, is an exceedingly
               neat border, with a Vignette to a Parent's Register. The illustrations
               of the past numbers have all been from celebrated pictures. If the remainder should contain as many illustrations from good pictures, the
               work would be worth having for the illustrations alone.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         <div class="biblTitle">Literary Intelligence</div>
         <div class="biblPage">62</div>
         <div class="head">LITERARY INTELLIGENCE.</div>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="sjones">Silas Jones</span>, Esq., the author of an Introduction to the
            Study of Legal Science, has a new work on Conveyancing,
            nearly ready for the press.
         </p>
         
         <p>We are informed that Mr. 
            <span class="person" id="rwgriswold">Griswold</span> will read the introduction to his new work on the Prose Writers of America,
            before the New York Historical Society, next month.
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="awbradford">Alexander W. Bradford</span>, the author of American Antiquities, has a work nearly ready for publication, on the Manners and Customs of the Ancient Mexicans.
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <span class="person" id="pbenjamin">Park Benjamin</span> and 
            <span class="person" id="hcwatson">Henry C. Watson</span>, have issued proposals for publishing a new weekly paper, to be called "The
            Musical Gazette and Register of the Fine Arts."
         </p>
         
         <p>Lea &amp; Blanchard, we are informed, are going to issue illustrated editions of 
            <span class="person" id="wcbryant">Bryant</span>'s, 
            <span class="person" id="hwlongfellow">Longfellow</span>'s, 
            <span class="person" id="fghalleck">Halleck</span>'s and
            
            <span class="person" id="rhdana">Dana</span>'s Poems.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s7">
         <div class="biblTitle">Varieties</div>
         <div class="head">VARIETIES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p26">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Meanness of English Life</div>
            <div class="biblPage">62</div>
            <div class="head">THE MEANNESSES OF ENGLISH LIFE.</div>
            
            <p>English travellers choose to express a good deal of horror
               for our crying sins, for which, perhaps, we have no right to
               complain. Our stabbing of members of State Legislatures,
               repudiating millions of debts, keeping three millions of fellow beings in bondage, and other offences of like magnitude,
               have all something grandiose and immense about them,
               which must give our enemies a magnificent idea of the national character. Great crimes are never perpetrated by
               paltry characters. Among all the affairs laid to our door by
               our British friends, meanness has never been enumerated.
               But if we are to believe one half of what the English tell of
               themselves, they are the meanest people in the world in their
               social relations. A year or two ago the Literary Gazette
               contained a series of papers under the head of "London one
               Lie," in which the paltry practices of the Cockneys were set
               forth, representing a littleness of character which could not
               be paralleled in any part of our Union.
            </p>
            
            <p>The practices of respectable tradesmen and royal servants,
               as exposed in the following dialogue, would make our smallest
               shopkeepers and lowest menials blush if charged with. Yet
               they are freely acknowledged by London tradesmen of high
               respectability, without causing any great astonishment.
            </p>
            
            <p>Bless me, here is another illustration of my exposures! Candles;
               and brought very properly to trial before that worthy and sagacious
               police magistrate, Mr. Hard-Wick. I have thought of candles; but
               this information before him beats even my information on the frauds.
            </p>
            
            <p>Pri. and Phi. What is it? what is it?</p>
            
            <p>Aunt M. A gentleman's under butler has been taken before his
               worship, having been detected in selling boxes of candles, whole and
               half-burnt, to a chandler in St. Martin's Lane. Their first price was
               2s. 2d. or 2s. 4d.; and the butler re-sold them at 9d. or 10d. per lb.
            </p>
            
            <p>Phi. Yes, yes, but they had been half-burnt?</p>
            
            <p>Aunt M. Many no doubt had been lighted, which is in itself a common deception, as you may notice in hundreds of London shop-windows; but they are lighted by the shop-keepers themselves.</p>
            
            <p>Pri. Surely they would lose by that!</p>
            
            <p>Aunt M. Not a farthing in 20 lbs. The wick is merely blackened
               and the other end is pared off into the melting-pots, and they are exhibited as best wax candles from the royal palaces or some other almost
               royal residence.
            </p>
            
            <p>Phi. I have seen the royal candle-ends with my own eyes delivered
               at the shop doors, from boxes with royal arms.
            </p>
            
            <p>Aunt M. And so have I; but that is all to aid imposition. The
               candles so vamped are of inferior materials; the inner part being one
               of several mixtures, which I shall hereafter explain to you, and only
               the outer casing of wax. I have found them so little combined, that I
               could push the interior small compound, 1-4 of an inch in diameter,
               out of its real wax wrapper, and make the latter like the tube of a --
            </p>
            
            <p>Phi. Pea-shooter.</p>
            
            <p>Aunt M. Exactly! And then the parings! Do you know there
               are but three houses in the wax trade who supply royalty; and in
               these economic days, they receive back the mass of the fragments
               (not the far gone bits), and pay half price for it to re-melt; and as
               for scraping the ends to fit them for chandeliers and candlesticks, the
               lord steward would speedily dismiss the officer or menial who dared
               to venture on such a perquisite. Whenever you see such, be aware
               they are unacquainted with a palace.
            </p>
            
            <p>Pri. Did Mr. Hard-Wick find this out?</p>
            
            <p>Aunt M. No, my dear; but when the master chandler came be
               fore him respecting the charge against his servant for purchasing the
               butler's ware, he frankly told the magistrate about some of the practices of the trade, which he at last deemed worthy of public exposure.
               He said he was sorry to say that many persons who called themselves
               respectable oilmen and wax-chandlers encouraged servants to rob
               their masters, and mentioned the names of several highly respectable
               tradesmen who did so. As they, however, did, he was obliged to do
               the same, and had been in the habit of doing so ever since he was an
               apprentice. He could assure gentlemen that if they would take these
               affairs into their own hands, they would save from 50 to 75 per cent
               in oil and candles alone. He was now prepared to state a case in
               which a butler had robbed his master to the amount of 75 per cent
               upon the article of sperm oil alone. After some farther agreeable
               chat, he repeated that if he did not buy from servants, like the rest,
               he might shut up shop directly, as he should be ruined were he not to
               comply with the custom of the trade.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            <div class="biblTitle">Letter from an Anxious Father</div>
            <div class="biblPage">62</div>
            <div class="head">LETTER FROM AN ANXIOUS FATHER.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">To the Editor of the Broadway Journal.</div>
            
            <p>Sir,--I am the father of two young men, still in their minority,
               whom I have educated for the profession of a Merchant. They have
               always paid implicit attention to my requests, and it has ever been
               one of the chief sources of my happiness to look forward to the time
               when they should be safely established in the business for which I
               have trained them. But latterly their conduct has given me many
               anxious moments. Instead of spending their evenings at home in
               improving conversation or study, as I would have them do; they rarely
               remain an hour in the house after dark. Their time is wholly employed in waiting upon young ladies of their acquaintance to balls, parties,
               and concerts. It is a source of pride to me, I must confess, to know
               that they are sought after, and that the education which I have given
               them, makes their company desirable, but I fear that their minds will
               be too much engrossed with frivolous matters, and that all my hopes
               of their respectability hereafter, will be disappointed. What makes 
               the case worse, is the fact that my wife and sisters secretly encourage
               them in setting my authority at defiance, by telling them that I was, at
               their age, one of the wildest young men about town, and a very great
               hand with the ladies. This is excessively mortifying to me, because
               I cannot deny it, for the date of my marriage, at a very early age, is
               put upon the family record. But it appears to me that times have
               changed, and that young men are not so prudent as they were before I
               was married. I have written this note to you, hoping that you will
               suggest some plan for inducing young gentlemen to remain contentedly
               at home with their own family. I tell my sons that I would ask for
               no greater happiness than to change places with them, and be allowed
               the privilege of spending a quiet evening with my parents, who have
               long been, as I trust, in Heaven. The only reply they make is, that
               they have no doubt of having the same feelings when they reach my
               age. But I do doubt it, for it is very evident that the young men of
               the present day cannot compare with the youths of the last century.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Your obedient servant.</div>
            George S. Prudence.
            
            <div class="note">P. S. You will confer a favor on all parents, by showing up the evil
               influences of the whole brood of writers of the Charles O'Malley school,
               who, I fear, together with a very Harry Lorruqueer-ish young gentleman, from Dublin, with whom my boys have formed an intimacy, are
               doing much to give them an appetite for frolicking and high life.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p30">
            <div class="biblTitle">To the Editor of the Broadway Journal</div>
            <div class="biblPage">63</div>
            <div class="ab">To the Editor of the Broadway Journal:
               
               <br></br>   Dear Sir,
            </div>
            
            <p>Generally speaking, "advice gratis" is anything but acceptable,
               but the example of Buonaparte in this respect is not unworthy of imitation. You will recollect he ascertained the opinions of his friends,
               and then followed his own inclination. As Sir Giles Overreach says,
               "Learn any thing from any creature--e'en from the devil himself-that can make thee great." But I am forgetting the object of this letter--touching the "Broadway Journal." As one of a considerable
               circle of social friends, I am requested to express their admiration
               and approval of your hebdomadal--of the high and manly tone of your
               articles--of your enlarged and liberal views on various subjects--the
               candor and elaborateness of your reviews, and in fact the general style
               and character of the work. Now there is one feature of the publication which they condemn, and that is the wood cuts. True, you have
               had but one, and a very beautiful specimen of the art it was, but you
               promise more. They say that they disfigure the work, and are unworthy of the "Broadway Journal"--that the space they will occupy
               might be more profitably filled with reading matter, and the expense
               more wisely applied to something of more real value.
            </p>
            
            <p>I am further directed to say, that this advice is perfectly gratuitous,
               and it is hoped you will receive it in that spirit, with which it is proffered. Trusting it may not prove intrusive, I am, in their behalf and
               my own,	                   One of a number of Subscribers.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are infinitely obliged by the kind advice contained in
               the above. We determined to give wood engravings in
               our paper with the sole view of giving encouragement to this
               art among us; but we necessarily incur a considerable expense in doing so, and it would better suit our interests to
               abandon the design. But we think it the only legitimate
               method of illustrating printed matter. It partakes of the
               quality of typography, and creates no incongruous feelings as
               the smoothness and delicacy of steel and lithographic engravings must do. Besides, it admits of a breadth and boldness of expression which can be given by no other method of
               pictorial illustration. Generally, we think that pictures
               should be kept apart from printed matter. They interfere
               with each other, and instead of helping to illustrate an idea,
               their mixed methods of conveying a thought tend to obscure
               it. In portraits, however, and architectural descriptions,
               drawings are necessary to convey correct ideas. In works
               of the imagination pictures always destroy the idea which
               the poet creates. Whoever has looked through a Byron Gallery, a Waverley Gallery, or a Shakspeare Gallery, must have
               felt this. It would be just as rational to give a pictorial illustration of Haydn's Surprise, as of the Midsummer Night's
               Dream.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p28">
         <div class="biblTitle">Notice to Readers and Correspondents</div>
         <div class="biblPage">63</div>
         
         <p>Notice to Readers and Correspondents.--Many thanks to our
            Hartford Correspondent for his valuable suggestions.
         </p>
         
         <p>The communication of "E. G. S." will appear in our next number.</p>
         
         <p>"G. H." will find a communication at our publishing office.</p>
         
         <p>The Tale by "P. S." is declined.</p>
         
         <p>"Matthew Truman" shall have a hearing next week.</p>
         
         <p>We shall give another wood-cut illustration in our next number, of a
            very peculiar character--representing a "Suspended Bishop."
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s8">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">63</div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DR. 
               <span class="person" id="tarnold">ARNOLD</span>'S LIFE AND CORRESPONDENCE.
            </div>
            
            <p>D. APPLETON &amp; CO. have just published, THE LIFE
               AND CORRESPONDENCE OF THOMAS ARNOLD, D.D.
               By Rev. 
               <span class="person" id="apstanley">E. P. Stanley</span>, M.A. From the Third English Edition, 2 vols.
               8vo. in 1 vol. 12mo. Price $1 50.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Life of Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="tarnold">Arnold</span> will be found to be of unusual value and interest to all literary persons, Heads of Colleges and Seminaries of
               Learning, Students and Teachers in public and private schools.
            </p>
            
            <p>No considerable review in England, representing either the high or
               low parties in Church or State--no weekly or daily publication has
               failed to express the wonderful power and beauty of this volume of
               Biography.
            </p>
            
            <p>NEW HISTORY OF THE FRENCH REVOLUTION. D. Appleton and Co. have recently published--History of the
               French Revolution--its causes and consequences; by 
               <span class="person" id="fmrowan">F. Maclean Rowan</span>; 2 vols 18mo, cloth 75 cts., or 1 vol. 63 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>"This work has many and valuable recommendations. Its compilation has been effected with care and good judgment; its style is essentially popular, its arrangements clear and methodical, and the
               whole form as condensed, comprehensive, and succinct a history of the
               most important event of this age, (both in itself and its consequences,)
               as we remember to have seen in so brief a space."--English Critic,
               Sept. 16, 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>In a few days, Part 2, price 25 cents--
               HISTORY OF FRANCE, from the earliest period;
               translated from the French of 
               <span class="person" id="jmichelet">M. Michelet</span>, by 
               <span class="person" id="ghsmith">G. H. Smith</span>.
            </p>
            
            <p>The celebrity of this work on the continent, and the want in English
               literature of a good history of France, has induced the publishers to
               introduce it to the American public at a price within the means of all.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
               The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow's
               professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">      Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo.                Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
               
               <br></br>    Joshua Herrick, Me.	                       John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               
               <br></br>     James Irvin, Pa.	                          J. Thompson, Miss.
               
               <br></br>Dr. A. G. Bigelow's Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">LEWIS KATEN, SIGN AND ORNAMENTAL PAINTER,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 45 WILLIAM STREET,
               
               <br></br>(BASEMENT OF THE LEATHER MANUFACTURERS' BANK.)
               
               <br></br>Block Letter Signs, Transparencies, Banners, &amp;c., Executed in the
               
               <br></br>neatest manner.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">GRAHAME'S UNITED STATES.</div>
            
            <p>THE HISTORY OF THE UNITED STATES OF
               NORTH AMERICA, from the plantation of the British Colonies
               till their revolt and Declaration of Independence. By 
               <span class="person" id="jgrahame">James Grahame</span>, Esq. In four volumes.
            </p>
            
            <p>The work will be put to press as soon as two hundred and fifty
               copies are subscribed for. It will be printed in an elegant style, equal
               to the last London edition, in four volumes octavo, and delivered to
               subscribers at two dollars a volume, in extra cloth binding.
            </p>
            
            <p> Subscribers names received and the books delivered by
               WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, New York.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Exploring Expedition.</div>
            
            <p>LEA &amp; BLANCHARD are preparing for publication,
               and will shortly issue, the Narrative of the United States
               Exploring Expedition, during the years 1838, 1839, 1840, 1841, and
               1842, by 
               <span class="person" id="cwilkes">CHARLES WILKES</span>, U.S.N., Commander of the Expedition, etc., etc., in five magnificent large imperial octavo volumes,
               with an Atlas of Large and Extended Maps. Price Twenty-five
               Dollars to Subscribers, done up in beautiful Extra Cloth Binding.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JOHN DOUGLAS,
               BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every de-
               
               <br></br>scription of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
               
               <br></br>with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, on terms which he feels con-
               
               <br></br>fident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">January 16, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">GENEALOGY OF GEORGE WASHINGTON.</div>
            
            <p>THIS day is published by Wm. A. COLMAN, No. 203
               Broadway, the Genealogy of George Washington, the celebrated Patriot. It is beautifully engraved, splendidly printed in gold
               and colors, and illuminated with the armorial bearings of the Washington Family and its alliances for a period of many centuries past;
               exhibiting at one view a complete family history. A space is left sufficiently large for any person who may desire to have his arms emblazoned on this elegant work, before he has it framed. Price $1,50.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Arms and Crests of individuals of all nations, found and emblazoned, equal in execution and correctness to the Herald's College
               of London, at reasonable charges.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">PROPOSALS FOR PUBLISHING BY SUBSCRIPTION,
               TRANSACTIONS
               OF THE
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">Ethnological Society of New York.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">VOLUME I.</div>
            
            <p>THIS volume will consist of articles by members of the
               Ethnological Society, relating to various topics of interest to the
               Antiquary and Philologist. It will consist of from four to five hundred
               pages 8vo., printed on good paper and in the best manner.
            </p>
            
            <p>A number of engravings illustrative of the several papers, will accompany the volume.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">CONTENTS OF THE VOLUME.
               
               <br></br>Art. I. Notes on the Semi-civilized Nations of Mexico, Yucatan, and
               
               <br></br>       Central America. By 
               <span class="person" id="agallatin">Albert Gallatin</span>.
               
               <br></br>Sec. 1st. Languages.--Vocabularies, grammar, derived and com-
               
               <br></br>       pounded words.
               
               <br></br>       2d. Numeration.--Vigintesimal.
               
               <br></br>       3d. Calendars and Astronomy.--Mexico, Yucatan, Chiapas.
               
               <br></br>            --Extent of Astronomical knowledge.
               
               <br></br>       4th. History and Chronology.--Paintings designating years;
               
               <br></br>            only four known.--Tradition; early writers discussed.--
               
               <br></br>            Uncertainty of dates and events.
               
               <br></br>       5th. Conjectures on origin of semi-civilization in Ameri-
               
               <br></br>             ca.--America inhabited at a very early date.--Astrono-
               
               <br></br>             my.--Agriculture.--Extinct race.
               
               <br></br>       No. 1. Appendix.--Grammatical notices.--Mexican, Tarasca,
               
               <br></br>            Ottomi, Maya, Guatemala, Huestaca.
               
               <br></br>       No. 2.	" Notes on Lord Kingsborough's collection.
               
               <br></br>            --All paintings, but one, Mexican.--All but four relate to
               
               <br></br>            Mythology and Judicial Astrology.--Codices Borgianus
               
               <br></br>            and Vaticanus.
               
               <br></br>Art. II. An Essay on the Grave-Creek Mound in the Ohio Valley.--
               
               <br></br>            By 
               <span class="person" id="hrschoolcraft">Henry R. Schoolcraft</span>, embracing:
               
               <br></br>       1st. A description of the Tumulus, its dimensions and mode of
               
               <br></br>            structure.
               
               <br></br>       2d. An accurate drawing and description of the Inscription found
               
               <br></br>            in one of the vaults.
               
               <br></br>       3d. Other antiquarian articles disclosed by the opening of that
               
               <br></br>            mound, or found in other parts of the Grave-Creek Valley
               
               <br></br>            and its neighborhood.
               
               <br></br>       4th. Conjectures upon the character of the Alphabet, and the
               
               <br></br>            probable era of the Inscription, &amp;c. The whole illustrated
               
               <br></br>            with carefully executed plates.
               
               <br></br>Art. III. A Dissertation on some curious evidences of an Era of An-
               
               <br></br>            cient Semi-civilization in the West, noticed in the progress
               
               <br></br>            of settlements in the Mississippi Valley and the Lakes. By
               
               <br></br>            
               <span class="person" id="hrschoolcraft">Henry R. Schoolcraft</span>.
               
               <br></br>       Description of some extensive Horticultural Beds and Furrows,
               
               <br></br>            found in the prairies and forests of the Lake Region, about
               
               <br></br>            the latitude of the sources of the Illinois and St. Joseph's,
               
               <br></br>            with an engraving.
               
               <br></br>Art. IV. An account of Ancient Remains in Tennessee. By 
               <span class="person" id="gtroost">Gerard
                  Troost
               </span>, M. D., Prof. of Chemistry, Geology, &amp;c. in the
               
               <br></br>            University of Tennessee.
               
               <br></br>       1.	The Mummies found in the Saltpetre Caves, with conjectures
               
               <br></br>            as to their antiquity.
               
               <br></br>       2.	The ancient Burial Places.
               
               <br></br>       3.	Traces of Phallic Worship among a people once occupying that
               
               <br></br>            section of country.
               
               <br></br>Art. V. On the recent discoveries of Himyaritic Inscriptions, and the
               
               <br></br>            attempts made to decipher them. By 
               <span class="person" id="wwturner">Wm. W. Turner</span>.
               
               <br></br>       Kingdom of the Himyarites.--Discovery of Inscriptions.
               
               <br></br>       Himyaritic Alphabet.--Alphabets found in Manuscripts.--
               
               <br></br>       Alphabets from the Inscriptions.--Ethiopic Alphabets.
               
               <br></br>       Himyaritic Language.--Ehkili Language.--General results.
               
               <br></br>Art. VI. A visit to the Lybio-Phoenician Monument at Dugga, near
               
               <br></br>            the site of ancient Carthage. By 
               <span class="person" id="fcatherwood">Frederic Catherwood</span>.
               
               <br></br>       With an account of the inscription; and a view and ground
               
               <br></br>            plan of this ancient and interesting monument.
               
               <br></br>Art. VII. An Account of the Serreculies, or Serranalies, with hints re-
               
               <br></br>            specting several other tribes or families of people composing
               
               <br></br>            the Fullah nation, and those inhabiting the neighboring
               
               <br></br>            Counties of Western Nigritia. By 
               <span class="person" id="tdwight">Theodore Dwight</span>, Jr.
               
               <br></br>       1. The statements of authors respecting the Serreculies.
               
               <br></br>       2. The Geography, History, Learning, Arts, &amp;c., of the Serrecu-
               
               <br></br>            lies. 
               
               <br></br>       3. Their Language.
               
               <br></br>       4.	Remarks on Neighboring Nations and Tribes.
            </div>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, Booksellers
               and Importers, 7 Astor House, New-York.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY</div>
            
            <div class="ab">AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
               
               <br></br>Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny's Jewelry Store,) awarded
               
               <br></br>the Medal, four first Premiums, and two "Highest Honors," at the
               
               <br></br>Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
               
               <br></br>the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
            </div>
            
            <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
               at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
               the score of economy.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B.--Imported German Cameras, also French and American Instruments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polishing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received
               promptly attended to.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lhsigourney">Sigourney</span>'s Pictorial Reader.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE PICTORIAL READER, for the Use of Schools, consisting of Original Articles for the Instruction of Young Children.
               By Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lhsigourney">L. H. Sigourney</span>. Being an Introduction to the Boy's Reading Book and Girl's Reading Book, by the same author. Illustrated
               by nearly One Hundred aed Fifty Engravings. A very interesting and
               instructive Book for Children, whether in school or out. Published by
                                                 TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John Street,
                                                          And for sale by all the Booksellers.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">The First Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for
               the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH'S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all
               (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms--Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationary. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours--9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen,
               and from 11 to 1 o'clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale "Goldsmith's Gems of Penmanship," elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">                                     From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith's Gems of Pennmanship.--The Chirographic art is
               much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
               Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">Goldsmith</span> may well claim to be considered at its head. The
               volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
               of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">                                     From the New York Express.</div>
            
            <p>Goldsmith's Gems of Penmanship.--We have seen the original, as
               executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
               wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
               to be "more potent than the sword," we never witnessed before.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">CHARLES PERABEAU,</div>
            <div class="ab">Professor of Music,
               
               <br></br>No. 9 Whitehall Street, New York.
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p29">
         <div class="biblTitle">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">63</div>
         
         <div class="head">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal,</div>
         
         <div class="ab">To be Published every Saturday.</div>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
            to make it worthy of patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers in the country; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may "let loose their
            thoughts," will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate.
            It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octavo form of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum--Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.</p>
         
         <p>A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.</p>
         
         <p>All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor
            of the Broadway Journal, and all letters on business to
                                    JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.</div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      <div class="note" id="n001">
         <a href="/#/issues/18450125/p3">*The singular vision here alluded to is thus described by 
            <span class="person" id="norlandini">Orlandinus</span>, in
            his History of the Society of Jesus: "A very comely image appeared to him
            in the air, the figure of which he could not clearly discern. It was lengthy,
            like the form of a serpent, bright, and of various hues, and glittering with
            many eyes, like stars: which, while it appeared rendered him happy, and
            when it vanished left him sorrowful." Lib. i. 22, p. 7. The conversion of
            Ignatius happened in 1521. He was in his thirty-first year.
         </a>
      </div>
      <div></div>
   </div>
</div>