<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450927</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 2.     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, SEPTEMBER 27, 1845.     NO. 12.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.   
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>Edited by 
         
         <br></br>EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau St. 
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>        
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Forest Reverie</div>
         <div class="biblPage">171</div>
         
         <div class="head">The Forest Reverie.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>’Tis said that when
            
            <br></br>The hands of men
            
            <br></br>Tamed this primeval wood,
            
            <br></br>And hoary trees with groans of wo,
            
            <br></br>Like warriors by an unknown foe,
            
            <br></br>Were in their strength subdued,
            
            <br></br>The virgin Earth
            
            <br></br>Gave instant birth
            
            <br></br>To springs that ne’er did flow.—
            
            <br></br>That in the sun
            
            <br></br>Did rivulets run
            
            <br></br>And all around rare flowers did blow—
            
            <br></br>The wild rose pale
            
            <br></br>Perfumed the gale
            
            <br></br>And the queenly Lily adown the dale
            
            <br></br>(Whom the Sun and the dew
            
            <br></br>And the winds did woo,)
            
            <br></br>With the gourd and the grape luxuriant grew.
            
            <br></br>So when in tears
            
            <br></br>The love of years
            
            <br></br>Is wasted like the snow.
            
            <br></br>And the fine fibrils of its life
            
            <br></br>By the rude wrong of instant strife
            
            <br></br>Are broken at a blow—
            
            <br></br>Within the heart
            
            <br></br>Do springs upstart
            
            <br></br>Of which it doth not know,
            
            <br></br>And strange, sweet dreams,
            
            <br></br>Like silent streams
            
            <br></br>That from new fountains overflow,
            
            <br></br>With the earlier tide
            
            <br></br>Of rivers glide
            
            <br></br>Deep in the heart whose hope has died—
            
            <br></br>Quenching the fires its ashes hide,—
            
            <br></br>Its ashes, whence will spring and grow
            
            <br></br>Sweet flowers, ere long,—
            
            <br></br>The rare and radiant flowers of Song!
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">A. M Ide.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Ligeia</div>
         <div class="biblPage">171</div>
         
         <div class="head">Ligeia.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">And the will therein lieth, which dieth not. Who knoweth the mysteries of
            
            <br></br>the will, with its vigor? For God is but a great will pervading all things by
            
            <br></br>nature of its intentness. Man doth not yield himself to the angels, nor unto
            
            <br></br>death utterly, save only through the weakness of his feeble will.
            
            <span class="person">JOSEPH GLANVILL.</span>
         </div>
         
         <p>I cannot, for my soul, remember how, when, or even precisely where, I first became acquainted with the lady
            Ligeia. Long years have since elapsed, and my memory
            is feeble through much suffering. Or, perhaps, I cannot
            now bring these points to mind, because, in truth, the
            character of my beloved, her rare learning, her singular
            yet placid cast of beauty, and the thrilling and enthralling eloquence of her low musical language, made their
            way into my heart by paces so steadily and stealthily progressive that they have been unnoticed and unknown.
            Yet I believe that I met her first and most frequently in
            some large, old, decaying city near the Rhine. Of her
            family—I have surely heard her speak. That it is of a
            remotely ancient date cannot be doubted. Ligeia! Ligeia! Buried in studies of a nature more than all else adapted to deaden impressions of the outward world, it is by
            that sweet word alone—by Ligeia—that I bring before
            mine eyes in fancy the image of her who is no more. And
            now, while I write, a recollection flashes upon me that I
            have never known the paternal name of her who was my
            friend and my betrothed, and who became the partner of
            my studies, and finally the wife of my bosom. Was it a
            playful charge on the part of my Ligeia? or was it a test
            of my strength of affection, that I should institute no inquiries upon this point? or was it rather a caprice of my
            own—a wildly romantic offering on the shrine of the most
            passionate devotion? I but indistinctly recall the fact
            itself—what wonder that I have utterly forgotten the circumstances which originated or attended it? And, indeed,
            if ever that spirit which is entitled Romance—if ever she,
            the wan and the misty-winged Ashtophet of idolatrous
            Egypt, presided, as they tell, over marriages ill-omened,
            then most surely she presided over mine.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is one dear topic, however, on which my memory
            fails me not. It is the person of Ligeia. In stature she
            was tall, somewhat slender, and, in her latter days, even
            emaciated. I would in vain attempt to portray the majesty, the quiet ease, of her demeanor, or the incomprehensible lightness and elasticity of her footfall. She came
            and departed as a shadow. I was never made aware of
            her entrance into my closed study save by the dear music
            of her low sweet voice, as she placed her marble hand
            upon my shoulder. In beauty of face no maiden ever
            equalled her. It was the radiance of an opium dream—
            an airy and spirit-lifting vision more wildly divine than
            the phantasies which hovered about the slumbering souls
            of the daughters of Delos. Yet her features were not of
            that regular mould which we have been falsely taught to
            worship in the classical labors of the heathen. “There is
            no exquisite beauty,” says Bacon, Lord Verulam, speaking truly of all the forms and genera of beauty, “without
            some strangeness in the proportion.” Yet, although I
            saw that the features of Ligeia were not of a classic regularity—although I perceived that her loveliness was indeed “exquisite,” and felt that there was much of
            “strangeness” pervading it, yet I have tried in vain to
            detect the irregularity and to trace home my own perception of “the strange.” I examined the contour of the lofty
            and pale forehead—it was faultless—how cold indeed that
            word when applied to a majesty so divine!—the skin rivalling the purest ivory, the commanding extent and repose,
            the gentle prominence of the regions above the temples;
            and then the raven-black, the glossy, the luxuriant and
            naturally-curling tresses, setting forth the full force of the
            Homeric epithet, “hyacinthine!” I looked at the delicate outlines of the nose—and nowhere but in the grace
            ful medallions of the Hebrews had I beheld a similar perfection. There were the same luxurious smoothness of
            surface, the same scarcely perceptible tendency to the
            aquiline, the same harmoniously curved nostrils speaking the free spirit. I regarded the sweet mouth. Here
            was indeed the triumph of all things heavenly—the magnificent turn of the short upper lip—the soft, voluptuous
            slumber of the under—the dimples which sported, and the
            color which spoke—the teeth glancing back, with a brilliancy almost startling, every ray of the holy light which
            fell upon them in her serene and placid, yet most exultingly radiant of all smiles. I scrutinized the formation
            of the chin—and here, too, I found the gentleness of
            breadth, the softness and the majesty, the fullness and the
            spirituality, of the Greek—the contour which the God
            Apollo revealed but in a dream, to Cleomenes, the son of
            the Athenian. And then I peered into the large eyes of
            Ligeia.
         </p>
         
         <p>For eyes we have no models in the remotely antique.
            It might have been, too, that in these eyes of my beloved
            lay the secret to which Lord Verulam alludes. They
            were, I must believe, far larger than the ordinary eyes of
            our own race. They were even fuller than the fullest of
            the gazelle eyes of the tribe of the valley of Nourjahad.
            Yet it was only at intervals—in moments of intense excitement—that this peculiarity became more than slightly
            noticeable in Ligeia. And at such moments was her
            beauty—in my heated fancy thus it appeared perhaps—
            the beauty of beings either above or apart from the earth
            —the beauty of the fabulous Houri of the Turk. The hue
            of the orbs was the most brilliant of black, and, far over
            them, hung jetty lashes of great length. The brows,
            slightly irregular in outline, had the same tint. The
            “strangeness,” however, which I found in the eyes, was
            of a nature distinct from the formation, or the color, or
            the brilliancy of the features, and must, after all, be referred to the expression. Ah, word of no meaning! behind whose vast latitude of mere sound we intrench our
            ignorance of so much of the spiritual. The expression
            of the eyes of Ligeia! How for long hours have I pondered upon it! How have I, through the whole of a
            midsummer night, struggled to fathom it! What was it
            —that something more profound than the well of Democritus—which lay far within the pupils of my beloved?
            What was it? I was possessed with a passion to discover. Those eyes! those large, those shining, those divine
            orbs! they became to me twin stars of Leda, and I to
            them devoutest of astrologers.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is no point, among the many incomprehensible
            anomalies of the science of mind, more thrillingly exciting than the fact—never, I believe, noticed in the schools
            —that, in our endeavors to recall to memory something
            long forgotten, we often find ourselves upon the very verge
            of remembrance, without being able, in the end, to remember. And thus how frequently, in my intense scrutiny of
            Ligeia’s eyes, have I felt approaching the full knowledge
            of their expression—felt it approaching—yet not quite be
            mine—and so at length entirely depart! And (strange,
            oh strangest mystery of all!) I found, in the commonest
            objects of the universe, a circle of analogies to that expression. I mean to say that, subsequently to the period
            when Ligeia’s beauty passed into my spirit, there dwelling as in a shrine, I derived, from many existences in the
            material world, a sentiment such as I felt always around
            within me by her large and luminous orbs. Yet not the
            more could I define that sentiment, or analyze, or even 
            steadily view it. I recognized it, let me repeat, sometimes in the survey of a rapidly-growing vine—in the
            contemplation of a moth, a butterfly, a chrysalis, a stream
            of running water. I have felt it in the ocean; in the falling of a meteor. I have felt it in the glances of unusually aged people. And there are one or two stars in heaven—(one especially, a star of the sixth magnitude, double
            and changeable, to be found near the large star in Lyra)
            in a telescopic scrutiny of which I have been made aware
            of the feeling. I have been filled with it by certain sounds
            from stringed instruments, and not unfrequently by passages from books. Among innumerable other instances, I
            well remember something in a volume of Joseph Glanvill,
            which (perhaps merely from its quaintness—who shall
            say?) never failed to inspire me with the sentiment;—
            “And the will therein lieth, which dieth not. Who
            knoweth the mysteries of the will, with its vigor? For
            God is but a great will pervading all things by nature of
            its intentness. Man doth not yield him to the angels, nor
            unto death utterly, save only through the weakness of his
            feeble will.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Length of years, and subsequent reflection, have enabled
            me to trace, indeed, some remote connection between this
            passage in the English moralist and a portion of the character of Ligeia. An intensity in thought, action, or
            speech, was possibly, in her, a result, or at least an index,
            of that gigantic volition which, during our long intercourse, failed to give other and more immediate evidence
            of its existence. Of all the women whom I have ever
            known, she, the outwardly calm, the ever-placid Ligeia,
            was the most violently a prey to the tumultuous vultures
            of stern passion. And of such passion I could form no
            estimate, save by the miraculous expansion of those eyes
            which at once so delighted and appalled me—by the almost magical melody, modulation, distinctness and placidity of her very low voice—and by the fierce energy
            (rendered doubly effective by contrast with her manner of
            utterance) of the wild words which she habitually uttered.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have spoken of the learning of Ligeia: it was immense—such as I have never known in woman. In the
            classical tongues was she deeply proficient, and as far as
            my own acquaintance extended in regard to the modern
            dialects of Europe, I have never known her at fault. Indeed upon any theme of the most admired, because simply
            the most abstruse of the boasted erudition of the academy, have I ever found Ligeia at fault? How singularly
            —how thrillingly, this one point in the nature of my wife
            has forced itself, at this late period only, upon my attention! I said her knowledge was such as I have never
            known in woman—but where breathes the man who has
            traversed, and successfully, all the wide areas of moral,
            physical, and mathematical science? I saw not then
            what I now clearly perceive, that the acquisitions of Ligeia were gigantic, were astounding; yet I was sufficiently aware of her infinite supremacy to resign myself,
            with a child-like confidence, to her guidance through the
            chaotic world of metaphysical investigation at which I
            was most busily occupied during the earlier years of our
            marriage. With how vast a triumph—with how vivid a
            delight—with how much of all that is ethereal in hope—
            did I feel, as she bent over me in studies but little sought
            —but less known—that delicious vista by slow degrees
            expanding before me, down whose long, gorgeous, and all
            untrodden path, I might at length pass onware to the goal
            of a wisdom too divinely precious not to be forbidden!
         </p>
         
         
         <p>How poignant, then, must have been the grief with
            which, after some years, I beheld my well-grounded expectations take wings to themselves and fly away! Without Ligeia I was but as a child groping benighted. Her
            presence, her readings alone, rendered vividly luminous
            the many mysteries of the transcendentalism in which we
            were immersed. Wanting the radiant lustre of her eyes,
            letters, lambent and golden, grew duller than Saturnian
            lead. And now those eyes shone less and less frequently
            upon the pages over which I pored. Ligeia grew ill.
            The wild eyes blazed with a too—too glorious effulgence;
            the pale fingers became of the transparent waxen hue of
            the grave, and the blue veins upon the lofty forehead
            swelled and sank impetuously with the tides of the most
            gentle emotion. I saw that she must die—and I struggled
            desperately in spirit with the grim Azrael. And the struggles of the passionate wife were, to my astonishment,
            even more energetic than my own. There had been much
            in her stern nature to impress me with the belief that, to
            her, death would have come without its terrors;—but not
            so. Words are impotent to convey any just idea of the
            fierceness of resistance with which she wrestled with the
            Shadow. I groaned in anguish at the pitiable spectacle.
            I would have soothed—I would have reasoned; hut, in the
            intensity of her wild desire for life,—for life—but for life
            —solace and reason were alike the uttermost of folly. Yet
            not until the last instance, amid the most convulsive writhings of her fierce spirit, was shaken the external placidity
            of her demeanor. Her voice grew more gentle—grew more
            low—yet I would not wish to dwell upon the wild meaning
            of the quietly uttered words. My brain reeled as I
            hearkened entranced, to a melody more than mortal—to
            assumptions and aspirations which mortality had never
            before known.
         </p>
         
         <p>That she loved me I should not have doubted; and I
            might have been easily a ware that, in a bosom such as hers,
            love would have reigned no ordinary passion. But in
            death only, was I fully impressed with the strength of her
            affection. For long hours, detaining my hand, would she
            pour out before me the overflowing of a heart whose more
            than passionate devotion amounted to idolatry. How had
            I deserved to be so blessed by such confessions?—how had
            I deserved to be so cursed with the removal of my beloved
            in the hour of her making them? But upon this subject I
            cannot hear to dilate. Let me say only, that in Ligeia’s
            more than womanly abandonment to a love, alas! all unmerited, all unworthily bestowed, I at length recognized
            the principle of her longing with so wildly earnest a desire for the life which was how fleeing so rapidly away.
            It is this wild longing—it is this eager vehemence of desire for life—but for life—that I have no power to portray
            —no utterance capable of expressing.
         </p>
         
         <p>At high noon of the night in which she departed, beckoning me, peremptorily, to her side, she bade me repeat
            certain verses composed by herself not many days before.
            I obeyed her.—They were these:
         </p>            
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Lo! ’tis a gala night
            
            <br></br>Within the lonesome latter years!
            
            <br></br>An angel throng, bewinged, bedight
            
            <br></br>In veils, and drowned in tears,
            
            <br></br>Sit in a theatre, to see
            
            <br></br>A play of hopes and fears,
            
            <br></br>While the orchestra breathes fitfully
            
            <br></br>The music of the spheres.
            
            <br></br>Mimes, in the form of God on high,
            
            <br></br>Mutter and mumble low,
            
            <br></br>And hither and thither fly—
            
            <br></br>Mere puppets they, who come and go
            
            <br></br>At bidding of vast formless things
            
            <br></br>That shift the scenery to and fro,
            
            <br></br>Flapping from out their Condor wings
            
            <br></br>Invisible Wo!
            
            <br></br>That motley drama!—oh, be sure
            
            <br></br>It shall not be forgot!
            
            <br></br>With its Phantom chased forevermore,
            
            <br></br>By a crowd that seize it not,
            
            <br></br>Through a circle that ever returneth in
            
            <br></br>To the self-same spot,
            
            <br></br>And much of Madness and more of Sin,
            
            <br></br>And Horror the soul of the plot.
            
            <br></br>But see, amid the mimic rout,
            
            <br></br>A crawling shape intrude!
            
            <br></br>A blood-red thing that writhes from out
            
            <br></br>The scenic solitude!
            
            <br></br>It writhes!—it writhes!—with mortal pangs
            
            <br></br>The mimes become its food,
            
            <br></br>And the seraphs sob at vermin fangs
            
            <br></br>In human gore imbued.
            
            <br></br>Out—out are the lights—out all!
            
            <br></br>And over each quivering form,
            
            <br></br>The curtain, a funeral pall,
            
            <br></br>Comes down with the rush of a storm
            
            <br></br>And the angels, all pallid and wan,
            
            <br></br>Uprising, unveiling, affirm
            
            <br></br>That the play is the tragedy, “Man,”
            
            <br></br>And its hero the Conqueror Worm.
         </div>
         
         <p>“O God!” half shrieked Ligeia, leaping to her feet
            and extending her arms aloft with a spasmodic movement,
            as I made an end of these lines—“O God! O Divine
            Father!—shall these things be undeviatingly so?—shall
            this Conqueror be not once conquered? Are we not
            part and parcel in Thee? Who—who knoweth the mysteries of the will with its vigor? Man doth not yield
            him to the angels, nor unto death utterly, save only
            through the weakness of his feeble will.”
         </p>
         
         <p>And now, as if exhausted with emotion, she suffered
            her white arms to fall, and returned solemnly to her bed
            of Death. And as she breathed her last sighs, there came
            mingled with them a low murmur from her lips. I bent
            to them my ear and distinguished, again, the concluding
            words of the passage in Glanvill—"Man doth not yield
            him to the angels, nor unto death utterly, save only
            through the weakness of his feeble will."
         </p>
         
         <p>She died;—and I, crushed into the very dust with sorrow,
            could no longer endure the lonely desolation of my dwelling in the dim and decaying city by the Rhine. I had
            no lack of what the world calls wealth. Ligeia had
            brought me far more, very far more than ordinarily falls
            to the lot of mortals. After a few months, therefore, of
            weary and aimless wandering, I purchased, and put in
            some repair, an abbey, which I shall not name, in one of
            the wildest and least frequented portions of fair England.
            The gloomy and dreary grandeur of the building, the almost savage aspect of the domain, the many melancholy and time-honored memories connected with both, had
            much in unison with the feelings of utter abandonment
            which had driven me into that remote and unsocial region
            of the country. Yet although the external abbey, with
            its verdant decay hanging about it, suffered but little alteration, I gave way, with a child-like perversity, and
            perchance with a faint hope of alleviating my sorrows,
            to a display of more than regal magnificence within.—
            For such follies, even in childhood, I had imbibed a taste
            and now they came back to me as if in the dotage of
            grief. Alas, I feel how much even of incipient madness
            might have been discovered in the gorgeous and fantastic
            draperies, in the solemn carvings of Egypt, in the wild
            cornices and furniture, in the Bedlam patterns of the carpets of tufted gold! I had become a bounden slave in
            the trammels of opium, and my labors and my orders had
            taken a coloring from my dreams. But these absurdities
            I must not pause to detail. Let me speak only of that
            one chamber, ever accursed, whither in a moment of mental alienation, I led from the altar as my bride—as the
            successor of the unforgotten Ligeia—the fair-haired and
            blue-eyed Lady Rowena Trevanion, of Tremaine.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is no individual portion of the architecture and
            decoration of that bridal chamber which is not now visibly before me. Where were the souls of the haughty
            family of the bride, when, through thirst of gold, they
            permitted to pass the threshold of an apartment so bedecked, a maiden and a daughter so beloved? I have
            said that I minutely remember the details of the chamber—yet I am sadly forgetful on topics of deep moment
            —and here there was no system, no keeping, in the fantastic display, to take hold upon the memory. The room
            lay in a high turret of the castellated abbey, was pentagonal in shape, and of capacious size. Occupying the
            whole southern face of the pentagon was the sole window—an immense sheet of unbroken glass from Venice
            —a single pane, and tinted of a leaden hue, so that the
            rays of either the sun or moon, passing through it, fell
            with a ghastly lustre on the objects within. Over the
            upper portion of this huge window, extended the trellicework of an aged vine, which clambered up the massy
            walls of the turret. The ceiling, of gloomy-looking oak,
            was excessively lofty, vaulted, and elaborately fretted
            with the wildest and most grotesque specimens of a semiGothic, semi-Druidical device. From out the most central recess of this melancholy vaulting, depended, by a
            single chain of gold with long links, a huge censer of the
            same metal, Saracenic in pattern, and with many perforations so contrived that there writhed in and out of them,
            as if endued with a serpent vitality, a continual succession of parti-colored fires.
         </p>
         
         <p>Some few ottomans and golden candelabra, of Eastern
            figure, were in various stations about—and there was the 
            couch, too—the bridal couch—of an Indian model, and
            low, and sculptured of solid ebony, with a pall-like canopy above. In each of the angles of the chamber stood
            on end a gigantic sarcophagus of black granite, from the
            tombs of the kings over against Luxor, with their aged
            lids full of immemorial sculpture. But in the draping of 
            the apartment lay, alas! the chief phantasy of all. The
            lofty walls, gigantic in height—even unproportionably so
            —were hung from summit to foot, in vast folds, with a
            heavy and massive-looking tapestry—tapestry of a material which was found alike as a carpet on the floor, as
            a covering for the ottomans and the ebony bed, as a canopy for the bed, and as the gorgeous volutes of the curtains which partially shaded the window. The material
            was the richest cloth of gold. It was spotted all over, at
            irregular intervals, with arabesque figures, about a foot
            in diameter, and wrought upon the cloth in patterns of
            the most jetty black. But these figures partook of the
            true character of the arabesque only when regarded from
            a single point of view. By a contrivance now common,
            and indeed traceable to a very remote period of antiqui- ty, they were made changeable
            in aspect. To one enter
            ing the room, they bore the appearance of simple monstrosities; but upon a farther advance, this appearance
            gradually departed; and step by step, as the visiter moved his station in the chamber, he saw himself surrounded
            by an endless succession of the ghastly forms which belong to the superstition of the Norman, or arise in the
            guilty slumbers of the monk. The phantasmagoric effect
            was vastly heightened by the artificial introduction of a
            strong continual current of wind behind the draperies—
            giving a hideous and uneasy animation to the whole.
         </p>
         
         <p>In halls such as these—in a bridal chamber such as
            this—I passed, with the Lady of Tremaine, the unhallowed hours of the first month of our marriage—passed
            them with but little disquietude. That my wife dreaded
            the fierce moodiness of my temper—that she shunned me
            and loved me but little—I could not help perceiving; but
            it gave me rather pleasure than otherwise. I loathed
            her with a hatred belonging more to demon than to man.
            My memory flew back, (oh, with what intensity of regret!) to Ligeia, the beloved, the august, the beautiful,
            the entombed. I revelled in recollections of her purity,
            of her wisdom, of her lofty, her ethereal nature, of her
            passionate, her idolatrous love. Now, then, did my spirit
            fully and freely burn with more than all the fires of her
            own. In the excitement of my opium dreams (for I was
            habitually fettered in the shackles of the drug) I would
            call aloud upon her name, during the silence of the night,
            or among the sheltered recesses of the glens by day, as
            if, through the wild eagerness, the solemn passion, the
            consuming ardor of my longing for the departed, I could
            restore her to the pathway she had abandoned—ah, could
            it be forever?—upon the earth.
         </p>
         
         <p>About the commencement of the second month of the
            marriage, the Lady Rowena was attacked with sudden
            illness, from which her recovery was slow. The fever
            which consumed her rendered her nights uneasy; and in
            her pertubed state of half-slumber, she spoke of sounds,
            and of motions, in and about the chamber of the turret,
            which I concluded had no origin save in the distemper of
            her fancy, or perhaps in the phantasmagoric influences
            of the chamber itself. She became at length convalescent—finally well. Yet but a brief period elapsed, ere a
            second more violent disorder again threw her upon a bed
            of suffering; and from this attack her frame, at all times
            feeble, never altogether recovered. Her illnesses were,
            after this epoch, of alarming character, and of more
            alarming recurrence, defying alike the knowledge
            and the great exertions of her physicians. With
            the increase of the chronic disease which had thus,
            apparently, taken too sure hold upon her constitution to be eradicated by human means, I could not
            fail to observe a similar increase in the nervous irritation
            of her temperament, and in her excitability by trivial
            causes of fear. She spoke again, and now more frequently and pertinaciously, of the sounds—of the slight sounds
            —and of the unusual motions among the tapestries, to
            which she had formerly alluded.
         </p>
         
         <p>One night, near the closing in of September, she pressed this distressing subject with more than usual emphasis upon my attention. She had just awakened from an
            unquiet slumber, and I had been watching, with feelings
            half of anxiety, half of a vague terror, the workings of
            her emaciated countenance. I sat by the side of her
            ebony bed, upon one of the ottomans of India. She partly arose, and spoke, in an earnest low whisper, of sounds
            which she then heard, but which I could not hear—of
            motions which she then saw, but which I could not perceive. The wind was rushing hurriedly behind the tapestries, and I wished to show her (what, let me confess
            it, I could not all believe) that those almost inarticulate
            breathings, and those very gentle variations of the figures
            upon the wall, were but the natural effects of that customary rushing of the wind. But a deadly pallor, overspreading her face, had proved to me that my exertions
            to reassure her would be fruitless. She appeared to be
            fainting, and no attendants were within call. I remembered where was deposited a decanter of light wine which
            had been ordered by her physicians, and hastened across
            the chamber to procure it. But, as I stepped beneath the
            light of the censer, two circumstances of a startling nature attracted my attention. I had felt that some palpable although invisible object had passed lightly by my
            person; and I saw that there lay upon the golden carpet,
            in the very middle of the rich lustre thrown from the
            censer, a shadow—a faint, indefinite shadow of angelic
            aspect—such as might be fancied for the shadow of a
            shade. But I was wild with the excitement of an immoderate dose of opium, and heeded these things but little,
            nor spoke of them to Rowena. Having found the wine,
            I recrossed the chamber, and poured out a goblet-ful,
            which I held to the lips of the fainting lady. She had
            now partially recovered, however, and took the vessel
            herself, while I sank upon an ottoman near me, with ray
            eyes fastened upon her person. It was then that I became
            distinctly aware of a gentle foot-fall upon the carpet, and
            near the couch; and in a second thereafter, as Rowena
            Was in the act of raising the wine to her lips, I saw, or
            may have dreamed that I saw, fall within the goblet, as
            if from some invisible spring in the atmosphere of the
            room, three or four large drops of a brilliant and ruby
            colored fluid. If this I saw—not so Rowena. She swallowed the wine unhesitatingly, and I forbore to speak to
            her of a circumstance which must, after all, I considered, have been but the suggestion of a vivid imagination,
            rendered morbidly active by the terror of the lady, by
            the opium, and by the hour.
         </p>
         
         <p>Yet I cannot conceal it from my own perception that,
            immediately subsequent to the fall of the ruby-drops, a
            rapid change for the worse took place in the disorder of
            my wife; so that, on the third subsequent night, the hands
            of her menials prepared her for the tomb, and on the
            fourth, I sat alone, with her shrouded body, in that fantastic chamber which had received her as my bride.—
            Wild visions, opium-engendered, flitted, shadow-like, before me. I gazed with unquiet eye upon the sarcophagi
            in the angles of the room, upon the varying figures of the
            draperry, and upon the writhing of the parti-colored fires
            in the censer overhead. My eyes then fell, as I called to
            mind the circumstances of a former night, to the spot beneath the glare of the censer where I had seen the faint
            traces of the shadow. It was there, however, no longer;
            and breathing with greater freedom, I turned my glances
            to the pallid and rigid figure upon the bed. Then rushed
            upon me a thousand memories of Ligeia—and then came
            back upon my heart, with the turbulent violence of a
            flood, the whole of that unutterable wo with which I had
            regarded her thus enshrouded. The night waned; and
            still, with a bosom full of bitter thoughts of the one only
            and supremely beloved, I remained gazing upon the body
            of Rowena.
         </p>
         
         <p>It might have been midnight, or perhaps earlier, or
            later, for I had taken no note of time, when a sob, low,
            gentle, but very distinct, startled me from my revery.—
            I felt that it came from the bed of ebony—the bed of
            death. I listened in an agony of superstitious terror—hut
            there was no repetition of the sound. I strained my vision to detect any motion in the corpse—but there was not
            the slightest perceptible. Yet I could not have been deceived. I had heard the noise, however faint, and my
            soul was awakened within me. I resolutely and perseveringly kept my attention riveted upon the body. Many
            minutes elapsed before any circumstance occurred tending to throw light upon the mystery. At length it became evident that a slight, a very feeble, and barely noticeable tinge of color had flushed up within the cheeks,
            and along the sunken small veins of the eyelids. Through
            a species of unutterable horror and awe, for which the
            language of mortality has no sufficiently energetic expression, I felt my heart cease to beat, my limbs grow rigid
            where I sat. Yet a sense of duty finally operated to restore my self-possession. I could no longer doubt that we
            had been precipitate in our preparations—that Rowena
            still lived. It was necessary that some immediate exertion be made; yet the turret was altogether apart from
            the portion of the abbey tenanted by the servants—there
            were none within call—I had no means of summoning
            them to my aid without leaving the room for many minutes—and this I could not venture to do. I therefore
            struggled alone in my endeavors to call back the spirit
            still hovering. In a short period it was certain, however,
            that a relapse had taken place; the color disappeared
            from both eyelid and cheek, leaving a wanness even more
            than that of marble; the lips became doubly shrivelled
            and pinched up in the ghastly expression of death; a repulsive clamminess and coldness overspread rapidly the
            surface of the body; and all the usual rigorous stiffness
            immediately supervened. I fell back with a shudder upon
            the couch from which I had been so startlingly aroused,
            and again gave myself up to passionate waking visions of
            Ligeia.
         </p>
         
         <p>An hour thus elapsed when (could it be possible?) I was
            a second time aware of some vague sound issuing from
            the region of the bed. I listened—in extremity of horror. The sound came again—it was a sigh. Rushing to
            the corpse, I saw—distinctly saw—a tremor upon the lips.
            In a minute afterward they relaxed, disclosing a bright
            line of the pearly teeth. Amazement now struggled in
            my bosom with the profound awe which had hitherto
            reigned there alone. I felt that my vision grew dim,
            that my reason wandered; and it was only by a violent
            effort that I at length succeeded in nerving myself to the
            task which duty thus once more had pointed out. There
            was now a partial glow upon the forehead and upon the
            cheek and throat; a perceptible warmth pervaded the
            whole frame; there was even a slight pulsation at the
            heart. The lady lived; and with redoubled ardor I betook myself to the task of restoration. I chafed and
            bathed the temples and the hands, and used every exertion which experience, and no little medical reading,
            could suggest. But in vain. Suddenly, the color fled,
            the pulsation ceased, the lips resumed the expression of
            the dead, and, in an instant afterward, the whole body
            took upon itself the icy chilliness, the livid hue, the intense rigidity, the sunken outline, and all the loathsome
            peculiarities of that which has been, for many days, a tenant of the tomb.
         </p>
         
         <p>And again I sunk into visions of Ligeia—and again,
            (what marvel that I shudder while I write?) again there
            reached my ears a low sob from the region of the ebony
            bed. But why shall I minutely detail the unspeakable
            horrors of that night ? Why shall I pause to relate how,
            time after time, until near the period of the gray dawn,
            this hideous drama of revivication was repeated; how
            each terrific relapse was only into a sterner and apparently
            more irredeemable death; how each agony wore the aspect of a struggle with some invisible foe; and how each
            struggle was succeeded by I know not what of wild
            change in the personal appearance of the corpse? Let
            me hurry to a conclusion.
         </p>
         
         <p>The greater part of the fearful night had worn away,
            and she who had been dead, once again stirred—and now
            more vigorously than hitherto, although arousing from a
            dissolution more appalling in its utter hopelessness than
            any. I had long ceased to struggle or to move, and remained sitting rigidly upon the ottoman, a helpless prey
            to a whirl of violent emotions, of which extreme awe
            was perhaps the least terrible, the least consuming. The
            corpse, I repeat, stirred, and now more vigorously than
            before. The hues of life flushed up with unwonted energy into the countenance—the limbs relaxed—and, save
            that the eyelids were yet pressed heavily together, and
            that the bandages and draperies of the grave still imparted their charnel character to the figure, I might have
            dreamed that Rowena had indeed shaken off, utterly, the
            fetters of Death. But if this idea was not, even then, altogether adopted, I could at least doubt no longer, when,
            arising from the bed, tottering, with feeble steps, with
            closed eyes, and with the manner of one bewildered in a
            dream, the thing that was enshrouded advanced boldly
            and palpably into the middle of the apartment.
         </p>
         
         <p>I trembled not—I stirred not—for a crowd of unutterable
            fancies connected with the air, the stature, the demeanor
            of the figure, rushing hurridly through ray brain, had paralyzed—had chilled me into stone. I stirred not—but
            gazed upon the apparition. There was a mad disorder in
            my thoughts—a tumult unappeasable. Could it, indeed,
            be the living Rowena who confronted me? Could it indeed
            be Rowena at all—the fair-haired, the blue-eyed Lady
            Rowena Trevanion of Tremaine? Why, why should I
            doubt it? The bandage lay heavily about the mouth—but
            then might it not be the mouth of the breathing Lady of
            Tremaine? And the cheeks—there were the roses as in
            her noon of life—yes, these might indeed be the fair cheeks
            of the living Lady of Tremaine. And the chin, with its
            dimples, as in health, might it not be hers?—but had she
            then grown taller since her malady? What inexpressible
            madness seized me with that thought? One bound, and I
            had reached her feet! Shrinking from my touch, she let
            fall from her head, unloosened,the ghastly cerements which
            had confined it, and there streamed forth, into the rushing
            atmosphere of the chamber, huge masses of long and disshevelled hair; it was blacker than the raven wings of the
            midnight! And now slowly opened the eyes of the figure
            which stood before me. “Here then, at least,” I shrieked
            aloud, “can I never—can I never be mistaken—these are
            the full, and the black, and the wild eyes—of my lost love
            —of the lady—of the Lady Ligeia!”
         </p>                 
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Edgar A. Poe.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Bread-Snatcher</div>
         <div class="biblPage">176</div>          
         
         <div class="head">The Bread-Snatcher.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>For two whole days we had no food;
            
            <br></br>For dark, gigantic Want
            
            <br></br>Beside our cold hearth-stone sat down,
            
            <br></br>With Hunger, grim and gaunt.
            
            <br></br>My wife and children made no moan,
            
            <br></br>Nor spoke a single word;
            
            <br></br>Yet in the chamber of my heart,
            
            <br></br>Their hearts’ complaint I heard.
            
            <br></br>Awearied by their weary eyes,
            
            <br></br>I left the house of wo,
            
            <br></br>And in the dusty village street
            
            <br></br>I paced me to and fro.
            
            <br></br>I stopped me at the baker’s shop,
            
            <br></br>Wherein my eyes could see
            
            <br></br>The great, round loaves of wheaten bread
            
            <br></br>Look temptingly on me.
            
            <br></br>“My children shall not starve!” I cried—
            
            <br></br>The famine in me burned—
            
            <br></br>I slyly snatched a loaf of bread,
            
            <br></br>When the baker’s back was turned.
            
            <br></br>I hurried home with eager feet,
            
            <br></br>And there displayed my prize;
            
            <br></br>While Joy, so long afar from us,
            
            <br></br>Came back and lit our eyes.
            
            <br></br>To fragments in our hunger fierce
            
            <br></br>That sweet, sweet loaf we tore;
            
            <br></br>And gathered afterwards the crumbs,
            
            <br></br>From off the dusty floor.
            
            <br></br>While yet our mouths were full, there came
            
            <br></br>A knock which made us start;
            
            <br></br>I spoke not, yet I felt the blood
            
            <br></br>Grow thicker at my heart.
            
            <br></br>The latch was raised, and in there came
            
            <br></br>The neighbors with a din;
            
            <br></br>They said I stole the baker’s bread,
            
            <br></br>Which was a grievous sin.
            
            <br></br>They toot me to the judge who said
            
            <br></br>’Twas larceny—no less;
            
            <br></br>And doomed me to the gloomy jail
            
            <br></br>For wanton wickedness.
            
            <br></br>He asked me why the penalty
            
            <br></br>Of guilt should not be paid;
            
            <br></br>And when I strove to state the case,
            
            <br></br>He laughed at what I said.
            
            <br></br>Then growing grave, he rated me
            
            <br></br>And told me it was time
            
            <br></br>To check the vices of the poor,
            
            <br></br>And stop the spread of crime.
            
            <br></br>In jail for three long months I lay—
            
            <br></br>Three months of bitter wo—
            
            <br></br>And then they opened wide the door
            
            <br></br>And told me I might go.
            
            <br></br>From out the prison I did not walk
            
            <br></br>But ran, with trembling feet,
            
            <br></br>Down through tfie hall and past the door,
            
            <br></br>And up the busy street.
            
            <br></br>My feet had scarce devoured ten rods
            
            <br></br>Of ground, before a hearse,
            
            <br></br>Came slowly on with coffins three—
            
            <br></br>Each coffin with a corse.
            
            <br></br>I asked the driver as he sung,
            
            <br></br>Therein who might he bear;
            
            <br></br>He answered not, but stopped his voice,
            
            <br></br>And on me fixed a stare.
            
            <br></br>The one beside him turned his head,
            
            <br></br>And when the hearse had past,
            
            <br></br>I heard him to the other say—
            
            <br></br>“His brain is turned, at last!”
            
            
            <br></br>I heeded not—I hastened home
            
            <br></br>And entered in my door,
            
            <br></br>Where Silence like a snake crept out
            
            <br></br>And slimed along the floor.
            
            <br></br>Our old cat from the corner came
            
            <br></br>And crooked her back and cried;
            
            <br></br>I stooped me down and stroked her hair,
            
            <br></br>And then I stood and sighed.
            
            <br></br>I left the house and sought the street—
            
            <br></br>My mind was growing wild;
            
            <br></br>And playing with a pile of dust,
            
            <br></br>I saw a chubby child.
            
            <br></br>"Come hither, my little dear," said I,
            
            <br></br>“Where did the people go,
            
            <br></br>Who lived within yon empty house,
            
            <br></br>Two years or nearly so?”
            
            <br></br>Then spake outright the little child,
            
            <br></br>While I grew deadly pale—
            
            <br></br>“The man, sir, was a wicked thief,
            
            <br></br>And he was sent to jail.
            
            <br></br>“His wife and children hid themselves,
            
            <br></br>But they were found to-day,
            
            <br></br>And in the gloomy poor-house hearse
            
            <br></br>Were taken far away.
            
            <br></br>“They say, they never will come back,
            
            <br></br>Because the three are dead—
            
            <br></br>But was it not a wicked thing
            
            <br></br>For THE MAN TO STEAL THE BREAD?”
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Thomas Dunn English.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Critical Notices</div>
         
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p4">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Prose Works of John Milton</div>
            <div class="biblPage">177</div> 
            
            <p>The Prose Works of John Milton, with a Biographical Introduction by Rufus Wilmot Griswold. In Two Volumes. Philadelphia: Herman Hooker.</p>
            
            <p>Dr. Griswold deserves the thanks of his countrymen
               for what he has here done:—it certainly is no credit to
               us, either as republicans or reverers of the true and noble
               in Literature, that no edition of the Prose Works of John
               Milton has hitherto been issued in America. Independently of the subject-matter, his treatises are among the
               roost remarkable ever written. Their mere style (we
               use the word in its widest sense) is absolutely unrivalled.
               It is a very difficult thing, indeed, to decide properly on
               the style of a period so remote as that of Milton; we are
               perpetually misled in our judgment, by the impossibility
               of identifying ourselves with the writers—of inducing
               a full sympathy with the circumstances which impelled
               them, and thus with the objects for which they wrote—
               the ends proposed in composition. In fact, it is only by
               the degree of its adjustment to the result intended, that
               any style can be justly commended as good or condemned
               as bad. But, folding in view this adjustment, and making the necessary allowances for lapses, effected through
               "Time, in the language, we feel ourselves fully warranted
               in saying, that no man has ever surpassed, if, indeed, any
               roan has ever equalled the author of the “Areopagitica”
               in purity—in force—in copiousness—in majesty—or, in
               what may be termed without the least exaggeration, a
               gorgeous magnificence of style. Some of his more directly controversial works rise at times into a species of
               lyrical rhapsody—divinely energetic—constituting for itself a department of composition which is neither prose
               nor poetry, but something with all the best qualities of
               each, and upon the whole superior to either.
            </p>
            
            <p>These two large volumes contain nearly all the prose
               works of Milton. We say nearly; for there is an unwarrantable omission in “The Christian Doctrine.” Of the
               authenticity of this treatise there can be no doubt. It
               was found in 1823, by Mr. Lemon, Deputy Keeper of the
               State Papers, in the course of some researches among his
               book-shelves. It was a Latin MS. enveloped with
               some foreign despatches in Milton’s own hand, and superscribed “To Mr. Skinner, Merchant.” According to
               Toland, this treatise was finished by its author soon after
               the Restoration:—a host of concurring circumstances render its genuineness certain. Its value depends chiefly on
               the curious developments it affords in relation to the
               poet’s Arianism and opinions about polygamy—but its
               Latinity is so peculiarly forcible and fluent, in spite of
               the difficulties of the matter handled, that, on this score
               alone, the treatise demands insertion in any and every
               collection of the author’s prose: it should be left untranslated, of course: Dr. Sumner’s version is feeble. Of the
               “Christian Doctrine,” Dr. Griswold says, in his Introduction, “it is a work which he [Milton] never would
               have given to the press himself.” For this idea there is
               but little authority. The MS. was no doubt taken to
               the State Paper office, in consequence of a general seizure of Milton’s papers, during the persecution of the
               Whigs upon the dissolution of the Oxford Parliament;
               for the poet must have fallen under suspicion. The publication was thus prevented; but evidence of the intent to
               publish is discoverable in the work itself. Dr. Griswold
               says also, that “in none of his great works is there a passage from which it can be inferred that he [Milton] was
               an Arian.” Here we entirely disagree with the compiler.
               The “Paradise Lost” abounds in such passages. Dr.
               Griswold’s Introduction is, nevertheless, well written
               and well adapted to its purposes. At points, however,
               it may be thought extravagant or dogmatic. We have
               no patience with the initial sneer at Bacon, as “the meanest of mankind.” These assertions are passes, and a
               truly profound philosophy might readily prove them ill
               based. We would undertake to show, à priori, that no
               man, with Bacon’s thorough appreciation of the true and
               beautiful, could, by any possibility, be “the meanest,”
               although his very sensibility might make him the weakest “of mankind.”
            </p>
            
            <p>When Dr. Griswold, in conclusion, terms Milton “the
               greatest of all human beings,” we really do think that
               he should have appended the words—“in the opinion, at
               least, of Dr. Griswold.”
            </p>
            
            <p>But these things are trifles. An important service has
               been rendered to our Letters, and he who renders it is
               entitled to thanks. The volumes are well printed and
               bound, and no one, pretending to even ordinary scholarship, can afford to do without them.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            <div class="biblTitle">Big Abel and the Little Manhattan</div>
            <div class="biblPage">177</div> 
            
            <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam’s Library of American Books, No. V.—
               Big Abel and the Little Manhattan. By Cornelius Mathews.
            </p>
            
            <p>The conception and execution of this book are both
               original. The narrative (if such it may be termed) forms
               merely the upper current of the true theme which flows
               below. The principal object is that of a suggestive parallel between the present and primitive condition of the
               Island of Manhattan. A secondary purpose is that of
               gossip about the New-York localities and customs—especially those appertaining to the terrae incognitae of
               remote districts, such as the East Bowery. The ostensible theme has reference to the adventures of a great
               grandson of Hudson, the navigator, and the heir of the
               last chief of the Manhattanese. These worthies are sup
               posed to institute, or to contemplate instituting, in the
               “Supreme Court of Judicature,” a claim against the
               Corporation of New-York, for the whole of its territory.
               Imbued with a strong prospective sense of their title, the
               claimants are represented as vagabondizing through the
               island, partitioning between them the property that is to
               be theirs upon the decision of the suit. It is their division of the spoils which affords opportunity for the
               suggestive parallel between the savage and the civilized
               condition. Big Abel’s attention is arrested, and his cupidity excited, by everything appertaining to commerce and
               modern usage. He claims, for example, the shipping,
               the markets, the banks, and the coffee-houses. The Little Manhattan has an eye to the fountains, the squares,
               and the Indian figures at the tobacco-shop doors. The
               conversation of the two claimants is little in itself—but
               is full of a delicate and skillful innuendo, which, indeed,
               is the staple of the book. An episode relating to a Poor
               Scholar and his mistress, serves well as an introduction
               for many touches of a homely or domestic pathos, in illustration of local details.
            </p>
            
            <p>The book, upon the whole, does great credit to its author. The conception is forcible and unique. Much skill
               is evinced in the general construction and conduct. The
               allegory is properly subdued. Many points evince acute
               observation, and a keen sense of the more delicate humor.
               There are also some passages of rich imagination. The
               style is nervous, but (intentionally) loose or abrupt, and
               has an original and, therefore, impressive effect. The great
               defect of the work is indefiniteness. The design is not
               sufficiently well made out. More hereafter.
            </p>
         </div> 
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="biblTitle">Puratinism</div>
            <div class="biblPage">178</div> 
            
            <p>Puritanism: or a Churchman's Defence against its Aspersions, by an Appeal to its own History. By Thomas
               W. Coit, D. D., Rector of Trinity Church, New-Rochelle, N. Y., and a Member of the New-York Historical
               Society. New-York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>A remarkably nervous, logical, and (to our minds, at
               least,) convincing book. It is based on certain communications, made by its author to “The Churchman,” during the year 1835, “concerning the Puritans and their
               harsh and unwearied cavils against Episcopalians.” A
               large portion of the work, however, is entirely new.—
               Some remarkable quotations preface the volume. The
               first of them is “Milton was a Puritan,” from Leonard
               Bacon’s Hist. Disc. Then follow three extracts from Milton’s Prose Works—extracts in opposition to Puritanism.
               A Note afterwards, says:—“An intelligent reader will
               not be surprised to learn that the Puritans have succeeded in suppressing the above passages, with a number like
               them, in most of the editions of Milton.” This is a serious charge—and not more serious than true. A very
               handsome volume of 527 pages octavo.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Medici Series of Italian Prose</div>
            <div class="biblPage">178</div> 
            
            <p>The Medici Series of Italian Prose, No. IV. The Citizen of a Republic, by Ansaldo Ceba. Translated and
               Edited by C. Edwards Lester. New-York: Paine &amp;
               Burgess.
            </p>
            
            <p>Ansaldo Ceba has been always considered as one of the
               ablest of Italian writers on Government, and the work
               now published is the most important which he has given
               to the world. If we regard only our conception of the
               word “Republic,” we shall find his title a misnomer—
               but the book itself is full of a thoroughly republican sentiment, and inculcates the democratic virtues. It is, indeed, a noble composition, replete with learning, thought,
               and the purest classicism. If deficient at all, it is in vigor—it has more of the Ciceronian character than pleases
               ourselves individually. It was written in the senility of
               its author.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">An Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy</div>
            <div class="biblPage">178</div> 
            
            <p>An Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy, Etc. Etc. New-
               York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>No. XI of this admirable work is just issued.</p>
         </div>          
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Wandering Jew</div>
            <div class="biblPage">178</div> 
            
            <p>The Wandering Jew. By Eugene Sue. New-York:
               Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>No. XVIII is issued—completing one of the most exciting naratives ever written in modern times.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Devotional Family Bible</div>
            <div class="biblPage">178</div> 
            
            <p>The Devotional Family Bible, by the Rev. Alexander
               Fletcher, A. M., Author of the Guide to Family Devotion, etc. etc. Containing the Old and New Testaments, with Explanatory Notes, Practical Observations,
               Copious Marginal References, etc. Eaery Part embellished with a highly finished Engraving on Steel,including Views of the Principal Places mentioned in Scripture, from Drawings taken on the Spot. New-York:
               R. Martin dp Co., 26 John Street.
            </p>
            
            <p>No. IX of this very beautiful Bible has been issued.—
               We repeat the full title by way of most readily describing the work. The parts are sold at 25 cents each.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">Journal of the Texian Expedition Against Mier</div>
            <div class="biblPage">178</div>   
            
            <p>Journal of the Texian Expedition against Mier; Subsequent Imprisonment of the Author; his Sufferings and
               Final Escape from the Castle of Perote, with Reflections upon the Present Political and Probable Future
               Relations of Texas, Mexico, and the United States.
               By Gen. Thomas J. Green. Illustrated by Drawings
               taken from Life by Charles M'Laughlin, a Fellow-Prisoner. New York: Harper and Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This work was prepared for the press soon after the
               writer’s escape from the castle of Perote, but has been
               kept back through fear of injuring the Texians detained,
               until recently, prisoners of war in Mexico.
            </p>
            
            <p>The title fully conveys the general design;—the narrative in the author’s own words, is one “of Texian daring,
               of battles lost and won, of dungeons and old castles, of
               imprisonment and hair-breadth escapes, of unparalleled
               sufferings and cruel murders.” No one can take up the
               book without becoming thoroughly interested in its details.
               The reflections on the political relations of Mexico, Texas and the U. States, are if not profound, at least acute,
               and we listen to them with respectful attention, as the
               views of an evidently sincere man, and one whose extensive personal experience entitles him to speak, on many
               points, with authority.
            </p>
            
            <p>By way of instancing the general manner of the book,
               we quote a passage giving an account of the escape from
               Perote:
            </p>
            
            <p>John Toowig was a son of Old Ireland, a small, energetic man,
               and a true-hearted Republican. His size and energy both befitting
               the operation in the hole, he had done more than his share of the
               work. He was the same who, in the spring of 1842, at San Antonio, put a match to a keg of powder and blew up his store, with
               several thousand dollars worth of goods, rather than they should
               fall into the hands of the Mexican General Vascus. It was less
               difficult for him than some others to get through the perforation in
               the wall. I found much difficulty in passing through, though I
               was now reduced from one hundred and sixty pounds, my usual
               weight, to one hundred and twenty. The gradual funnel-shape of
               the breach made it like driving a pin into an auger-hole, for the
               deeper we went, the closer the fit. The smallest of us having gone
               through first, for fear that the largest might hang in the hole and
               stop it up, it now came to Stone’s turn, who was a large man.
            </p>
            
            <p>He hung fast, and could neither get backward nor forward. In
               this situation, being wedged in as fast as his giant strength could
               force him, our friends on the inside of the room, who had been assisting us, had to reach in the hole, tie ropes to his hands, and draw
               him back. This operation was very like drawing his arms out of
               his body, but did not satisfy him. “I have a wife and children at
               home,” says he, “and I would rather die than stay here longer: I
               will go through, or leave no skin upon my bones." So saying, he
               disrobed himself: his very great exertion, causing him to perspire
               freely, answered nearly as well for the second effort as if he had
               been greased, and he went through after the most powerful labour
               leaving both skin and flesh behind.
            </p>
            
            <p>John Young, if anything, was a larger man than Stone, but was
               much his junior in years: he was as supple as a snake, and no
               Roman gladiator ever exhibited more perfectly-formed muscles:
               nor was his determined temper in bad keeping with his physical
               conformation. He was the last that came out; and while the balance of us sat under the side of the wall, we feared that it would
               be impossible for him to get through. Presently, with the aid of a
               dim sky above us, we saw his feet slowly protruding, then his
               knees, and when he came to his hip joints, here for many minutes
               he hung last. When this part of his body was cleared, the angular use of his knees gave him additional purchase to work by; but
               still our boys said, "Poor fellow! it will be impossible to gel his
               muscular arms and shoulders through." We sat under him with
               an agony of feeling not to be described, while he ceased not his
               efforts. His body was now cleared to his shoulders, but still he
               hung fast. Having the full purchase of his legs, he would writhe,
               first up and down, and then from side to side, with Herculean
               strength; and when he disengaged himself, if it was not like the
               drawing of a cork from a porter-bottle, it was with the low, sullen,
               determined growl of a lion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Being now through our greatest difficulty about the castle, we
               adjusted carefully, though silently, our knapsacks and blankets,
               passing orders from one to another in low whispers, which were interrupted alone by the almost perpetual cry of "centinela alerta"
               of the sentinels above us, both upon the right and left bastions, and
               between which we had now to pass. The moon had gone down at
               8 o'clock; and being favoured by the darkness in the bottom of the
               moat, through which the sentinels overhead could not penetrate, we
               slowly crossed over to the outer wall in Indian file, then felt along
               the wall until we came to a flight of narrow steps eighteen inches
               wide, up which we crawled upon all-fours. When we reached the
               top of the wall, which formed the outer side of the moat, we passed
               on to the chevaux de frize, which was about twelve feet high, of
               pointed timbers set upright in the ground. These upright timbers
               passed through a horizontal sill about six feet from the ground,
               which we could reach with our hands, and then pull ourselves up,
               from which we could then climb over the sharp points of the upright posts, thence down to the bottom of the outside ditch, up the
               outside bank of which we crawled, it not being walled. When
               we reached the lop we breathed more freely, for we were now in
               the wide world, and felt more like freemen; and as the sentinels
               drolled out their sleepy notes of "centinela alerta," we jumped up,
               and cracked our heels together three times, as a substitute for
               cheers three times three.
            </p>
            
            <p>The volume is beautifully printed and bound—a large
               octavo of 487 pages.
            </p>
         </div>            
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">The May-Flower</div>
            <div class="biblPage">179</div> 
            
            <p>The May-Flower, for 1846. Edited by Robert Hamilton.
               Boston: Saxton &amp; Kelt. For sale in New York by
               Saxton &amp; Huntingdon, at the Boston Book-Store, 295
               Broadway.
            </p>
            
            <p>The first published Annual, we believe, of the season,
               and one which will not be readily excelled;—the editor,
               Mr. Robert Hamilton, is entitled to great credit for the
               taste and tact displayed in its whole getting up. The
               plates are seven mezzotints by Sartain, from paintings by
               Deveria, Billings, Topham, Van Holst, Crowley, Winterwaller, and Wilkie. All of these are good and some admirable. “Cup-Tossing” will be universally admired.
               The contributions are, generally, from the most noted
               names in American letters. Mr. Hamilton himself contributes several fine poems. We shall speak of the book
               more in detail next week. It is beautifully printed, and
               bound in embossed morocco.
            </p>
         </div>
           
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Miscellaneous Works of Thomas Arnold</div>
            <div class="biblPage">179</div>  
            
            <p>The Miscellaneous Works of Thomas Arnold, D. D., Late
               Head-Master of Rugby School and Regius Professor
               of Modern History in the University of Oxford. First
               American Edition, with Nine Additional Essays not Included in the English Collection. New York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a well printed octavo of more than 500 pages,
               and is based upon the volume of “Arnold’s Miscellaneous
               Works” published in London, June 1845; in which, however there were many important omissions as well as redundancies. In the American edition (now issued) the
               former are supplied and the latter avoided. The “Fragment on the Church”; the “Essay on Church and State”
               and the “Christian Life, its Course, its Hindrances and
               its Helps” will be found in this the American, but not in
               the English edition. The “Christian Life” is, in fact,
               absolutely necessary for the proper understanding of many
               other essays, in which allusion or reference is made to it.
               Besides these papers, we have, in the way of addition,
               “The Church of England”; “Early Roman History”;
               “Faith and Reason”; “The Oxford Malignants and Dr.
               Hampden”; “The Sixth Chapter of the Gospel by John”;
               “Tracts for the Times”; and “Tradition”—the whole
               including 256 pages, or one half the present volume.
            </p>
            
            <p>The articles omitted are merely ephemeral compositions never meant for preservation—letters from old newspapers, and other similar matter of a purely local or temporary character, but constituting nearly one fourth of the
               English edition, in which the main object appears to
               have been the making of a book sufficiently bulky to sell
               at a certain price.
            </p>
            
            <p>Some other improvements have been effected; as regards for example, the arrangement of matter; and the
               work, upon the whole, cannot fail to be highly acceptable
               to the admirers of Dr. Arnold. It is indeed an indispensable sequel to the “Life and Correspondence” and the
               “Lectures on Modern History.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">Wrongs of American Women</div>
            <div class="biblPage">179</div> 
            
            <p>Wrongs of American Women. First Series. The Elliott Family; or the Trials of New York Seamstresses.
               By Charles Burdett, Author of “Never too Late” etc.
               etc. New-York: E. Winchester.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Author of “Never too Late” has attained an enviable reputation for the truthfulness and interest of his
               moral and domestic tales. “The Elliott Family” is the
               first of a series for which we bespeak the attention of
               our readers—a series whose subject (The Wrongs of
               American Women) should and must recommend it to all
               except those interested in the persecutions which it will
               expose and condemn. The story is one of intense pathos
               and the greater portion of it is absolutely true—the names
               of the parties only being changed. We hope every honorable man connected with the press will use his utmost
               exertions to give currency to this all-important series of
               books.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Introduction to the American Common-School Reader and Speaker</div>
            <div class="biblPage">179</div> 
            
            <p>Introduction to the American Common-School Reader and
               Speaker; Comprising Selections in Prose and Verse:
               with Elementary Rules and Exercises in Pronun ciation. By William Russell and John Goldsbury, authors
               of the above-mentioned Reader. Boston: Charles Tappan. New-York: Saxton &amp; Huntingdon.
            </p>
            
            <p>This useful book, as its title announces, is designed as
               an introduction to the previous work of the authors; and
               its principles of elocution arc, of course, such as belong
               to an elementary treatise. They are “intended for practical training in the rudiments of orthoepy.” The two
               volumes form an admirable and nearly perfect system.
            </p>
            
            <p>The selections are made with unusual judgment. We
               observe that a poem entitled “The Ocean” is printed
               anonymously. It is a beautiful lyric, and its author
               should be known—J. Augustus Shea, lately deceased.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Elements of Morality</div>
            <div class="biblPage">180</div> 
            
            <p>The Elements of Morality, including Polity, By William Wheewell, D. D. author of the "History and Philosophy of the Inductive Sciences." In two vol. Harper &amp; Brothers.</p>
            
            <p>The Harpers have just published this admirable and
               most valuable work, in two beautifully printed and well
               bound duodecimo volumes, as the first number of a new
               series of Standard Books which they intend to issue under
               the general title of “Harper’s New Miscellany.” If
               this work is to be regarded as, in any sense, a specimen of
               the scries, we have no hesitation in saying that it will be
               by far the most useful and important Library of its kind
               ever published in this country. Prof. Whewell is very
               widely known as a writer upon Moral Science of the most
               profound ability. He stands, indeed, at the head of the
               living philosophical professors in England, and his work
               on the Inductive Sciences is universally regarded as of the
               very highest authority.
            </p>
            
            <p>In this work on Morality, which has but just been published in England in two large octavo volumes, after a series of very full and exact elementary notices and definitions, he has laid down, in a manner far more complete,
               precise and methodical than any former writer, the Laws
               of Morality as applied to every department of individual,
               social, political and ecclesiastical action. The nature,
               obligations and rights of Society,—Divine Laws and their
               Sanction,—the idea, rights, deties and obligations of the
               State,—the nature of Oaths, of International Law &amp;c. &amp;c.
               are discussed in the most full, systematic and satisfactory
               manner. The work can hardly fail to become a text book
               in all our colleges and higher schools:—but we are also
               glad that it has been published in such a form and at so
               cheap a price, as must insure its universal circulation. It
               is a work which deserves to be studied by every citizen of
               this republic.
            </p>
            
            <p>The two volumes contain over 400 pages each,—closely
               and yet very distinctly printed upon fine, white paper, and
               are substantially and elegantly bound in muslin, gilt, and
               sold at fifty cents a volume. This is to be the style and
               price of all the succeeding volumes of the Miscellany,
               which will contain important historical, scientific, biographical and other works. The publishers, in their prospectus, state that the main, controlling aim of the entire
               collection, will be instruction rather than amusement.
               Such a series of books is greatly needed:—and we hazard
               little in saying that this will prove the most useful, if not
               the most popular Library ever issued in this country.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">Pictorial History of the World</div>
            <div class="biblPage">180</div> 
            
            <p>Pictorial History of the World. By John Frost, LL.D.
               No. 8. Philadelphia: Walker &amp; Gillis. For sale in
               New-York by Wm. H. Graham.
            </p>
            
            <p>To be completed in 30 numbers—at 25 cents each.</p>
         </div>           
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">While Going to Press</div>
            <div class="biblPage">180</div> 
            
            <p>While about going to press, we have received from
               Messrs. Stanford &amp; Swords, Lady Mary; or Not of the
               World. By the Rev. Chas. B. Tayler, M. A., Author of
               "The Records of a Good Man's Life," etc., and Sermons
               on Certain of the Less Prominent Facts and References
               in Sacred Story. By Henry Mellvill, D. D., Principal
               of the East India College, etc. Second Series.——These
               works will be noticed more fully in our next—when we
               shall also speak of the Aristidean; of Simms’ Magazine
               for September; of Godey and Graham for October, and ofthe New-York Illustrated Magazine, edited by L. Labree, of which the second number is just issued.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p19">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fairy's Burial</div>
         <div class="biblPage">180</div> 
         
         <div class="head">The Fairy's Burial</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>The Fairy’s burial!
            
            <br></br>Starlight, the pall—
            
            <br></br>Starlight so bright:
            
            <br></br>Bright shone the stars above,—
            
            <br></br>Emblems of peace and love,—
            
            <br></br>Eyes of the night.
            
            <br></br>Sad were the fairies, then,
            
            <br></br>Coming from hill and glen;—
            
            <br></br>Sadly they came;
            
            <br></br>One, from the fairy throne,
            
            <br></br>Had now forever flown—
            
            <br></br>No more to reign.
            
            <br></br>Death and his brother Sleep
            
            <br></br>Now the young fairy keep,
            
            <br></br>Voiceless and still;
            
            <br></br>Low lies the fairy now,—
            
            <br></br>She of the golden brow—
            
            <br></br>She of the laughing rill.
            
            <br></br>Oh!’t was a sadening sight—
            
            <br></br>Wreathed in the lilies white,
            
            <br></br>Calmly she lay.
            
            <br></br>Ah!’t was a lovely flower,
            
            <br></br>Called from the fairies bower—
            
            <br></br>Withered away.
            
            <br></br>Made they the fairy’s grave,
            
            <br></br>Near to the dancing wave,
            
            <br></br>Singing its song,
            
            <br></br>Ringing their silvery knells
            
            <br></br>Sighing their wild farewells—
            
            <br></br>Sad fairy throng!
            
            <br></br>Floateth a silvery sound;
            
            <br></br>Over the flower-clad ground.
            
            <br></br>Softly they steal.
            
            <br></br>Fays from the fairy-land,
            
            <br></br>Led by an angel-hand—
            
            <br></br>Sweetly they kneel:
            
            <br></br>Music floats sweetly there,
            
            <br></br>Borne on the rosy air.
            
            <br></br>Music so still—
            
            <br></br>Warbled from flowery dell,
            
            <br></br>Floating from fairy shell—
            
            <br></br>Wildly doth thrill.
            
            <br></br>Robed in the starlight fair,
            
            <br></br>Wreathed in their golden hair,
            
            <br></br>Stars gleaming bright.
            
            <br></br>Fairies in beauty come,
            
            <br></br>Guarding the young fay’s tomb,
            
            <br></br>Through the lone night.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Marcus H. Trowbridge.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Department</div> 
         
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">Oratorio of the Seven Sleepers</div>
            <div class="biblPage">180</div>
            <p>ORATORIO OF THE SEVEN SLEEPERS.—The Tabernacle
               was densely crowded on Thursday evening, the 18th inst.
               We have rarely seen so large an audience gathered together; there must have been over three thousand persons present. The production of an Oratorio, by a composer of great merit, for the first time in this country,
               could scarcely fail to attract much attention among the
               people generally, but more especially among the lovers
               of fine Sacred Music, of which there is a large class in
               and about the city. More than ordinary attention, however, was given to the announcement of the forthcoming
               work, from the fact that the gentleman under whose direction it was to be produced, was known to be always
               the most forward in the cause of sterling music, and had
               proved himself, beyond a doubt, the most competent leader in the country. Every confidence was therefore placed
               upon his skill and judgment, and the public went to the
               Tabernacle, fully assured that they would meet with an
               intellectual entertainment. Their expectations were fulfilled.
            </p>
            
            <p>The following is a cast of the characters:</p>
            
            <div class="ab">Antipater, (Proconsul at Ephesus,)         Mr. S. Pearson.
               
               <br></br>Honoria, (his wife,) -	Mrs. Strong.
               
               <br></br>Martinus, (Bishop of Ephesus,)              Mr. S. P. Cheney.
               
               <br></br>Malchus,......................   Mrs. Edward Loder.
               
               <br></br>Serapion, ----- Miss Cheney.
               
               <br></br>Johannes,	-	-	-	-	-	Miss DeLuce.
               
               <br></br>Constantine, ...	-  Mr. John Johnson.
               
               <br></br>Dionysius,	-	:	-	-	-	Mr. S. O. Dyer.
               
               <br></br>Marianus,.....................  Mr. R. Andrews.
               
               <br></br>Maximianus,...................  Mr. D. S. B. Bennett.
            </div>
            
            <p>The plan of the Oratorio we detailed in our paper a
               week or two since. It is of so purely dramatic a character, that much of the interest it would otherwise excite
               is lost for want of scenic effect and dresses appropriate.
               A most magnificent Sacred Opera could be formed from
               the Oratorio of the Seven Sleepers: far superior to David; it would equal in effect, we think, Rossini’s Israelites in Egypt. What could be more effective, for instance,
               than the whole of the second act—the High Priest blessing the banner of the soldiers, who are going forth to
               fight the enemies of the Cross—the people, in throngs,
               crowding to witness the ceremony. Malchus, the youngest of the Seven Sleepers, enters in the midst; he gazes
               around him in wild amazement!—it is not Ephesus he
               beholds—the people are not the same—the symbol of the
               Cross waves everywhere triumphant, while yesternight,
               as he supposes, the infidel held sway over all. His
               strange dress, and yet stranger manners, attract the attention of the people. They believe him to be a spy—
               they seize and bear him before a Roman Consul, who examines and extracts from him his strange and incredible story.
               The people believe it to be a miracle of the Most High,
               and with an eagerness which cannot be restrained, they
               tush towards Mount Celion. In all this there is vivid action, and aided by scenery, dresses, and by the music,
               which is descriptive to an extraordinary degree, would
               form, we believe, a scene of thrilling excitement.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Music itself denotes unmistakeably the class to
               which it belongs. We have said that it is descriptive,
               and it is not partially so, but every feature in the plot
               has its appropriate music:—pastoral, martial, solemn and
               agitated. But there is one striking feature in the composition which strikes us as a marvellously fine thought.—
               Between the time at which the Brothers fell asleep, and
               the period of their waking, two hundred years are supposed to have elapsed. The two periods are distinctly
               Marked by the music. While the Brothers chaunt forth
               a solemn chorale, quaint, crude, and almost harsh in
               its character, the people of Ephesus sing in a more
               Modern style. The contrast is most strongly marked, and
               the effect is striking and peculiar. This admirable
               thought would alone stamp the genius of the composer.
               Of the music itself we must record our honest admiration. Looking at it, as an Oratorio, we should complain
               of a want of dignity, solidity and grandeur  It lacks the
               elements of the sublime; there is too great a mingling
               of the petty passions and worldly strife, with the solemn
               thoughts which should be absorbed in contemplating the
               miracles vouchsafed by the Almighty. But as a Sacred
               Drama, we do not hesitate to say that the Seven Sleepers is the very highest of its class. Judging it in this
               light, we take a lowlier standard, and the composition
               rises in our estimation. The music allotted to the Seven
               Brothers ranks foremost in point of excellence. A quiet,
               dreamy and yet solemn feeling pervades each successive
               piece. The first piece, commencing “Lord God our refuge,” in which the voices join in in rotation, beginning
               with Maximianus and ending with Malchus, is truly an
               awakening from a deep slumber; and the last piece, commencing with the line, “Now with unseen wings approaching,” in which the same figure is reversed, is as
               truly the gradual approach of their second and last slumber. In short, the music of the Brothers forms a musical pyramid, of which Malchus is the apex, and Maximianus is the base. A more perfect musical figure it is impossible to conceive. The music given to Malchus is
               undoubtedly the most charming in the Oratorio; its simplicity is marvellous, and its melody is of the most chaste
               and pleasing character. The Aria of Johannes ranks
               next in point of beauty; its gravity impresses one sensibly, while its simplicity and pathos enhance the impression. Martinus (the Bishop) is entrusted with some
               grand and imposing music, particularly the Aria in
               the third part. Antipater and Honoria have much to
               do, yet, though their music is very charming, it fails in
               exciting interest when compared with the other characters. The chorusses, judged by the standard we have
               established, are fine compositions; the fugues, judged by
               any standard, must be acknowledged as masterly compositions, but they are designed, with the exception of the
               last, to represent action, and require action to take off the
               appearance of scientific elaboration.
            </p>
            
            <p>The instrumentation is exceedingly beautiful, although,
               with several exceptions, it is decidedly operatic. There
               are many charming combinations and exquisite points
               throughout the work; the partitions of the several fugues
               are really striking examples of ingenuity and knowledge
               applied to the Orchestra, and the accompaniments to the
               Bishop’s Music are particularly happy in producing the
               effect of grandeur and dignity.
            </p>
            
            <p>On the whole, it is undoubtedly a great work—great
               in its simplicity, great in its elaboration, great in its conception, and great in its execution. We have not entered
               as fully into its beauties as we could wish; but we trust
               we have said enough to draw the attention of ameteurs
               to its merits.
            </p>
            
            <p>From Mrs. E. Loder, as Malchus, much was expected,
               and the expectations were fulfilled. She sang the music
               throughout most admirably. In her recitatives especially,
               she displayed the striking advantage of a thorough musical education. Every word was distinctly enunciated,
               and each point was delivered with proper emphasis.—
               Her solos were executed with a chasteness of expression
               and a purity of style, which are the distinguishing characteristics of the school. It was loudly and deservedly
               applauded.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mrs. Strong sang the music of Honoria very sweetly.
               Her style is somewhat too cold, and her delivery wants
               the freedom of a practised artist; but in her execution she
               has very much improved since we last heard her. Her
               music, as we have before remarked, is the least pleasing,
               or, at all events, the least effective, in the Oratorio; but
               the melody of her voice added much to its interest and
               effect.
            </p>
            
            <p>Miss Cheney had but little to do, and that little was
               mostly concerted. It would not, therefore, be fair to
               form a judgment upon her capacities.
            </p>
            
            <p>Miss De Luce, as Johannes, acquitted herself exceedingly well. She has a mezzo soprano voice of a most
               lovely quality—rich, full and melodious. It tells wonderfully in any piece of moderate movement, requiring sustained expression. Miss De Luce sang the air, “God be
               with you,” in a chaste and careful manner. She began a
               little flat, which was evidently caused by extreme fright;
               for as soon as this abated, the fault was no longer visible.
               If this young lady should study seriously, she could not
               fail to attain a high position in her profession.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Sidney Pearson was the Antipater of the evening,
               We were both pleased and surprised at the excellence of
               his performance. He has many faults; his pronunciation
               is broad and inelegant—his intonation is by no means faultless; and he lacks passion and expression. But he sang his
               music correctly, attempted no interpolations, and was on
               the whole, perhaps, as good a representative of the character as could be found in the city.
            </p>
            
            <p>Messrs. Bennett and Cheney are Amateurs. They have
               both good voices, but the want of education in every respect is so glaringly apparent, that criticism would be useless. Of the two, however, Mr. Cheney has decidedly the
               advantage in point of voice and intonation. A year’s study
               under careful direction, would place Mr. Cheney in a good
               position as a singer of Sacred Music.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Chorusses were performed in a style of excellence
               truly remarkable. The Choral performances of the Sacred Music Society have always been noted for want of
               precision, firmness, power, and capability to produce due
               effects. But on this occasion the same materials were employed (nearly all the Chorus singers being members of
               the S. M. S.) yet none of these defects were in any part to
               be observed. Every point was taken up with admirable
               precision; the pianos were duly cared for, and the crescendos were truly grand in their effects. The only visible want, was a want of power, and this want could only
               be remedied by an increase of members, which under the
               circumstances could not be obtained. A striking fact might
               be elicited were we to pursue the enquiry as to the cause
               of the marked difference in the performance of the same
               people upon this occasion and upon previous occasions.
               We will, however, leave our readers to draw the inference
               themselves.
            </p>
            
            <p>The instrumental performance was equally remarkable
               for its excellence. The Band was kept in admirable subjection to the voices, and the recitatives were better accompanied than we have ever heard before in this country. The band was also deficient in power, not through
               any meanness on the part of those engaged in producing 
               the work, but from the fact that most of the good instrumental performers of the city, were engaged at the several Theatres.
            </p>
            
            <p>At the next representation which will be on the 9th of
               October, greater facilities will undoubtedly be available,
               and the only want observable in the performance will then
               be remarked.
            </p>
            
            <p>We must repeat the praise which we awarded Mr. Loder at the commencement of the notice; for to his skill,
               judgment and firmness, must be attributed all the excellence which we have described.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>We must also compliment Mr. Timm upon the artistlike manner in which he introduced the Organ, and brought
               its full power to bear upon those points where it could tell
               with the best effect. He proved himself indeed a worthy
               coadjutor of the talented conductor.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have yet a word or two to say about the public-spirited gentleman at whose individual risk the whole performance was got up. Mr. Henry Meigs, is known to the
               public as former Secretary of the New York Sacred Music Society. We presume he felt the insufficiency of that
               Society, under its present management, to produce anything but those works at which they have been drumming for years, without attaining any point beyond respectable mediocrity. Acting upon this feeling, he determined to produce, at his own expense, a work of standard
               merit, never before performed in this city, in the best style
               that money could command. He determined also that besides benefiting the public by his undertaking, he would
               also benefit the resident professors:—a singular determination, we allow, as the very last thought in the minds of the
               projectors of any Musical undertaking, is to consider that
               class which is most worthy of consideration. Mr. Meigs
               consulted his conductor, and the Oratorio of the Seven
               Sleepers was chosen. No sooner did the “Society” gain
               information of the fact, than they acted the part of Many
               Sleepers Awakened, (from a long sleep too,) and decided
               upon producing the work in opposition to this individual
               enterprize. This was certainly somewhat unworthy of an
               incorporated Society; but we must excuse them, from the
               fact that they were rather roughly awakened, and had
               hardly time to rub their eyes before they decided upon a
               course of action.
            </p>
            
            <p>A large proportion of the Society joined Mr. Meigs in
               his undertaking, without however withdrawing from the
               Society, and to these ladies and gentlemen, who scorned to
               endure the trammels which would serve to keep music
               back a hundred years, the thanks of the public and the
               profession are due. How well they acquitted themselves
               the thousands who were present can testify.
            </p>
            
            <p>We call upon the public to support Mr. Meigs in his
               undertaking, for upon their support the success or the failure of every undertaking depends; we call upon the public to come forward, not to benefit the individual, but the
               Art: for the success of this undertaking will ensure the
               production of a series of standard classical works, which
               cannot be produced through any other agency.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <div class="biblTitle">Park Theatre</div>
            <div class="biblPage">182</div>
            <p>PARK THEATRE.—Opera is still the rage at this establishment. Miss Delcy, since our last, has appeared in
               the character of Cinderella, and as Zerlina in Fra Diavolo.
               She has gained considerably in public estimation, and
               will, we are confident, become a great favorite; for a generous public will always stand forward in defence of a
               woman, especially if she be as young and as pretty as
               Miss Delcy, against hired critics and interested professional slanderers. We have seen no reason to alter our expressed opinion of Miss Delcy’s powers, but we still say
               that she is full of promise for the future, and has many
               advantages over some who have occupied, for several
               years, the situation she now holds. We trust that the
               public will give her a fair chance, and hope she may continue successful.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Gardner has proved the truth of our remarks in
               every respect. As soon as he shall have recovered the
               full power of his voice, which has been temporarily disarranged, from the combined effect of the sea voyage and
               change of climate, we insure for him a good share of the
               public approbation.
            </p>
            
            <p>Miss Moss acquitted herself, as Lady Allwash, exceedingly well, both in her singing and her acting, and Mr.
               Brough, as Beppo, was perfectly correct in his music
               throughout, and has some difficult and catchy bits to
               sing. He is evidently becoming pains-taking, and we are
               glad to see and hear it.
            </p>
            
            <p>Want of space precludes the possibility of our lengthening this notice.</p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p21">
         <div class="biblTitle">Criticisms on the Popular Errors of the Age, No. I</div>
         <div class="biblPage">183</div> 
         
         <div class="head">Criticisms on the Popular Errors of the Age.
            NO. I.
         </div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Is Error dead, since, as the Teuton
            <span class="footnote" id="n001">
               <span class="footnoteLink">1</span>
               <span class="footnoteText">*Copernicus</span>
            </span> found,
            
            <br></br>’Twas not the Sun, but Earth, that whirled around?
            
            <br></br>Or reason fixed, because by Bacon’s spell
            
            <br></br>The schoolmen, heaps on heaps, confounded fell?
            
            <br></br>Is science sure, since Black or Davy tried,
            
            <br></br>Air to create, and water to divide?
            
            <br></br>Nay—when the Prince of Peace, his flag unfurled,
            
            <br></br>Was truth, at once, triumphant o’er the world?
            
            <br></br>I wot that ancient Erebus doth still
            
            <br></br>New hydras hatch as fast as truth can kill,
            
            <br></br>Sending fresh broods, with horns and talons rife.
            
            <br></br>To chase mankind, and glut their rage on life.
            
            <br></br>Else, why this seven-years’-tempest—mad in looks,
            
            <br></br>Of teachers, doctors, reasoners,—men and books,
            
            <br></br>All fierce with zeal—all eloquent to show
            
            <br></br>What fools there lived a hundred years ago.
            
            <br></br>See B-----h —ah B------h hath o’er his ivied head:
            
            <br></br>The shield of lettered honors strongly spread.
            
            <br></br>Ensconced in Hebrew—redolent to tell
            
            <br></br>How by a dagesh many a meaning fell,
            
            <br></br>Or by a rule—an old and honored rule—
            
            <br></br>One writer in, ranks fifty out of school.
            
            <br></br>But school or no school, sacerdotal wit
            
            <br></br>Hath on his page its golden plaudit writ.
            
            <br></br>Hath he not found—a thing for Paul too vast,—
            
            <br></br>The Resurrection is already past?
            
            <br></br>Is it not clear that he who dies is dead
            
            <br></br>Foot, hand and heart, nerves, cerebrum and head,
            
            <br></br>And one and all, with an eternal “must”
            
            <br></br>Are doomed to “dissipate” in gas and dust?
            
            <br></br>Can “that” again arise? Pray, who shall find
            
            <br></br>His body in the earth, or leaves, or wind?
            
            <br></br>Whoever dies is dead by an “election,”
            
            <br></br>And spirits only, feel the resurrection.
            
            <br></br>Sir, Christ arose, and took his “body” too, [2.]
            
            <br></br>But that might be to balk the raging Jew [A.]
            
            <br></br>Yet he ate meat, all doubt to disenthrone [2.)
            
            <br></br>And prove that he was veritable flesh and bone.
            
            <br></br>The doctor took the pulpit at this point,
            
            <br></br>Pride in his heart, but fear in every joint.
            
            <br></br>“Such facts may answer well a trustful church,
            
            <br></br>“But leave philosophy quite in the lurch.
            
            <br></br>“Give crowds strong faith, they want but little knowledge.
            
            <br></br>“I write for reason, honors, and a college.
            
            <br></br>“But ’tis not reason, I should so dilute
            
            <br></br>“My thoughts, each vague objector to refute
            
            <br></br>"And draw my tenets out so very thin,
            
            <br></br>"That common minds should grasp me, and refine.
            
            <br></br>“Viewed by a subtil neologic light,
            
            <br></br>“My treatise and the scriptures both are right.”
            
            <br></br>So closed the sermon. People sat in doubt,
            
            <br></br>While snatching up his hat, the Dean walked out.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Alolo.</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p22">
         <div class="biblTitle">Editorial Miscellany</div>
         <div class="biblPage">183</div> 
         
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>
         
         <p>IN OUR NOTICE, last week, of an article on “American
            Humor” by Mr. William Jones, we mentioned that Mr.
            Graham, the editor of “Graham’s Magazine,” had rejected a contribution from Mr. Jones; and we gave this
            as our only supposable reason for the latter’s sweeping
            denunciation of the three-dollar Magazines. We have
            since received, from a warm personal friend of Mr. Jones,
            a somewhat different version of the story—which runs
            thus:
         </p>
         
         <p>A contract was entered into by “Graham’s Magazine” for several articles from the pen of Mr. Jones. The articles were written; they did not suit the tone of the Magazine (which might
            have been a virtue or not in the contributor, according to the subject matter): some delay occurred; but the negotiation was ultimately completed, according to the agreement, by Mr. Graham
            paying the author.
         </p>
         
         <p>We are happy to afford Mr. Jones the full benefit of
            this variation. Our own opinion of the matter is not materially changed. When a critic so far forgets himself
            as to speak in wholesale terms of disparagement of a
            work made up altogether of contributions from the elite
            of our literature, we naturally seek some unusual reason
            for the abuse—some reason which does not appear upon
            the surface—in short, some private and personal cause.—
            If we have wronged Mr. Jones, we regret it very sincerely—although he has made no scruple of wronging us and
            our friends. Still, we by no means think that we have
            wronged Mr. Jones.
         </p>
         
         <p>His apologist (for whom personally and as an author,
            we have the highest respect) goes on to say:
         </p>
         
         <p>Whatever sins of dogmatism Mr. J. may have to answer for,
            (and we must still regret that his last article was not submitted to
            a judicious pruning and emendation) we are assured that he is
            utterly incapable of any of the prevalent sins of literary immorality. True men of letters are not so abundant in the community as
            to be wantonly injured in their good fame......Mr. Jones is
            an individual writer of the dogmatic school, who requires for a
            subject one strictly in harmony with his sentiment and experience,
            when he is enthusiastic, brilliant, and profound: out of his personal range he is careless, ineffective, and apparently unjust.....
            The article upon Mr. Dana, written by Mr. Jones and published
            in an early number of this [The Broadway] Journal, exhibits him
            in his true element.
         </p>
         
         <p>With much of all this we agree. Mr. Jones is what
            may be termed an “elegant” essayist of a by-gone school.
            His articles are always graceful, pointed, gentlemanly,
            in thought and tone. They lack vigor, originality, and
            consecutiveness. They leave no definite impression.—
            We read one of them and say—not that we have been
            convinced of anything, or that we have derived any new
            ideas—but that, upon the whole, Mr. Jones is a very clever writer of essays. His most reprehensible fault, however, is that he can see nothing excellent out of the limits of Boston Common. Again:—if we have done him
            injustice, we beg his pardon—but we do not think that
            we have.
         </p>
         
         <p>HON. EDWARD EVERETT and family returned home in
            the Britannia.
         </p>
         
         <p>MR. MCLANE, the American Minister in England, has
            taken up his residence at 38 Harley street, Cavendish
            square.
         </p>
         
         <p>FIELD, the gentlemanly and clever editor of the St.
            Louis Reveillé, has sued the editors of the People’s Or
            gan, a paper published in that city, for libel; laying his
            damages at $10,000. The libel consisted in the publication of a letter abusive of Mr. Field, written by Mr.
            Green, the reformed gambler.
         </p>
         
         <p>New and Fashionable Harps. Our attention has been
            called to those beautiful instruments, manufactured by J.
            F. Browne, 281 Broadway and 83 Chambers street.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Harp, as an instrument, is but little known in this
            country, although in Europe it is considered as a necessary
            accomplishment to ladies of refined education, occupying
            any position in fashionable society. It is a singular fact,
            but it is no less true than singular, that while the ladies of
            the South, particularly of Charleston and New Orleans,
            cultivate a knowledge of this instrument with considerable success, our Northern ladies display a marked indifference on the subject. Were we inclined to write an
            essay upon the history of the Harp, we might say how it
            flourished thousands of years before the Christian Era—
            we might trace its course down to that period and through
            the Dark Ages (when it survived most other instruments)
            even up to the present time—we might describe its various shapes and scales at the different periods even up to
            our own days, showing how greatly the balance is in
            favor of us Modems—but we will not do all this; we will
            content ourselves by simply stating that every lady should,
            for many reasons, be a little familiar with this truly drawing-room instrument. In the first place it is a capital exercise, bringing the muscles into gentle and healthful play;
            in the next place it is an excellent accompaniment to the
            voice; and lastly it displays the beautiful and graceful
            proportions of nature’s handicraft, to the greatest advantage. Well might a learned Theban eloquently observe,
            to some young beaux, on beholding a young and graceful
            woman seated in the most fascinating position, like the
            Divine Cecilia at her Harp—well might this learned Theban observe, we say, "if you have hearts prepare to lose
            them now.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Browne’s Harps are by far the most magnificent instruments that we ever saw. Through his perfect knowledge of the instrument he has effected many important
            improvements in the mechanical department, and in the
            tone there is an extraordinary addition of sweetness, purity
            and power. The pillars are elaborately and gorgeously
            carved and gilded, while the frames are elegantly shaped
            and finished.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is at present in his show room 281 Broadway (up
            stairs) a splendid Grand Concert Harp, six and a half octaves in compass, recently sold to a lady of North Carolina, which is without exception the most elegant, chaste
            and powerful instrument we have ever heard in this country. It combines all the latest improvements, and we
            should advise our fair friends, if only as a matter of curiosity, to visit Mr. Browne’s establishment, before the instrument leaves it for its final destination. We can cordially recommend Mr. Browne’s instruments, as we are
            well acquainted with the character of the firm of which
            he is the resident representative.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have received two Elementary Musical Works, for
            review, the one by J. F. Warner, and the other by E. Ives,
            Jr.; which we shall notice in our next.
         </p>
         
         <p>OUR ARTICLES upon the fine Arts are unavoidably crowded out this week; also a full description of the opening
            of Mr. Erben’s Organ, at Dr. Potts’ new Church. These
            shall duly appear in our next.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>WE TAKE the following truly characteristic and especially French paragraph from the excellent “Courier
            des Etats Unis.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Deux nouveaux-nes dans notre famille.—C’est une carrière
            toujours laborieuse et rarement lucrative, que celle du journalisme,
            et pourtant chaque jour nous voyons s’y aventurer de nouveaux
            imprudens. Depuis huit jours, la nombreuse et féconde famille
            de nos confreres Américains s’est grossie de deux membres, le Star
            et le Globe, paraissants tous les jours, celui-là le soir et celui-ci
            le matin. Qu’ils soient les bien-venus! plus la route est périileuse et plus on a besoin d’amis pour la parcourir. Du reste,
            nous ne voulons pas faire de ces réflexions un décourageant pronostic pour ces nonveaux-nés de la presse. Jamais il n’en
            surgit de plus eiables, de plus dignes de la confiiance et du
            patronage du public qui tient en ses mains les destinées des journalistes. Ce ne sont même pas des débutantes qui nous arrivent,
            car sous des noms nouveaux, nous trouvons de vieilles connaissances qui ont déjà trop bien fait leurs preuves pour que nous doutions de leurs futurs succés. Il en est un surtout, le Globe, avec lequel nous avons vécu en trop bonne fraternité, lorsqu’il s’appelait
            Plebeian, pour que nous n’accueillions pas avec plaisir sa résurrection opérée par la plume puissante de M. Levi D. Slam, l’un
            des plus consciencieux et des plus éloquens publicistes du parti
            démocratique.
         </p>
         
         <p>AMONG THOSE who have furnished original papers for
            the “Broadway Journal,” are Mrs. Osgood, Mrs. Kirkland, Mrs. Child, Mrs. Lowell, Mrs. Hewitt, Miss Fuller,
            Miss Lawson, Miss Wells—J. R. Lowell, H. R. Schoolcraft, Park Benjamin, E. A. Duyckinck, Wm. A. Jones,
            T. D. English, Wm. Wallace, A. M. Ide, Henry B. Hirst,
            Wm. Page (the artist), Henry C. Watson, the author of
            “The Vision of Rubeta,” Littleton Barry, and Edgar A.
            Poe. We have also numerous anonymous contributors
            who would do honor to any journal in the land. Mr.
            Simms, the novelist, Mrs. Ellett, and many others of note,
            will hereafter contribute. We mention these facts to do
            away with any evil impressions that might arise from a
            statement made in the September number of Simms’ Magazine, by a New-York correspondent, who no doubt intended us well.
         </p>
         
         <p>THE DATE of “The Saturday Courier” (of Philadelphia) from which we quoted a portion of Mr. Whittier's
            story, “The Broken-Hearted,” is June 19, 1841.
         </p>
         
         <p>IT WILL BE seen that we make our appearance this
            week in a new dress—and this will account for a little
            delay in our time of issue. It is our intention gradually
            but steadily to improve the paper at all points.
         </p>
         
         <p>THE EMBARRASSMENT, the delay, and general inconvenience arising from bad penmanship, can be thoroughly
            understood only by an editor. We are compelled, every
            week, to throw aside many valuable contributions merely
            because the wretched MS. renders them too expensive to
            be used. Once again, we say to our friends—write legibly or not at all. Take lessons of Mr. Goldsmith. You
            will find him in Broadway—289. We know no one so
            well qualified to teach a fluent, beautiful, and, what is of
            still more consequence, a legible hand-writing. We advise, at all events, a visit to his rooms, where in the way
            of really good penmanship, some absolute curiosities are
            to be seen. His Advertisement will be found in another
            column.
         </p>
         
         <p>MR. AUSTIN PHILLIPS and Mr. H. C. Watson, are about
            to establish a Glee Class upon a large scale. Full particulars will be announced next week.
         </p>
         
         
         
         <p>TO CORRESPONDENTS. Many thanks
            to M. O. of Lebanon Springs—also to
            the fair author of “Pictures”—also to
            A. M. I. We are forced to decline
            “Margarette”—“The Warrior’s Battle-Song”—“Hope”—and “On the
            Death of a Favorite Young Dog.” Our
            friends P. B.—P. P. C.—and T. H. C.
            shall hear from us in full in a few days.
            What has become of M. L. of Philadelphia. We are greatly indebted to
            Miss M. O.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">185</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">ӔOLIAN ATTACHMENT.</div>
            
            <p>HERMANN S. SARONI, Professor of Music, 116
               Leonard street, New York, leaches the Piano
               Forte, with or without Colemans celebrated Attachment.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">New Book and Stationery Store.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">SAXTON &amp; HUNTINGTON,
               
               <br></br>PUBLISHERS AND BOOKSELLERS,
               
               <br></br>No. 295 Broadway,
            </div>
            
            <p>KEEP on hand a full assortment of Theological, School, and Miscellaneous Books; also,
               Stationery, Fancy Articles, &amp;c.&amp;c.
            </p>
            
            <p>S. &amp; H. are Agents for the sale of the Publica-
               tions of the following Boston Houses, viz:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">James Munroe &amp; Co.              W. J. Reynolds,
               
               <br></br>Charles Tappan,	     Waite, Pierce &amp; Co.
               
               <br></br>Saxton &amp; Kelt,	    Crosby &amp; Nichols.
               
               <br></br>B. Perkins &amp; Co.                 Otis, Broaders &amp; Co.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PENMANSHIP.</div>
            
            <p>Reopening of goldsmiths writing
               ACADEMY, 289 Broadway. La Farge Build
               ings, corner of Reade Street. Terms reduced to
               THREE DOLLARS, AND NO EXTRA CHARGE.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the
               citizens of New York and Brooklyn, that his rooms
               are now open, during the day and evening, for Pu 
               pils and Visiters. Mr. G’s specimens of
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">PENMANSHIP</div>
            
            <p>has received the First Premium Five Years, from
               the American Institute, and he guarantees to all in
               Ten EASY AND INTERESTING EXERCISES,
               a free and elegant style of writing, that the pupils
               cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale at the Academy GOLDSMITH'S GEMS
               OF PENMANSHIP.
            </p>
            
            <p>Ladies' Class meets daily at 11 o'clock. Gentle
               men’s day and evening. See Circular. s18 2wis
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES</div>
            <p>—H. WORCHESTEB, NO. 139
               THIRD AVENUE, Corner of 14th Street, res
               pectfully informs his friends and the public, that he
               has a good assortment of Piano Fortes, in Rosewood
               and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons
               wishing to purchase will find it to their advantage
               to call and examine before purchasing elsewhere.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES</div>
            <p>—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy and Pethick,) invites the attention of the
               musical public to the elegant and varied assortment
               he now has at his Old Establishment, corner of Cottage Place and Bleecker street, which he will sell
               at prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J.P. having been actively engaged in the business
               for the last twenty years, and, for a large portion of
               that time manufacturing for two of the largest
               Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying
               that his instruments will bear a favorable compari
               son with those of the best makers in this country
               or Europe, and that they contain all the real improvements of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Secondhand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged,
               also Tuned and Repaired.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, April 23d, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">WEDDING, VISITING, &amp; PROFESSIONAL
               CARDS.
            </div>
            <div class="ab">engraved and printed at VALEN-
               
               <br></br>TINE'S, 1 Beekman street—Lovejoy’s Hotel.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES</div>
            <div class="ab">—V.F. HARRISON, CANAL
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron Frames, &amp;c., with a compass
               of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice
               materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience 
               in the business.
            </p>
            
            <p>N.B. Wanted a second hand Parlor Organ.</p>
            
            <p>Piano Fortes hired by the month.</p>
         </div>           
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES.</div>
            <p>—THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
               (formerly Conductor to Dubois and Stodart),
               No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment
               of the latest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes,
               of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared
               to guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch,
               and External Finish, and to endure in any climate.
               A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano
               Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always
               on hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">161 Broadway, September, 1845.</div>
            
            <div class="head">WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'S
               LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">"BOOKS WHICH ARE BOOKS."</div>
            
            <p>THE PUBLISHERS of the Library of Choice
               Reading beg leave to call attention to the fol
               lowing classification of the books published in the
               series by which it will appear that novelty, variety,
               and standard merit have always been preserved,
               and the promise of the original prospectus faithfully
               kept. It was proposed to publish “the best books of
               Travels, Biographies, works of Classic Fiction—
               where the moral is superior to the mere story, without any sacrifice of the interest—occasional choice
               volumes of Poetry. Essays, Criticism, Contributions
               to History, and generally such single volumes, writ
               ten by men of genius. as will equally delight the
               scholar and the general reader.” The books already
               issued and ready for immediate publication may be
               arranged as follows:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">BOOKS OF TRAVELS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">EOTHEN, OR TRACES OF TRAVEL BROUGHT
               
               <br></br>HOME FROM THE EAST.
               
               <br></br>THE FRENCH IN ALGIERS. By Lady Duff
               
               <br></br>Gordon.
               
               <br></br>THE CRESCENT AND THE CROS3—2 vols. By
               
               <br></br>Warburton.
               
               <br></br>SIR FRANCIS HEAD'S BUBBLES FROM THE
               
               <br></br>BRUNNEN.
               
               <br></br>BECKFORD’S ITALY, SPAIN, PORTUGAL, AND
               
               <br></br>VISIT TO THE MONASTERIES OF ALCO
               
               <br></br>BACA AND BATALHA—in press.
               
               <br></br>NOTES OF A JOURNEY THROUGH FRANCE
               
               <br></br>AND ITALY. By Hazlitt—IN PRESS.
            </div>
            
            <p>These will be followed by SIR FRANCIS HEAD’S
               Rough Notes of a Journey across the Pampas;—
               WATERTON’S Wanderings in South America; MISS
               RIGBY’S Letters from the Baltic; HENRY NELSON
               COLDERIGE’S Six Months in the West Indies, and
               THACKERAYSs Notes of a Journey from London to
               Cairo, and others—forming altogether one of the
               most original and select collections of books of tra
               vels ever published.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">CLASSIC FICTION.</div>
            
            <p>MARY SCHWEIDLER, THE AMBER WITCH
               The most interesting Trial for Witchcraft ever
               published.
            </p>
            
            <p>UNDINE AND SINTRAM AND HIS COMPANIONS. From the German of La Motte Fouque.</p>
            
            <p>THE DIARY OF LADY WILLOUGHBY</p>
            
            <p>HEADLONG HALL AND NIGHTMARE ABBEY
               ZSCHOKKE’S TALES. Translated by Parke Godwin.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE CROCK OF GOLD. By Marlin Farquhar
               Tupper.
            </p>
            
            <p>HEART AND THE TWINS. By Martin Farquhar
               Tupper.—IN PRESS.
            </p>
            
            <p>Under this department will be included the choicest
               new works of fiction as they issue from the press,
               and choice translations from the writers of the Continent. The following have been already announc
               ed: Mrs. Inchbald’s Nature and Art; Tales from
               Tuck and HOFFMAN, the White Lady and Peter
               Schlemihl; The Life and Adventures of Peter Wilkins, a Cornish Man; Melincourt and Crotchet Cas
               tle, by the author of Headlong Hall.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">ILLUSTRATIONS OF ENGLISH LITERATURE
               
               <br></br>LEIGH HUNT’S IMAGINATION AND FANCY
               
               <br></br>HAZLITTS DRAMATIC WRITERS OF THE
               
               <br></br>AGE OF ELIZABETH.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT’S CHARACTERS OF SHAKSPEARE
               
               <br></br>WILSON’S GENIUS AND CHARACTER OF
               
               <br></br>BURNS.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT'S LECTURES ON THE COMIC WRI-
               
               <br></br>TERS—IN PRESS.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT'S LECTURES ON THE ENGLISH
               
               <br></br>POETS—IN PRESS.
            </div>
            
            <p>The work of HAZLITT in this department, the 
               most eloquent commentator on English Literature,
               will be followed by various writings of CAMPBELL,
               WILSON, COLERIDGE, SOUTHEY, ELLIS, and others
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">BIOGRAPHY AND GENERAL LITERATURE
               
               <br></br>LEIGH HUNT'S INDICATOR AND COMPA-
               
               <br></br>NION—2 vols.
               
               <br></br>HOOD'S PROSE AND VERSE—2 vols.
               
               <br></br>CHARLES LAMB'S ESSAYS OF ELIA.
               
               <br></br>HAZLITT'S TABLE TALK—2d series, 2 vols.
               
               <br></br>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF BENVENUTO CELLINI
               
               <br></br>—IN PRESS.
            </div>
            
            <p>A complete collection of the writings of HAZLITT
               and LEIGH HUNT will form part of the series to be 
               published at short intervals; WALTER SATAGE LAN
               DOR's writings: DE QUINCET'S (the English opium
               eater) Miscellaneous Writings; James Smith's Rejected Addresses and the Poems and Ballads of BON
               GUALTIER.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">OLD ENGLISH LITERATURE.
               
               <br></br>BASIL MONTAGU'S SELECTIONS FROM TAY
               
               <br></br>LOR, SOUTH, BARROW, FULLER. &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>CHARLES LAMB'S SPECIMENS OF OLD ENG-
               
               <br></br>LISH DRAMATISTS WHO LIVED ABOUT
               
               <br></br>THE TIME OF SHAKSPEARE.
            </div>
            
            <p>These, the most perfect collections of the kind 
               ever published, will form the introduction in prose
               and verse to a series of the old English writers,
               including Sir Thomas MorE, Herbert, FULLER,
               Sir Thomas Browne, Milton, Selden, Bacon and
               others.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">AMERICAN SERIES.</div>
            
            <p>Of the "Library of American Book," the fol-
               lowing have already been issued:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">JOURNAL OF AN AFRICAN CRUISER, EDITED
               
               <br></br>BY NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE.
               
               <br></br>TALES BY EDGAR A. POE.
               
               <br></br>LETTERS FROM ITALY, BY J. T. HEADLEY.
               
               <br></br>THE WIGWAM AND THE CABIN. BY W. GIL-
               
               <br></br>MORE SIMMS
               
               <br></br>BIG ABEL AND THE LITTLE MANHATTAN,
               
               <br></br>BY CORNELIUS MATHEWS.
               
               <br></br>WANDERINGS OF THE PILGRIM UNDER THE
               
               <br></br>SHADOW OF THE JUNGFRAU, BY GEORGE
               
               <br></br>B, CHEEVER, D. D.—JUST READY.
            </div>
            
            <p>The following are in press:—Western Clearings,
               by Mary Clavers (Mrs Kirkland); Wanderings
               of a Pilgrim under the Shadow of the Jungfrau. by
               George B. Cheever; Views and Reviews in American History, Literature, and Fiction, a Miscellany,
               by W. Gilmore Simms; The Forest and the Prairie,
               by James Hall, author of the Border Tales; a new
               volume, by Nathaniel Hawthorne; The Old English Library, by W. N Jones; and other productions
               of American authors.
            </p>
         </div>     
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MESSRS. HARPER &amp; BROTHERS</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PUBLISH THIS DAY,
               
               <br></br>Elements of Morality and Polity.
               
               <br></br>BY PROF. HEWELL.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS valuable new production, from the pen of
               one of the most eminent scholars of the age,
               exhibits, in a most lucid, exact, and elegant style,
               the great principles of moral, political, and ecclesiastical science in a far more complete and methodical manner than has ever yet been presented to the
               public. In offering this great work to the American
               reader, the publisher begs leave to introduce it as
               the commencement of a new and attractive series
               of sterling books, to he issued by them, under the
               general designation of
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">HARPER’S NEW MISCELLANY;</div>
            
            <p>the volumes of which will be legibly printed, in
               duodecimo, on fine paper, and
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Bound in extra Muslin Gilt—Price
               
               <br></br>Fifty Cents a Volume,
            </div>
            
            <p>and issued at short intervals To render accessible
               to the million, the fullest advantages of popular instruction in the various divisions of human knowledge, is the design of the above series It is apparent in the present day, that books of intrinsic value
               are demanded by the people. Formerly the popu
               lar taste preferred mainly works of mere amusement
               —the great body of readers now seek them as vehicles of general knowledge books of a more permanently valuable caste—devoted to some of the
               departments of science, or general literature. A
               new race has sprung up, glowing with the first
               energies of youth, requiring more expanded ideas
               of the world in which they live, and a more reliable
               and well-digested knowledge of the men. and the
               events of other times and countries. A class of
               books expressly adapted to this demand, it is the
               aim of the publishers to supply; and at a price so
               exceedingly cheap that every perron of ordinary
               taste and advantages may thus become possessed
               of a
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Complete Library of the Best Litera-
               
               <br></br>ture of the Age.
            </div>
            
            <p>In this collection it is intended to include the best
               productions in every department of knowledge;
               popular philosophical treatise on topics of universal interest; the most compact and brilliant historical books; valuable biographical memories; modern
               voyages and travels, &amp;c.; together with scientific
               and other collateral divisions; in the selection of 
               all which, the most careful discrimination will be
               observed. A mere glance over the wide domain of
               our English literature will exhibit much yet unexplored and uncultivated, from which might be gathered the fruits of a rich, luxuriant harvest; besides
               which, the ever-teeming issues of the European
               press open a vast revenue of literary wealth, from
               which the above collection may be literally supplied. Original productions from American writers
               will also occasionally be introduced. In submitting,
               therefore, the esteemed work of Prof. WHEWLL
               as a kind of first-fruits of their "New Miscellany,"
               the publishers deem it only necessary to add, that
               their arrangements for carrying forward the enterprise being of the most complete and efficient kind,
               they confidently rely upon their efforts being met
               with a ready response from the entire reading community.
            </p>
            
            <p>This, they venture to believe, will be insured to
               their MISCELLANY, no less from the intrinsic value
               of the collection, than from its unparalleled econo
               my; each volume being elegantly produced, bound
               IN HANDSOME AND SUBSTANTIAL STYLE FITTED WITHOUT FARTHER EXPENSE FOR PERMANENT PRESERVATION in the library; the whole series being issued
               in uniform binding, while the price of each volume
               will be only Fifty Cents—far below the cost of
               any similar series of books yet published in this,
               or, it is believed, any other country.
            </p>
         </div>              
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES CHEAP FOR CASH.</div>
            <p>—THE
               subscribers have on hand a handsome assortment, 6, 6 1/2 and 7 octave, mahogany and rosewood
               pianos. which they will warrant and sell low f r
               cash or approved paper.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">GLENN, ROGERS &amp; CO., Manufacturers,
               
               <br></br>152 Fulton street, East of Broadway.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. F. BROWNE &amp; CO.
               manufacturer of the
               IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION HARP
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years with Erard.</div>
            
            <p>J. F. BROWNE respectfully informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has established
               himself for the manufacture
               and importation of these very beautiful instruments, at
            </p>	
            
            <div class="ab">281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET.</div>
            
            <p>His arrangements are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices,
               thereby saving purchasers the high duties 
               imposed by Tariff on these Instruments.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. F. Browne would observe, these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
               with all the modern improvements of
               London and Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy of tone, fineness of touch, and perfectness
               of mechanism. Particular care is taken
               to fit them for the extremes of climate in this country, in which respect they will
               be found far superior to any of European manufacture, imported in the usual way.
            </p>
            
            <p>These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and professional talent in
               Europe; among the latter, he would mention
               N. C. Boscha, who invariably selects from this establishment.
            </p>	
            
            <p>J. F. Browne begs to offer the opinions of some of the first professional talent in
               this country.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making
               a professional use of your Harps, and of
               testing their qualities, it affords me pleasure to certify, that in point of tone,
               workmanship, and above all, a solidity that stands proof
               against the inconstancy of our trying climate, they have in all cases given me the
               most entire satisfaction.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">January, 1845.	I am yours, CHARLES THIBAULT, No. 40 Beach St., N. Y.</div>
            
            <p>Dear Sir:—I write to express the delight I experienced in performing on one of your
               Harps at Sig. Casella's Concert in this city.—	
               The mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly superior to any harp I
               have heard for many years. I remember my old
               Master, Boscha, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no
               other. Yours, most truly, H.G. Trust.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Philadelphia, March 4th, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make
               I performed on at the St. George's Society
               Concert, is, in brilliancy of tone, touch, and elegance of workmanship, the finest
               I ever played on. This will apply to all your Harps.
               The grand six and a half Gothic Double action, is a most splendid instrument. Yours
               with respect, ELIZABETH SLOMAN.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, January 16th, 1845.		A pupil of N. C. Boscha.</div>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—Having at your request closely scrutinized your double-action
               Harps, I find they possess the best qualities of the first makers in Europe combined. That in the ease of touch, by which the
               most brilliant tone is obtained, in perfection and
               ease of modulation, they are superior to any I have used; their elegance of exterior
               must gratify the most refined taste. Your new
               Grand Gothic six and a half octave, is the most splendid effort of art yet produced
               in the musical world; it will give me great pleasure
               in recommending your Harps at every opportunity.	Yours Truly, HENRY HORN.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">January 12th, 1845.	An eminent professor, and Member of the Royal Academy.</div>
            
            <p>These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
               show the estimate of persons every way capable of
               making a correct decision. J. F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the
               Society of Arts, Philadelphia, for his splendid
               improvements in this delightful Instrument.
            </p>	
            
            <div class="ab">Harps from 300 to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.</div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The southern literary messenger</div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Proprietor. Published monthly,
               
               <br></br>at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            </div>
            
            <p>The MESSENGER has been established since
               1835, has a large subscrip ion list, and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office
               of the "Broadway Journal," 135 Nassau street.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PAINE &amp; BURGESS,</div>
            <div class="ab">will publish on Saturday
               
               <br></br>Medici Series of Italian Prose, Part 4th.
            </div>
            
            <p>The Citizen of a Republic—by Ansaldo Ceba, 1 vol.
               12mo. Price 50 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of the political writers of Italy, Ceba is consider
               ed the best. Bold and independent in his spirit—
               rich and varied in his learning lofty in his heroism
               —pure in his patriotism—unsullied in his piety—full
               of years, and ripe in experience he wrote this treatise. From the time it appeared, it became the text
               book of republicans in Italy and the manual of every
               generation of his countrymen.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">LATELY PUBLISHED.
               
               <br></br>CHALLENGE OF BARLETTA.—1 vol. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>THE FLORENTINE HISTORIES—2 vols. do.
            </div>
         </div>          
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JUST PUBLISHED BY H. G. DAGGERS,</div>
            <div class="ab">30 Ann
               
               <br></br>Street, New York.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE COTTON LORD. By Mrs. Stone. A Ro
               mance of the Rich and Poor, written by a lady of
               brilliant talents. 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>FRANKENSTEIN, by Mrs. Mary W. Shelley,
               wife of the illustrious poet. “It is among the most
               exciting and terrible of modern romances.”—Tri
               bune. 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>LAWRIE TODD, by John Galt, with an original
               preface by the original Lawne Todd, viz: Grant
               Thorburn, Esq. “Mr. Thorburn’s Preface is worth
               more than the price asked for the novel.” 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE NUN; or, Life in a Convent. By one of
               the Sisterhood. "A terrible exposition of the secret
               practices of Roman Catholics." 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>POOR JACK. By Captain Marryatt, author of
               Midshipman Easy, Peter Simple, &amp;c. 25 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B. All of the above will be sent for One Dol
               lar to any person ordering them through Postmasters, who are by law authorized to remit money to
               publishers. Any Postmaster ordering the above
               shall be presented with either novel he may select.
            </p>
         </div>
                       
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BEETHOVEN’S MOUNT OF OLIVES AND
               the SEVEN SLEEPERS
            </div>
            <p>—During the week of
               the American Musical Convention.—The sublime
               Oratorio of the Mount of Olives, by the immortal
               Beethoven, and the Seven Sleepers, by Dr. Lowe,
               will he performed at the Tabernacle, on Thursday
               evening, the 9th October next, under the direction of
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">MR. GEORGE LODER</div>
            
            <p>The Chorus and Orchestra will be full and effective, and the solo parts will be sustained by resident 
               talent
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. H. C. TIMM will preside at the Organ.</p>
            
            <p>Tickets, 50 cents each, may be obtained on and
               after Thursday next, at the principal music stores
               Subscribers will receive three tickets for one dollar
               as usual.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B.—The first rehearsal takes place on Thurs
               day evening next, at the Coliseum, 456 Broadway;
               where the undersigned will be most happy to meet
               all who have formerly rehearsed with him, and any
               other good readers who are disposed to aid in the
               attempt to bring out a d encourage resident talent.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">HENRY MEIGGS, 446 Broadway.</div>
         </div>          
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">G. H. DERWORT, PROFESSOR OP SINGING.</div>
            
            <p>Guitar and Piano Forte, has opened a class
               for Young Ladies, from 7 to 10 years of age, among
               whom are three of his own daughters, whom he
               proposes to thoroughly instruct in the art of Singing
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Derwort’s system is the remit of many years'
               observation and experience, during which be his
               successfully taught in Germany, London, and New
               York. His method cannot fail to impart to hit pupils a clear perception and a thorough knowledge
               of the grammatical principles of music with the
               ability to harmonize any simple given melody.
            </p>
            
            <p>Parents and guardians are invited to rail at his
               Rooms, 427 Broadway, when every inquiry will be
               answered.
            </p>
            
            <p>Terms $20 per annum, payable quarterly in ad
               vance. Lessons three times a week.
            </p>
            
            <p>Private instruction as heretofore.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER</div>
            <p>—JAMES
               PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near
               Elm. A Large Stock of the finest instruments al
               ways on hand. Terms moderate. FOR SALE—A
               Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be told at a great
               bargain for cash.
            </p>
         </div>
                       
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. BALLARD, PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Singing, and Flute, No. 135 Spring street.</div>
         </div>       
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">CARD OF REMOVAL.</div>
            <p>—MR. W. A KING,
               Professor of Music and Teacher of the PianoForte and Organ, has Removed to the First House
               above Twenty-Fifth Street on the Rail-Road (4th
               Avenue)
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>    
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p23">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">186</div>
         <div class="note" type="headnote">Our First Volume.—A few copies of
            the first volume of the Broadway Jonrnal are for sale at the office, either in
            numbers or neatly bound.
         </div>
         
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY
            JOURNAL.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>M. Baullemet, Mobile, Ala.
            
            <br></br>Robinson A Jones, Cincinnati, O.
            
            <br></br>D. M. Dewey, Rochester, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>W. E. Russell, Schenectady, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Levi Willard, Troy, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>G. Jones, Albany, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>S F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore, Md.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.
            
            <br></br>Thos. H. Pease, New-Hsven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>J. C. Morgan, New-Orleans.
            
            <br></br>W. W. Kingsley, New-London, Ct.
            
            <br></br>G. N. Beesley, Utica, N Y.
            
            <br></br>H. B. Strang, Peekskill, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Haliburton &amp; Dudley Boston, Masss.
            
            <br></br>S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Peter Cooke, Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>H. Esten, Providence, R.I.
            
            <br></br>Safford &amp; Park, Norwich. Ct.
         </div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      <div class="note" id="n001">
         <a href="/#/issues/18450927/p21">*Copernicus</a>
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>