<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450621</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. I.     NO. 10. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JUNE 21, 1845.     NO. 25.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum. 
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS.
         
         <br></br>Published at 153 BROADWAY, 
         
         <br></br>by JOHN BlSCO.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Adventures of a Gentleman in Search of a Dinner.</div>
         <div class="biblPage">385</div>
         
         <div class="head">THE ADVENTURES OF A GENTLEMAN IN SEARCH OF A DINNER.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">RELATED BY HIMSELF.</div>
         
         <p>In the year eighteen hundred and something, I forget the
            figures, but it was the year of the cholera in New York, I became acquainted in Paris with a gentleman of my own years
            named Julius Bartol. Our first meeting was at a ball at the
            American Ambassador's, and our last at the Rocher, where we
            had such a dinner as the Rocher alone could produce. Bartol
            was a New Yorker by birth, and he gloried in being called a
            Knickerbocker, but his tastes, his predilections, his habits and
            his education were thoroughly French. He had been sent to
            Paris at an early age to be placed in a commercial Academy,
            for his father was a merchant and meant that his son should
            be one; but before his education was completed, old Bartol
            died and left him a very large estate. He abandoned the idea
            of business, and after spending a few years in Paris returned
            to New York, and married a lady with an estate equal to his
            own. His position in society, from his great wealth, being infinitely above my own, I had purposely avoided him after his
            return home, but one day as I was crossing the Park, after
            having suffered martyrdom in a cross-examination by two impertinent lawyers in the City Hall, I met him and he expressed so much unaffected good will towards me, that I accepted
            an invitation to dine with him the next day.
         </p>
         
         <p>"You remember our dinner at the Rocher?" said Bartol.</p>
         
         <p>"Remember it," I replied, "as the Hoosier said, I remember nothing else."</p>
         
         <p>"Very good," said Bartol, "I am glad to hear it, I will give
            you a better one to-morrow; our cook is a second Vatel; but
            that is nothing; my wife will dine with us, and you shall know
            what it is to sit down with an angel. But come early and romp
            with my little girls before dinner; there will be but two or
            three friends besides."
         </p>
         
         <p>I am no glutton, I am not even a bon vivant, but I have a
            passion for good dinners, and although I have a tolerably enthusiastic feeling for works of what are called fine art, I am
            not ashamed to own that no tableau ever charmed me like a
            well appointed table. The extent of the benefit to be derived
            from a picture is a momentary sensation of pleasure, but the
            benefits of a good table are health, life, cheerfulness, content,
            pleasant dreams and a lively fancy. There can be no doubt
            that infinite harm has been done in our day by the wickedness
            of business and learned men, in affecting an indifference to
            the table. All stoicism is false and injurious, but the stoicism
            of the dinner table is the most false and injurious of all. We
            make the most lavish and ostentatious provisions for the nurture
            of the mind, but leave the body to the mercies of the most ignorant and degraded parties of our household; and, as if we
            were afraid of enjoying good health, we heap every term of
            contempt upon the servant in whose integrity and skill the
            health of body and mind depend, namely, the cook. Perhaps
            much of the indifference shown towards the table, is owing to
            the frequency of our meals, which allowing us no time to gain
            an appetite, renders eating rather a nauseous duty, than a keen
            delight. It is surprising that among our classicists, no one has
            ever thought of imitating the Romans in regard to their meals.
            They, as is well known, ate but once a day, and then they
            came to their dinners with good appetites and a lively sense of
            the importance of the duty of eating. Dispepsia was unknown
            among them, and any schoolboy will talk to you of Roman
            firmness, of Roman courage, of Roman patriotism and a thousand other virtues, which I fear will never be honored by an
            American prefix. And then what arms and legs, and necks
            and shoulders, do sculptors and painters give to Roman
            soldiers and even Roman poets. To sum up the whole matter
            in two words, the Romans dined but once a day and conquered
            the world. Gen. Jackson has sometimes been called an old
            Roman, and one of his admirers has lately sent him the sarcophagus of Alexander Severus for his coffin; but there is as
            much difference between the shrunk shanks of the modern and
            the thews and sinews of the old Roman, as there is between
            the wooden coffins of the modem and the marbles ones of the
            ancients. We must go back to the one meal system before
            stone coffins will seem applicable for our slender carcasses. It
            is the pernicious system of eating four times a day that has
            led to the invention of all the salmis and potages, which cause
            gout, dyspepsia and dropsy, by tempting us to eat when we
            have no inclination for the table; but eating once a day would
            not only lead us to attach more importance to the ethics of the
            table, but would save us from the frightful amount of charlatanry and empiricism, that are practiced in our kitchens, as
            well as in our universities and legislatures.
         </p>
         
         <p>Do I practice what I preach? Of course I do, and I am
            never troubled with a disinclination for my dinner. On the
            contrary, I am sure of one great pleasure every day of my
            life, let what will happen, for I can hardly conceive of any
            trouble of sufficient magnitude to make a man in good health,
            who eats but once a day, forget his dinner. There was one
            thing to dampen in a degree the pleasure which I anticipated
            in dining with my friend Bartol. His dinner hour was three
            o'clock, while my own is invariably five. Therefore my appetite would lack two hours sharpness; but I obviated this
            difficulty by eating a lighter dinner the day before. I omitted
            exactly one fresh roll and a meringue, which balanced very
            nearly the two hours, for when one o'clock came I felt about
            the same degree of hunger that I usually do at three.
         </p>
         
         <p>Let me satisfy my friend, the reader, in the outset of my
            adventures, that I had no mercenary motive in accepting the in vitation of Bartol, for I was compelled to buy a white vest, a
            pair of kid gloves, a linen pocket handkerchief, and a pair of
            Mack French cassimere pantaloons, the cest of which would
            have paid for a good many dinners. The truth is, that I very
            seldom go to a dinner-party, because I have found by experience that a good dinner is very uncertain, and, therefore, I
            had not on hand the necessary apparel to appear in on such an
            occasion. But I had no fear of Bartol; I knew that his dinner
            would justify me in the expense of an entire suit, although it
            so happened that my funds were extremely low, and I had neglected to cultivate a credit at any of the tailoring establish ments. After I had paid for my new clothes I had just a half
            
            eagle and two shilling pieces in my pocket, and I had no expectation of getting more until next dividend day, a month off,
            unless the publisher of a certain Review should keep his
            promise and pay me for my essay on "Dinners in the time of
            the Revolution," an event which I had no right to hope for,
            having nothing better than an editor's word to depend upon.
         </p>
         
         <p>As Bartol lived in the most fashionable extremity of the city
            I was forced to take a cab, for the streets were dusty as usual,
            when they are not muddy, and the cab hire was but a trifle
            compared with the injury which my clothes would receive from
            the dust. The cabman was a saucy fellow and demanded three
            shillings, but I had induced him to take me for two, for I was
            loth to break in upon my half eagle. The fellow drove off
            pretty briskly until he had got entirely clear of the cab stand,
            and then he slacked up and let his horse walk.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Come, Sir," I said, "this will never do; drive faster."</p>
         
         <p>"Are you in a hurry?" said the cabman.</p>
         
         <p>"Certainly, I am," I replied.</p>
         
         <p>"Well, I am not," said the cabman; "I agreed to take you
            for two shillings, but I shall take my own time for it; unless
            you give me another shilling."
         </p>
         
         <p>"I will not give you another penny, you blackguard," I replied.</p>
         
         <p>"Very well," said he, "here goes then, slow and easy. I
            like it and so does my hoss, Bossy. Take your time, Mister."
         </p>
         
         <p>I felt for my watch, and missing it, remembered that I had
            left it at the watch-maker's to be cleaned. There was time
            enough, however, even at the slow pace at which I was going,
            to reach Bartol's by three, provided that we made no stops,
            and I should only miss romping with the children, which I
            rather preferred doing. Drag; drag; drag; I grew impatient
            every moment; I caught a glance at a clock in a soda shop,
            and it lacked ten minutes of three. "Do have the goodness,
            my friend," I said in a subdued voice, "to drive a little faster.
            I must get to Marmion-place by three."
         </p>
         
         <p>"What did you observe?" said the driver.</p>
         
         <p>"I observed that you must drive faster, or I shall be too
            late for dinner."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Whoa! Whoa," said the cabman, checking his horse and
            coming to a dead halt. "What did you observe, Sir; there is
            such a noise that I couldn't hear."
         </p>
         
         <p>"You'll repent of this, you scamp," said I, "go a-head."</p>
         
         <p>"What makes you think so, Sir," he said, looking me in the
            face; "perhaps you'll repent of not paying me my full fare."
         </p>
         
         <p>I saw there was no use in parleying with the scoundrel, so I
            swallowed the hard words that were rising in my throat and
            made him no reply. He whistled, "Take your time, Miss Lucy,"
            and put his horse in motion again, but he came to a halt at the
            corner of fourth street, to let a couple of omnibusses go past
            that had started on a race from Union Square. I knew it must
            be three, and I fancied that the soup was put upon the table.
            I was fast losing all command of myself, but I was determined
            not to be bullied out of a shilling; the French roll and the
            meringue were too much for two hours, and my appetite was
            sharper than usual at five. When a man eats but once in
            twenty-four hours, it is very essential that his dinner should not
            be delayed. "I tell you how it is, Sir," I said to the cabman in
            a sharper tone, "if you do not drive me to Marmion-place in
            less than five minutes, I will make an example of you, you
            villain."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Who do you call a villain, Mister?" said the enraged cabman jumping from his box. "I am no villain. I am an honest
            man. I work for my living; my name is Bunkum. I don't
            take that from nobody."
         </p>
         
         <p>On any other occasion I would not have cared a copper for
            the fellow. I could have flogged him with ease. But now I
            could do nothing but run, the passers-by began to gather on
            the side-walk, and to escape a row I opened the cab door, and
            jumping out began to walk very briskly towards Marmionplace, which was but a short distance off. The cabman jumped upon his box again and followed me, crying out, "pay me
            my fare, will you, pay me my fare." At first I said I would
            not pay him, but not caring to be followed by the rogue to
            Bartol's door, I put my hand in my pocket and reached him
            the two shillings. It was five minutes past three by St. Bartholomew's clock, but I hurried on and at the corner of Eighth
            street, encountered a spiral cloud of dust and anthracite ashes,
            which nearly blinded me, and made my shirt bosom look like
            a soot bag. I could have cried for vexation if I had not been
            so hungry; but I shook myself and hurried on, and reached
            Marmion-place precisely ten minutes past three. I shall certainly miss the soup, I said to myself, as I glanced up at a
            bronze door with the name of Bartol emblazoned on a silver
            plate. If I had known nothing of the owner, I should have
            said at a glance, "here lives a giver of good dinners." The
            house was one of the best specimens of a city residence that I
            had ever seen. It had a bit of green sward on one side with
            a small tree in the centre, the expense of which, was probably
            greater than an ordinary farm of three or four hundred acres;
            for in a city land rises in cost as it falls in real value. The
            house was exactly such a one as I should have expected a man
            of Bartol's refinement to build; large and imposing, but without anything that looked like ostentation or a love of show. I
            was so well satisfied with the exterior, that, bating my appetite, I was impatient to see its interior, and above all, the table.
            The front blinds were closed, which looked strange, as there
            was an umbrage screened by a woodbine and trellis-work. I
            pulled the bell. The door was instantly opened by a black
            servant, who put up his hand as I stepped upon the door-sill,
            and said:
         </p>
         
         <p>"Don't come in, Sir, if you please, their's a contiguous
            disorder in the house."
         </p>
         
         <p>"A what!" I exclaimed.</p>
         
         <p>"A contiguous disease, Sir. Miss Agnes has been took
            very ill with the scarlet fever--"
         </p>
         
         <p>"Perhaps I have mistaken the house; is this Mr. Charles
            Bartol's?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"Ah! F," said Bartol, who came running through the hall.
            "My darling little Agnes has broken out with the scarlet fever
            and we are in a terrible fright. Don't come in, I am told that
            it is dangerous to visit when the disease is in a house. Dear
            little girl! I have not left her bedside a moment since she
            was taken, for my wife is quite distracted. God help us, but
            I fear the poor child will not survive. I am every moment
            expecting a consultation of physicians." A very faint cough
            was heard and Bartol darted away without saying another
            word, and the servant closed the door in my face. A few moments before the bronze door looked like the gates of Paradise,
            it now looked as gloomy as 
            <span class="person" id="dalighieri">Dante</span>'s gates in the Inferno. What
            was to be done. I tried to think of some friend living in the
            neighborhood whom I could drop in upon at a family dinner;
            but I couldn't think of a soul. It was a good mile from any
            respectable restaurant, and I had neglected to order dinner as
            usual at my lodgings. I had never in my life been so sharp
            set before. The vision of Bartol's dinner which had haunted
            my imagination for the past twenty-four hours had caused a
            flood of gastric juice that called for dinner in accents not to
            be misunderstood.
         </p>
         
         <p>The holy Saint Wulstan confessed that thoughts of dinner
            had sometimes intruded themselves upon his devotions; and
            another good English saint, according to Dr. 
            <span class="person" id="rsouthey">Southey</span> used
            often to exclaim--
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>"O belly, belly
            
            <br></br>You would be gormandizing now I know,
            
            <br></br>But it shall not be so
            
            <br></br>Home to your bread and water, home,
            
            <br></br>I tell ye."
         </div>
         
         <p>How then could I, who am no saint but a poor sinner, keep
            my mind free from such thoughts in an extremity like this? I
            I turned my back upon the uppish people and with my face
            towards down-town began to debate in my mind whether it
            would be better to dine at Delmonico's, or Blancard's. I settled
            upon the latter, because it was the nearest, and not from any
            preference to its gloomy facade, which looks more like a prison
            than a salle a manger Granite is a very unsuitable material
            for an eating-house, unless it were one where Norfolk dumplings or some such solids are served up. The white marble
            Corinthian columns at the entrance of Delmonico's triangular
            cafe give a very cheerful and inviting aspect to the house, and,
            I have no doubt are great promoters of digestion.
         </p>
         
         <p>As I passed by the New York hotel, and heard the tantalizing clatter of knives and plates in the dining-room, I recollected that my friend H. had recently taken up his quarters
            there, and driven by hunger, I walked into the office of the
            hotel, and inquired for him, trusting that he might invite me to
            dine with him. He came to me in a moment with a napkin in
            his hand, and begged me to wait one minute until he had
            finished his soup. But he said not a word about my dining
            with him. In a minute or two, which seemed like an hour to
            me, he reappeared, saying that he was deuced glad to see me
            for he was going out of town that afternoon, and had only time
            to eat a plate of soup for his dinner, and would be eternally
            obliged to me if I would call upon his partner in the morning
            and say that he had left his bank-book at the Merchant's Bank.
            I am afraid that I did not treat him with much courtesy, for he
            has never spoken to me since. But politeness in my condition
            was out of the question. I came out of the hotel and walked
            very rapidly towards Blancard's with my eyes averted from 
            oyster cellars, and baker's shops, lest I should be tempted into 
            them and so lose a regular dinner. Arrived at the Globe I
            entered its heavy looking portal and hurried through the
            marble hall into the dining room. What a delightful sight! what 
            an altogether charming and cheering place it is! A perfect
            gem of a restaurant. There was but one unoccupied table
            which I took possession of, and casting my eye over the potages
            on the Carte du jour, began to feel the most delightful of all titilations. I knew the soups perfectly well by name and I knew
            also that the julien was particularly good. So I ordered that
            but first a dozen of Shrewsbury oysters in the shell, with a
            lemon, then a filet de boeuf au champignons and a meringue 
            and coffee; wine I never drink when I can get Croton water.
            This was a very moderate dinner to be sure, but I have already
            said that I am no glutton; the fresh rolls and the butter are
            particularly fine at the Globe, and the appointments of the
            table are so perfect that even so moderate a dinner may be
            eaten with entire satisfaction. I might have eaten a trifle 
            more, a croquet or a plate of maccaroni; but I began moderately. The composure with which I spread my napkin and
            cut my loaf was really marvellous. The waiter had been
            gone just three minutes for the oysters, when a person came in
            and seated himself at the table opposite to me, in whose presence I could not eat my dinner in peace. It is too long a
            story, to tell the reasons of my antipathy to him; he had
            wronged me in a manner that debarred me from any other satisfaction than contempt; my dinner, though ordered, had not been
            touched, and being too much excited in my feelings to make
            any explanations to the clerk, I rose from the table immediately and walked out of the house, intending to return the next
            day and make an apology. Now then, there was no choice,
            Delmonico's was the next resource. Here the dinners were
            quite as good, the carle as extensive, and the prices as low,
            perhaps lower; but the company was more promiscuous and
            the finish was not so high. I had always had an objection to
            the great mirrors in the dining-room, and the monstrous bronze
            chandeliers, to say nothing of two unceasing harpers who are
            forever clanging the songs of the last opera, and worse than
            all the black pepper in square salt cellars. These things more
            than counterbalanced the white marble pillars; but I shut my
            eyes very heroically to all minor defects and entered the coffee
            room with a determination of repeating the orders that I had
            given at the Globe. Oysters, potage a la julienne, filet de
            boeuf au champignons, and a meringue au something. Although
            I never drink wine, as I have already stated, yet I sometimes
            drink absynthe very much diluted, and fearing that my long fast
            would injure my stomach, I stopped at the bar and called for a
            glass of that bitte stuff, which I drank and put my hand in my
            pocket, for the half eagle, when, O, horror! the thought of the
            thing makes me sick even now, I found only a shilling. I had
            given my half eagle to that villain cab-man by mistake. My
            glass of wormwood cost me a shilling, and I had not another
            copper to bless myself with. What could I do! A thought
            struck me; and a very happy thought it was; I will order the
            dinner and go and pawn my watch; by the time that I get back
            from Chatham street it will be ready and what a dinner I shall
            make! I varied the order by the addition of a lobster salad
            and hurried off. When I reached Chatham street I remembered that ray watch was at the watchmaker's; never mind
            that, I had a gold pencil-case, but worse and worse, it was
            Saturday afternoon and not a pawnbroker's shop was open,
            What religious rascals those Jews are. Every moment my
            appetite was getting sharper and sharper, and I began to think
            of the "French and English" dining saloons, in Nassau street,
            where a plate of any thing may be had for a sixpence; but I
            hadn't the sixpence even; and Mr. Gosling, in spite of his
            name is too old a bird to be caught with chaff; I could not descend to ask him to give me credit for a sixpenny dinner;
            neither could I return to Delmonico's and request them to trust
            me. In passing down Nassau street I encountered the sign of
            Mons. Napoleon Bunel, restaurateur from Paris. If there is
            any thing in a name, I thought, this Napoleon among restaurateurs must be a grand place for a dinner, and if he has any
            of the great qualities of his namesake he will not refuse me
            credit for a filet. Hunger makes its own laws, and I had
            only to obey its dictates. I made a bold push therefore into
            the saloon of Mons. Bunel, and was charmed at once by the
            coup d'oeil Madame B. a jolly looking creature wearing a
            lace cap and violet ribbons, sat behind the bar, in the character
            of dame du Comptoir; a large boquet of roses and a box of
            segars on either side of her. The floor was sanded, which I
            disliked, it gives one the feeling of dining in the street; the
            walls were painted by some unhappy artist who had made terrible work in trying to give a resemblance of trees and green
            fields, which rather added to the outer-doorishness of the
            saloon. However, I am never given to fault finding, and I had
            no disposition to be critical just then; so I took my seat at one
            of the marble slabs, and opened the yellow covered carte with
            a palpitation of the heart. A tall lusty looking garcon in a
            white jacket stood by me with his ear a little inclined towards
            ray mouth to catch the first accents of my order. I had set
            my heart upon potage a la julien and so forth, and I gave the
            same order that I had given at the Globe and Delmonico's, with
            the addition of a fricandeau, and a Charlotte ruse, for
            my appetite had grown to a boundless craving. Off ran
            the garcon and I heard the confused sound of deshuits
            potage julie filet deboeufau champignonpommedeterr ala'mait ode'
            hotellobstersaladfricandeaudeVeauepinardmeringueaumarsquin
            charlotterusevanillecafe as the order was shouted through
            a tin tube that communicated with the kitchen. I debated with myself one moment whether it would be better to
            ask Mons. Bunel to give me credit before or after eating the
            dinner, but I decided at once on the first as being the most
            honorable, although the latter would be the most certain. Accordingly I beckoned to Mons. B. who came to me with a smile
            on his countenance and a spotless napkin on his arm. You
            have a capital place here, Mons. Bunel, quite a little Rocher;
            Mons. bowed. I have ordered a bit of a dinner, some soup
            and a trifle or two, but I made the oddest mistake just now in
            giving a cabman a half eagle for a shilling, and I have not got
            another copper in my pocket and the banks being closed I cannot get any money before to-morrow. I suppose you will have
            no objections to giving me credit for my dinner?
         </p>
         
         <p>Mons. never smiled again, at least in my presence;--he not
            only refused to trust me, but he refused to take my gold pencil
            in pawn; expressing some doubts of its being honestly come
            by. At that moment the waiter made his appearance with the
            Shrewsburys and the lemon, but they immediately disappeared
            again, and I was compelled to make my retreat under the searching eyes of Madame and all the guests at the tables.
         </p>
         
         <p>What must I do? What could I do? I was completely at
            my wit's end. A happy thought popped into my head. The
            proprietor of the Franklin coffee-house knew me well. He would
            trust me of course. I hurried immediately down to his establishment, and looked at the larder as I passed into the diningroom. What a magnificent sight his larder is! Turkies, saddles of mutton, salmon, lobsters, sirloins, rounds of beef, roastingpigs, cauliflowers and strawberries. These were a few of the
            objects that caught my eye, and I determined at once upon a
            thorough English dinner. Confound your potages and fricandeaus. I will have, I said, as I walked into this glorious eatinghouse, salmon and melted butter, a mug of ale, roast lamb and
            mint sauce, with potatoes and cauliflowers, then a magnificent
            slice of roast beef with asparagus, and bread and butter; then
            a rhubarb tart and Gloster cheese, and a dish of strawberries
            and cream. This is one of the most enticing places to a
            hearty eater that New-York can boast of. Everything about
            it is solid and substantial,--long marble counters, old mahogany
            chairs, thick, heavy and comfortable, immense mirrors, pictures of game and sporting scenes; and then the host himself,
            bluff, red-faced, bull-necked and hearty, with immense jowls,
            and a mouth that seems to have been made expressly for
            eating; one of those plethoric apertures which one never
            anticipates any good thing from, notwithstanding that good
            things are continually going in thereat. Like certain favorites
            of the public who are in constant receipt of favors, but never
            make any bestowals in return.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">[To be continued.]</div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Morella</div>
         <div class="biblPage">388</div>
         <div class="head">MORELLA.</div>
         
         <p>Avro Ka?' avro ???' avrov, ?ovo ?id?? ai?i ov.
            Itself, by itself solely, one everlastingly, and single.
            
            <span class="person" id="plato">Plato</span>. Sympos.
         </p>
         
         <p>With a feeling of deep yet most singular affection I regarded
            my friend Morella. Thrown by accident into her society many
            years ago, my soul, from our first meeting, burned with fires it
            had never before known; but the fires were not of Eros , and
            bitter and tormenting to my spirit was the gradual conviction
            that I could in no manner define their unusual meaning, or regulate their vague intensity. Yet we met; and fate bound us
            together at the altar; and I never spoke of passion, nor
            thought of love. She, however, shunned society, and,attaching
            herself to me alone, rendered me happy. It is a happiness to
            wonder;--it is a happiness to dream.
         </p>
         
         <p>Morella's erudition was profound. As I hope to live, her talents were of no common order--her powers of mind were gigantic. I felt this, and, in many matters, became her pupil. I
            soon, however, found that, perhaps on account of her Presburg
            education, she placed before me a number of those mystical
            writings which are usually considered the mere dross of the
            early German literature. These, for what reason I could not
            imagine, were her favorite and constant study--and that, in
            process of time they became my own, should be attributed to the
            simple but effectual influence of habit and example.
         </p>
         
         <p>In all this, if I err not, my reason had little to do. My convictions, or I forget myself, were in no manner acted upon by
            the ideal, nor was any tincture of the mysticism which I read,
            to be discovered, unless I am greatly mistaken, either in my
            deeds or in my thoughts. Persuaded of this, I abandoned myself implicitly to the guidance of my wife, and entered with an
            unflinching heart into the intricacies of her studies. And then
            --then, when, pouring over forbidden pages, I felt a forbidden
            spirit enkindling within me--would Morella place her cold hand
            upon my own, and rake up from the ashes of a dead philosophy some low, singular words, whose strange meaning burned
            themselves in upon my memory. And then, hour after hour,
            would I linger by her side, and dwell upon the music of her
            voice--until, at length, its melody was tainted with terror,--and
            there fell a shadow upon my soul--and I grew pale, and shuddered inwardly at those too unearthly tones. And thus, joy
            suddenly faded into horror, and the most beautiful became the
            most hideous, as Hinnon became Ge-Henna.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is unnecessary to state the exact character of those disquisitions which, growing out of the volumes I have mentioned,
            formed, for so long a time, almost the sole conversation of
            Morella and myself. By the learned in what might be termed
            theological morality they will be readily conceived, and by the
            unlearned they would, at all events, be little understood. The
            wild Pantheism of Fichte; the modified Παλτγγευεστα of the
            Pythagoreans; and, above all, the doctrines of Identity as urged by Schelling, were generally the points of discussion presenting the most of beauty to the imaginative Morella. That
            identity which is termed personal, Mr. Locke, I think, truly defines to consist in the sameness of a rational being. And since
            by person we understand an intelligent essence having reason,
            and since there is a consciousness which always accompanies
            thinking, it is this which makes us all to be that which we call
            ourselves--thereby distinguishing us from other beings that
            think, and giving us our personal identity. But the principium
            individuationis--the notion of that identity which at death is or
            is not lost forever, was to me--at all times, a consideration of
            intense interest; not more from the perplexing and exciting nature of its consequences, than from the marked and agitated
            manner in which Morella mentioned them.
         </p>
         
         <p>But, indeed, the time had now arrived when the mystery of
            my wife's manner oppressed me as a spell. I could no longer
            bear the touch of her wan fingers, nor the low tone of her musical language, nor the lustre of her melancholy eyes. And she
            knew all this, but did not upbraid; she seemed conscious of
            my weakness or my folly, and, smiling, called it Fate. She
            seemed, also, conscious of a cause, to me unknown, for the
            gradual alienation of my regard; but she gave me no hint or
            token of its nature. Yet was she woman, and pined away
            daily. In time, the crimson spot settled steadily upon the
            cheek, and the blue veins upon the pale forehead became prominent; and, one instant, my nature melted into pity, but, in the
            next, I met the glance of her meaning eyes, and then my soul
            sickened and became giddy with the giddiness of one who gazes downward into some dreary and unfathomable abyss.
         </p>
         
         <p>Shall I then say that I longed with an earnest and consuming desire for the moment of Morella's decease? I did; but
            the fragile spirit clung to its tenement of clay for many days--
            for many weeks and irksome months--until my tortured nerves
            obtained the mastery over my mind, and I grew furious through
            delay, and, with the heart of a fiend, cursed the days, and the
            hours, and the bitter moments, which seemed to lengthen and
            lengthen as her gentle life declined--like shadows in the dying
            of the day.
         </p>
         
         <p>But one autumnal evening, when the winds lay still in heaven, Morella called me to her bed-side. There was a dim mist
            over all the earth, and a warm glow upon the waters, and, amid
            the rich October leaves of the forest, a rainbow from the firmament had surely fallen.
         </p>
         
         <p>"It is a day of days," she said, as I approached; "a day of
            all days either to live or die. It is a fair day for the sons of
            
            earth an life--ah, more fair for the daughters of heaven and
            death!"
         </p>
         
         <p>I kissed her forehead, and she continued:</p>
         
         <p>"I am dying, yet shall I live."</p>
         
         <p>"Morella!"</p>
         
         <p>"The days have never been when thou couldst love me--
            but her whom in life thou didst abhor, in death thou shalt
            adore."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Morella!"</p>
         
         <p>"I repeat that I am dying. But within me is a pledge of
            that affection--ah, how little!--which thou didst feel for me,
            Morella. And when my spirit departs shall the child live--thy
            child and mine, Morella's. But thy days shall be days of sorrow--that sorrow which is the most lasting of impressions, as
            the cypress is the most enduring of trees. For the hours of thy
            happiness are over; and joy is not gathered twice in a life, as
            the roses of Paestum twice in a year. Thou shalt no longer,
            then, play the Teian with time, but, being ignorant of the myrtle and the vine, thou shalt bear about with thee thy shroud on
            earth, as do the Moslemin at Mecca."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Morella!" I cried, "Morella! how knowest thou this?"--
            but she turned away her face upon the pillow, and, a slight
            tremor coming over her limbs, she thus died, and I heard her
            voice no more.
         </p>
         
         <p>Yet, as she had foretold, her child--to which in dying she
            had given birth, and which breathed not until the mother breathed no more--her child, a daughter, lived. And she grew
            strangely in stature and intellect, and was the perfect resemblance of her who had departed, and I loved her with a love more
            fervent than I had believed it possible to feel for any denizen
            of earth.
         </p>
         
         <p>But, ere long, the heaven of this pure affection became darkened, and gloom, and horror, and grief, swept over it in clouds.
            I said the child grew strangely in stature and intelligence.-Strange indeed was her rapid increase in bodily size--but terriable, oh! terrible were the tumultuous thoughts which crowded upon me while watching the development of her mental being. Could it be otherwise, when I daily discovered in the
            conceptions of the child the adult powers and faculties of the
            woman?--when the lessons of experience fell from the lips of
            infancy? and when the wisdom or the passions of maturity I
            found hourly gleaming from its full and speculative eye? When,
            I say, all this became evident to my appalled senses--when I
            could no longer hide it from my soul, nor throw it off from those
            perceptions which trembled to receive it--is it to be wondered
            at that suspicions, of a nature fearful and exciting, crept in upon
            my spirit, or that my thoughts fell back aghast upon the wild
            tales and thrilling theories of the entombed Morella? I snatched from the scrutiny of the world a being whom destiny compelled me to adore, and in the rigorous seclusion of my home,
            watched with an agonizing anxiety over all which concerned
            the beloved.
         </p>
         
         <p>And, as years rolled away, and I gazed, day after day, upon
            her holy, and mild, and eloquent face, and poured over her maturing form, day after day did I discover new points of resemblance in the child to her mother, the melancholy and the dead.
            And, hourly, grew darker these shadows of similitude, and more
            full, and more definite, and more perplexing, and more hideously
            terrible in their aspect. For that her smile was like her mother's I could bear; but then I shuddered at its too perfect identity
            --that her eyes were like Morella's I could endure; but then
            they too often looked down into the depths of my soul with
            Morella's own intense and bewildering meaning. And in the
            contour of the high forehead, and in the ringlets of the silken
            hair, and in the wan fingers which buried themselves therein,
            and in the sad musical tones of her speech, and above all--oh,
            above all--in the phrases and expressions of the dead on the
            lips of the loved and the living, I found food for consuming 
            thought and horror--for a worm that would not die.
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus passed away two lustra of her life, and, as yet, my
            daughter remained nameless upon the earth. "My child" and
            "my love" were the designations usually prompted by a father's
            affection, and the rigid seclusion of her days precluded all other
            intercourse. Morella's name died with her at her death. Of
            the mother I had never spoken to the daughter;--it was impossible to speak. Indeed, during the brief period of her existence
            the latter had received no impressions from the outward world
            save such as might have been afforded by the narrow limits of
            her privacy. But at length the ceremony of baptism presented
            to my mind, in its unnerved and agitated condition, a present 
            deliverance from the terrors of my destiny. And at the baptismal fount I hesitated for a name. And many titles of the wise
            and beautiful, of old and modern times, of my own and foreign
            lands, came thronging to my lips, with many, many fair titles of
            the gentle, and the happy, and the good. What prompted me,
            then, to disturb the memory of the buried dead? What demon
            urged me to breathe that sound, which, in its very recollection
            was wont to make ebb the purple blood in torrents from the
            temples to the heart? What fiend spoke from the recesses of
            my soul, when, amid those dim aisles, and in the silence of the
            night, I whispered within the ears of the holy man the syllables
            --Morella? What more than fiend convulsed the features of
            my child, and overspread them with hues of death, as starting
            at that scarcely audible sound, she turned her glassy eyes from
            the earth to heaven, and, falling prostrate on the black slabs of
            our ancestral vault, responded--"I am here!"
         </p>
         
         <p>Distinct, coldly, calmly distinct, fell those few simple sounds
            within my ear, and thence, like molten lead, rolled hissingly into
            my brain. Years--years may pass away, but the memory of
            that epoch--never! Nor was I indeed ignorant of the flowers
            and the vine--but the hemlock and the cypress overshadowed
            me night and day. And I kept no reckoning of time or place,
            and the stars of my fate faded from heaven, and therefore the
            earth grew dark, and its figures passed by me, like flitting shadows, and among them all I beheld only--Morella. The winds
            of the firmament breathed but one sound within my ears, and
            the ripples upon the sea murmured evermore--Morella. But
            she died; and with my own hands I bore her to the tomb; and I
            laughed with a long and bitter laugh as I found no traces of the
            first, in the charnel where I laid the second--Morella.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">A Holiday on the Hudson</div>
         <div class="biblPage">389</div>
         <p>A HOLIDAY ON THE HUDSON.--Last Monday was a redletter day in the lives of four or five hundred happy souls, who
            made a trip in the new steamer Niagara to West Point.
            The sun was bright, the breeze fresh, the waters blue, and the
            new boat for the time was the flower of the river. She
            should be called the Flor-del-rio. Nothing could be more
            inappropriate for such a joyous craft than to call her a
            floating palace. There never was half the light and graceful elegance in any palace that ever was built. The Niagara
            is a day boat, and her cabin forms one spacious saloon two
            hundred and seventy feet in length, without any of those
            stifling encumbrances, called berths, which give to night boats
            the appearance of soldiers barracks. All the appointments of
            the boat are quite perfect at a matter of course, and she presents, in her interior, the appearance of a picture gallery, so
            profusely are her pannels decorated with prettily executed
            paintings. Besides a capital band of music on the upper deck,
            there was piano-forte playing in the ladies cabin; and several
            amateur musicians very obligingly sang duets and solos. But
            even without the music there was no lack of harmony. The
            boat arrived at West Point about two in the afternoon, and gave
            an opportunity for a ramble over that romantic and interesting
            region, to those who were in search of the picturesque; but
            others availed themselves of a chance to witness an examination of a class of cadets in chemistry. Among the dignitaries
            who wore gold lace on the occasion, was Gen. Scott, his big
            burly figure being considerably increased in its proportions, by
            epauletts and other gilt appliances. Mr. Weir was also among
            the examiners, and he sat leaning his head upon his hand, looking very fat and contented. The steamer left the dock at three,
            and soon after a sumptuous repast was served up, of unusual
            elegance for a floating palace. A good many bottles of champagne were emptied, but no toasts or set speeches marred the
            joyousness of the occasion. Then there were music and singing again, and afterwards cotillions and the Polka. Before
            reaching the dock, Mr. Embury of Brooklyn, was put into a
            velvet rocking-chair and proclaimed chairman of a meeting,
            which passed some grateful resolutions in which not one half
            the good nature was expressed that was felt. We remember
            the last one only, which we are sure everybody else must also
            remember.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Resolved. That the Steamer Niagara will be as distinguished in
            the waters of the east, as the great Cataract whose name she bears
            is among the waters of the west."
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Two Noble Poems</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p4">
            <div class="biblTitle">Introduction</div>
            <div class="biblPage">390</div>
            <p>[The two noble poems subjoined have already appeared in
               print--although we are unable to say in what work they originated. They are the composition of one of our most justly
               distinguished poetesses--Miss 
               <span class="person" id="aclynch">ANNE CHARLOTTE LYNCH</span>. We
               have no excuse to offer for copying them in the "Journal"--except that we have been profoundly impressed with their excellence. In modulation and force of rhythm--in dignity and
               loftiness of sentiment--and in terse energy of expression-they equal if they do not excel any thing of the same character written by an American.--EDS. B. J.]
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Ideal</div>
            <div class="biblPage">390</div>
            <div class="head">THE IDEAL.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"La vie est un somneil, l'amour en est la reve."
               
               <br></br>A sad, sweet dream! It fell upon my soul
               
               <br></br>When song and thought first woke their echoes there,
               
               <br></br>Swaying my spirit to its wild control,
               
               <br></br>And with the shadow of a fond despair,
               
               <br></br>Darkening the fountain of my young life's stream,
               
               <br></br>It haunts me still and yet I know 'tis but a dream.
               
               <br></br>Whence art thou, shadowy presence, that canst hide
               
               <br></br>From my charmed sight the glorious things of earth?
               
               <br></br>A mirage o'er life's desert dost thou glide?
               
               <br></br>Or with those glimmerings of a former birth,
               
               <br></br>A "trailing cloud of glory," hast thou come
               
               <br></br>From some bright world afar, our unremembered home?
               
               <br></br>I know thou dwell'st not in this dull, cold Real,
               
               <br></br>I know thy home is in some brighter sphere,
               
               <br></br>I know I shall not meet thee, my Ideal,
               
               <br></br>In the dark wanderings that await me here;
               
               <br></br>Why comes thy gentle image then, to me,
               
               <br></br>Wasting my night of life in one long dream of thee?
               
               <br></br>The city's peopled solitude, the glare
               
               <br></br>Of festal halls, moonlight, and music's tone,
               
               <br></br>All breathe the sad refrain--thou art not there;
               
               <br></br>And even with nature I am still alone;
               
               <br></br>With joy I see her summer bloom depart;
               
               <br></br>I love stern winter's reign--'tis winter in my heart.
               
               <br></br>And if I sigh upon my brow to see
               
               <br></br>The deep'ning shadow of Time's restless wing,
               
               <br></br>'Tis for the youth I might not give to thee.
               
               <br></br>The vanished brightness of my first sweet spring;
               
               <br></br>That I might give thee not the joyous form
               
               <br></br>Unworn by tears and cares, unblighted by the storm.
               
               <br></br>And when the hearts I should be proud to win,
               
               <br></br>Breathe, in those tones that woman holds so dear,
               
               <br></br>Words of impassioned homage unto mine,
               
               <br></br>Coldly and harsh they fall upon my ear,
               
               <br></br>And as I listen to the fervent vow
               
               <br></br>My weary heart replies, "Alas, it is not thou!"
               
               <br></br>Depart, O shadow! fatal dream, depart!
               
               <br></br>Go, I conjure thee, leave me this poor life,
               
               <br></br>And I will meet with firm, heroic heart,
               
               <br></br>Its threat'ning storms and its tumultuous strife,
               
               <br></br>And with the poet-seer will see thee stand
               
               <br></br>To welcome my approach to thine own Spirit-land.
               
               <br></br>And when the thoughts within my spirit glow
               
               <br></br>That would out-pour themselves in words of fire,
               
               <br></br>If some kind influence bade the music flow
               
               <br></br>Like that which woke the notes of Memnon's lyre,
               
               <br></br>Thou, sunlight of my life, wak'st not the lay
               
               <br></br>And song within my heart unuttered dies away.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Ideal Found</div>
            <div class="biblPage">390</div>
            <div class="head">THE IDEAL FOUND.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>I've met thee, whom I dared not hope to meet
               
               <br></br>Save in th' enchanted land of my day dreams:
               
               <br></br>Yes, in this common world, this waking state,
               
               <br></br>Thy living presence on my vision beams,
               
               <br></br>Life's dream embodied in reality!
               
               <br></br>And in thine eyes I read indifference to me!
               
               <br></br>Yes, in those star-like eyes I read my fate,
               
               <br></br>My horoscope is written in their gaze:
               
               <br></br>My "house of life" henceforth is desolate;
               
               <br></br>But the dark aspect my firm heart surveys.
               
               <br></br>Nor faints nor falters even for thy sake,--
               
               <br></br>'Tis calm and nerved and strong--no, no, it shall not break.
               
               <br></br>For I am of that mood that will defy;
               
               <br></br>That does not cower before the gathering storm;
               
               <br></br>That face to face will meet its destiny,
               
               <br></br>And undismayed confront its darkest form.
               
               <br></br>Wild energies awaken in this strife,
               
               <br></br>This conflict of the soul with the grim phantom Life.
               
               <br></br>But ah! if thou hadst loved me! had I been
               
               <br></br>All to thy dreams that to mine own thou art.
               
               <br></br>Had those dark eyes beamed eloquent on mine,
               
               <br></br>Pressed for one moment to that noble heart
               
               <br></br>In the full consciousness of faith unspoken,
               
               <br></br>Life could have given no more--then had my proud heart
               
               <br></br>broken!
               
               <br></br>The Alpine glacier from its height may mock
               
               <br></br>The clouds and lightnings of the winter sky,
               
               <br></br>And from the tempest and the thunder's shock
               
               <br></br>Gather new strength to lift its summit high;
               
               <br></br>But kissed by sunbeams of the summer day
               
               <br></br>It bows its icy crest and weeps itself away.
               
               <br></br>Thou know'st the fable of the Grecian maid
               
               <br></br>Wooed by the veiled immortal from the skies,
               
               <br></br>How in his full perfections, once she prayed,
               
               <br></br>That he would stand before her longing eyes,
               
               <br></br>And how that brightness, too intense to bless,
               
               <br></br>Consumed her o'er-wrought heart with its divine excess.
               
               <br></br>To me there is a meaning in the tale.
               
               <br></br>I have not prayed to meet thee; I can brook
               
               <br></br>That thou shouldst wear to me that icy veil;
               
               <br></br>I can give back thy cold and careless look;
               
               <br></br>Yet shrined within my heart still thou shalt seem,
               
               <br></br>What there thou ever wert--a beautiful, bright dream!
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p7">
         <div class="biblTitle">A Just View of a Bad Habit.</div>
         <div class="biblPage">390</div>
         <div class="head">A JUST VIEW OF A BAD HABIT.</div>
         
         <p>We find the following very sensible remarks, in a late number of the Charleston Mercury, and we copy them to give currency to such excellent sentiments. But we must resist the
            imputation of the last sentence. We think that New York is
            the debtor in this case.
         </p>
         
         <p>A New Image of War.--Among the men of former times, hunting was termed "the image of war"--especially the pursuit of
            wild boars, lions and other ferocious beasts. It had some claim to
            the distinction. It combined violent exercise, personal peril, the
            submission to privation and the distinctions, of success, skill and
            courage. In our day there is enough said about "campaigns,"
            "battles," "victories," "defeats," "glory" and all that, to make a
            stranger think we were engaged incessantly in the business of
            knocking each other's brains out--that a bloody and desolating
            civil war was waged from year's end to year's end. What sort of
            fight and what sort of victory it is, we need not explain. But the
            dialect is perfectly devilish, and its use is, we are persuaded, of
            most demoralizing consequence. Those of the opposite party we
            call the "enemy;" when we put them out of office, we call them
            the "vanquished,"--and contrary to the laws of modern war, we
            proceed to treat them as criminals. Dismissing them from office
            is known by the terms "slaughtering," "guilatining," "cutting off
            heads," and simillar bloody-minded phrases.
         </p>
         
         <p>Now aside from the bad taste of using such murderous language,
            it can hardly fail that this habitual dressing up of our party contests
            in the phraseology of war and crime, does tend insensibly to embitter them; to deprive the elections of their peaceable character,
            and to deepen in personal feeling the differences of opinion on public measures. In our dialect too, the offices of the country are the
            "spoil" of the successful party, and they are seized upon as the
            plunder of the "enemy." All this vile phraseology and much of
            the equally vile practices connected with it, we owe to New York.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Now, who could expect, after reading the above, to find what
            follows from the pen of the same writer in the same column of
            the same paper. It will require no very extraordinary gift in 
            this case, for the Editor of the Mercury to see himself as
            others see him, if he will be at the trouble of reading both his
            articles at the same sitting.
         </p>
         
         <p>The South awoke--with one hand she strangled one Presidential candidate, and with the other, she drew that old sword, (the 
            proud spirit of the South) before whose keen edge, no foes or party, 
            since the foundation of the government had ever been able to stand.
            She triumphed in the Presidential election. The struggle came on;
            in Congress. She triumphed again in spite of foes and traitors,
            South and North. Flushed with her recent victories, there she
            stands, with stern defiance on her brow, and her yet unsheathed 
            and dripping sword in her hand. Before heaven! she shall not 
            sheath it, uutil she is safe, and safe forever. Texas shall be hers,
            in spite of a world in arms; and to crown her redemption, the
            fetters of unjust taxation shall be torn from her free limbs. She
            will no longer endure to be the mock and ribald scoff of fools and
            fanatics, or the impassive and plundered victim, of mean, venal
            and dastard monopolists. She will vindicate her rightful station
            amongst the people of the earth; and whilst fearing none, command the respect and peace of all.
         </p>
         
         <p>We do not remember ever having seen so much belligerent
            bluster, and warlike word-spilling as this, in any New York
            political Journal, even the day before an election. If the
            South is really indebted to New York for her coinage of hot
            words, she uses them with a degree of liberality that her
            teacher never indulged in.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p8">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Heart of Man</div>
         <div class="biblPage">391</div>
         <div class="head">THE HEART OF MAN.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">SUGGESTED BY A FRAGMENT OF F. SIELER.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>A strange, unsounded, glorious thing,
            
            <br></br>The heart of man hath ever been,
            
            <br></br>Where light and gloom alternate spring
            
            <br></br>With many a changing shade between.
            
            <br></br>There earnest love and frantic hate
            
            <br></br>Have their deep fountains, side by side;
            
            <br></br>There sweetest hopes and feelings mate
            
            <br></br>With basest fear, with rankling pride.
            
            <br></br>Like some strong harp whose thousand strings
            
            <br></br>Vibrate to every passing tone,
            
            <br></br>Now with deep passion-notes it rings,
            
            <br></br>Now melts in sorrow's gentlest moan.
            
            <br></br>The magic of a kindling eye,
            
            <br></br>The music of a gentle voice,
            
            <br></br>May thrill its chords with agony
            
            <br></br>Or bid its noblest powers rejoice.
            
            <br></br>A word, a look, a tone, that falls
            
            <br></br>On memory's fount, seal'd up for years.
            
            <br></br>All the bright, glowing past recalls,
            
            <br></br>Its passionate hopes, its vows, its tears.
            
            <br></br>Shape after shape of glorious light,
            
            <br></br>It summons from that living tomb,
            
            <br></br>With forms whose aspects, once all bright,
            
            <br></br>Are shadowed now by softest gloom.
            
            <br></br>The kindling eye, the open brow,
            
            <br></br>The sunny smile of youth are there;
            
            <br></br>The faces dimmed by sorrow now,
            
            <br></br>The hopeless glance of pale despair.
            
            <br></br>O heart of man! O heart of man!
            
            <br></br>What magic of the spirit's lore,
            
            <br></br>What heav'n-enkindled glance may scan
            
            <br></br>Thy fountains, hidden evermore!
            
            <br></br>No Earthly wisdom may avail;
            
            <br></br>No eye but His who set the springs
            
            <br></br>In the heart's depths, can pierce the veil
            
            <br></br>That o'er their silent workings clings.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">ULRIC HORN.</span>
            Hellgate, L. I.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p9">
         <div class="biblTitle">Thorwaldsen's Statue of Byron</div>
         <div class="biblPage">391</div>
         <div class="head">THORWALDSEN'S STATUE OF 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">BYRON</span>.
         </div>
         
         <p>We copy the annexed account of this interesting work of
            Art from the London Art-Union, which does not, however,
            tell the whole story respecting it. The English boast a good
            deal of their liberality in money affairs, and not without some
            cause, while the one-string of slander on which they never
            cease playing, when alluding to this country, is our worship
            of the almighty dollar. But we do not remember having
            met with any anecdote of American manners so thoroughly
            characteristic of a mean and stingy nature as the statement
            which we find in some of the London papers respecting the
            monument to Lord 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span>.
         </p>
         
         <p>It must be remembered that he was a lord, and his personal
            friends were among the better classes, in every respect, of
            English society.
         </p>
         
         <p>It appears that soon after 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span>'s death, some of his friends
            and admirers set about a subscription, for the purpose of placing a statue to his memory in Westminster Abbey; and
            when they had gained all the money they could, they offered
            the amount to Chantrey, and asked him to make the statue.
            But the sum was so small that he refused to accept it, as he
            said it would not half pay him for his labor; the admirers of
            the noble poet applied next to Thorwaldsen, who with great
            dignity of feeling told them that he could not afford to work
            for nothing, and he would therefore accept the money, although it was too small to be considered pay, and would give
            the statue out of respect to the poet, whom he had known
            personally and loved.
         </p>
         
         <p>Thorwaldsen's Statue of Lord 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span>.--This monument,
            of which so much has been said and written, will at length find a
            resting-place in the library of Trinity College, Cambridge, after
            having remained upwards of twelve years in the cellars of the
            custom-house, during the whole of which period it has been more
            or less--as well from its own particular history, as from the great
            name to which it is dedicated--an object of public solicitude,
            which of late has increased in consequence of the death of two
            individuals, the name of one of whom is associated more nearly
            with it than is usual in his position, while that of the other will be
            remembered with various feelings in connexion with the monument of Byron--we mean the decease of the amiable sculptor
            himself, and of the late Dean of Westminster. An extract of a
            letter from Stockholm, which appeared in a German paper,
            among other matters in reference to Thorwaldsen, stated that his
            executors reclaimed the statue of 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span>, and at the same time
            some improbable statements appeared in our own newspapers in
            reference to the work. It was hoped that on the death of Dean
            Ireland the objection to its admission to Westminster Abbey might
            be set aside, but his successor is on willing to impugn his decision
            by a reversal. These events have perhaps had the effect of causing a destination to be determined upon for the work; at least they
            have been the means of reviving throughout Europe the circumstances of in execution and exclusion from Westminster Abbey.
            The monument it temporarily deposited in the studio of Sir Richard Westmacott, and it the property of a body of subscribers,
            friends and admirers of 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span>, by whom the commission was offered to Chantrey, who declined it in consequence of the inadequacy of the amount subscribed. It was then proposed to Thorwaldsen, who at once undertook it, agreeing to receive the sum
            collected. Many statements have been current as to whether
            Thorwaldsen did or did not receive remuneration for the work. It
            is mentioned as a fact that he received the subscription, and set
            about the monument in admiration of the poet, and in gratitude to
            his country, for he bore in mind that, while almost despairing, and
            yet a young artist, he was about to return to bis own country from
            want of employment in Italy--the first commission he received
            was from the late Mr. Hope. The statue is life-sized, and represents the poet seated on the fragment of a rained temple, with his
            left foot resting on the broken shaft of a column, while on the left,
            low down, is a skull, and above that the Athenian owl. The
            head seems to have been worked out from the portrait by Briggs;
            with the addition of age. In a posthumous work of this kind,
            had the artist perfectly succeeded, his work had been a miracle of
            Art: the defects, therefore, are not his, but those of circumstances.
            The forehead is heavy, and wants the refined modelling which
            distinguished the head of Byron, nor is the mouth moulded into
            that expression of which even years could not deprive it; the hands
            are also somewhat coarse, and by no means worthy of the compliment paid to those of 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span> by Ali Pacha. The attire of the
            figure is a frock-coat,over which is thrown a cloak; in the left
            hand is a volume superscribed "Childe Harold," and the right
            holds a pencil or style up to the mouth, as if he were busied in
            composition. As regards the destination of this statue, it is deeply to be regretted that the monument of 
            <span class="person" id="ggbyron">Byron</span> has not found a
            resting-place in the metropolis.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">An Essay on the Philosophy of Medical Science</div>
            <div class="biblPage">392</div>
            
            <p>An Essay on the PHILOSOPHY OF MEDICAL SCIENCE, by 
               <span class="person" id="ebartlett">Elisha
                  Bartlett
               </span>, M. D., &amp;c.--Philadelphia, Lea &amp; Blanchard, 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE PRINCIPLES OF THE CHRONO-THERMAL SYSTEM OF MEDICINE;
               with Fallacies of the Faculty. By 
               <span class="person" id="sdickson">Samuel Dickinson</span>, M.D., &amp;c.
               With introduction and notes, by 
               <span class="person" id="wturner">William Turner</span>, M. D., &amp;c.--
               New-York, J. S. Redfield, Clinton Hall, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>These are two books diametrically opposite in their aims,
               yet both significant signs in the Medical World; it is on this
               account that we bring them together, that we may expound
               their meaning, for the benefit of our readers who happen to
               be uninitiated in the mysteries of Esculapius' worship. Dr.
               
               <span class="person" id="ebartlett">Bartlett</span>, by way of preliminaries to dispose the good-natured
               reader to a favorable judgment of his cause, devotes a few
               chapters of his book to demonstrating what constitutes a correct
               mode of observing and reasoning, or, in one word, of philosophizing in exact sciences; and having thus built a ladder, to
               step upon, he drags his reader up the heights of Medical science,
               showing him all the while, how firmly and securely, and how
               philosophically he ascends to the possible in the knowledge of
               the healing art. Doubtless, the unsuspecting, and not very
               keen-sighted reader, will believe, on laying down Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="ebartlett">Bartlett</span>'s book, that he has drank deeply at the very source of truth.
               But for ourselves who have dabbled in those matters upon
               which the learned doctor is so eloquent, we can declare that
               we rose from the intellectual repast which the doctor cooked
               up, with a hungry stomach, for the quantity we have consumed proved but a few grains of truth in a bushel of chaff.
               Yet, we are free to confess that the doctor is an excellent cook
               in his way, indeed, there are not many such in his profession.
               There is both mechanical and intellectual legerdemain,the doctor's work is an evidence of the latter; he is a schoolman who
               has learned to muster his words in a phalanx, as a drill-sergeant does his men, but without the aid of scholastic glasses he
               is incapable of looking upon nature, and marking her workings.
               The aim of the book is to teach how to philosophize in medicine, but it strikes us, taking the doctrines he favors as an
               evidence, that he has not learnt the art himself; for he talks
               grandiloquently of such nonsense as a correct nosology, the
               bug-bear of inflammation, and believes in the means of reducing it by bleeding--things that have a foundation only in the
               brains of professors and their dupes, but not in nature. He
               condemns hypotheses, but insists that naked facts should make
               up the science. He forgets that it is as easy for those who are
               not fit for the task, and these are numerous, to make wrong
               experiments, and call them naked facts, as it is for another set
               of persons equally unfit for their undertaking, to make incorrect hypotheses and call them true explanations of nature's
               mysteries. The alchemists have collected numerous so-called
               facts, but they did not know what to make of them, for they
               experimented foolishly, and they might have gone on still
               longer putting wrong questions to nature, and remain as ignorant as ever. It was left for the intellect of Lavoisier, Guy
               Lussac and others, who could at a glance surmise correctly
               nature's purposes, to question her accordingly; and thus they
               were enabled to raise the structure of exact sciences.
            </p>
            
            <p>The fact is, that it is permitted but to few to make correct
               hypotheses and have them verified by experience; but those
               few cannot teach others to do the same; nor will they stop to
               give us an account of the mental processes that led them to
               their discoveries. There is a larger class of minds that, when
               discoveries are made and interpreted, can logically, step by
               step, verify and enlarge the experience of others, but who
               would never discover anything themselves; and there is another class of men still more numerous, who can write upon
               the correct manner of making discoveries, and collecting facts:
               but yet these last are not the persons to be employed for the
               purposes of the art they teach; they are mere self-satisfied
               and self-glorifying schoolmen. Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="ebartlett">Bartlett</span>'s book sufficiently
               justifies us in making the above observations; his aim seems
               to have been to raise the credit of the old school of medicine,
               which of late, has lost so much in public estimation. With
               those who cannot see for themselves, he will undoubtedly succeed; but there will be yet a few left, cunning enough to see
               through the legerdemain of his logic, and who will persist in
               mistrusting the learning of the faculty. The author of this
               book is a striking illustration of that calibre of mind that can
               spend itself in petty details with great gusto and considerable
               credit; but is incapable by summing them up, to rise to generalities, and seize upon the secrets of nature. Unfortunately for
               mankind, we had too many such men in the profession, and it
               is they especially, more even than the intrinsic difficulty of the
               subject, who contributed so much to swell the lumbering trash
               of medical libraries. Yes, it is these men of details, and of
               specialities, who split a hair with the greatest delicacy, who
               mole-like cannot see beyond the mole-cast they make, that
               give force to 
               <span class="person" id="ebdecondillac">Condillac</span>'s saying when applied to medicine,
               "that man never has so much to say of a subject, as when he
               knows the least of it." A different spirit we find in Dr.
               
               <span class="person" id="sdickson">Dickinson</span>'s lectures. In commencing his observations, he
               was fully impressed with the idea that details, different as they
               may appear, merge in each other, that they may be lost in
               unity,--this being an all-pervading law of nature; and so his
               results are as grand as they are just in conception. We can
               speak here, with the assurance of personal experience, for in
               our own studies we have come to similar though not identical
               results, long before we ever heard of the Fallacies of the Faculty. His views may be briefly stated to consist in unity of
               disease, in variety of symptoms, the intermittent fever being
               the type of all the suffering that flesh is heir to. The nervous
               system in general, and the brain in particular, is the citadel
               from which life issues, and which disease assails. An equilibrium of temperature throughout the body is, in his opinion,
               absolutely essential to health; and any derangement of if,
               causes as well as accompanies disease; the evident indication
               in the cure therefore is, to restore it to its due degree by appropriate appliances. Thus periodicity of recurrence of disease
               and variability of temperature are the landmarks by which the
               physician is to be guided in his treatment.
            </p>
            
            <p>The doctor advocates his views with great force of reasoning
               and abundance of wit and fancy; so much so, that the book
               is exceedingly attractive even to an unprofessional reader.
               With unsparing severity he points out many of the learned
               follies of the faculty, and with the most satisfactory proof he
               confutes the unphilosophical and murderous practice of bloodletting in all its forms.
            </p>
            
            <p>Much as we admire the common-sense views of Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="sdickson">Dickin</span>son, yet we are not entirely satisfied with him, for he has overlooked some things and underrated others. His views do not
               enable us to look upon the economy of the human system, as
               complete in all points; perhaps he gives us only what he sees
               himself, and what is the most essential in the removal of diseases. Be it as it may, he deserves our gratitude for what he has
               done. It requires great moral courage to speak against the
               follies of mis-called science, and especially among the most conservative of all classes of men. Medicine never will be thoroughly reformed till men of common sense and decided talent,
               whose minds are stored with a variety of information, bring their
               ability to bear upon medical practices and theories, with no other aim than to advance Truth. The love of professional lucre
               too often stands in the way of truth--and it is asking too much
               from human nature to expect immolation of self on the altar of
               truth, at the hands of the medical profession--and especially
               when it is so crowded that a cunning dunce often stands a better chance of success than a man of modest talent and uprightness. It should be impressed upon the minds of men that what
               was said of poets is applicable to physicians with double force:
               Physicians are born, not made. Many who have received their
               doctorate find on their coming into the daylight of experience, that instead of the doctor's they have been crowned with
               the fool's-cap.
            </p>
            
            <p>Looking upon the state of the medical profession in these times,
               we cannot but see omens of great good to come. It is so divided by different sects holding more or less correct views, that
               each must modify the other; and here and there a brave opponent arises who challenges them all; and a suspicious public
               begins to be aroused from its stupidity, and thinks that
               the evil is not in her body, but in that of the doctors--all this
               ferment of opinion may clarify man's judgment upon the subject,
               and some genius may arise who will select the truth that gives
               partial currency to the pretensions of each system, and render a lasting benefit to mankind. Perhaps his name may be Andrew Sniadecki, who some time ago developed his theory of organic beings, and whose death Poland was made too soon to lament,
               or he upon whomever his cloak has fallen. We mention the distinguished Pole, because in the whole range of our medical reading, we find none who applies, in a more simple and beautiful
               diction, such a rigorous method of reasoning to such a vast fund
               of information; so much so that medicine in his hands almost
               becomes one of the exact sciences.
            </p>
         </div> 
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">Plato Contra Atheos</div>
            <div class="biblPage">393</div>
            <p>PLATO CONTRA ATHEOS.--Plato against the Atheists; or the Tenth
               Book of the Dialogue on Laws, accompanied with Critical Notes,
               and followed by Extended Dissertations on some of the Main
               Points of the Platonic Philosophy and Theology, especially as
               compared with the Holy Scriptures, by 
               <span class="person" id="tlewis">Tayler Lewis</span>, LL. D.,
               Professor of the Greek Language and Literature, in the University in the city of New York.--New York, Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Laws of Plato were probably the work of his old age
               --of his extreme senility--and although Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="tlewis">Lewis</span> insists
               upon this point, as one tending to make us think more favorably of the composition, on the ground of its embodying the
               philosopher's most matured and best settled opinions--we cannot help regarding the question as disputable. As a dramatic
               work, all admit it to be inferior to the Republic. There are
               but three interlocutors--Clinias, a Cretan; Megillus, a Spartan; and a stranger, who is spoken of only as the Athenian
               --but, who is the Socrates of the colloquy; the two first, being merely listeners, or speaking but for the purpose of foils.
               The nine first books are occupied with legislative schemes
               given at length, with preambles, and arguments in support of
               both preambles and schemes. The tenth book (now published)
               deals with laws enacted against violators of religion--that is
               to say, public worship--it being taken for granted that State
               and Church can never properly exist apart. The greater portion--indeed nearly the whole of the book, however, is taken
               up with an exordium, investigating the reasons for the laws--
               the latter in fact occupying only a few of the concluding
               pages.
            </p>
            
            <p>The argument is directed first, against those who deny the
               Divine existence--secondly, against those who deny a Providence while admitting the existence of a God--thirdly, against
               those who, admitting both, yet maintain that the Deity is easily
               propitiated by sinners.
            </p>
            
            <p>Clinias opens the first branch of this argument, by asserting
               that the existence of God is readily shown by the universality
               of man's belief in his existence, as well as by the evidences
               of design in natural phenomena.
            </p>
            
            <p>This ease of demonstration the Athenian denies; declaring,
               however, that whatever difficulty there is, is not innate in the
               subject, but springs from the perverseness of the Ionic Atheists
               in imposing upon the world the ideas of chance, nature, art,
               etc., and in the refutation of these ideas the reasoner discusses
               at length the nature of soul as involving, necessarily, selfmotion. Thence, he deduces the priority in time of soul to
               body--thence, again, of the properties of soul to the properties of body. The inference is, that Art is the mother of Nature
               --that law, will, thought, or design, must have been before
               qualities, such as hardness, weight--etc, etc.
            </p>
            
            <p>The intention here is to refute the particular opinion of the
               Atheist, that religion had no better foundation than conventionality, since belief in the existence of God is the production
               of human law--which, again, is a product of Art--Art itself
               being regarded as the offspring of Nature.
            </p>
            
            <p>The question of motion is examined very minutely--and all
               kinds of motion are divided into motion by impulse, and, that
               which moves something else by commencing motion in itself;
               the latter species being psyche, or soul.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the next place, occurs the question whether one or more
               souls are at work in the Universe. It is decided that there
               are two--the soul of good and the soul of evil.
            </p>
            
            <p>The second grand division of the subject is the investigation of the arguments which deny a Providence. The Athenian maintains a minute, special interference with human affairs, chiefly on the ground that the whole is composed of its
               parts, and that to neglect the smallest portion is to neglect the
               whole.
            </p>
            
            <p>In entering the third division of his theme, the speaker opposes the arguments of those who maintain that the Deity is
               easily appeased, by adverting to the pre-supposed antagonism
               between good and evil. Where a conflict is continually going
               on, he says, the least neutrality or supineness--that is to say,
               the least mercy shown to sin, would be treason against the
               cause of the Right throughout the Universe.
            </p>
            
            <p>The offenders against religion are divided into six classes,
               or rather grades. The book ends with a specification of penalties, and a law, in especial against private rites and churches.
            </p>
            
            <p>Such is a fair, although very succinct synopsis of a work
               comparatively little known, although very frequently made the
               subject of converse.
            </p>
            
            <p>No one can doubt the purity and nobility of the Platonian
               soul, or the ingenuity of the Platonian intellect. But if the
               question be put to-day, what is the value of the Platonian
               philosophy, the proper answer is--"exactly nothing at all."
               We do not believe that any good purpose is answered by popularizing his dreams; on the contrary we do believe that they
               have a strong tendency to ill--intellectually of course.
            </p>
            
            <p>We could wish that Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="tlewis">Lewis</span> (however excusable may be
               his evident enthusiasm for his favorite) had less frequently interspersed his comments with such passages as the following:
            </p>
            
            <p>"Then surely should Plato be studied, if for no other purpose, as a
               matter of curiosity, to see if there may not possibly bo some other philosophy than THIS NOISY BACONIANISM ABOUT WHICH THERE IS KEPT UP
               SUCH AN EVERlASTING DIN, or that still more noisy because more empty
                transcendentalism which some would present as its only antidote.
            </p>
            
            <p>* * * * Especially will this be the case at a time when physical
               science, in league with a subtle pantheism, is everywhere substituting
               its jargon of laws and elements, nebular star-dust, and vital forces,
               and magnetic fluids, for the recognition of a personal God and an ever
               wakeful, ever energizing special Providence."
            </p>
            
            <p>For our own parts we vastly prefer even the noise of Bacon,
               the laws of Combe, or the nebular star-dust of Nichols to
               what Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="tlewis">Lewis</span> will insist upon terming "the clear, simple,
               common-sense philosophy of Plato,"--but these things are
               perhaps merely matters of taste. It would be as well, however, to bear in mind the aphoristic sentence of 
               <span class="person" id="gwleibniz">Leibnitz</span>--"La
               plupart des sectes ont raison en beaucoup de ce qu'lles avancent, mais non pas en ce qu'elles nient."
            </p>
            
            <p>We regret that it has been thought advisable to give the
               Greek text unaccompanied with a translation. The object, so
               far as we can comprehend the annotator, seems to have been
               the placing of the doctrines of Plato more immediately within the reach of the public. For this end we should have had
               a paraphrase, at least.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">Harper's Illuminated and Illustrated Edition of Shakespeare</div>
            <div class="biblPage">394</div>
            
            <p>Harper's Illuminated and Illustrated Edition of Shakespeare. Nos. 55 &amp; 56: Containing parts of "As You Like It,"
               and "Midsummer Night's Dream." Price 25cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have already expressed a favorable opinion of this truly
               beautiful edition of 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakespeare</span>; but the present issue comes to
               us with so liberal an enrichment of wood cuts, that we cannot
               refrain from expressing once more our opinion of its cheapness
               and beauty. Here are twenty-nine spirited wood cuts, from
               good designs, printed with great clearness and beauty in ink of
               unusual brilliancy and on fine paper, accompanying a play by
               
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakespeare</span>, and sold for the inconsiderable price of 25 cents.
               The cover to this edition of 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakespeare</span> is a very handsome design by Catherwood, a thousand times superior to the hideous
               thing designed by R. W. Weir, N. A. A more thoroughly
               contemptible affair, exhibiting not only an utter poverty of imagination, but the most meagre acquirements in art, was never
               put off upon the public, than the cover which was first published
               by Mr. Hewitt, when this edition of 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakespeare</span> was issued
               by him. Thanks to the liberality and discernment of the
               present publishers, we are no longer annoyed by the apparition of the Weir sisters, and the figure of 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakespeare</span> in a
               canoe, on the cover of these plays. It is a disgrace to American Art, that we have never been able to produce the shadow of
               an ornamental design, and nothing can more plainly prove the
               entire inadequacy of the system of instruction adopted by our
               National Academy than the wretched abortions which the artists
               who write N. A. at the end of their names, have produced in
               their attempts at ornamental drawings. They prove beyond a
               question that they have not been grounded in the A. B. C. of
               art. Now that the academy has got an artist for its President,
               we have hopes that something better may be produced.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="gcverplanck">Verplanck</span> is doubtless very competent to edit Shakespeare, but we have noticed some very strange readings in one
               or two of the earlier issues of the edition, which must have been
               owing either to gross carelessness, or something worse.
            </p>
            
            <p>We take a few passages only for example. Where it is material, we point according to copy,</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Is execution done on Cawdor: or not
               
               <br></br>Those in commission yet return'd?"
            </div>
            
            <p>This should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Is execution done on Cawdor? Are not
               
               <br></br>Those in commission yet return'd?
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Send forth great largess to your offices,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Send forth great largess to your officers.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"We would spend it in some words upon that business,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Would spend it in some words upon that business--[Without the
               
               <br></br>"We"--Macbeth was not then king.]
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"The curtain'd sleep,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>The curtain'd sleeper.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Thy very stones,"
            </div>
            
            <p>We think should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>The very stones.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"And all-thing unbecoming,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>And all things unbecoming.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"To be thus is nothing,
               
               <br></br>But to be safely thus;"
            </div>
            
            <p>A more weighty point than a comma is wanted after "nothing."</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"To make them kings, the seeds of Banquo kings!"
            </div>
            
            <p>Same after "kings"--and "seeds" should be seed.</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Now, go to the door,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Now to the door.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"To pray for this good man,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>To pray for that good man.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Whom we to gain our peace, have sent to peace,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Whom we, to gain our place, have sent to peace.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>--"the feast is sold,
               
               <br></br>That is not often vouch'd while 'tis a making;
               
               <br></br>'Tis given with welcome."
            </div>
            
            <p>A comma after "vouch'd" and another after "making," in
               the room of the semicolon there, would have given the true reading--which is turned into nonsense by the false pointing in this
               new edition.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"If trembling I inhabit then,"
            </div>
            
            <p>Should be:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>If trembling I inhibit then.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"tell me if your art
               
               <br></br>Can tell so much)
            </div>
            
            <p>Where is the other mark of the parenthesis?</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"and with him,
               
               <br></br>To leave no rubs nor blotches in the work,)
            </div>
            
            <p>Where is the other mark of this parenthesis?</p>
            
            <p>But this is painful work: we will therefore end it, for the present, by a short notice of something that, in itself, is enough to
               injure the whole edition in which it occurs,--we mean, in the
               opinion of 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakespeare</span>'s "lovers."
            </p>
            
            <p>The play is Twelth Night. In the first interview between
               Olivia and Viola, Olivia, after Viola has said, "Good madam,
               let me see your face," is made to reply, "Have you any commission from your lord to negociate with my face? You are
               now out of your text: but we will draw the curtain, and show
               you the picture. Look you, sir; such a one I was this present:
               is't not well done!" [Unveiling.]
            </p>
            
            <p>Now, which looks most like 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakespeare</span>, that, or this:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>"Look you, Sir: Such a one as I was, this presents.
               
               <br></br>Is't not well done?"--[Unveiling.]
            </div>
            
            <p>The word "as," the comma after "was," and the additional s to the word "present," make all the difference.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Pilgrimage to Treves</div>
            <div class="biblPage">394</div>
            
            <p>A PILIGRAMAGE TO TREVES, through the Valley of the Meuse and
               the Forest of Ardennes in the year 1844. Harper &amp; Brothers,
               1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have here another new book from the pen of an American,
               and a very modest and entertaining one it is. The author, a
               son of the Rev. Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Anthon</span> of this city, says that, having determined to "attempt the production of a book," he took up his
               residence in Spa to carry on its manufacture, for three sensible
               reasons; first because it is a pleasant place to live in; secondly
               because it is a fashionable watering place which being deserted
               at that time afforded him excellent accommodations; and
               thirdly because it is in the vicinity of Liege and Brussels, from
               which cities he could obtain all the books of which he stood in
               need. We like this manner of producing a book, and we only
               regret that all authors cannot, like Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Anthon</span>, select their
               cities of refuge when the fit of production comes over them.
               But there have been many books produced in garrets and
               prisons and other places very far from being pleasant, which
               will be read with delight, and have power to make any place
               pleasant when the "Pilgrimage to Treves" will have been
               utterly forgotten.
            </p>
            
            <p>We do not mean to underrate Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Anthon</span>'s work because
               it was produced under circumstances so exceedingly agreeable.
               There are but few young gentlemen of his years and opportunities who ever think of producing a book at all, or if they
               should make the attempt, would succeed as well as he has
               done.
            </p>
            
            <p>The author begins his book with Charlemagne and Aix-laChapelle and serves up anew several bits of history which do
               not possess much novelty to recommend them. The "Pilgrimage" is not commenced until we reach the middle of the
               book, when the interest of the work begins. The author set
               out from Dinant on the 4th of September to join the pilgrims
               who were flocking in immense numbers to Treves to witness
               the exhibition of the sacred robe of Christ which happens to
               be in possession of the church of that city. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Anthon</span> informs us, however, that he does not himself attach any importance to relics, and very conclusively argues that the chances
               are a considerable many to nothing that Christ never had the
               sacred robe of Treves on his back.
            </p>
            
            <p>In some of his descriptions he is sufficiently exact, but in
               others he is exceedingly vague and uncertain: for instance, in
               speaking of Hardenne, a seat of the King of the Belgians, he
               says it is "furnished in a style of simple elegance," which
               must be interpreted according to the reader's own ideas of
               what constitutes simple elegance. Probably some readers if
               made acquainted with the realities of Hardenne would say
               that it was furnished in a style of the most superb and thrilling magnificence, for we saw in one of our morning papers, a
               day or two since, an allusion to a new Broadway Omnibus
               which was styled "a truly palacial carriage," and every newspaper reader know's that all the steamboats in our waters are
               "floating palaces."
            </p>
            
            <p>The sacred tunic was presented to Treves by the Empress
               Helena, she having procured it in Palestine three hundred
               years after the crucifixion.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Since the exposition which took place in the year 1512, the
               Tunic has been publicly displayed nine times, seven times a
               Treves and twice at Ehrenbreitstein, to which place it bad been
               transported on account of the risk of destruction or plunder to
               which it was exposed during the war which distracted Germany
               The last exposition occurred in 1810, and lasted 19 days. The
               number of strangers who visited Treves during this time amounted to 227,000. According to the belief of some, miraculous cures were wrought by the sight and touch of the relic. It is
               said that many paralytics, and other persons so sick or infirm that
               they had to be carried before it, afterward walked without assistance.
            </p>
            
            <p> Those who dread the predominance of the Roman Catholic
               faith, and look with anxiety on the signs which seem to indicate
               that she is about to resume much of her ancient dominion, will be
               struck by the fact that the exposition of the sacred Robe in the
               year 1844 has attracted a greater host of pilgrims than on any previous occasion. The number of strangers who visited Treves from
               the 17th of August to the 6th of October amounted to upward of
               450,000!"
            </p>
            
            <p>The sacred robe is deposited in a chamber of the Cathedral,
               where it is kept except on occasions of exhibition.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The crowd of pilgrims entering the great portal on the right
               in regular procession, two and two, reached the central nave
               where they separated into two files, one on each side of it. Ad
               vancing in this order, marshalled by officers with scarfs of red and
               yellow, the colours of Treves, they travelled the whole length of
               the choir, and arrived at its upper end, where the two files again
               united at the foot of an elevated platform of variegated marble, ascended on each side by a broad flight of steps, and decorated for
               the occasion with flowering plants. In the centre of this platform
               directly in front of the treasure chamber, from which it had been
               taken, was displayed the revered object of their pilgrimage, spread
               out on a glass case, and decked with white satin and blue drapery
               trimmed with gold. The people mounted the platform by the
               right-hand staircase, and passed in front of the relic, where they
               were permitted to pause for an instant, while they gave to one of
               the attending priests some small object, such as a medal, a rosary,
               or a representation of the Robe, embroidered on silk, or engraved
               on paper. The priest touched these to the Tunic, and having
               thus, in the opinion of the orthodox, extracted some of its virtues
               restored them to their owners, who then descended the flight of
               steps on the left, and quitted the Cathedral by a side door. Upon
               a table were seen the offerings of the pilgrims, an immense pile of
               copper coins, testifying at once to the multitude of the donors and
               to their individual poverty.
            </p>
            
            <p>I am not ashamed to confess that, as I stood upon this elevation,
               and surveyed the whole scene which was passing, I felt deeply
               moved. The spectacle which the interior of that venerable edifice then presented might indeed excuse a moment's credulity.
               On one side the pilgrims were pressing forward with faces of
               eager expectation, chastened by religious awe, while the solemn
               melody of the organ conspired to elevate the thoughts all from
               earth; and as they descended, it was easy to read on their countenances the joy and gratitude with which they were filled.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Roman Catholics seize eagerly on examples of the emotion
               which so impressive a ceremony can hardly fail to excite, as proofs
               of a peculiar and divine influence which the relic exerts on the
               stubborn hearts of heretics. A chronicler of the exposition relates,
               for instance, with considerable naivete, that an Israelitish woman,
               on seeing it, burst into tears, and immediately made an offering of
               four thalers, which, in his opinion, is a very strong testimony to
               the authenticity and virtue of the Robe."
            </p>
            
            <p>There are a few more pages, but properly, the pilgrimage
               ends here.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">New Works Lately Received</div>
         <div class="head">NEW WORKS LATELY RECEIVED.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">Satanstoe, or the Littlepage Manuscripts</div>
            <div class="biblPage">395</div>
            
            <p>Satanstoe, or the Littlepage Manuscripts. A Tale of the Colony:
               by 
               <span class="person" id="jfcooper">J. Fennimore Cooper</span>. In 2 vols. New-York: Burgess,
               Stringer &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>Satanstoe appears to be the first of a series of three tales
               written to illustrate a principle, the principle of anti-rentism,
               which Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="jfcooper">Cooper</span> considers a greater disgrace to the State of
               New-York than repudiation to Mississippi. We have but little faith in stories that are written to illustrate any other principle than the principle of human nature, and we doubt whether Satanstoe will be read with much interest by any class excepting those who have read the author's other productions, for
               the sake of the story. It appears that Satanstoe is a neck of
               land somewhere in Westchester county, its precise locality we
               are not acquainted with, but it is probably in the neighborhood
               of Devilshoof. Of the merits of the work we are unable to
               speak at present. We give the concluding paragraph of the
               author's preface, for the sake of its manly tone, which wil
               neet with a hearty response from all honest men.
            </p>
            
            <p>"For ourselves, we conceive that true patriotism consists in
               laying bare every thing like public vice, and in calling things
               by their right names. The great enemy of the race has made
               a deep inroad upon us, within the list ten or a dozen years,
               under cover of a spurious delicacy on the subject of expressing
               national ills; and it is time that they who have not been afraid
               to praise when praise was merited, should not shrink from the
               office of censuring, when the want of timely warnings may be
               one cause of the most fatal evils. The great practical defect
               of institutions like ours, is the circumstance that "what is
               everybody's business, is nobody's business," a neglect that
               gives to the activity of the rogue a very dangerous ascendency over the more dilatory corrections of the honest man."
            </p>
         </div>          
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Notes, Explanatory and Practical, on the Epistles of Paul</div>
            <div class="biblPage">395</div>  
            
            <p>Notes, Explanatory and Practical, on the Epistles of 
               <span class="person" id="paul">Paul</span> to the
               Ephesians, Philipians, and Colossians. By 
               <span class="person" id="abarnes">Albert Barues</span>. New
               York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>The learning and industry which distinguish these Notes
               are points about which we have heard little difference of opinion. Not the least interesting portion of the work is the Introduction, which embraces an account of the situation of
               Ephesus, and the character of its people, as well as of the
               advent of the Gospel among them--also notices of the Hisory of its Church--of the time and places of writing the
               Epistle--with an inquiry as to its object and to whom it was
               written. This Introduction is illustrated with two wood engravings of the present Ephesus.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">De Rohan; or The Court Conspirator.</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>De Rohan; or The Court Conspirator. An Historical Romance.
               By 
               <span class="person" id="esue">M. Eugene Sue</span>. author of "The Mysteries of Paris," etc. 
               etc. New York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is number 54 of Harper's "Library of Select Novels." 
               It is by no means as good a book as we have a right to expect
               from the author of "The Mysteries of Paris;" its interest has
               been materially impaired by too close an adherence to historical fact. The chief actors are two young girls, nobly
               born, and each of an heroic devotion beautifully diverse in
               character; a youth of great sensitiveness and timidity; a
               cynical and brutal giant and buffoon; a nobleman of the gay
               Court of Louis XIV; and an eccentric Dutch philosopher,
               of great genius and erudition.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">Ocean Work, Ancient and Modern</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>Ocean Work, Ancient and Modern: or, Evenings on Sea and Land.
               By 
               <span class="person" id="jhwright">J. Hall Wright</span>, author of "Breakfast-table Scenes." (Science.) New York, Appleton &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>This neat little book is one of the second series of "Tales
               for the People and their children," and in our estimation is
               one of the best among them. A little more science and a little less prattle would have greatly enhanced its value as a
               book for the people, but even in its present shape it contains
               a great amount of knowledge in a very limited space.
            </p>
         </div>       
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Age of Elizabeth</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>The Age of Elizabeth. By 
               <span class="person" id="whowitt">William Howitt</span>. No. 13 of Wiley &amp;
               Putnam's Library of choice reading. _Wiley &amp; Putnam. Price
               50 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>The expressive title of this series of works, choice reading,
               may be applied with as great truth to this book as to any one
               yet issued. The "age of Elizabeth," contains some of the
               best criticisms and most agreeable writing of the author.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Blind Girl, with Other Tales</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>The Blind Girl, with Other Tales: by 
               <span class="person" id="ecembury">Emma C. Embury</span>. New
               York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This little volume includes Constance Latimer, or The
               Blind Girl;" "The Son and Heir;" "The Village Tragedy;"
               "Newton Ainslie;" and "Frank Morrison." The first was
               originally written as a contribution to a Fair for the benefit of
               the Institution for the Blind:--it is an exceedingly pathetic
               tale. The others are also excellent, each in a different way.
               Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="ecembury">Embury</span> is one of the very best of our female writers.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Dutchman's Fireside</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>The Dutchman's Fireside: a Tale, by the author of "Letters
               from the South," "John Bull in America," "The Backwoodsman," &amp;c. Two volumes in one, New York; Harper &amp;
               Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is number 9 of the Harpers' "Pocket Edition of Select Novels." The novel itself is too well known in America
               to need comment. It is, perhaps, the best work of its author.
               We particularly admire the clear print and convenient form of
               these editions.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">A System of Latin Versification</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>A System of Latin Versification: in a series of Progressive
               Exercises, including specimens of Translation from English and 
               German Poetry into Latin verse. For the use of Schools and
               Colleges: by 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Charles Anthon</span>, LL.D.. Professor of the Greek
               languages in Columbia College, New York, etc. etc. New York: 
               Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>A very admirable volume which we shall, of course, notice 
               more fully hereafter.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Gambler's Wife</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>The Gambler's Wife. A Novel. By the Author of the "Young
               Prima Donna," "The Belle of the Family," "The Old Dower
               House," etc. etc. New York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>Number 50 of the "Library of Select Novels." A wellwritten and well-constructed story of profound, although
               homely interest.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Smuggler and Other Books</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>The Smuggler, a Tale, by 
               <span class="person" id="gprjames">G. P. R. James</span>. No. 56 of
               Harper's Library of Select Novels. The Mysteries of Berlin, Part 4, published by W. H. Collyer. An Encyclopaedia of Domestic Economy, Part 5: Harper &amp; Brothers.
               
               The Nevilles of Garrettstown, Part 4. Martin's Bible, Part
               5. 
               <span class="person" id="elittell">Littell</span>'s Living Age, No. 58, from Taylor, No. 2, Astor
               House. Narrative of the Life of 
               <span class="person" id="fdouglass">Frederick Douglas</span>, an
               American Slave, written by himself, from W. H. Graham, Tribune buildings.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>           
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p24">
         <div class="biblTitle">Number One's</div>
         <div class="biblPage">396</div>
         <div class="head">NUMBER ONE'S.</div>
         
         <p>We have received the first number of three new weekly
            Magazines during the past week. Two of them sprung up in
            Boston, and one in New-York. The most important of these
            new comers, in appearance, and doubtless containing the largest
            amount of vitality, is called "The Harbinger;" it is dedicated
            to "Social and Political Progress." No editor is named, but
            it is to be furnished with matter by 
            <span class="person" id="pgodwin">Park Godwin</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="whchanning">W. H.
               Channing
            </span>, 
            <span class="person" id="abrisbane">Albert Brisbane</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="omacdaniel">Osborne Macdanniel</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="hgreeley">Horace
               Greely
            </span>, 
            <span class="person" id="gripley">George Ripley</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="cadana">Charles A. Dana</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="jsdwight">John S. Dwight</span>, 
            <span class="person" id="lwryckman">L.
               W. Ryckman
            </span>, 
            <span class="person" id="jallen">John Allen</span>, and 
            <span class="person" id="fshaw">Francis S. Shaw</span>. Some of
            these gentlemen we know to be matter-full men, and if they
            lend their aid to this new magazine, it must shortly become an
            important organ in the world of journalism. It emanates from
            the Brook Farm Association at West Roxbury, and is, as a
            matter of course, an advocate of Fourierism. The first number contains the beginning of 
            <span class="person" id="gsand">George Sand</span>'s famous story
            "Consuelo," translated, we suppose, by 
            <span class="person" id="fshaw">F. S. Shaw</span>, as the
            copy-right is secured to him. The Harbinger is as well printed
            as any paper of its class, but coming from an Association like
            that at Brook Farm, we expected a greater degree of elegance
            in its externals. Tuttle &amp; Dexter are the general agents.
         </p>
         
         <p>"The Jester," is another Boston birth; an imitation of
            Punch, but a very slender imitation indeed. The illustrations
            are better than the matter illustrated, an unusual case in an
            American publication. It wants a Lemon to give it flavor.
         </p>
         
         <p>"The New-Yorker," a semi-monthly paper of eight pages,
            devoted to Temperance, Morality, and several other good
            things, is published in New-York.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="head">THE FINE ARTS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p25">
            <div class="biblTitle">We Have Seen a Proof Impression</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>We have seen a proof impression of an engraving by Smillie
               and Hinshelwood, intended for part five of Martin's edition of
               the Bible, which will reflect great credit upon the skill of the
               artists and the liberality of the publishers. The subject is the
               "departure of the Israelites" from a picture by David Roberts,
               one of the best painters of Eastern life and scenery now living. This picture has much of the grandeur of feeling peculiar to Martin's designs, and though but a few inches in size,
               is capable of creating as sublime and lofty emotions, as though
               it were stretched over an acre of canvass. The cheapness of
               illustrated books is a growing marvel. This print is of a class
               rarely sold at a price less than two dollars, yet it is here given
               away to the purchaser of one of the parts of the superb work
               which it is meant to illustrate.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have before us, also, parts 29 and 30 of Harper's Bible,
               which is more legitimately ornamented by wood-cuts, containing
               an amount of pictorial illustrations, which, a few years ago, would
               have been considered an impossibility at the price for which
               they are now sold. The great defect of the illustrations of
               "Harper's Bible," arises from their sameness of character.
               One author may well be illustrated by one artist; but to give
               all the Prophets, Psalmists, and Evangelists of the Sacred
               Book, into the hands of the same man for illustration, was a very
               dangerous experiment. To fulfil such a task properly, as the
               illustration of the whole Bible, requires an amount of genius
               and learning, which no individual ever did, or ever can, possess.
               If the Bible itself were pervaded by one tone of expression,
               it would be the most wearisome book in existence. But one
               of the charms which attracts all readers, is the almost infinite
               variety of styles in which it is written. The Harpers' edition,
               however, has claims to favor irrespective of its illustrations,
               which would render it a cheap and valuable work, even though
               it did not contain a tenth part of its pictures. The type, paper and ink, the correctness of the text and notes, are the
               points which must give it a permanent and reliable value.
            </p>
         </div> 
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p26">
            <div class="biblTitle">A New Painting</div>
            <div class="biblPage">397</div>
            
            <p>A NEW PAINTING, BY C. DEAS, has lately been added to the
               Exhibition of the American Art-Union. It represents a party
               of Indians at play, and though an interesting picture, as exhibiting a trait of Indian life, it is by no means equal to the
               two last which were purchased by the Art-Union.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mr. E. L. Carey</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>MR. E. L. CAREY.--Philadelphia and the whole circle of
               American artists, have met with a great loss in the death of
               Mr. E. L. Carey, who had been an invalid for the last three
               years, but was at last suddenly snatched away from his sphere
               of usefulness, after an illness of only two days. Mr. Carey
               was the most liberal and discriminating purchaser of works of
               art in the country, and he had made the very best, if not the
               most extensive collection of the productions of modern artists,
               to be found in the Union. Mr. Carey was peculiarly liberal
               towards young artists, and gave them orders without waiting
               for them to become famous. The destruction of the Pennsylvania Academy of Fine Arts is a calamity, no doubt; but it is
               one that can be repaired; the loss of an enlightened and liberal patron, however, is one that the world of art cannot
               repair. We trust, however, that Mr. Carey's example will not 
               be lost on the men of wealth in Philadelphia and elsewhere.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p28">
            <div class="biblTitle">Horace Kneeland</div>
            <div class="biblPage">396</div>
            
            <p>HORACE KNEELAND.--We are happy to learn that this deserving artist has received a very liberal order from a few gentlemen of this City, Philadelphia and Boston, for another
               equestrian statue of Washington, which is to be cast in bronze.
               The model will be made here, but it will be taken to Berlin by 
               Mr. Kneeland and there cast. The commission for this statue 
               reflects the highest credit upon Mr. Kneeland's past works,
               and is an honor to the discernment and liberality of the gentle- 
               men who have commissioned him. It also reflects disgrace, 
               which the whole country should see, on the National Academy,
               which recently refused to confer the poor title of associate 
               upon Mr. K., who has, during the past four years, exhibited
               the first busts in the annual exhibitions of the Academy, if we 
               except those by Mr. Powers. But while there are so many
               spoilers of canvass among the academicians, it can hardly be 
               expected that they should admit an artist of respectable abilities
               among their associates. In justice to the Academy, it should
               be known that the best artists belonging to it were in favor of
               Mr. Kneeland's election.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p29">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Concert Room</div>
         <div class="biblPage">397</div>
         <div class="head">THE CONCERT ROOM.</div>
         
         <p>New York Philharmonic Society vs. the Musical
            Fund Society of Philadelphia.--It seems that some person corresponding with the Mirror, from Philadelphia, takes 
            the opportunity of speaking of the Musical Fund in terms of
            high commendation, while he does considerable, although perhaps unintentional injustice to the Philharmonic Society. 
            This Society, although by no means a benefit society, according to its constitution, has yet taken a noble stand in the cause
            of humanity. We know of several instances where the funds
            have been judiciously applied, either to aid the sick, or to bury 
            the deceased brother. There is no party feeling here; all is
            forgotten but the necessity of the case. A member of the N.
            Y. P. S., in answer to the Mirror, states that the remuneration of the members, barely amounts to one dollar for their at-
            tendence at the numerous rehearsals which occur during the
            season.
         </p>
         
         <p>This is indeed poor pay for two or three hours' tedious rehearsals during each week. It is indeed so poor that nothing
            but the right spirit of enthusiasm for their profession can induce the members to submit to such a loss.
         </p>
         
         <p>For loving their art so well they should be commended and
            respected, but there are other points which entitle them, in
            our opinion, to still higher commendation and respect. Why
            is it that their dividend is so small--why is it that they have to
            work so hard for a remuneration so inadequate? The Society is successful! it is prosperous in the highest degree--the
            favorite with the profession and the public! What then is the
            reason of its apparent poverty--it is that they all must willingly yield the greater portion of the results of their hard labor for
            the sake of a charity which is wide and embracing. Besides
            this, many of the members are liberal subscribers to the concerts, for their families and their friends, and in this way contribute individually to the prosperity of the society. We know
            some, who instead of receiving any dividend from the receipts,
            were by their liberal subscriptions indebted to the society.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Philharmonic Society deserve more credit for their liberality, from the fact that they pretend to nothing, but do all
            that charity requires in a sure but secret, unostentatious manner.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have long known the necessity of a fund which should
            be devoted to the relief of indigent or aged musicians, and we
            trust that at no distant period an institution so much needed
            and so charitable in its purposes will be established; but in the
            meantime we assure our friends in Philadelphia, that the sick
            or the needy musician, is not entirely friendless, and cannot be,
            while the Philharmonic Society continues to extend its beneficial influence over the profession of New York.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Fry,--his Critics and his Friends.--Our remarks
            upon Mr. Fry's Leonora have called forth a lengthy reply in
            the Evening Express.
         </p>
         
         <p>The reply is of very little moment, as nothing we have said
            is therein refuted; indeed, the only attempt at refutation is in
            the case of Newkomn's fine song, King Death, and in this the
            writer has signally failed, as we shall show. The writer of
            the Express first quotes our words--
         </p>
         
         <p>"Montalvo's first song is 'King Death was a rare old fellow.'
            This song as composed by Chevalier Newkomn is universally
            known, and what could have induced Mr. Fry to introduce it into
            his Opera, unless to suggest comparison, we are at a loss to conceive. Comparisons will be drawn, and to his disadvantage, for
            the first phrases of his version prove, beyond a doubt, that Newkomn's fine song was fresh in his memory, and suggested, if not
            supplied the thoughts."
         </p>
         
         <p>He then adds:</p>
         
         <p>"Now, it so happens that Mr. Fry's version of the song has been
            lying for years in his repertoire, and was sung in public and in
            private--(just as it is bodily introduced into 'Leonora,' and performed by Mr. Seguin,) when 
            <span class="person" id="bwprocter">Barry Cornwall</span>'s words were new,
            and probably long before the Chev. Newkomn ever thought of
            setting."
         </p>
         
         <p>Now, we don't pretend to doubt the truth of the assertion
            that Mr. Fry's version has been lying in his repertoire for
            years, for the original is old enough to allow of it; we remember it some twelve or fourteen years. With regard to the "probability" that Mr. Fry set the words before Newkomn saw
            them, we positively state that there is not a shadow of a possibility that such should be the case, for it is a well-known fact
            that 
            <span class="person" id="bwprocter">Barry Cornwall</span>, or 
            <span class="person" id="bwprocter">Proctor</span>, wrote the words one morning
            while Newkomn was with him, and that the Chevalier composed the music to them, as it was afterwards published, before
            he left the room. The two artists were on terms of the most
            intimate friendship, and 
            <span class="person" id="bwprocter">Barry Cornwall</span> wrote all his lyrics
            
            especially for Newkomm, because, as he said, a foreigner appreciated them, and discovered their musical adaptability, when
            his own countrymen passed them by unnoticed. Mr. Fry, or
            his friends, may still claim priority, originality, &amp;c. &amp;c., but
            the fact as we have stated it cannot be disputed.
         </p>
         
         <p>The editor of the Express refers with excessive satisfaction
            to a long, tumid, fulsomely laudatory article which appeared in
            the Express on the 9th inst.; and which he flatteringly denominates a criticism, comparing it triumphantly with our notice of
            the Opera. It will be seen by the following quotation that he
            considers the relative value and truth of the two articles to
            be determined by the corrections of our statement respecting
            "King Death."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Now, after this opera of 'Leonora' had been played four times
            we published in this paper an extended criticism of it from the
            pen of one of the best and most impartial musical judges in this
            country. His favorable judgment of the composition and its performance have been corroborated by other writers equally unprejudiced, and equally experienced. The 'Broadway Journal,'
            on the other hand, has this elaborate condemnation of the opera;
            and now, who is to decide which of all these critics is right?
            Which is best entitled to public confidence, as to the merits of the
            composition in question? We take leave to say that the paragraph
            above quoted ought to settle the dispute definitely, so far as the
            authenticity of the Journal's infallibility is concerned, at least."
         </p>
         
         <p>We are content to leave "the authenticity of the Journal's
            infallibility," to be decided by the truth or the contrary of our
            statement.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our criticism throughout was a fair and impartial one, and
            has placed Mr. Fry in his true position as an imitator and not
            a creator. His blind idolatry of the modern Italian school,
            has led him to think not merely similarities, but positive identities. He may believe honestly that they are original; his
            friends and such writers as the one in the Express, may confirm him in the belief, but we assure him and them that the
            whole is a delusion. Any honest and competent writer would
            scorn to toady the individual at the expense of the art! What
            man possessing any knowledge of music, or respect for truth
            after hearing Leonora, with its endless robberies from Bellini
            &amp; Co., could sit down and pen so wilful and absurd a falsehood as the following from the critique in the Express--"As
            we said in a former article, he takes rank by this work with
            the first of living masters." Is this writer aware of the existence of Rossini? of Auber? or even of those trifling writers
            Mendelssohn, Spohr, Beissiger, Marschner, Meyerbeer, and a
            hundred other writers, the least of them enjoying a sterling
            reputation from their published works, by far exceeding the
            written-up-by-my-brother's-reputation of Mr. Fry.
         </p>
         
         <p>Again, says this writer, "He has achieved that which no
            man speaking the English language has yet equalled." What
            bombast! what fustian! Handel spoke the English language
            fluently, Weber also, and Oberon was the result; Ferdninand
            Reiss too, and the Ice Witch was the consequence,--the Ice
            Witch was by the by, composed in six weeks, so that Reiss
            beat Fry by six weeks;--Jules Benedict may be said to have
            advanced beyond the rudiments of the English language, and
            his Operas of the Gipsey's Warning, and the Bride of Venice
            are still extant. Then we have John Barnett, Edward Loder,
            Mcfarren, Balfe, and even Rooke, who speak English, though,
            some of them are Irish to be sure, and each of these has done
            more to win a lasting reputation than Mr. Fry in his Leonora
            gives evidence of being capable of doing. They have not
            before, certainly, contrived the monstrosity of a recitative
            Opera; but there is one man who had the audacity and the
            misfortune to live before Mr. Fry, we mean Dr. Arne who
            wrote the recitative Opera of Artaxerxes. We will not draw
            a comparison between the two works, lest we should be considered partial; but we doubt if Leonora will live to as good
            an old age as the venerable Artaxerxes.
         </p>
         
         <p>The "best and most impartial of musical judges," as the
             writer in the Express calls the writer in the Express for we
            believe that both the critique and the criticism upon our criticism, own the same paternity--we had almost said fry-ternity
            --the "best and most impartial of musical judges," we say-as the Express says--must be a very ignorant pretender in
            the art which he professes to criticise. A more uncouth jumble of unmeaning phrases will seldom be found huddled together
            in one article. He has, however, found out one great, original and peculiar beauty in Leonora, for which Mr. Fry certainly owes him one; we find it described in two places, in the
            following words:--"The finale follows, introduced with a short
            passage by the Chorus fortissimo on a high key." "The end
            of the finale is in syncopated passages on high keys for the
            whole Chorus." Good gracious! which are the high keys?
            --and if it be not an impertinent question, did the whole of the
            Chorus sing in different high keys? this is an important query,
            and we should be glad to send its solution to Europe, as the
            effect of vast bodies in high keys--the Irish already have highlowes--may become a standard of its class!!
         </p>
         
         <p>There are many absurdities equally glaring, which we will
            reserve for a future article.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p30">
         <div class="biblTitle">To Correspondents</div>
         <div class="biblPage">398</div>
         <p>TO CORRESPONDENTS.--We are greatly indebted to the author of
            the Correspondence between a Mother and Governess--also to A.
            M. J.--to J. T. of Jackson--to T. H. C.--and to F.W.C. of Boston.
            We are forced to decline "The Heart Unshared." We are anxious
            to hear from Ellen of N., in D.
         </p>
      </div>            
      
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">398</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">VANDENHOFF'S ELOCUTION.</div>
            
            <p>SECOND EDITION.--This valuable work is being introduced
               into a large number of the best Schools in the City and
               Country.
            </p>
            
            <p>It only needs to be generally known to become universally
               established.
            </p>
            
            <p>Testimonials are received from every quarter.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">From Rev. R. F. Burnham, Rector of St. Paul's Church, Hoboken.</div>
            
            <p>"Having seen, with much pleasure, a second edition, by your
               house, of "A Plain System of Elocution," I beg leave to express
               to you my opinion of the high merit of that work.
            </p>
            
            <p>Its title is in keeping with the plan pursued in the book; a rare
               fact in this age of making many books. In the work may be found
               what this age needs--a System of Elocution, that presents to the
               learner something tangible; and that combines meaning with
               beauty, and beauty with force.
            </p>
            
            <p>I hereby express the opinion that the Principals of Seminaries
               of Learning would benefit the department of Elocution, by the
               introduction of Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="gvandenhoff">Vandenhoff</span>'s System."
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">C. SHEPARD, Publisher,
               
               <br></br>191 Broadway, opposite John-street.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">The National Magazine and Industrial Record, No. I.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">EDITED BY REDWOOD FISHER,
               
               <br></br>ASSISTED IN THE STATISTICAL DEPARTMENT BY MR. 
               <span class="person" id="ewilliams">EDWIN WILLIAMS</span>.
               
               <br></br>Published Monthly, in Numbers of 96 pages, $5 per Annum.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE DESIGN OF THIS WORK IS TO DEVELope all the great resources of the country, as they are shown in
               its Agriculture, Manufactutes and Commerce. Essays and statements
               on these great interests will be given, with notices of Manufacturing
               Towns and Villages, Internal Improvements, New Inventions, snd Statistical Details, exhibiting the progress of American industry.
            </p>
            
            <p>FROISSART'S CHRONICLES of England, France and Spain,
               with an Essay on the Character and Society of the Middle Ages. One
               vol. 4to. pp. 634. $3.
            </p>
            SCARCE WORKS.
            
            <p>THE BRITISH NAVAL CHRONICLE; a General and Biographical History of the Royal Navy. 20 vols. 8vo., bound, with numerous
               plates. Price $50.
            </p>
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="hniles">NILES</span>' WEEKLY REGISTER, (Subscriber's Copy) in 30 vols.
               8vo., bound. Price, $50.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received to all the American and English Periodicals
               and orders for books promptly executed.
            </p>
            
            <p>FINDEN'S LANDSCAPE ILLUSTRATIONS, of the Prose and
               Poetical Words of Sir 
               <span class="person" id="wscott">Waller Scott</span>, with portraits of the principal female characters. The designs from Westall, Landseer, Leslie, Stanfield,
               Prout, &amp;c., with letter-press descriptions. 3 vols. Containing 120
               plates; turkey morocco, extra. Price $12.
            </p>
            
            <p>FOR SALE, a single copy of "Sparking," the last print of the American Art Union.</p>
            
            <p>LANDSCAPE ILLUSTRATIONS of the Bible, from original
               sketches by eminent artists.
            </p>
            
            <p>A few copies of the "Blind Fiddler," from 
               <span class="person" id="dwilkie">Wildie</span>.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">J. SMITH HOMANS,
               
               <br></br>Sun Office, corner of Fulton and Nassau Streets.
            </div>
         </div>
           
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">This Day is Published,</div>
            
            <div class="head">LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING.</div>
            
            <p>NO.'S XI AND XII OF THE LIBRARY OF CHOICE
               READING, Containing the Crescent and the Cross, by Eliot Warburton, Esq. Two thick parts, 12mo. beautifully printed in large clear
               type, on fine white paper, each 50 cts.
            </p>
            
            <p>"
               <span class="person" id="ewarburton">Eliot Warburton</span>, who is known to be the author of these brilliantly
               sparkling papers, the "Episodes of Eastern Travel," which lit up our
               last November. His book (The Crescent and the Cross) must and will
               be capital."--Vide "Eothen," page 179.
            </p>
            
            <p>"This delightful work is, from first to last, a splendid panorama of
               Eastern scenery, in the full blaze of its magnificence. The crowning
               merit of the book is, that it is evidently the production of a gentleman,
               and a man of the world, who has lived in the best society, and been an
               attentive observer of the scenes and characters which have passed before
               him during his restless and joyous existence. To a keen sense of the
               ludicrous, he joins a power of sketching and grouping which are happily
               demonstrated."--Morning Post.
            </p>
            
            <p>"We could not recommend a better book as a travelling companion
               than Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="ewarburton">Warburton</span>'s. Admirably written as is the work, and eminently graphic as are its descriptions, it possesses a yet more exalted merit
               in the biblical and philosophical illustrations of the writer."--United
               Service Magazine.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="ewarburton">Warburton</span> has fulfilled the promise of his title-page. The
               'Realities' of 'Eastern Travel' are described with a vividness which invest them with deep and abiding interest; while the 'Romantic' adventures which the enterprising tourist met with in his course are
               narrated with a spirit which shows how much he enjoyed these reliefs
               from the ennui ot every-day life."--Globe.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Published and for sale by	WILEY &amp; PUTNAM,
               
               <br></br>161 Broadway.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">LONDON AND PARIS LITERARY AGENCY.
                RICH &amp; SONS.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">AGENTS FOR THE PURCHASE OF BOOKS FOR
               
               <br></br>AMERICA.
               
               <br></br>Agents for the Library of Congress,
               
               <br></br>The New-York Society Library.
               
               <br></br>The Albany Institute,
               
               <br></br>The Boston Athenaeum, &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>12 Red Lion Square, London.
               
               <br></br>12 Rue Pot de Per. Paris.
            </div>
            
            <p>MR. RICH Respectfully informs his friends and fellow-citizens that he
               has formed an establishment in Paris, in connexion with his old establishment in Red Lion Square, for the purpose of furnishing BOOKS
               published on the continent without the heavy expense attending their
               transmission through England. Each of these establishments will be
               conducted by one of his sons, under his own general superintendence.--
               This new arrangement, he trusts, will prove of signal advantage to his
               correspondents, and no exertions will be wanting to execute their orders
               on the most advantageous terms. Orders may be sent through, and
               small sums payed to Messrs. Goodhue &amp; Co. of New-York. Two and a
               half per cent will be allowed to all those who make a remittance with
               their orders.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. RICH, having made Bibliography his special study for forty years,
               possesses a knowledge of books and editions not often to be met with,
               and will be happy to give any advice and information respecting the formation of Libraries or Collections of Books in any particular branch of
               literature or science. For information in regard to his efficiency, he
               begs to refer to Messrs. 
               <span class="person" id="whprescott">Prescott</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="gticknor">Ticknor</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="jsparks">Sparks</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="wirving">Irving</span>, and other literary characters in the United States, to whom be is known. Intending
               to devote the remainder of his life to literary pursuits, his greatest pleasure will arise from sending rare and valuable books to his own country;
               and he trusts to live long enough to see in the United States a Library
               which may bear a comparison with the most celebrated in Europe. If
               he can live to say, "I ALSO ASSISTED IN ITS FORMATION," his most ardent wishes will be gratified.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="orich">Rich</span> has in press--Bibliotheca Americana Nova: a Catalogue of Books relating to America, including Voyages to the South
               Seas and round the World: Part III. from 1831 to 1845, with supplement
               and index completing the work.
            </p>
            
            <p>He has also ready for the press, Bibliotheca Americana Vetus: a
               Catalogue of Books relating to America from the discovery to the year
               1700; with notes and observations: in one vol. 8 vo., of about 400 pages.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr 
               <span class="person" id="orich">Rich</span> has also ready a reprint from 
               <span class="person" id="mthevenot">Thevenot</span>'s Collection of 
               <span class="person" id="jmarquette">Father Marquette</span>'s account of the discovery of the Mississippi, entitled,
               'Decouverte de quelques Pays et Nations de l'Amerique Septentrionale.'
               Only 125 copies are printed, which will be distributed among Mr. Rich's
               friends and correspondents.
            </p>		
            
            <p>Mr Rich has also purchased the remaining copies of the part relating
               to America of L'Art de Verifier lea Dates; of which ten volumes in octavo by 
               <span class="person" id="dbwarden">D. B. Warden</span>, Esq., are printed, and two volumes more, completing the work, will be published during the course of the present year.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Price of the ten volumes published, - - - -	40 francs</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Complete sets of the Art de Verifier les Dates, in 44 vols. 8vo, 160 francs,
               
               <br></br>instead of 308, the original price.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Paris, May 1,1845.       may24</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person" id="lpsmith">SMITH</span>'S WEEKLY VOLUME.
            </div>
            
            <p>A SELECT CIRCULATING LIBRARY BY THE ORIGINAL
               Editor of Wadlie'e Library. This popular periodical is regularly received at the office of the Broadway Journal. Terms, $4
               per anuum, single numbers 8 cts.
            </p> 
            <div class="ab">JOHN BISCO, Publisher,
               
               <br></br>135 Nassau st., Clinton Hall.
            </div>
         </div>
                     
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">VALUABLE BOOKS OF TRAVEL.
               IN PRESS OR JUST PUBLISHED
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">By harper &amp; Brothers,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NEW YORK.</div>
            I.
            
            <div class="ab">TRAVELS IN THE EAST.
               
               <br></br>BY 
               <span class="person" id="jpdurbin">JOHN P. DURBIN</span>, D. D.,
               
               <br></br>Author of "Observations in Europe,"
               
               <br></br>[In press.]
            </div>
            II.
            
            <div class="ab">THE TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO.
               
               <br></br>With Notes and Illustrations.
               
               <br></br>BY 
               <span class="person" id="hmurray">HUGH MURRAY</span>, ESQ.
               
               <br></br>[In press.]
            </div>
            III.
            
            <div class="ab">VOYAGES ROUND THE WORLD.
               
               <br></br>From the Death of Capt. Cook to the Present Time, &amp;c.
            </div>
            IV.
            
            <div class="ab">
               <span class="person" id="jlstephens">STEPHENS</span>' CENTRAL AMERICA.
               
               <br></br>Comprising interesting Sketches of the remarkable Ruins of that
               
               <br></br>Country.
               
               <br></br>2 vols. 8vo. Numerous Plates.
            </div>
            V.
            
            <div class="ab">STEPHENS' YUCATAN.
               
               <br></br>Including copious Details and Illustrations of the Stupendous
               
               <br></br>Architectural Relics of the Peninsula.
               
               <br></br>2 vols.8 vo. 120 fine Engravings.
            </div>
            VI.
            
            <div class="ab">DR. 
               <span class="person" id="wfisk">FISK</span>'S TRAVELS IN EUROPE,
               
               <br></br>England, Ireland, Scotland, France, Italy, Switzerland, &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>With numerous Engraved Illustrations.
            </div>
            VII.
            
            <div class="ab">HUMBOLDT'S TRAVELS.
               
               <br></br>Being a condensed Narrative of his Explorations in Central
               
               <br></br>America, Asiatic Russia, &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>1 vol. 18mo. With Cuts.
            </div>
            VIII.
            
            <div class="ab">
               <span class="person" id="eroberts">ROBERTS</span>' COCHIN-CHINA, SIAM, &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>An Account of his Embassy to those Courts.
               
               <br></br>1 vol. 8vo.
            </div>
            IX.
            
            <div class="ab">
               <span class="person" id="tjjacobs">JACOBS</span>' ADVENTURES IN THE PACIFIC.
               
               <br></br>Comprising a Narrative of Scenes and Incidents in the Islands of
               
               <br></br>the Australasian Seas, &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>1	vol. 12mo. Plates.
            </div>
            X.
            
            <div class="ab">DR. 
               <span class="person" id="hhumphrey">HUMPHREY</span>'S TOUR.
               
               <br></br>In Great Britain, France and Belgium, &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>2 vols. 12mo.
            </div>
            XI.
            
            <div class="ab">INCIDENTS OF TRAVEL IN GREECE,
               
               <br></br>Turkey, Russia, Poland, &amp;c.
               
               <br></br>BY 
               <span class="person" id="jlstephens">JOHN L. STEPHENS</span>, ESQ.
               
               <br></br>2 vols. 12mo. Plates.
            </div>
            XII.
            
            <div class="ab">
               <span class="person" id="jlstephens">STEPHENS</span>' TRAVELS IN EGYPT,
               
               <br></br>Arabia Petrae, and the Holy Land.
               
               <br></br>2	vols. 12mo. Plates.
            </div>
            XIII.
            
            <div class="ab">RESEARCHES IN CAFFRARIA.
               
               <br></br>Describing the Customs, Character, and Mortal Condition of the
               
               <br></br>Tribes Inhabiting the Southern Portions of Africa,
               
               <br></br>BY 
               <span class="person" id="skay">STEPHEN KAY</span>.
               
               <br></br>12mo. Plates.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MANESCA'S ORAL SYSTEM OF TEACHING</div>
            
            <div class="ab">THE FRENCH LANGUAGE, pursued by his daughter, Madame
               
               <br></br>Durand, either in class or private lessons, to Ladies and Gentlemen, at
               
               <br></br>No. 35 Walker-street.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
            
            <p>SIR--WE WILL THANK YOU TO CAUTION
               the public against a set of imposters who are calling upon our customers, asserting that they are engaged by us in the capacity of agents.
               In several instances they have succeeded in obtaining orders. But when
               the goods are delivered great dissatisfaction has been given by the infamous and utterly base imitations. But still persisting that the cards 
               are our manufacture, they too often succeed in foisting them upon the
               unsuspecting. We ourselves would strenuously caution the said parties 
               that, should they persist after this notice, we will try what effect a State
               Prison will have upon them.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">We are, Sir, Your most obt'y,
               
               <br></br>J. B.CAREY &amp; CO.,
               
               <br></br>Ornamental Show Card Manufacturers, 323 Broadway.
            </div>
            
            <p>An agent wanted for New-York City. Also one for New-York State
               --whose name will be published as our authorized agent.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE,
               THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE YEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTITUTE
               FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH'S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double entry Book-keeping, FIFTEEN DOLLARS, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
               Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>CLASS HOURS--9 A. M, 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M. daily for gentlemen, and
               from 11 to 1 o'clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale "
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">GOLDSMITH</span>'S GEMS OF PENMANSHIP," elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
            
            <p>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANOFORTE,
               ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank-street, where his terms
               for giving instruction can be ascertained.	myl7
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <p>PHILIP ERNST, Teacher of the Flute and Guitar, would inform the lovers of Music that he has now for sale several of the above celebrated instruments, constructed in every respect in
               accordance with those now in use at the Paris and London Royal Academies. To be seen at PHILIP ERNST'S Music Saloon, 395 Broadway,
               near Walker-st.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">(NEW INVENTION.)
               
               <br></br>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the Conservatorie at Paris,
               
               <br></br>and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
            </div>
            
            <p>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the 'Boehm Flute,'
               110 Fulton-St. N.Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of this
               city the above Important Invention, which has been so enthusiastically received and generally used by the most distinguished European artists, feels happy in being able to place before them the following
               testimonial to its merits, signed by two of the most distinguished of our
               resident Artists.
            </p>
            
            <p>We hereby certify to the excellence of the Boehm Flute, as manufactured
               by Mr. J. D. Larrabee; to the beauty of its tone, the perfection of
               its tune, and the simplicity of its fingering, which renders a brilliant execution comparatively easy.
            </p>
            
            <p> PHILIP ERNST, (who has already introduced it
               successfully among his pupils.)
            </p>
            
            <p>JOHN A. KYLE, Principal Flute of the Philharmonic Society, and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm
               Flute, 41 Forsyth-st. New-York.
            </p>
            
            <p>Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory, 110
               Fulton-st. and judge for themselves.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor to
               Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the largest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most
               superior quality: such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned
               and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on hire.
            </p>
         </div>            
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER,
               
               <br></br>88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER-STREET, NEAR ELM.
            </div>
            
            <p>A Large Stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS MODERATE.
               
               <br></br>N. B. Wanted, a second hand Parlor Organ.
               
               <br></br>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">--A. H. GALE &amp; CO.'s Ware-
               
               <br></br>Rooms, No. 289 Broadway--Manufactory Third Avenue, corner of
               
               <br></br>13th street.
            </div>
            
            <p>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assortment
               of Rosewood and Mahogany Piano Fortes, with from six to seven octaves, embracing every variety of patterns, made in their well-known
               substantial manner, under their immediate and personal superintendence,
               by skillful and experienced mechanics, from the best seasoned materials.
            </p>
            
            <p>These instruments embrace many important improvements, which
               will RECOMMEND THEMSELVES, and are finished in the highest state of
               perfection, with the best French grand action, warranted in every respect
               by the manufacturer.
            </p>
         </div>            
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished,
               in elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
               the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
               to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
               upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNAM,
               
               <br></br>34 Beekman-St. (late 323 Broadway.)
               
               <br></br>Manufactory, I3th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
            </div>
            
            <p>N. B. A good second-hand pianoforte for sale.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES. </div>
            <p>--JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to the
               elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, corner of Cottage-Place and Bleecker-street, which he will sell as
               prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P, having been actively engaged in the business for the last twenty
               years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two of the
               largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the best makers in
               this country or Europe, and that they contain all the real improvements
               of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
               Repaired.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">New-York, April 28d, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">--V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal-
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
               Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from
               choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the business.
            </p>
            
            <p>FOR SALE--A splendid harp, nearly new. To be sold at a great
               bargaia for cash.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">F RILEY &amp; CO.,</div> 
            <p>No. 297 Broadway, (between
               Reade and Duane-Streets,) N. Y., Publishers of Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition to
               their own catalogue (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep
               on hand the publications of all the principal Music houses. They are
               erecting a large Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes of a
               superior quality, will constantly be kept on hand
            </p>
         </div>        
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">BERTINI</span>'S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            </div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
               work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this
               method, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
               The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises,
               scales and studies are given in such progressive order, that they enlist
               the interests of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly through those
               mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often made irksome in
               other instruction books. The time has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is only by the study of
               such methods as Bertini's that pupils will he enabled to Read music
               with facility, and at the same time become good musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the
               rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each
               lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations from
               professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s
               Method over all others yet published in this country, most of them
               having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to
               give a few of the names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Boston.	New-York.
               
               <br></br>Messrs. G. J. Webb,	Messrs. H. C. Timm,
               
               <br></br>J. G. Maedar,	W. Alpers,
               
               <br></br>H.T. Hach,	U.C. Hill,
               
               <br></br>E. L. White,	F. H. Brown.
               
               <br></br>David Paine,	Philadelphia,
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek,	B. C. Cross,
               
               <br></br>T. R. Moses.	Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>Albany--O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
               American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197
               Washington-street, Boston.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p31">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">400</div>
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co..............................Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance........................Philadelphia, Pa.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. Huntington,....................Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>George Jones,...........................Albany, N.Y.
            
            <br></br>Thomas H Pease,.........................New-Haven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>L. Willard...............................Troy.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">J. R, Winser, Printer 138 Fulton-street.</div>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>