<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div>
         
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">VOL. 2.,NEW YORK,
            SATURDAY, OCTOBER 4,1845.
            NO. 13.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Three Dollars per Annum. Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">edited by EDGAR A. POE and HENRY C. WATSON. </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Published at 135 Nassau-St. By JOHN BISCO.</div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Lines.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Peace of the hallowed day—how pure and deep!
            <br>On the green earth—in the blue boundless air,
            <br>How do all things invite the soul to prayer!
            <br>Her solemn Sabbath how doth Nature keep!
            <br>Doth silence reign, that hither down may float 
            <br>The full deep waves of Heaven’s own harmony—
            <br>That favored man, from earthly coil set free,
            <br>Listening in awe, may catch the angelic note? 
            <br>O dreamer! see to it—that nought within 
            <br>The faint, yet glorious diapason mar!
            <br>Crush thy heart’s whispers; fix thy gaze alar,
            <br>And turn thee from the Siren lure of sin!
            <br>It is a “still small voice” that speaks His will 
            <br>Before whom sank the ocean billows, and were still.
            <br>O weary heart! there is a rest for thee;
            <br>O truant heart! there is a blessed home—
            <br>An isle of gladness on life’s treacherous sea,
            <br>Where storms, that vex the waters, never come. 
            <br>Through groves perennial, streams that cannot die 
            <br>Bear blessing round that fair and fertile shore;
            <br>And shipwrecked ones, beneath that bending sky,
            <br>Dream of the terrors of the deep no more.
            <br>Winnowed by wings immortal that sweet isle;
            <br>Vocal its air with music from above;
            <br>There meets the exile aye a welcoming smile;
            <br>There ever speaks a summoning voice of love 
            <br>"Say to the heavy laden and distressed—
            <br>‘Come unto me, and I will give you rest.’ ”
            
            <div class="byline"><span class="person">E. F. Ellet.</span></div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Gift of Prophecy.</div>
         
         <p>Our life is hid. Shadows dark as the raven’s wing
            shut us in.and shut us out from what is within—from 
            the only substantial. We know not the meaning of sight 
            We know not what we see when sight is given. When 
            glimpses of the Divine that is within and all around us, 
            come athwart our darkness, they seem so beautiful, so 
            heavenly, that we say we are under the dominion of the 
            marvellous, and we fear that reason is reeling from her throne.
         </p>
         
         <p>If there are no Prophets, or Seers, whence has come
            the idea of such? The skeptic says from the Imagination, or in other words the image-making power. But 
            whence comes the original of an image in the mind?
         </p>
         
         <p>Of the gift of Prophecy I will speak what I know.— 
            The “reasonable” man will pass my statements unread,
            or lie will smile pityingly at ray “hallucinations.”
         </p> 
         
         <p>From an early age I have had the gilt of Prophecy. 
            Not at all times; not for all events. But at particular
            seasons the foreshadow, or foreshine of the Future has
            come so deeply or so brightly upon my soul, that I have 
            been compelled to feel, if not to utter the Prophecy. But
            apart from these seasons I could never divine for myself, 
            or another. That is, in what is called my natural state,
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>I could not do this. Of the influence of Mesmerism I 
            shall speak hereafter. The first distinct shadowing of 
            unknown events upon my consciousness that I remember, 
            was when I was very young. From infancy I had been 
            baptized in tears, and it is no strange thing that my first 
            experience as a Seer should be sorrowful. I had been 
            from home some time, and was returning. Within a mile 
            of my father’s house the shadow fell. I was certain that
            evil had come to those I loved. I was particularly certain that the blow had fallen upon my mother. I could 
            hardly support myself till I reached home, so intense and 
            terrible was my agitation and distress at the certainty 
            that had come to me. My sister met me at the door, 
            with an expression of suffering on her countenance that 
            told a sad tale. She put her finger to her lip, closed the 
            door softly, and drew me aside to say in a whisper, that 
            our mother’s life was despaired of. It was what I expected, but I do not know that I was any better prepared
            for the event. However, as yet I was but a novice in 
            “Second Sight.” It is sometimes said that we should be 
            miserable if we knew the future, and that this is the reason why it is shut out from us. I suppose this is true 
            of our ordinary state, but our whole being is changed 
            when the prophetic sense is fully awakened, and we are 
            not always, or often wretched in view of the trials of the 
            future, but girded to meet them.
         </p>
         
         <p>Once in my life a great trial was hid from me, and 
            revealed to a brother seer. My heart did not respond in 
            faith to his vision. I smiled when he detailed with minuteness, great sorrows that were coming to me. My 
            heart was a little faint when I thought it might be that 
            he spoke truly. He told me of blessings that should be
            mine, through the medium of these trials. When all the sorrow came,
            I knew that he had thus far told me truly, 
            yet I did not believe in the blessing he had predicted.— 
            What a bundle of enigmas is man! But the blessing 
            came as truly as the sorrow had come.
         </p>
         
         <p>Once when I had been very ill and was recovering, my 
            Prophetic Light was clear, and comparatively far-reaching. I saw, as it were, a scroll, written in light, with 
            the deeds of years engraven on it. What no one had 
            done, I saw with mid-day clearness that I should do. I 
            saw that I should dare much, and accomplish much— 
            that curses and blessings should be mine. With a heavenly awe, and a peace not of earth, for hours I read the 
            scroll of Destiny. Whatever I sought to know, appeared emblazoned in living light before me. At that moment, weak and faint from what all had deemed the bed 
            of Death, I seemed to have superhuman strength to do 
            all that waited my doing. Years of the most intense activity, deeds that have awakened men from the deathsleep of centuries, were crowded on that life-scroll. For 
            hours I gazed without tiring, and then gradually all faded from before me, and I was left alone, with the weakness of an infant, counting my heart-throbs, to see if I 
            had forgotten how to count. I slowly gained health, and
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page188"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            forgot the vision—and not until the days of its accomplishment had passed, did I again call it to mind. People try at this day to explain all this neurologically, or 
            mesmerically, but their explanations need explaining as 
            much as my phenomena. I know that I am, that my 
            gift is. Do they know more? Again and again since 
            that Record of Destiny was unrolled to me, I have seen 
            the Future. Many times my sight has been opened 
            through Mesmerism, but then I seem to see with less of 
            Beauty and of Life. On one occasion I was mesmerized, 
            and the events of the coming year passed in rapid succession before me. I wrote them, that I might have the 
            record when the vision had faded from my sight. I folded the Prophecy into my common-place-book, and weeks 
            afterward I read it. I felt solemn in view of what I had 
            seen, but calm and resigned. Only one event seemed to 
            call for resignation, and that was to shut me from the 
            world yet a little longer, perhaps till I have passed away. 
            What boots it whether the world knows its benefactors? 
            What boots it whether I steal into hearts an inspiration 
            silent as the gentle and refreshing dew, or whether I 
            come like the hoarse thunder which purifies the atmosphere ’mid terror and admiration? So that the heavenly 
            cycles roll on, and God’s work is done, I am content. I 
            have often had the Prophetic sense awakened for myself and others by the hand of the mesmerizer, and I 
            have then seen strange and wonderful things, in this
            world, and in the real world, where all is substance, 
            not shadow. But men are not prepared for the wonders 
            of this world—what then would they say to the events of 
            the spiritual world? The God-Man of Nazareth said, “I 
            have many things to say to you, but you cannot bear 
            them now."
         </p>
         
         <p>The mesmeric state does not seem to be fully mine. In 
            that I seem to be away from home. What is called the 
            natural or spontaneous mesmeric state, in which I see 
            the abstract, the distant, the future, in a word the spiritual, as my own Soul, this is the state I love. This is 
            the foreshine of that world that we are all entering
            upon.
         </p>  
         
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">Mary Orme</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Pictures.</div>
         
         <div class="byline">BY <span class="person">MISS COLMAN</span>.
         </div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Wearily, wearily,
            <br>Drowned in her tears,
            <br>Sitting so lonelily,
            <br>Trembling with fears,
            <br>Hearken how sobbingly,
            <br>Come forth her sighs!
            <br>See, see how absently 
            <br>Wander her eyes!
            <br>Listen I—she dreamily 
            <br>Murmurs a word,
            <br>Soft, and how touchingly!
            <br>Scarce is it heard.
            <br>Now she prays mourningly,
            <br>Bent to the earth;
            <br>Angels, that tenderly,
            <br>Watched her from birth,
            <br>Sooth her now lovingly 
            <br>Sinking with grief—
            <br>In voices so heavenly 
            <br>Whisper relief.
            <br>Ah, is it not pitiful 
            <br>To look on her there,
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div><br>Good, and so beautiful
            <br>Laden with care?
            <br>Listen now, thankfully 
            <br>Chagned is her tone;
            <br>No longer drooping,
            <br>Sits she alone.
            <br>No longer tearfully 
            <br>Clouded her sight;
            <br>From her eyes cheerfully 
            <br>Shineth love’s light.
            <br>See, see how gladsomely 
            <br>Bounds she along,
            <br>While from her lips merrily 
            <br>Ripples a song!
            <br>Upward, she lovingly 
            <br>Raises her eyes,
            <br>Gazing so gratefully 
            <br>Into the skies.
            <br>Angels that weepingly 
            <br>Prayed with her there,
            <br>Look on her smilingly,
            <br>Saved from despair.
            <br>Ah, we can happily 
            <br>Look on her now,
            <br>Joy reigns so peacefully 
            <br>On her lair brow.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Island of the Fay.</div>
         
         <div class="cit"><span class="quote">Nullus enim locus sine genio est.</span><div class="bibl">——<span class="person">Servius.</span></div>
         </div>
         
         <p>“La musique," says Marmontel, in those “Contes Moraux”<span class="anchor" id="a001"><a href="#n001"> Link </a></span> which, in all our translations, we have insisted 
            upon calling “Moral Tales” as if in mockery of their 
            spirit—“la musique est le seul des talens qui jouissent de 
            lui méme; tous les autres veutent des temoins." He here 
            confounds the pleasure derivable from sweet sounds with 
            the capacity for creating them. No more than any other 
            talent, is that for music susceptible of complete enjoyment, where there is no second party to appreciate its exercise. And it is only in common with other talents that 
            it produces effects which may be fully enjoyed in solitude. The idea which the raconteur has either failed 
            to entertain clearly, or has sacrificed in its expression to 
            his national love of point, is, doubtless, the very tenable 
            one that the higher order of music is the most thoroughly 
            estimated when we are exclusively alone. The proposition, in this form, will be admitted at once by those who 
            love the lyre for its own sake, and for its spiritual uses. 
            But there is one pleasure still within the reach of fallen 
            mortality—and perhaps only one—which owes even more 
            than does music to the accessory sentiment of seclusion. 
            I mean the happiness experienced in the contemplation of 
            natural scenery. In truth, the man who would behold aright the glory of God upon earth must in solitude behold 
            that glory. To me, at least, the presence—not of human 
            life only—but of life in any other form than that of the 
            green things which grow upon the soil and are voiceless 
            —is a stain upon the landscape—is at war with the genius of the scene. I love, indeed, to regard the dark valleys, and the grey rocks, and the waters that silently 
            smile, and the forests that sigh in uneasy slumbers, and 
            the proud watchful mountains that look down upon all— 
            I love to regard these as themselves but the colossal 
            members of one vast animate and sentient whole—a
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page189"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            whole whose form (that of the sphere) is the most perfect and most inclusive of all; whose path is among associate planets; whose meek handmaiden is the moon; 
            whose mediate sovereign is the sun; whose life is eternity; whose thought is that of a God; whose enjoyment is 
            knowledge; whose destinies are lost in immensity; 
            whose cognizance of ourselves is akin with our own cognizance of the animalculae which infest the brain—a being which we, in consequence, regard as purely inanimate and material, much in the same manner as these 
            animalculae must thus regard us.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our telescopes, and our mathematical investigations 
            assure us on every hand—notwithstanding the cant of 
            the more ignorant of the priesthood—that space, and 
            therefore that hulk, is an important consideration in the 
            eyes of the Almighty. The cycles in which the stars 
            move are those best adapted for the evolution, without 
            collision, of the greatest possible number of bodies. The 
            forms of those bodies are accurately such as, within a 
            given surface, to include the greatest possible amount of 
            matter;—while the surfaces themselves are so disposed 
            as to accommodate a denser population than could be accommodated on the same surfaces otherwise arranged. 
            Nor is it any argument against bulk being an object with
            God, that space itself is infinite; for there may be an 
            infinity of matter to fill it. And since we see clearly 
            that the endowment of matter with vitality is a principle 
            —indeed as far as our judgments extend, the leading 
            principle in the operations of Deity—it is scarcely logical to imagine it confined to the regions of the minute, 
            where we daily trace it, and not extending to those 
            of the august. As we find cycle within cycle without 
            end—yet all revolving around one far-distant centre
            which is the Godhead, may we not analogically suppose,
            in the same manner, life within life, the less within the 
            greater, and all within the Spirit Divine ? In short, we
            are madly erring, through self-esteem, in believing man,
            in either his temporal or future destinies, to be of more
            moment in the universe than that vast “clod of the valley” which he tills and contemns, and to which he denies a soul for no more profound reason than that he
            does not behold it in operation.<span class="anchor" id="a002"><a href="#n002"> Link </a></span></p>
         
         <p>These fancies, and such as these, have always given to 
            my meditations among the mountains, and the forests, by
            the rivers and the ocean, a tinge of what the every-day
            world would not fail to term the fantastic. My wanderings amid such scenes have been many, and far-searching,
            and often solitary; and the interest with which I have
            strayed through many a dim deep valley, or gazed into
            the reflected Heaven of many a bright lake, has been an
            interest greatly deepened by the thought that I have
            strayed and gazed alone. What flippant Frenchman was
            it who said, in allusion to the well-known work of Zimmerman, that, “la solitude est une belle chose; mais il
            faut quelqu 'un pour vous dire que la solitude est une belle
            chose?” The epigram cannot be gainsayed; but the necessity is a thing that does not exist.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was during one of my lonely journeyings, amid a far
            -distant region of mountain locked within mountain, and
            sad rivers and melancholy tarns writhing or sleeping
            within all—that I chanced upon a certain rivulet and
            island. I came upon them suddenly in the leafy June,
            and threw myself upon the turf, beneath the branches of
            an unknown odorous shrub, that I might doze as I con
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>templated the scene. I felt that thus only should I look
            upon it—such was the character of phantasm which it 
            wore.
         </p>
         
         <p>On all sides—save to the west, where the sun was
            about sinking—arose the verdant walls of the forest.
            The little river which turned sharply in its course, and
            was thus immediately lost to sight, seemed to have no
            exit from its prison, but to be absorbed by the deep green
            foliage of the trees to the east—while in the opposite
            quarter (so it appeared to me as I lay at length and
            glanced upward) there poured down noiselessly and continuously into the valley, a rich golden and crimson waterfall from the sunset fountains of the sky.
         </p>
         
         <p>About mid-wav in the short vista which my dreamy 
            vision took in, one small circular island, profusely ver
            -dured, reposed upon the bosom of the stream.
         </p>
         
         <p>So blended bank and shadow there,
            That each seemed pendulous in air—
         </p>
         
         <p>so mirror-like was the glassy water, that it was scarcely
            possible to say at what point upon the slope of the emerald turf its crystal dominion began.
         </p>
         
         <p>My position enabled me to include in a single view
            both the eastern and western extremities of the islet; and
            I observed a singularly-marked difference in their aspects.
            The latter was all one radiant harem of garden beauties.
            It glowed and blushed beneath the eye of the slant sunlight, and fairly laughed with flowers. The grass was
            short, springy, sweet-scented, and Asphodel-interspersed.
            The trees were lithe, mirthful, erect—bright, slender and
            graceful—of eastern figure and foliage, with bark smooth,
            -glossy, and parti-colored. There seemed a deep sense of
            life and joy about all; and although no airs blew from
            out the Heavens, yet every thing had motion through the
            gentle sweepings to and fro of innumerable butterflies,
            that might have been mistaken for tulips with wings.<span class="anchor" id="a003"><a href="#n003"> Link </a></span></p>
         
         <p>The other or eastern end of the isle was whelmed in
            the blackest shade. A sombre, yet beautiful and peaceful gloom here pervaded all things. The trees were
            dark in color and mournful in form and attitude—wreath
            -ing themselves into sad, solemn, and spectral shapes,
            that conveyed ideas of mortal sorrow and untimely death.
            The grass wore the deep tint of the cypress, and the
            heads of its blades hung droopingly, and, hither and thither among it, were many small unsightly hillocks, low,
            and narrow, and not very long, that had the aspect of
            graves, but were not; although over and all about them
            the rue and the rosemary clambered. The shade of the
            trees fell heavily upon the water, and seemed to bury
            itself therein, impregnating the depths of the element
            with darkness. I fancied that each shadow, as the sun
            descended lower and lower, separated itself sullenly from
            the trunk that gave it birth, and thus became absorbed
            by the stream; while other shadows issued momently
            from the trees, taking the place of their predecessors thus
            entombed.
         </p>
         
         <p>This idea, having once seized upon my fancy, greatly
            excited it, and I lost myself forthwith in reverie. “If 
            ever island were enchanted,”—said I to myself—“this is 
            it. This is the haunt of the few gentle Fays who remain
            from the wreck of the race. Are these green tombs
            theirs?—or do they yield up their sweet lives as mankind
            yield up their own? In dying, do they not rather waste
            away mournfully; rendering unto God little by little
            their existence, as these trees render up shadow after
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page190"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            shadow, exhausting their substances unto dissolution?
            What the wasting tree is to the water that imbibes its
            shade, growing thus blacker by what it preys upon, may
            not the life of the Fay be to the death which engulfs it?
         </p>
         
         <p>As I thus mused, with half-shut eyes, while the sun
            sank rapidly to rest, and eddying currents careered
            round and round the island, bearing upon their bosom
            large, dazzling, white flakes of the bark of the sycamore 
            —flakes which, in their multiform positions upon the
            water, a quick imagination might have converted into
            anything it pleased—while I thus mused, it appeared to
            me that the form of one of those very Fays about whom I
            had been pondering, made its way slowly into the darkness from out the light at the western end of the island.
            She stood erect in a singularly fragile canoe, and urged
            it with the mere phantom of an oar. While within the 
            influence of the lingering sunbeams, her attitude seemed
            indicative of joy—but sorrow deformed it as she passed
            within the shade. Slowly she glided along, and at
            length rounded the islet and re-entered the region of light. 
            “The revolution which has just been made by the Fay,” 
            continued I musingly—“is the cycle of the brief year of 
            her life. She has floated through her winter and through
            her summer. She is a year nearer unto Death: for I did
            not fail to see that as she came into the shade, her shadow fell from her, and was swallowed up in the dark 
            water, making its blackness more black.”
         </p>
         
         <p>And again the boat appeared, and the Fay; but about
            the attitude of the latter there was more of care and uncertainty, and less of elastic joy. She floated again from 
            out the light, and into the gloom (which deepened momently) and again her shadow fell from her into the
            ebony water, and became absorbed into its blackness. 
            And again and again she made the circuit of the island,
            (while the sun rushed down to his slumbers) and at
            each issuing into the light, there was more sorrow about
            her person, while it grew feebler, and far fainter, and 
            more indistinct; and at each passage into the gloom,
            there fell from her a darker shade, which became
            whelmed in a shadow more black. But at length, when
            the sun had utterly departed, the Fay, now the mere 
            ghost of her former self, went disconsolately with her
            boat into the region of the ebony flood—and that she issued
            thence at all I cannot say,—for darkness fell over all
            things, and I beheld her magical figure no more.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">Edgar A. Poe</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Myrrha</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Oh! with a delicate art, how quaintly taught,
            <br>Sweetly around thy lattice thou hast wrought,
            <br>In many a mazy twine,
            <br>The forest vine.
            <br>Its sweets requite thee, and as summer comes,
            <br>It yields thee precious odors and gay blooms,
            <br>And, folded in thy breast,
            <br>Its birds are blest.
            <br>Am I less worthy of thy care, this hour,
            <br>Than the frail blossom of thy summer bower—
            <br>Of humbler claim to share Thy smile, thy care?
            <br>Why hast thou taught my feelings then to twine 
            <br>Thus hopeful round thee like that summer vine,
            <br>If still denied like rest Upon thy breast?
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">W. Gilmore Simms</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of American Books. No IV.
            The Wigwam and the Cabin. By William Gilmore
            Simms.
         </p>
         
         <p>This is one of the most interesting numbers of the Library yet published—and decidedly the most American 
            of the American books. “The Wigwam and the Cabin” 
            is merely a general or generic title;—the volume is a 
            collection of tales most of which were written for the 
            Annuals, and thus have failed in circulating among the 
            masses of the people. We are truly glad to see them in a 
            compact form.
         </p>
         
         <p>In a recent number of our Journal we spoke of Mr. 
            Simms as “the best novelist which this country has,
            upon the whole, produced;” and this is our deliberate 
            opinion. We take into consideration, of course, as well
            the amount of what he has written, as the talent he has 
            displayed;—he is the Lopez de Vega of American writers of fiction. His merits lie among the major and his 
            defects among the minor morals of literature. His earlier works of length, such as “The Partisan,” were disfigured by many inaccuracies of style, and especially by 
            the prevalence of the merely repulsive, where the horrible was the object—but in invention, in vigor, in movement, in the power of exciting interest, and in the artistical management of his themes, he has surpassed, we 
            think, any of his countrymen:—that is to say, he has 
            surpassed any of them in the aggregate of these high 
            qualities. His best fictions, in our opinion, are “Martin 
            Faber” (one of his first tales, if not his very first published 
            one); “Beauchampe";“Richard Hurdis”;“Castle Dismal”;“Helen Halsey”; and “Murder will Out.” “Martin Faber” has been said to resemble “Miserrimus”— 
            and in fact we perceive that the individual minds which
            originated the two stories have much in them of similarity 
            —but as regards the narratives themselves, or even their
            tone, there is no resemblance whatever. “Martin Faber” 
            is the better work of the two. “Beauchampe” is intensely interesting; but the historical truth has somewhat 
            hampered and repressed the natural strength of the artist. “Richard Hurdis” is the perfection of rough vigor
            in conception and conduct—a very powerful book. “Castle Dismal” is one of the most original fictions ever
            penned and deserves all that order of commendation 
            which the critics lavished upon Walpole’s Castle of 
            Otranto. No man of imagination-can read this story
            without admitting instantly the genius of its author;—
             still the narrative has important defects. “Helen Halsey” is more “correct” (in the French sense of the word) 
            but less meritorious upon the whole. We believe it is a 
            favorite with its author; and the public have received it 
            with marked approbation. “Murder Will Out” is the 
            first and the most meritorious of the series now lying before us. We have no hesitation in calling it the best 
            ghost-story we ever read. It is full of the richest and 
            most vigorous imagination—is forcibly conceived—and
            detailed throughout with a degree of artistic skill which 
            has had no parallel among American story-tellers since 
            the epoch of Brockden Brown.
         </p>
         
         <p>The other tales of the volume are all excellent in their 
            various ways. Their titles are “The Two Camps, a Legend of the Old North State”; “The Last Wager, or
            the Gamester of the Mississippi";“The Arm-Chair of
            Tustenugge, a Tradition of the Catawba”;"The Snake
            of the Cabin";“Oakatibbe, or the Choctaw Sampson";
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page191"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            and "Jocassee, a Cherokee Legend.” The author says
            of them, in an advertisement—“The material employed 
            will be found to illustrate, in large degree, the border,
            history of the South. I can speak with confidence of the
            general truthfulness of its treatment. The life of the 
            planter, the squatter, the Indian and the negro—the bold
            and hardy pioneer and the vigorous yeomen—these are 
            the subjects. In their delineation I have mostly drawn
            from living portraits, and, in frequent instances, from
            actual scenes and circumstances within the memories of 
            men.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Simms has exercised a very remarkable influence
            upon the literature of his country—more especially upon
            that of its Southern regions—nor do we regard this influence as in any degree the less important because a Mr.
            William A. Jones "regards slightingly the mass of his
            romantic and poetical efforts.” We shall speak again
            of “The Cabin and The Wigwam,” and in the meantime
            we quote a passage from “Murder Will Out.” Our 
            readers must bear in mind, however, the absolute impossibility of conveying, by extract, any just conception of a 
            story whose main element is its skilful adaptation of 
            parts:
         </p>
         
         <p>“It’s very strange!" soliloquized the youth, as he wandered
            along the edges of the dense bay or swamp-bottom, which we 
            have passingly referred to,—“it’s very strange what troubles me
            so! I feel almost frightened, and yet I know I’m not to be frightened easily, and I don’t see anything in the woods to frighten me.
            It’s strange the major didn’t come along this road! Maybe he
            took another higher up that leads by a different settlement. I
            wish I had asked the man at the house if there’s such another 
            road. I reckon there must be, however, for where could the major have gone?”
         </p>
         
         <p>The unphilosophical mind of James Grayling did not, in his 
            farther meditations, carry him much beyond this starting point; 
            and with its continual recurrence in soliloquy, he proceeded to
            traverse the margin of the bay, until he came to its junction with,
            and termination at, the high-road. The youth turned into this,
            and, involuntarily departing from it a moment after, soon found
            himself on the opposite side of the bay thicket. He wandered on
            and on, as he himself described it, without any power to restrain
            himself. He knew not how far lie went; but instead of maintaining his watch for two hours only, he was gone more than four;
            and, at length, a sense of weariness which overpowered him all
            of a sudden, caused him to seat himself at the loot of a tree, and
            snatch a few moments of rest. He denied that he slept in this
            time. He insisted to the last moment of his life that sleep never
            visited his eyelids that night,—that he was conscious of fatigue
            and exhaustion, but not drowsiness—and that this fatigue was so
            numbing as to be painful, and effectually kept him from any sleep.
            While he sat thus beneath the tree, with a body weak and nerveless, but a mind excited, he knew not how or why, to the most 
            acute degree of expectation and attention, he heard his name
            called by the well-known voice of his friend, Major Spencer.
            The voice called him three times,—“James Grayling!—James! 
            —James Grayling!" before he could muster strength enough to
            answer. It was not courage he wanted,—of that he was positive,
            for he felt sure, as he said, that something had gone wrong, and
            he was never more ready to fight in his life than at that moment
            could he have commanded the physical capacity; but his throat
            seemed dry to suffocation,—his lips effectually sealed up as if
            with wax, and when he did answer, the sounds seemed as fine
            and soft as whisper of some child just born.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Oh! major, is it you?’’</p>
         
         <p>Such he thinks, were the very words he made use of in reply;
            and the answer that be received was instantaneous, though the
            voice came from some little distance in the bay, and his own
            voice did not hear. He only knows what he meant to say.
            The answer was to this effect.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is, James!—It is your own friend, Lionel Spencer, that
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>speaks to you; do not be alarmed when you see me! I have
            been shockingly murdered!’’
         </p>
         
         <p>James asserts that he tried to tell him that he would not be 
            frightened, but his own voice was still a whisper, which he himself could scarcely hear. A moment after he had spoken, he
            heard something like a sudden breeze that rustled through the
            bay bushes at his feet, and his eyes were closed without his effort,
            and indeed in spite of himself. When he opened them, he saw 
            Major Spencer standing at the edge of the bay, about twenty
            steps from him. Though he stood in the shade of a thicket, and 
            there was no light in the heavens save that of the stars, he was
            yet enabled to distinguish perfectly, and with great ease, every 
            lineament of his friend’s face.
         </p>
         
         <p>He looked very pale, and his garments were covered with
            blood; and James said that he strove very much to rise from the
            place were he sat and approach him;—"for in truth,” said the
            lad, “so far from feeling any fear, I felt nothing but fury in my
            heart; but I could not move a limb. My feet were fastened to
            the ground; my hands to my sides; and I could only bend forward and gasp. I felt as if I should have died with vexation that
            I could not rise; but a power which I could not resist, made
            me motionless and almost speechless. I could only say, ‘ Murdered!’—and that one word I believe I must have repeated a 
            dozen times.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Yes, murdered!—murdered by the Scotchman who slept
            with us at your fire the night before last. James, I look to you
            to have the murderer brought to justice! James!—do you
            hear me, James?"
         </p>
         
         <p>“These,” said James, “I think were the very words, or near
            about the very words, that I heard; and I tried to ask the major
            to tell me how it was, and how I could do what he required; but I
            didn’t hear myself speak, though it would appear that he did, for
            almost immediately after I had tried to speak what I wished to
            say, he answered me just as if I had said it. He told me that
            the Scotchman had waylaid, killed, and hidden him in that very
            bay; that his murderer had gone to Charleston; and that if I
            made haste to town, I would find him in the Falmouth packet,
            which was then lying in the harbour and ready to sail for England. He farther said that everything depended upon my making
            haste,—that I mast reach town by to-morrow night if I wanted to
            be in season, and go right on board the vessel and charge the
            criminal with the deed. ‘Do not be afraid,’ said he, when he
            had finished; ’be afraid of nothing, James, for God will help and
            strengthen you to the end.’ When I heard all I burst into a flood
            of tears, and then I fell strong. I felt that I could talk, or fight,
            or do almost anything; and I jumped up to my feet, and was just
            about to run down to where the major stood, but with the first 
            step which I made forward, he was gone. I stopped and looked
            all around me, but I could see nothing; and the bay was just as 
            black as midnight. But I went down to it and tried to press in 
            where I thought the major had been standing; but I couldn’t get
            far, the brush and bay bushes were so close and thick. I was
            now bold and strong enough, and I called out, loud enough to be
            heard half a mile. I didn’t exactly know what I called for, or
            what I wanted to learn, or I have forgotten. But I heard nothing
            more.
         </p>
         
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Heading, No. XXIV.
            Bubbles from the Brunnen of Nassau. By An Old
            Man.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Old Man is Sir Francis Head. His bubbles have a
            sparkle about them which has insured and must insure
            their popularity. Few books have met with more cordial reception. The author’s preface happily conveys the
            manner of the book:
         </p>
         
         <p>The writer of this trifling Volume was suddenly sentenced, in
            the cold evening of his life, to drink the mineral waters of one of
            the bubbling springs, or brunnen, of Nassau. In his own opinion,
            his constitution was not worth so troublesome a repair; but being
            outvoted, he bowed and departed.
         </p>
         
         <p>On reaching die point of his destination, he found not only water-bibbing—bathing—and ambulation to be the order of the day,
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page192"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            but it was moreover insisted upon, that the mind was to be relaxed
            inversely as the body was to be strengthened. Daring this severe
            regimen, he was driven to amuse himself in his old age by blowing as he tottled about, a few literary Bubbles. His hasty sketches
            of whatever chanced for the moment to please either his eye, or
            his mind, were only made—because he had nothing else in the world
            to do; and he now offers them to that vast and highly respectable
            class of people who read from exactly the self-same motive.
         </p>
         
         <p>The critic must, of course, declare this production to be vain
            empty—light—hollow—superficial .... but it is the nature of
            Bubbles to be so.
         </p>
         
         <p>
            <div class="cit"><span class="quote">The earth has bubbles, as the water has,
                  And these are of them.
                  Macbeth, Act I. Scene 3.</span></div>
         </p>
         
         <p>Lady Mary; or Not of the World. By the Rev. Chas.
            B. Tayler, M. A., Author of “The Records of a Good
            Man's Life," etc. New-York: Stanford if Swords,
            139 Broadway.
         </p>
         
         <p>Since our last number, in which we announced the issue of this beautiful little work, we have read it through
            with deep interest. It is admirably written and well
            adapted to its end—the rebuke of vice and folly among the
            more cultivated classes of society. We have seldom, if
            ever, seen a more appropriate gift-book, especially for the 
            young.
         </p>
         
         <p>Sermons on Certain of the Less Prominent Facts and
            References in Sacred Story. By Henry Melvill, D. 
            D., Principal of the East India College, and Chaplain
            to the Tower of London. Second Series. New-York:
            Stanford &amp; Swords.
         </p>
         
         <p>These are very peculiar, and for this reason, as well as
            for others, very interesting discourses. We give the titles
            of the several sermons, as the best way of conveying, in 
            brief, the character of the book:—“The Young Man in
            the Linen Cloth;" “The Fire on the Shore;" “The Finding the Guest-Chamber “The Spectre’s Sermon, a Truism;" “Various Opinions (about Christ);” “The Misrepresentations of Eve;” “Seeking after Finding;" “The 
            Bird’s Nest "Angels our Guardians in Trifles	“The
            Appearance of Failure;" “Simon, the Cyrenian;" “The
            Power of the Eye;" “Pilate’s Wife;"and“The Examination of Cain.” These sermons are brief. The volume
            consists of only 130 pages octavo.
         </p>
         
         <p>A Latin Grammar, Comprising all the Rules and Observations necessary to an Accurate Knowledge of the Latin 
            Classics. By James Ross, LL. D. WITH Latin Idioms 
            and a New Prosody, and other Important Additions and 
            Emendations, by N. C. Brooks, A. M., Professor of the 
            Latin and Greek Languages, and Principal of the Latin
            High School, Baltimore. Philadelphia: Thos. Cowpperthwait &amp; Co.
         </p>
         
         <p>This is a judicious attempt on the part of Mr. Brooks
            (no less distinguished as an imaginative and graceful poet than by his classical acquirements) to restore the Latin Grammar of Dr. Ross to the position it once held in
            our Academies and Colleges. There can be no doubt
            that the book, in its original form, had many demerits,
            but we believe that these were far more than counterbalanced by merits not elsewhere to be found.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Brooks, in his edition, has omitted, as superfluous,
            the author's Remarks on English Articles, Nouns and
            Pronouns. In Orthography he has given the division of
            the letters, with more particular rules for their pronunciation. In Etymology he has made many new arrangements—placing, for example, under the head of “Gender,” its rules and exceptions:—these in the original
            work were interspersed at random, throughout. In 
            Verbs, too, there are several important alterations and ad
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>ditions—deleo is conjugated in place of doceo; the latter, 
            not being accurately regular. Mr. Brooks gives, also,
            (what is essential) an explanatian of the nature of the
            Gerund and Supine. In Syntax the rules are much simplified and abridged, and some Remarks on Latin Idioms.
            Syntatical Arrangement and Analysis are, with great
            judgment, introduced. The Prosody of Ross is entirely
            remodelled, and for this portion of his labor, Mr. Brooks
            is entitled to very especial credit. His work, upon the 
            whole, is one of high value, and we are happy to hear of
            its general introduction into schools.
         </p>
         
         <p>We must do Mr. Brooks the justice of appending to this
            very imperfect notice, the opinion of a scholar whose
            good word is of weight; the letter annexed will speak
            for itself:
         </p>
         
         <p>Baltimore, September 13, 1845.</p> 
         
         <p>Dear Sir—Having carefully examined Ross’ Latin Grammar,
            as revised and amended by you, I find the book every way equal, if
            not superior to any that art used in our schools. After a thorough 
            perusal of your “Latin Lessons,” I take pleasure in acknowledging that never, even in my “fatherland,” have I read a book better calculated to facilitate the study of the Latin language. It
            should be in the hands of every beginner. Moreover, the many
            sentences it contains embracing facts in the history of my adopted
            country, must make it interesting not only to the student, but dear
            to every patriotic heart. Yours respectfully,
         </p>
         
         <p>A. Frietog, LL. D.</p>
         
         <p>[Of the University ef Gottingen.]</p>
         
         <p>Of the “Latin Lessons” here alluded to, we spoke in a
            previous number. They are admirably adapted to their 
            purpose. Messrs. Thomas Cowperthwait &amp; Co., of Philadelphia, are the publishers.
         </p>
         
         <p>Blackwood's Magazine for September, has been re-published by Leonard Scott 4c Co. It has several interesting
            articles—among which are “English Landscape”; “The 
            Historical Romance”; “A Few Words for Bettina”; and 
            “Margaret of Valois.” “North’s Specimens of the British Critics” is continued in a paper replete with coarse
            malignity, and the customary Wilsonic rant.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Book of Useful Knowledge. A Cyclopædia of Several Thousand Practical Receipts etc. in the Arts, Manufactures and Trades, including Medicine, Pharmacy 
            and Domestic Economy, etc. etc. By Arnold James Cooley, Illustrated with Numerous Engravings. New York:
            D. Appleton &amp; Co.
         </p>
         
         <p>No IV of this invaluable work, is just issued. It has
            now proceeded as far as the word Lead. The numbers
            are sold at 25 cts. each.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Treasury of History. New York: Daniel Adee.
            This is Maunder’s noted work. To be completed in 12
            numbers. No IX is issued.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Young Man’s Mentor on his Entrance into Life; 
            "With Rules for his general Conduct after leaving School, 
            etc. etc. By A Friend to American Youth, New York:
            William H. Graham.
         </p>
         
         <p>Simms Monthly Magazine for September is, as usual,
            excellent. It contains, among other able papers, the conclusion of “The Epochs and Events of American History
            as suited to the Purposes of Art in Fiction"—No. 3 of “A 
            Foreigner’s First Glimpses of Georgia"—No. 7 of "The 
            Marion Family," and some remarkably tine poems. We
            allude especially to “The Maiden’s First Dream of Love" 
            and “Elodie, a Ballad." These are anonymous, and we
            attribute them to the same hand. We quote the first
            stanza of the one first named.
         </p>
         
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page193"></div>
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Soft, O! how softly sleeping,
            <br>Shadowed by beamy she lies,
            <br>Dreams, as of rapture, creeping,
            <br>Smile by smile, over her eyes;
            <br>Lips, O! how sweetly parting,
            <br>As if the delight between,
            <br>With its own warm pulses starting,
            <br>Strove to go forth and be seen,
         </div>
         
         <p>Whoever has written these two poems, will undoubtedly be distinguished.</p>
         
         <p>Godey's Magazine for October, has a good engraving
            of “The Battle of Concord Bridge” from a painting by
            Frankenstein—also a clean-looking plate by Ellis, illustrating the Scriptural words, “Behold the place where
            they laid him.” The customary fashion-plate is very
            well done. The contributions of “The Lady’s Book”
            have been steadily rising in merit for the last year, and are
            now, generally, better than those of any Magazine of its
            class. They seem to be carefully written—less dependence being placed upon the mere name of the author, and
            more upon the intrinsic merit of his composition. The 
            best article in the present number is “The Duchess of
            Bavaria,” a story of the highest romantic interest, beautifully told by Mrs. E. F. Ellet. Mrs. Hale, Miss Leslie,
            Mrs Hentz, Mrs. Adams, Miss Rand, Mrs. Lee, Tuckerman, Frost, Sullivan and others have, also, very excellent
            contributions. Mr. Godey, we learn, is making unusual
            exertions for next year’s campaign. His Magazine has
            about it a “keeping,” a consistency, which is one of the
            surest indications of long and prosperous life. We miss
            one or two of his old contributors. What has become of
            Mrs. Osgood? Her papers were wont to be the charm of
            the “Book.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Graham's Magazine for October, has a portrait and biography of Robert Morris, the gentlemanly editor of the
            Philadelphia “Inquirer.” This is the best likeness of the 
            series. There is also a spirited engraving of a Maunitarri Warrior. Grund contributes an interesting paper on 
            “The Continental Historians”; Alfred B Street has “A 
            Day’s Fishing in the Kalikoon”—very picturesque; and
            Mrs. Osgood furnishes “Leonora L’Estrange,” one of her
            invariably graceful compositions. We purloin from it an
            epigrammatic song:
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>I have been true to all I loved—
            <br>To Honor, Love and Truth;
            <br>These were the idols of my soul
            <br>In my believing youth—
            <br>And these I worship londly still,
            <br>With vows all pure and free—
            <br>Alas I that truth to them involves
            <br>Unfaithfulness to thee.
         </div>
         
         <p>The Aristidean for September looks and speaks remarkably well. Its papers are all pointed and forcible.
            “Travels in Texas” is one of the most interesting sketches we have seen in a year, and puts us in mind of the vigorous add imaginative “Jack Long" and the “San Saba Hills.” There is a scorching review of Hirst’s Poems—a good thing for everybody but Mr. Hirst;—this is
            a very laughable article. “Tourists in America’ is also
            exceedingly pungent:—both these papers, we presume,
            are from the pen editorial. We notice, also, as especially meritorious, “Popular Governments and Institutions”; and “ Leaves from aLog-Book." The Notices 
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>of New Books are unusually full and particularly independent. The poetry of the number is, nevertheless, its
            chief feature. “Sir Albert De Veniter” is capital.
         </p>
         
         <p>Here is an excellent epigram:</p>
         
         <div class="cit"><span class="quote">
               <div class="lg"><br>ALAS!
                  <br>To work like a Turk—what a life is an editor’s.!
                  <br>News-clipping, ink-dipping,
                  <br>Pasting and wasting,
                  <br>No rest ever tasting,
                  <br>And pestered to death with his creditors.
                  <br>Go loll on the soil, or dig cellars like Dan Nichols;
                  <br>Plough a field, trowel wield,
                  <br>Worry and flurry,
                  <br>And live in a hurry,
                  <br>But wear not an editor’s manacles.
               </div></span></div>
         
         <p>Many of the other poetical pieces interspersed throughout the number, are of a high order of excellence. “The
            Aristidean” is, upon the whole, an admirable journal,
            and will yet do good service.
         </p>
         
         <p>A Popular Treatise, on the Science of Astrology, Embracing all that is Requisite for erecting a Horoscope, and
            resolving a Horary Question. New York: T.J.Coowen.
         </p>
         
         <p>This treatise is prepared by a gentleman who has given
            many year’s attention to the subject. It is not to be
            classed with the Oracula and Napoleon-Books of fate, but
            is a straight-forward analysis and exposition of the Science of Astrology. The name of Lord Bacon, the last
            great avowed adherent of the belief, casts a certain interest on the subject even at this distant day.
         </p>
         
         <p>As we were going to press we received from Messrs. 
            Lea &amp; Blanchard, of Philadelphia, the first volume of the 
            Historical Sketch of the Second War between the United 
            States of America and Great Britain, declared by Act of
            Congress, the I8th of June 1812, and Concluded by
            Peace, the 15th of February 1815. By Charles J. Ingersoll. In 3 volumes.
         </p>
         
         <p>Vol. I embraces the events of 1812—13.</p>
         
         <p>Received, also, too late for notice, Herbert’s admiratranslation—Winchester’s edition—of the Wandering 
            Jew.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Fairyland.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Dim vales—and shadowy floods—
            <br>And cloudy-looking woods,
            <br>Whose forms we can’t discover 
            <br>For the tears that drip all over.
            <br>Huge moons there wax and wane—
            <br>Again—again—again—
            <br>Every moment of the night—
            <br>Forever changing places—
            <br>And they put out the star-light
            <br>With the breath from their pale faces.
            <br>About twelve by the moon-dial
            <br>One, more filmy than the rest 
            <br>(A kind which, upon trial,
            <br>They have found to be the best)
            <br>Comes down—still down—and down
            <br>With its centre on the crown 
            <br>Of a mountain’s eminence,
            <br>While its wide circumference
            <br>In easy drapery falls
            <br>Over hamlets, over halls,
            <br>Wherever they may be—
            <br>O’er the strange woods—o’er the sea—
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page194"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            <br>Over spirits on the wing—
            <br>Over every drowsy thing—
            <br>And buries them up quite 
            <br>In a labyrinth of light—
            <br>And then, how deep! O, deep!
            <br>Is the passion of their sleep !
            <br>In the morning they arise,
            <br>And their moony covering 
            <br>Is soaring in the skies,
            <br>With the tempests as they toss,
            <br>Like——almost any thing—
            <br>Or a yellow Albatross.
            <br>They use that moon no more
            <br>For the same end as before—
            <br>Videlicet a tent—
            <br>Which I think extravagant:
            <br>Its atomics, however,
            <br>Into a shower dissever,
            <br>Of which those butterflies,
            <br>Of Earth, who seek the skies,
            <br>And so come down again 
            <br>(Never-contented things!)
            <br>Have brought a specimen
            <br>Upon their quivering wings.
         </div>
      </div>	
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Fine Arts.</div>
         
         <p>After many pompous announcements, and laudatory paragraphs, the collection of Paintings at Bordentown came
            under the scattering fiat of Mr. Birch, the auctioneer of
            Philadelphia; and as the distance was too great to admit our reaching the scene of action in sufficient time
            on the 17th, the day of sale, to inspect the paintings previous to their being sold, we left New-York by the Philadelphia Railroad the day before, intending to devote every moment after our arrival until nightfall, to the admiration of the widely praised rarities of Art; but the sequel proved, that in this, as in other matters of greater
            moment, our intentions may be our own, but their fulfilment is beyond us, and that
         </p>
         
         <p>There is a Divinity doth shape our ends, rough hew them as we 
            will;
            for ere we had completed the second mile on the banks
            of the canal beyond Princeton, by the gross, inexcusable
            neglect of the engineer the train came to a stoppage, and
            an express was despatched to the nearest station to bring 
            up an auxiliary engine. During this detention, an empty
            tow boat came down the canal, when, flattering themselves that the tortoise might beat the hare while he
            slept, several of the railroad passengers, whose destiny
            was not beyond the next station, hailed and embarked on
            board the boat. It is true they proceeded on their journey, but those only who have marked the weary pace of 
            a toil-worn horse on a towing path, can judge how slowly. The day was beautiful—the scenery of the varying 
            landscape delightful—the air sweet and refreshing; but
            time passed, and alas for poor frail humanity! it must be
            fed; some of the passengers leaving home at an early
            hour, had made but a sorry breakfast—and with a vertical sun bearing strong upon them, Hunger became quite
            irresistible. On hoard there was nought save water— 
            therefore to alleviate their sufferings, one of the boatmen
            was landed, with instructions to obtain anything in the
            shape of refreshments. After some delay he returned 
            th a basket of green apples, and therewith a loaf of
            new bread, freely and kindly given by one of the hospitable Jersey farmers, whose house and grounds skirted
            the canal. Our passengers quelled the rapacity-of their 
            stomachs—affording a pretty illustration of our constitu
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>tional declaration that all men are equal.
         </p>
         
         <p>The frail and humble bark was honored with carrying
            representatives of the Senate, the Bar, and the Mart, and
            ey, forced into a momentary forgetfulness of the worldly dignities with which adventitious circumstance had
            endowed them, were content with
         </p>
         
         <p>Wholesome thirst and appetite more grateful,
            to partake of a primitive, temperate lunch of bread, fruit,
            and water, on board of a coal barge. This little incident was scarcely past, when the spires of Trenton
            churches broke on our view, and in a very short period
            the locomotive came up with its long and burthensome
            train of carriages. On reaching Bordentown, we hastened to the object of our journey. The day was fast
            waning—the rays of the setting sun contrasting finely
            with the coming shades of evening, in the beautiful dale
            in which the house is situated, afforded some rich bits
            for the sketch-book: and we ourselves involuntarily fell
            under the influence of the moment and the place, for it
            was with a feeling of deep sympathy we regarded the
            willows and the blighted tree which, standing at the entance from the road, are typical of the desolation and
            fallen fortunes of the family whose meteor-like career
            ce lit up and electrified Europe. Shaking off these
            reflections on the past, we entered the mansion and were
            much gratified by the inspection of the statuary and family paintings—mementos of their temporary greatness—
            now become heirlooms to a scion to whom they are treasures sacred and beyond price, and of which no time or
            circumstance ought to deprive him, unless influenced by
            the passion which actuated his relative, the late Cardinal, when, refusing the princely ofl'er which was made 
            for his extensive collection of pictures, he exclaimed, “Je 
            suis Francais; ma galerie appartient à la France; elle est
            destinee à mon diocese, si j’ai le bonheurd’y rentrer”—he 
            devotes them to enrich one of the national museums of
            France. We particularly allude to an original painting
            by David, representing Napoleon on his charger ascending the Alps. This picture, which is considered a chef
            d’ceuvre, has been repeatedly engraved, and is too well 
            known to need eulogium, hangs in the drawing-room on
            the left, opposite which is a full length by the same artist, of Joseph in his state robes as King of Naples; and
            over the mantel-piece, a full length of Napoleon as Emperor. The whole of these portraits are faithful resemblances, painted with much care; the coloring being sedate, the expression true, and the details elaborated with
            a degree of perfection not often seen. It is recorded in 
            the life of this painter, that Napoleon’s admiration of 
            his talents was so great that on entering his paintingroom the Conqueror of Austerlitz advanced two steps, and
            taking off his hat, exclaimed, “Sir, I salute you.” On
            a side table at the entrance of the same room, stands a 
            bust by Canova, of Charles, Prince of Canino; and opposite thereto a bust of Zencid, daughter of Joseph, by
            Bartolini. These were the parents of the present prince.
            In the adjoining room was a bust of Marie Louise, and
            in the dining-room the following busts, all by Canova:
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Madame, Mére de Napoleon.
            <br>Pauline, Sister of Napoleon.
            <br>Eliza, 	“
            <br>Charles. Pere de Napoleon.
            <br>Lucien,
            <br>Jerome.
         </div>
         
         <p>We know of no terms sufficiently warm to speak our 
            admiration of these gems of art, for they possess a minute delicacy of expression, a softness of contour, and a 
            truthfulness of the party represented, that we never re
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page195"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            collect to have seen equalled, and which impels us to
            acknowledge that the artist capable of executing such
            work, did not depend for success on the caprice or pride
            of his employers, but by his taste and genius was confident of immortality. In the catalogue of the Statuary
            for sale there were several busts by Bosig, but in which
            we looked in vain for the hand of the great master. Lot
            78, called Pauline, by Canova, was much chipped and 
            discolored, and smaller in dimensions than the bust spoken
            of in the dining-room. The other matters we shall speak
            of hereafter.
         </p>
         
         <p>The collection of Paintings for sale did not realize
            our expectations; for, from the opportunities possessed
            by the late proprietor, and of which it is known he availed himself, we expectted to have found much more 
            of originality and talent than were there, for if an exception is taken to some twenty pictures, the collection was
            far below mediocrity—not one cabinet painting of even
            ordinary pretensions being offered for sale; and this in
            face of the fact that one picture, fourteen inches by sixteen, on panel, by Correggio, representing Christ in the
            Garden of Olives, was, when Joseph Bonaparte and 
            Jourdain were routed at Vittoria, captured with his baggage, his crown, and all the paraphernalia of his ephemeral monarchy, by Wellington, in whose possession the
            gem now is, and which is estimated at the value of 3000
            guineas. The remaining portion of the catalogue consisted of bad copies of very doubtful originals, in a direful state
            of dilapidation from neglect, damp, and repeated cleaning 
            and restoration.
         </p>
         
         <p>As it is to be expected that many pictures will hereafter be in the market dignified with the reputation of 
            coming from the Bonaparte collection, we give herewith
            a list of the greater part of the collection, with the names
            of the purchasers, and the prices given, which we consider to have been extremely liberal: and we do not hesitate to assert that in London or Paris, the gross amount
            of the sale—near $20,000—would not have been exceeded.
            We admit that a few pictures might have brought higher
            prices: but then, on the remainder, comprising the doubtful and the injured, the prices would have been considerably less, bringing the aggregate to about the same 
            amount.
         </p>
         
         <p>While on the subject of painting, we cannot refrain
            from alluding to the short-sighted policy of the Legislature in levying a duty of twenty per cent, on foreign
            paintings, as being inimical to the best interests of art,
            and preventing, in the infancy of painting in this country, the introduction of a picture of known merit, to aid
            the studies of our young artists.
         </p>
         
         <p>The influence of the pencil has always been great, and
            in perfect accordance with the advance of general intelligence; for the sentiments which painting is capable of 
            inspiring, are truly wonderful. Nor is it possible to overfate the merit of one who has the power of speaking to
            all hearts through his silent but universal language;therefore it was without surprise we saw assembled at
            the sale, amateurs and collectors from all parts of the
            Union. Amongst the gentlemen whose penchant for the 
            Fine Arts is well known, we noticed Col. Hunter (whose 
            fine collection cannot be sufficiently praised), and Mr.
            Grattan, H. B. M. Consul at Boston, when the latter, by
            his able criticisms fully substantiated the report of his 
            fine taste and judgment. It was to be expected that Mr.
            Birch, the auctioneer, would have favored the company
            with some remarks respecting the pictures; but with a 
            propriety highly creditable, he refrained therefrom, leav
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>ing the genuineness of the collection, and its being without exchange or addition, to be inferred.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">6. De Marne. Landscape—Arrival of a Diligence at the 
            <br>gates of the City. This was a pleasing subject, but its 
            <br>authenticity strongly questionable; the figures were wretch-
            <br>edly done—Mr. Robb,	$190
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">8. S. Denys. Storm at Night—Barn on Fire.—The cattle 
            <br>exceedingly well drawn, and the whole of the composi-
            <br>tion spirited—Mr. Oldfield,	105
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">12 &amp; 13. Vernet. The Falls of Tivoli, taken from two points
            <br>of view.—Two pleasing pictures of the school of Vernet, 
            <br>but possessing nothing to warrant the price given—Mr.
            <br>Robb,	220
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">11. Rubens. Two Lions and a Fawn—canvass 7 ft. 8—4
            <br>ft. 7.—This picture painted with an infinite degree of merit 
            <br>—and from the price at which it was withdrawn highly
            <br>prized by the owner—is one of those specimens of talent
            <br>which at times produce so much discussion amongst con-
            <br>noisseurs. In this collection it is attributed to Rubens. In
            <br>the Fisch collection sold in the early part of this year,
            <br>there was a picture 5 ft. 6x4 ft. 4 numbered 224 in the second
            <br>part of their Catalogue Raisonneé, termed Lions poursuitants
            <br>un Chevreuil, and the description of which, might without 
            <br>alteration stand for the present painting; indeed so great is
            <br>the similarity of design, grouping of the animals and gen-
            <br>eral composition, that nothing but the difference of size
            <br>would decide that it was not one and the same picture— 
            <br>bought in,	300
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">17. Natoire. The Toilette of Venus—canvass 5 feet 6X6
            <br>feet 5.—The coloring of this picture is mellow and of a 
            <br>pleasing tone; the position of the figures natural, and the 
            <br>head of Venus charmingly executed—Mr. Robb,	325
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">20. Jos. Vernet. A Marine Piece—canvass 8 feet 4x5 feet. 
            <br>—This picture and lot 21 is stated by the catalogue to have
            <br>been engraved—a distinction they richly deserve, being 
            <br>fine compositions of great merit—No. 20 having several
            <br>figures on the foreground, and a ship with sails loose, in
            <br>the centre. The undoubted genuineness and purity of this
            <br> picture ought to have created greater competition—Mr.
            <br> Robb,	950
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">21. J. Vernet. Marine Piece, 10 feetx5 feet—Storm clear-
            <br>ing off— Ship on the Rocks—the inhabitants of the coast 
            <br>rescuing the Passengers.—We know not which to admire
            <br>most in this painting, the boldness of the design, or the
            <br>skillfulness of its execution. The look of nature which
            <br>appears upon the still agitated waters, the position of the
            <br>vessel, the brightening sky dispelling the horrors of the
            <br>storm, all combine to render it a masterpiece—Mr. Watts, 1,000
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">22. Dutch School. View of a Country Palace.—This was a
            <br>delightful composition—the figures small, and designed 
            <br>with a surprising exactness—the clouds transparent, and
            <br>the sky beautifully serene—although without a name in
            <br>the catalogue, was extremely cheap at the selling price—
            <br>Mr. Mawson,	45
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">26. S. Denys. Rich Landscape—canvass 7 feet 6X5 feet 4.—
            <br>This work is distinguished by a warm coloring and an
            <br>agreeable choice of situation; the cattle in the foreground
            <br>are finished with the usual accuracy of this artist—Mr.
            <br>Robb,	725
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">27. S. Denys View of the Bay of Naples—canvass 7 feet
            <br>3—5 feet 2—a companion to the last picture, but of finer 
            <br>quality—the trees being most delicately handle, every leaf 
            <br>touched distinctly; in truth, in every part has the look of 
            <br>nature—Mr. Robb,	1,000
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">30. F. Franch. A Dutch Fair.—Numerous figures, well 
            <br>drawn and nicely painted—Unsold.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">53. Bassano. The Entrance into the Ark.—The animals in 
            <br>pairs, passing the foreground. The catalogue stated the 
            <br>style of the composition to be solemn and grand. We sup-
            <br>pose it was, for it found a purchaser—Mr.	Marshall,	225
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">60. A. Carracci. Christ and his Disciples at Sea in a Boat—
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page196"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            <br>the Saviour sleeping.—Boldly painted, in the artist’s best
            <br>style—canvass 5 feetx2 feet 3—Mr. Cuthbert,	125
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">65 &amp; 66. A Pair of Marine Views, said to be by Vernet.—
            <br>The purchaser of these pictures is reputed a lair judge of
            <br>paintings, but from the evident restorations we should have
            <br>declined the purchase at a fourth of the price given for the 
            <br>pair—Mr. Watts,	320
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">STATUARY.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">71.	Splendid Medici Vase of Porphyry, 3 feet 1 in height—
            <br>Mr. Robb,	400
            <br>72.	The Companion. Damaged—	100
            <br>73. Bronze Casting from Pompeii—Mr. Paterson,	135
            <br>74.	“	“	“	“	“ Stevens,	135
            <br>The above were magnificent specimens of art.
            <br>75.	A Splendid Piece of Sculpture, by Barlolini—Diana and
            <br>Hound—Mr. La Coste,	380
            <br>76. Female Figure in Roman Dress—Mr. Devereux,	80
            <br>77. Ceres to Match, both by Bosig—Mr. Dana,	102
            <br>78.	Bust—Pauline—by Canova—Mr. Flauden,	260
            <br>76. “	Eliza—Mr. Stevens,	50
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">PAINTINGS.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">93. Buchern. Landscape—cattle and figures—Mr. Robb,	150
            <br>95. Herodias receiving the Head of John the Baptist.—Bold-
            <br>ly painted, and well colored—Robb,	400
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">101. Rubens and Sneyders. This was held as the crack pic-
            <br>ture of the collection, and no doubt merited the distinc-
            <br>tion, for all the peculiarities of beauty and imperfection of
            <br>the great master were visible in the group of children oc-
            <br>cupying the centre. The fruit and flowers surrounding 
            <br>a wreath above them, were stated to be by Sneyders. This 
            <br>we think an error, believing the associate master to be
            <br>Seghers; and we are the more inclined to this opinion, see-
            <br>ing that Pilkington mentions a very splendid performance
            <br>then in the Jesuits’ Church at Antwerp—subject by Dan-
            <br>iel Seghers—a Garland of Flowers and Fruits, in which 
            <br>seemed to be collected all that was beautiful in nature of 
            <br>these objects, and in the centre the picture of the Virgin
            <br>and Child, painted by Rubens. However, as it was the 
            <br>practice of Rubens to employ his pupils of talent in the 
            <br>execution of his great designs, and these excellent artists
            <br>so thoroughly understood the nature of tints, and were so 
            <br>expert in their handling, that every picture, although fin-
            <br>ished by the combined works of two or three different hands,
            <br>appeared to have been the composition of one master, it be-
            <br>comes a matter of fine judgment and experience to distin-
            <br>guish correctly the particular hand. The figures in this pic-
            <br>ture representing the Infant Saviour, St. John, and three 
            <br>Angels playing with a Lamb, are disposed with great skill
            <br>in the centre of the foreground, attracting the eye of the
            <br>spectator from the glowing colors of the surrounding ob-
            <br>jects, but appeared to us incorrect in outline, being ex-
            <br>aggerated, the limbs too thick and too short—Not sold.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">102.	Magdalen and two Cupids—canvass 4 feet 4X5 feet 3.—
            <br>The composition of this picture is in the style of Guido— 
            <br>the heads are admirable, the expression just, and the whole 
            <br>finished with great care—Mr. Potter,	200
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">105.	Rubens. The Lion caught in a Net.—A subject in it-
            <br>self perfectly uninteresting, treated in this great master's 
            <br>inimitable style becomes an object of admiration; which
            <br>is the case with this painting, representing a rampant Lion
            <br>in the meshes of a stroug net—Mr. Flauden,	1,800
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">106.	S. Del Pimbo. Visitation of St. Anna.—A magnificent
            <br>painting, well drawn, and beautifully colored—a fine spe-
            <br>cimen of the master—Mr. Robb,	300
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">116. Landscape near Naples.—A finely-designed painting,</div>
         
         <div class="ab">enriched with figures and buildings—slightly damaged at
            <br>one end, but might be restored by shortening the picture,
            <br>without injuring the subject—Mr. Walls,	550
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">121.	Sneyders. Hawk among Chickens.—A superb picture,
            <br>much in the style of Hondekoter—Mr. Robb,	160
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">122.	P. De Champagne. Massanissa and Sophonisba.—A 
            <br>badly drawn and wretchedly colored composition, attribu-
            <br><div class="columnbreak"></div>ted to a master whose pictures have an agreeable tone
            <br>of color, and are designed correctly—Francini,	200
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">127. G. Delle Notta, or Gherard Honthorst. Christ Break-
            <br>ing Bread with his Disciples.—A picture of some merit,
            <br>in the style of Caravaggio, but from the general coloring
            <br>we should judge the master to be Wm. Honthorst, whose
            <br>works are often sold as Gherard’s. The powerful manner
            <br>in which the light and shade are contrasted, rendered this 
            <br>painting very attractive—Dr. Kecker,	170
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>Niblo’s.—Mrs. Mowatt, we learn, has been here gathering fresh laurels in Juliet and other roles. We deeply
            regret that we have not been permitted an opportunity
            of seeing her.
         </p>
         
         <p>Park Theatre—Mrs. Bland.—On Saturday last this 
            lady made her first appearance in New-York, in Knowles’
            play of the Hunchback, and again received the most enthusiastic applause from a delighted audience. Her performance of the Lady of Lyons at once stamped her as an 
            artist of the highest order in her profession; and now,
            that we have witnessed her Julia, we unhesitatingly pronounce her to be fully equal to any tragedian that has
            ever appeared in this country. When we shall have seen
            her in her various range of characters, it is very possible
            we may give her a still higher rank. Mrs. Bland's excellences are not confined to one or two scenes in a play.
            Her conception of a character is perfect from beginning
            to end, and she is equally true to nature, whether pourtraying the soft emotions of the heart, the sprightly naiveté of the lady of fashion, or the intense and violent passions of remorse, anger or despair. In the latter, indeed,
            she is so truly great that the audience are frequently electrified, and a breathless attention alone shows their perfect sympathy with the heroine. She possesses, moreover, a voice of intense power, of the finest quality, and
            capable of all the varieties of modulation. In the part
            of Julia, Mrs. Bland had the opportunity—rarely met with
            in one play—of exhibiting all these beauties in a very
            prominent degree. We consider the character a very
            difficult one; one, in fact, to test the ability of any artist, and to decide her pretensions to the highest rank in
            the histrionic art. This lady, by her performance on Saturday, has decided this point beyond dispute. It would
            be impossible (not having the book before us) to point out
            to our readers every beauty in her performance, or even
            the most conspicuous of them; but some of the scenes we
            cannot pass over without notice. Her remorse on discovering that by her own frivolity and apparent heartlessness, she had caused the estrangement of Sir Thomas
            Clifford, blended at the same time with the angry feelings natural to a high-minded and haughty damsel on being schooled by her lover, was most admirably depicted.
            Her struggle between pride and love, ere she determines
            to give her hand to Lord Rochdale, and the reckless despair with which she seizes the pen and affixes her name
            to the document, were not less favorable points. Her surprise and emotion on discovering in the voice of the Secretary, her lover; her many fruitless efforts to look round
            and see if it be really he; her extreme agitation on finding him at her feet, his arm encircling her waist; and,
            when suddenly aroused to a sense of the danger of her
            situation, she assumes the dignity of an insulted woman,
            and frees herself from his embrace, were all so beautifully and forcibly given, that we are disposed to consider
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page197"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            this scene the finest in the whole play; though it would
            be difficult, perhaps, for any thing to exceed the beauty of 
            her acting in the subsequent scene with Master Walter,
            when imploring him not to force her to marry Lord Rochdale. Her wretchedness, and almost utter despair, lest
            there should be no means by which she could with honor
            avoid the detested nuptials, were so true to nature, so exquisitely pathetic, that cold indeed must have been his
            heart who could have witnessed this scene with an unmoistened eye. As a whole, Mrs. Bland’s Julia is highly
            meritorious: and we very much doubt if, in this character, she is excelled by any actress on the English
            stage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Bland played Sir Thomas Clifford, a part by no
            means agreeable to the actor, particularly in the latter
            half of the play; but he acquitted himself admirably.—
            This gentleman is an accomplished reader, and poetry
            never loses any of its beauties in his hands. He has much
            judgment and discretion, and a most musical voice, which
            he perfectly well knows how to modulate. We have now
            seen him several times—for he is put into all sorts of parts
            —and have found, invariably, that his excellence increases in proportion to the difficulty of the character he has to
            represent. He must become an established favorite on the
            Park boards.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Hunchback was, altogether, well brought out.— 
            Though there were no striking excellences in the cast of
            the other characters, they were nevertheless very creditably sustained by Mr. Bass, Mr. De Walden, Mrs. Abbott, 
            &amp;c.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
         
         <p>Sacred Music Society.—This Society performed the
            Oratorio of the Seven Sleepers at the Tabernacle on the 
            20th instant. Our remarks last week upon the plot and
            the music of this Oratorio, performed under the direction of Mr. George Loder, preclude the necessity of our
            alluding to them again. We must, however, state that
            much of the character of the music was lost, on the second representation, through the conductor (Mr. U. C. 
            Hill) mistaking the tempo of several pieces.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">The following is a cast of the characters:
            <br>Antipater. . . .           Mr. Fraser.
            <br>Honoria, (his Wife) .	.	Mrs. Jameson.
            <br>Martinus, (the Bishop) .	.	Mr. Seguin.
            <br>Malchus,	.	.	.         Miss J. L. Northall.
            <br>Serapion,	...	“ Windmuller.
            <br>Johannes,	...         A Lady Member.
            <br>Constantine,  Sons of Auicianua, Mr. R. Dunning. 
            <br>Dionysius, 	...		D. B. Bell.
            <br>Marianus, 	...	“	R. Andrews.
            <br>Maximianus, 	...	“	F. H. Nash.
         </div>
         
         <p>Mr. Fraser sang the music of the Antipater admirably. 
            His voice was in fine order : he sang with feeling and expression ; he exhibited a pure and refined taste, and he 
            delivered his recitatives in a straight-forward and energetic manner, enunciating his words at the same time
            with great distinctness. We have never heard Mr. Fraser to such advantage, and cannot but compliment him 
            on his careful and excellent performance.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Seguin, as the Bishop, was almost all that we
            could have wished. He sang his music with the utmost 
            precision and accuracy, and his beautiful voice added a
            great interest to the fine compositions he had to sing, but
            there was hardly sufficient force and emphasis to his performance.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss Julia Northall has improved in one respect: she
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>seems almost content to sing the music nearly as it is
            written; she has given over embellishing too lavishly
            the composer’s ideas, and confines herself to a decided relantando and a trifling cadence at the close. This selfdenial will work out a vast improvement in her style, 
            which we shall hail with pleasure. There is so much
            good material in Miss Northall, that we should regret to
            see her departing from the road to improvement. She 
            has much to do before she can maintain a first position in
            the profession. One prominent fault in her style, would,
            if carefully regulated, become a positive excellence: we
            allude to her decidedly theatrical method of delivery. 
            This she indulges incessantly, until it loses all effect,
            from the want of judicious eontrast. Miss Northall is
            however very young yet, and we sincerely believe that if
            she at present does not consider herself perfect, but will 
            practise with a view to improvement, she will become a
            very charming singer.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mrs. Jameson has a very good voice, and sang the part
            of Honoria quite respectably. She has no particular style
            at present, and requires much schooling; but Mrs. Jameson has every thing in her favor—a good figure, a charming face, and a vocal organ capable of high cultivation.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mrs. Windmuller gives evidence of some good education; but her extreme fright rendered her incapable of
            doing justice to herself. She sang painfully out of tune
            all the evening.
         </p>
         
         <p>A Lady Member has a fine voice, but she is uneducated,
            and does not therefore know how to manage it.
         </p>
         
         <p>The chorus singers were very numerous, but the power
            was by no means commensurate with the numbers. We 
            have, however, never heard the choruses so well executed upon any previous performance of the Sacred Music
            Society. We account for this naturally enough, from the 
            fact that the principal part of the performers had been
            thoroughly drilled for three or four months by Mr. Loder,
             at his rehearsal of the same Oratorio. But despite of all 
            this drilling, and notwithstanding the excellence of their 
            first performance, they were still unsteady in many points
            and confused in others; particularly in the fugues.
         </p>
         
         <p>The band was pretty good, many portions being executed with effect, while in the more delicate instrumentation, a great want of lightness was observable; particularly in Honoria’s recitative, which is descriptive of alarm 
            and agitation. The conductor did not feel this, and the
            result was a want of the correct expression. Most of the 
            principal performers were engaged in Mr. Loder’s representation, and the music ought therefore to have gone
            much smoother.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Hill misconceived the tempo in several pieces—in
            the duett between Honoria and Antipater, in the first act,
            which was very much too slow, causing partial interruption of the continuous and flowing character of the melody. 
            The duett between Malchus and Serapion was altogether
            too slow; the tempo was totally at variance with the
            character of the composition; and the tempo of Johannes’
            exquisite song was much too fast, by which the grace and
            prophetic tone of the sentiment were destroyed.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Hill is a very estimable and worthy man in his private relations; but as a conductor, we can award him but
            little commendation. He certainly strives to make up in 
            perseverance what he wants in knowledge and appreciation, but he has made loo many distinct failures to command the respect of the performers, without which, oneness of performance in execution and effect can never be 
            secured.
         </p>
         
         <p>The President of the Society announced from the or
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page198"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            chestra that David would be given on the 10th of October.
            We may reasonably expect that this performance will exhibit some marked degree of excellence, as the Society
            should by this time be up in it, having performed it all
            the time for the last half dozen years.
         </p>
         
         <p>Items.—Mr. Templeton has arrived in this city. It is
            his purpose, we understand, to try his fortune writh a class
            of entertainment which Henry Phillips has already tried
            before, and failed to render popular. Mr. Jones, of the 
            Park Theatre, was the first who introduced these musical
            Lectures. He commenced by illustrating the Ancient
            Jewish History, but the public did not support him and 
            he did not continue his services. Mr. Horncastle, that is 
            Professor Horncastle, advertised his Irish Entertainments,
            but the respectability of his Brother militated so strongly
            against him, that his first entertainment was his last, for
            the room was nearly empty. We regret this, because 
            Professor Horncastle is a man of acknowledged talent,
            sings in a chaste and classical style, and we have not a
            doubt that his lectures would have proved well worthy
            public patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the face of all these failures, Mr. Templeton is determined to risk, in the same way, the success which his 
            reputation ought certainly to command, and which it certainly would command were he to place himself in any 
            other way before the public. It is just possible to be sure
            that_he may succeed; for success in Music, as in every
            thing else, very frequently depends upon the turning of a
            straw. The public may take it into its head to make
            these entertainments the fashion, and if it do, then Mr.
            Templeton will make a fortune here; for it is an established fact, although not admitted by our neighbors of
            Boston and Philadelphia, that the favorable fiat of the
            New York Public, is a passport for the whole Union.
         </p>
         
         <p>We wish for Mr. Templeton’s sake that the public may
            incline towards him, but we wish for our own, that he 
            had brought out with him a Soprano and Basso, and had
            engaged with the Park Management to give a series of 
            Grand Operas. We do not entertain a doubt, that even
            with this division of profits, Mr. Templeton would have
            gained more than his individual experiment will yield
            him. It is a common error for man to grasp at everything, and the result is most frequently a shadow in place
            of a substance. We trust that such may not be the result in Mr. Templeton’s case.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Operas were stopped at the Park Theatre for several nights, in consequence of the illness of Miss Deley.
            After the performance on Wednesday week, she was 
            seized with a severe hoarseness, which proved very obstinate and difficult to overcome. It is a very common thing
            for Singers just come from Europe, to be attacked in this
            way, the more especially if they exert the voice much
            immediately on their arrival.
         </p>
         
         <p>We sincerely trust that Miss Deley will shortly recover her powers.</p>
         
         <p>The Seven Sleepers, and Beethoven’s Mount of Olives.—We call the attention of our readers to the advertisement in another column,under the above head. The performance will take place on the 9th inst., at the Tabernacle, and will be under the direction of Mr. George Loder.
            Two such works upon one evening, will form a Musical 
            Entertainment never before equalled in this country. We 
            have every confidence that the performance will he excellent, and can therefore consistently recommend the public 
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>to attend it. It is just that the people of New York
            should support the spirited undertaking of Mr. Meigs, for
            a better entertainment is given for fifty cents, than the Sacred Music Society offer, in opposition, for one dollar.
         </p>
         
         <p>We trust that all those who wish to enjoy a choice selection of fine Sacred Music, and at the same time support the worthy resident talent, will go to the Tabernacle on the 9th inst.</p>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>
         
         <p>Thomas Dunn English, the editor of the “Aristidean,”
            wrote for the “New Mirror,” a short time after it was 
            established, a poem called “Ben Bolt” to which he appended his initials. From its simplicity of diction and
            touching truthfulness of narrative, it became popular, and
            being extensively copied, induced the author to acknowledge it. It runs thus:
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>Don’t you remember sweet Alice, Ben Bolt?
            <br>Sweet Alice whose hair was so brown,
            <br>Who wept with delight when you gave her a smile,
            <br>And trembled with fear at your frown?
            <br>In the old churchyard in the valley, Ben Bolt,
            <br>In a corner obscure and alone,
            <br>They have fitted a slab of the granite so gray,
            <br>And Alice lies under the stone.
            <br>Under the Hickory tree, Ben Bolt,
            <br>Which stood at the foot of the hill,
            <br>Together we’ve lain in the noonday shade,
            <br>And listened to Appleton’s mill.
            <br>The mill-wheel has fallen to pieces, Ben Bolt,
            <br>The rafters have tumbled in,
            <br>And a quiet which crawls round the walls as you gaze,
            <br>Has followed the olden din.
            <br>Do you mind the cabin of logs, Ben Bolt.
            <br>At the edge of the pathless wood,
            <br>And the button-ball tree with its motley limbs,
            <br>Which nigh by the door-step stood?
            <br>The cabin to ruin has gone, Ben Bolt,
            <br>The tree you would seek in vain;
            <br>And where once the lords of the finest waved,
            <br>Grow grass and the golden grain.
            <br>And don’t you remember the school, Ben Bolt.
            <br>With the master so cruel and grim,
            <br>And the shaded nook in the running brook,
            <br>Where the children went to swim? 
            <br>Grass grows on the master’s grave, Ben Bolt.
            <br>The spring of the brook is dry,
            <br>And of all the boys that were schoolmates then,
            <br>There are only you and I.
            <br>There is change in the things I loved, Ben Bolt
            <br>They have changed from the old to the new;
            <br>But I led in the core of any spirit the truth,
            <br>There never was change in you.
            <br>Twelvemonths twenty have past, Ben Bolt.
            <br>Since first we were friends, yet I hail
            <br>Thy presence a blessing, thy friendship a truth—
            <br>Ben Bolt, of the salt-sea  gale.
         </div>
         
         <p>Several musical people have attempted to adapt an
            air to these Words; and there are, in consequence, live
            editions of the song afloat, issued under the auspices of 
            various publishers. In some of these a portion of the
            stanzas are taken—and in all there are various errors.
            They are such errors, however, us seem to be without
            intention, and bear every evidence of their accidental nature. The one before us is of a different kind. It occurs
            on two pages of music and words, published by Oliver &amp;
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page199"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            Ditsen, Washington street, Boston, with the following title:—
         </p>
         
         <p>There's a change in the things I love. Composed and respectfully dedicated to his friend B. F. Baker, Esq., by Joseph P: Webster.</p>
         
         <p>The evident intention of Mr. Webster is to claim the
            authorship of the words as well as the music—which latter has in it nothing remarkable. But whether this is, or
            is not, the intention of Mr. Webster, he has committed a
            most vile fraud upon Mr. English. Instead of printing
            the poem as given above, he gives four of the stanzas
            only, and in the following form—the italics, which mark
            the alterations and additions, being our own:—
         </p>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>O don’t you remember sweet Alice, Ben Bolt,
            <br>Sweet Alice with hair so brown;
            <br>Who wept with delight when you gave her a smile,
            <br>And trembled with fear at your frown.
            <br>In the old church-yard in the Abbey, Ben Bolt,
            <br>In a comer obscure and alone,
            <br>They have fitted a slab of the granite so gray,
            <br>And Alice lies under the stone.
            <br>O don't you remember the wood, Ben Bolt,
            <br>That grew on the green sunny hill;
            <br>Where oft ire bote played ’neath its wide-spreading shade,
            <br>And listened to Appleton’s mill.
            <br>The mill bets gone to decay, Ben Bolt,
            <br>And the rafters have fallen in,
            <br>And a quiet has settled on all around,
            <br>In the place of the olden din.
            <br>O don’t you remember the school, Ben Bolt,
            <br>With the master so cruel and grim; 
            <br>And the quiet nook and the running brook,
            <br>Where the school boys went to swim.
            <br>Grass grows on the master’s grave, Ben Bolt,
            <br>And the running brook is dry:
            <br>And of all the boys who were schoolmates then,
            <br>There is only you and I.
            <br>There's a change in the things I love, Ben Bolt,
            <br>A change from the old to the new;
            <br>But I feel in the core of my heart, Ben Bolt,
            <br>There never was change in you.
            <br>Twelve months—twenty have passed, Ben Bolt,
            <br>But still with delight I hail 
            <br>Thy presence a blessing, thy friendship a truth,
            <br>Ben Bolt of the salt sea gale.
         </div>
         
         <p>Now, in the name of the craft of authors we protest
            against such impudent thieving as this. The thing is
            growing to a nuisance. No sooner does a literary man
            produce anything worthy of especial note, than some
            lack-brained fellow—some Mr. Joseph P. Webster—takes
            it up, and either passes it off as his own, or mangles it
            shamefully in an attempt at emendation—or perhaps
            both. If caught, he sneaks off in silence, like a detected
            robber of hen-roosts—if not, he chuckles at his successful
            rascality, and enjoys a reputation obtained for him by
            alien brains.
         </p>
         
         <p>Much has been said, of late, about the necessity of
            maintaining a proper nationality in American Letters;
            but what this nationality is, or what is to be gained by
            it, has never been distinctly understood. That an American should confine himself to American themes, or even
            Prefer them, is rather a political than a literary idea—
            and at best is a questionable point. We would do well
            to bear in mind that “distance lends enchantment to the
            view. Ceteris paribus, a foreign theme is, in a strictly
            literary sense, to be preferred. Alter all, the world at
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>large is the only legitimate stage for the autorial histrio.
         </p>
         
         <p>But of the need of that nationality which defends our own
            literature, sustains our own men of letters, upholds our own
            dignity, and depends upon our own resources, there cannot
            be the shadow of a doubt. Yet here is the very point at
            which we are most supine. We complain of our want of an
            International Copyright, on the ground that this want justifies our publishers in inundating us with British opinion
            in British books; and yet when these very publishers, at
            their own obvious risk, and even obvious loss, do publish
            an American book, we turn up our noses at it with supreme
            contempt (this as a general thing) until it (the American
            book) has been dubbed “readable” by some illiterate Cockney critic, Is it too much to say that, with us, the opinion of Washington Irving—of Prescott—of Bryant—is a
            mere nullity in comparison with that of any anonymous
            sub-sub-editor of The Spectator, The Athenæum or the
            “London Punch”? It is not saying too much, to say
            this. It is a solemn—an absolutely awful fact. Every
            publisher in the country will admit it to he a fact. There
            is not a more disgusting spectacle under the sun than
            our subserviency to British criticism. It is disgusting,
            first, because it is truckling, servile, pusillanimous—secondly, because of its gross irrationality. We know the
            British to bear us little but ill will—we know that, in no
            case, do they utter unbiassed opinions of American books
            —we know that in the few instances in which our writers have been treated with common decency in England,
            bthese writers have either openly paid homage to English
            institutions, or have had lurking at the bottom of their
            hearts a secret principle at war with Democracy:—we
            know all this, and yet, day after day, submit our
            necks to the degrading yoke of the crudest opinion that
            emanates from the fatherland. Now if we must have
            nationality let it be a nationality that will throw off this
            yoke.
         </p>
         
         <p>The chief of the rhapsodists who have ridden us to
            death like the Old Man of the Mountain, is the ignorant
            and egotistical Wilson. We use the term rhapsodists
            with perfect deliberation; for, Macaulay, and Dilke, and
            one or two others, excepted, there is not in Great Britain 
            a critic who can be fairly considered worthy the name.
            The Germans and even the French are infinitely superior. 
            As regards Wilson, no man ever penned worse criticism
            or better rhodomontade. That he is “egotistical” his
            works show to all men, running as they read. That he is
             ignorant” let his absurd and continuous schoolboy blunders about Homer bear witness. Not long ago we ourselves pointed out a series of similar inanities in his review of Miss Barrett’s poems—a series, we say, of gross
            blunders arising from sheer ignorance—and we defy him
            or any one to answer a single syllable of what we then 
            advanced.
         </p>
         
         <p>And yet this is the man whose simple dictum (to our
            shame be it spoken) has the power to make or to mar any
            American reputation! In the last number of Blackwood,
            he has a cotinuation of the dull “Specimens of the nBri
            -tish Critics,” and makes occasion wantonly to insult one
            of the noblest of our poets, Mr. Lowell. The point of the
            whole attack consists in the use of slang epithets and
            phrases of the most ineffably vulgar description. “Squabashes” is a pet term. “Faugh!” is another. “We are 
            Scotsmen to the spine!' says Sawney—as if the thing were
            not more than self-evidont. Mr. Lowell is called “a magpie,” an “ape,” a “Yankee cockney,” and his name is
            intentionally mis-written John Russell Lowell. Now
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page200"></div>
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>
            were these indecencies perpetrated by any American 
            critic, that critic would be sent to Coventry by the whole 
            press of the country, but since it is Wilson who insults,
            we, as in duty bound, not only submit to the insult, but
            echo it, as an excellent jest, throughout the length
            and breadth of the land. Quamdiu Catilina? We do
            indeed demand the nationality of self-respect. In Letters
            as in Government we require a Declaration of Independence. A better thing still would be a Declaration of
            War—and that war should be carried forthwith “into Africa.”
         </p>
         
         <p>A Friend “who knows,” writing to us in reference to
            the Whittier and Bulwer parallel, says,
         </p>
         
         <p>En passant the gem which you present in your last, as attributed to both Whittier and Bulwer “went the rounds,” some years
            ago, as the property of George D. Prentice, to whom by the way,
            more than one of the Abolition poet’s waifs have been awarded.
            A few years back “The Hesperian,” (Gallagher’s Magazine, at
            Columbus, Ohio,) contained a little poem “To a Lady,” beginning
            “We are not strangers,” &amp;c., over the signature of George D.
            Prentice, which had previously appeared in the “New England
            Review,” then conducted by Whittier, over the initials, J. G. W.
            But why speak of these things?—"de minimis nun curat lex."
         </p>
         
         <p>The unworthy cabal lately entered into by some of
            our most “influential” citizens, to foist upon the public
            attention, through a concerted movement of puffs anticipatory, a collection of rather indifferent and very unoriginal verses by one Mr. William W. Lord, has met,
            we rejoice to find, the most signal and universal rebuke.
            Tricks of this kind will scarcely be attempted again. 
            A mere trick it was. Mr. Lord had written some matters
            of which he had an exalted opinion. In New Jersey he
            had for neighbour a very gentlemanly personage connected with the press. To him application was made,
            and the whole scheme was immediately arranged. Auspice Teucro nothing was to be feared. The press as a
            matter of course, would be dumb—or open its mouth
            only to echo the cos plaudite of the King. Mr. Appleton is
            invited to dinner. Mr. Lord is invited to recite his
            poems; he reads them, we have been informed, with remarkable unction. It is decided in full conclave, that
            henceforth he shall be the “American Milton." No
            member of that illustrious assembly ever dreamed that
            there was anything farther to do—for this whole thing
            had, to a certain extent, been repeatedly managed before.
         </p>
         
         <p>The result has placed Mr. Lord in a very remarkable, and certainly in a very amusing position. There
            is no immediate need, however, of his cutting his throat.
            The letter to Mr. Wordsworth, was the most absurd
            of all moves; or if a letter was to be sent to Mr. Wordsworth, why did Mr. Lord think it necessary to make
            use of Bishop Doanc as an amanuensis—or a catspaw?
            This was hardly fair play. To “one Mr. Lord” beseeching a complimentary letter about his own poems, the
            patriarch of the Lakes might have had no scruple in
            replying—“Mr. Lord, it is my honest opinion that your
            book is not much better than it should be”—but an
            answer of this kind was clearly impossible from so wellbred a man as Wordsworth, to his personal acquaintance,
            the Bishop of New Jersey. This letter then -or this
            presentation copy of the Poems—to Wordsworth was,
            after all, nothing in the world hut trick No. 2. The fact
            is, we are ashamed both of Mr. Lord and of his book.
            His chicaneries have done more to convince the public
            of his utter want of poetic (or of any other kind of) spir
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>it, than even the bombast, egotism, and inanity of “Niagara” itself.
         </p>
         
         <p>There is a rumor that the plates of the Natural History Department of the Exploring Expedition book are in
            course of preparation either in London or Pans. Have
            we no artists at home—or no soul to sustain them?
            Perhaps the amiable “superintendent of the plates” at
            Washington can afford us some information about the
            truth or falsity of the report in question.
         </p>
         
         <p>Among the American books of exceeding merit which,
            through accident, have been nearly overlooked, we may
            mention “George Balcombe,” a novel by Judge Beverly 
            Tucker, of Virginia, and “The Confessions of a Poet,”
            a very vigorous and powerful fiction by the author of
            “The Vision of Rubeta.”
         </p>
         
         <p>In our list, last week, of contributors to “The Broadway Journal,” we made some important omissions. We
            have published original articles from Mrs. Osgood, Mrs.
            Ellet, Mrs. Kirkland, Mrs. R. S. Nichols, Mrs. Child,
            Mrs. Lowell, Mrs. Hewitt. Miss Fuller, Miss Mary
            Orme, Miss Colman, Miss Lawson, Miss Wells, W. G.
            Simms, J. R. Lowell, H. R. Schoolcraft, H. T. Tuckerman, Park Benjamin, E. A. Duyckinck, T. D. English, Wm. Page (the artist), Wm. Wallace, A. M. Ide,
            Jr., Henry B. Hirst, Wm. A. Jones; the author of the
            Vision of Rubeta, Henry C, Watson, Littleton Barry and
            Edgar A. Poe. Our corps of anonymous correspondents
            is, moreover, especially strong.
         </p>
         
         <p>In a very complimentary notice, by Miss Fuller, of
            “Tales by Edgar A. Poe,” the critic objects to the phrases “he had many books but rarely employed them”—
            and “his results, brought about by the very soul and
            essence of method, had, in fact, the whole air of intuition.” We bow to the well-considered opinions of Miss
            Fuller, whom, of course, we very highly respect—but
            we have in vain endeavored to understand, in these cases, the grounds of her objections. Perhaps she will
            explain.
         </p>
         
         <p>The London Builder, speaking of extraordinary mosaics, mentions an exquisite specimen—a portrait of Pope
            Paul V., in which the face alone consists of more than a
            million and a half of fragments, each no larger than a
            millet seed; and from this size up to two inches square,
            pieces are employed in various ways. Another celebrated specimen is that which Napoleon ordered to be made
            when his power was paramount in Italy. It was to be a
            mosaic copy of the celebrated “Last Supper,” by Leonardo da Vinci; and to be of the same size of the original,
            viz, 24 feet by 12. The artist to whom the task was entrusted was Glacono Raffaelle, and the men under his direction, eight or ten in number, were engaged for eight
            years on it. The mosaic cost more than seven thousand
            pounds—and afterwards came into the possession of the
            Emperor of Austria.
         </p>
         
         <p>We Are Delighted to hear that Wiley and Putnam’s
            “Library of American Books,” is meeting with unequivocal success. We had feared that Americans would
            condescend to read nothing less than English. Even of
            our own book, more than fifteen hundred copies have been
            sold here.
         </p>
         
         <p>The editor of “Graham’s Magazine" assures us that
            certainly he has paid, (according to Dr. Griswold’s contract.) for Mr. William Jones’articles—hut that he (Mr.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page201"></div>
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>Graham) has not the slightest intention of ever using them. No doubt
            they are at Mr. Jones’ service.
         </p>
         
         <p>To Correspondents.—Shall we not'
            again hear from M. O.? Her many
            excellences are appreciated by no one
            more fully than by ourselves. A thousand thanks to W, G. for the beautiful'
            lines without a title—also to the author of “ Constance.”
         </p>
      </div>	
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PAINE &amp; BURGESS
            <br>HAVE JUST PUBLISHED
            <br>THE CITIZEN OF a REPUBLIC, by
            <br>Ansaldo Ceba. 1 vol. 12 mo. “ A book
            <br>of rare and condensed thoughts, like dia-
            <br>monds finely polished and richly set.”
            <br>The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli,
            <br>2 vols. 12 mo. “The charmed records of
            <br>the classic city of the Arno, by the master
            <br>spirit of his age.”
            <br>The Challenge of Barletta, a Romance of
            <br>the Times of the Medici. 1 vol. 12 mo. “A
            <br>gem gathered from the jewelled mines of
            <br>Italian Romance.”
            <br>WILL PUBLISH SOON,
            <br>The Autobiography ol Alfieri.
            <br>Melodies, by Gen. Geo. P. Morris.
            <br>The Artist, Merchant and Statesman. 2
            <br>vols. 12 mo. By C. Edwards Lester.
            <br>Prairiedom; or Texas and New Estrama-
            <br>dura. By a Southerner. 1 vol. 12 mo.
            <br>A New Work on Greece. By G. A. Per-
            <br>dicari, U. S. Consul at Athens. 2 vols. 12
            <br>mo.
            <br>Rambles by Land and Water, or Notes of
            <br>Travel in Cuba and Mexico. By B. M.
            <br>Norman, author of Rambles in Yucatan, etc.
            <br>1 vol. Illustrated.
            <br>Fanny Forrester’s First Book of Sketches. 
            <br>Man in the Republic. By C. Matthews.
            <br>32 mo. Gilt. A new and carefully revised
            <br>edition.
            <br>The Prince. By Machiavelli.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">GURNEY’S
            <br>PREMIUM DAGUERRIAN GALLERY, 
            <br>189 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.
            <br>PICTURES taken at this Establishment
            <br>are not excelled in this country—so say
            <br>his numerous patrons. The public are in-
            <br>vited to call and judge for themselves. 02
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTFS—V.F. HARRlSON, 23 CANAL
            <br>Street, N. Y.
            <br>Instruments made with the most recent improve-
            <br>ments, such as Iron Frames, &amp;c., with a  compass
            <br>of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice
            <br>materials, and highly finished, with the most faith-
            <br>ful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience
            <br>In the business.
            <br>N. B. Wanted a second hand Parlor Organ.
            <br>Piano Fortes hired by the month.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO-FORTES.—THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
            <br>(formerly Conductor to Dubo's and Stodart)
            <br>No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment
            <br>of the latest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, 
            <br>of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared
            <br>to guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch
            <br>and External Finish, and to endure in any climate.
            <br>A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano
            <br>Fortes Tuned and R. paired. Piano Fortes always
            <br>on here.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PENMANSHIP.
            <br>Reopening of goldsmiths writing
            <br>ACADEMY, 289 Broadway. La Farge Build-
            <br>ings: corner of Reade Street. Terms reduced to
            <br>THREE DOLLARS, AND NO EXTRA CHANGE
            <br>Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the
            <br>citizens, of New York and Brooklyn, dial his rooms
            <br>are now open, during the day and evening, for Pu-
            <br>pils and Visiters. Mr. G'a specimens of 	
            <br>PENMANSHIP
            <br>has received the First Premium Five Years, from
            <br>the American Institute, and he guarantees to all in
            <br>TEN EASY AND INTERESTING EXERCISES,
            <br>a free and elegant style of writing, that the pupils
            <br>cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice.
            <br>For sale at the  Academy GOLDSMITH’S GEMS
            <br>OF PENMANSHIP.
            <br>Ladies’ Class meets daily at 11 o'clock. Gentle-
            <br>men's day and evening. See Circular. s18 2wis
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div>
         <div class="ab">161 Broadway, September, 1845.
            <br>WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'S 
            <br>LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING.
            <br>“books which are books.”
            <br>THE PUBLISHERS of the Library of Choice
            <br>Reading be" leave to call attention to the fol-
            <br>lowing classification of the book.- published in the
            <br>series by which it will appear that novelty, variety
            <br>and standard merit have always burn preserved, 
            <br>and the promise of the original prospectus faithfully
            <br>kept. It was proposed to publish “the best books of 
            <br>Travels, Biographies, works of Classic Fiction—
            <br>where the moral is superior to the mere story, with
            <br>out ary sacrifice of the interest—occasional choice 
            <br>volumes of Poetry. Essays, Criticism, Contributions
            <br>of History, and generally such single volumes, writ-
            <br>ten by men of genius. as will equally delight the
            <br>scholar and the general reading The books already
            <br>issued and ready for immediate publication may be
            <br>arranged as follows:
            <br>BOOKS OP TRAVELS.
            <br>EOTHEN', OR TRACES OF TRAVEL BROUGHT
            <br>HOME FROM THE EAST.
            <br>THE FRENCH IN ALGIERS. By Lady Duff
            <br>Gordon.
            <br>THE CRESCENT AND THE CROSS—2 vols. By 
            <br>Warburton.
            <br>SIR FRANCIS HEAD S BUBBLES FROM THE 
            <br>BRUNNEN.
            <br>BECKFORD's  ITALY. SPAIN, PORTUGAL, AND
            <br>VISIT TO THE MONASTERIES OF ALCO
            <br>BACA AND BATALHA—in press.
            <br>NOTES OF A JOURNEY THROUGH FRANCE
            <br>AND ITALY. By Hazlitt-—in press.
            <br>There will I be followed by Sir Francis Head's 
            <br>Rough Notes of a Journey across the Pampas;—
            <br>Waterton’s Wanderings in South America; Miss
            <br>Rigby's Letters from the Baltic; Henry Nelson
            <br>Coleridge's Six Months in the West Indies, and
            <br>Thackeray's Notes of a Journey from London to
            <br>Cairo, and others—forming altogether one of the
            <br>most original and select collections of books of tra-
            <br>vels ever published.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">CLASSIC FICTION.
            <br>MARY SCHWEIDLER, THE AMBER WITCH
            <br>The most interesting Trial for Witchcraft ever 
            <br>published.
            <br>UNDINE AND SINTRAM AND HIS COMPAN-
            <br>IONS. From the German of La Motte Fouque.
            <br>THE DIARY OF LADY WILLOUGHBY
            <br>HEADLONG HALL AND NIGHTMARE ABBEY
            <br>ZSCHOKKE'S TALES Translated by Parke God-
            <br>win.
            <br>THE CROCK OF GOLD. By Marlin Farqubar 
            <br>Tupper.
            <br>HEART AND THE TWINS. By Marlin Farqubar
            <br>Tupper.—in press.
            <br>Under this department will be included the choicest
            <br>new works of fiction as they issue from the press
            <br>and choice translations from the workers of the Con-
            <br>tinent. The following have been already announc-
            <br>ed: Mrs. Inchbald’s Nature and Art; Tales from
            <br>Tieck and HOFFMAN, the White Lady and Peter
            <br>Schlemihl; The Life and Adventures of Peter Wil-
            <br>kins, a Cornish Man; Melincourt and Crotchet Cas-
            <br>tle, by the author of Headlong Hall.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">ILLUSTRATIONS OF ENGLISH LITERATURE.
            <br>LEIGH HUNT'S IMAGINATION AND FANCY
            <br>HAZLITT'S DRAMATIC WRITERS OF THE
            <br>AGE OF ELIZABETH.
            <br>HAZLITT'S CHARACTERS OF SHAKSPEARE.
            <br>(WILSON'S GENIUS AND CHARACTER OF
            <br>BURNS.
            <br>HAZLITT'S LECTURES ON THE COMIC WRI-
            <br>TERS—in press.
            <br>HAZLITT'S LECTURES ON THE ENGLISH
            <br>POETS—in press.
            <br>Tne works of HAZLITT in this department, the
            <br>most eloquent commentator on English Literature,
            <br>will be followed by various writings of CAMPBELL,
            <br>WILSON, COLERIDGE, SOUTHEY, ELLIS and others.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">BIOGRAPHY AND GENERAL LITERATURE
            <br>LEIGH HUNT'S INDICATOR AND COMPA 
            <br>NION—2 vols.
            <br>HOOD S PROSE AND VERSE—2 vols.
            <br>CHARLES LAMB'S ESSAYS OF ELIA.
            <br>HAZLIIT'S TABLE TALK-2d series, 2 vols.
            <br>AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF SENVENUTO CELLINI
            <br>IN PRESS.
            <br> A complete collection of the writings of HAZLITT 
            <br>and Leigh Hunt will form part of the scene, to be
            <br>published. at short intervals; WALTER SATAGE LAN
            <br>DOR's. writings: De QUINCET's (the English opium
            <br>eater) Miscellaneous Writings; James Smith's Re-
            <br>jected Addresses and the Poms and Ballads of BON 
            <br>GUALTIER.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">OLD ENGLISH LITERATURE
            <br>BASIL MONTAGU'S SELECTIONS FROM TAY
            <br>LOR, SOUTH BARROW. FULLER, &amp;c.
            <br>CHARLES LAMB'S SPECIMENS OF OLD ENG-
            <br>LISH DRAMATISTS WHO LIVED ABOUT
            <br>THE TIME OF SHAKSPEARE.
            <br>These, the most perfect collectitons of the kind
            <br> ever published, will form the introduction in prose
            <br>and verse to a series of the old English writers.
            <br>including Sir Toons. More. Herbert Fuller.
            <br> Sir Thomas Browne, Milton. Selden, Bacon and
            <br>others
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">AMERICAN SERIES. 
            <br>Of the “Library of American Books,’ the fol
            <br><div class="columnbreak"></div>lowing have already been issued:
            <br>JOURNAL OF AN AFRICAN CRUISER, EDITED
            <br>BY NATHANIEL HAWTHORNE.
            <br>TALES BY EDGAR A. POE.
            <br>LETTERS FROM  ITALY BY J. T. HEADLEY.
            <br>THE WIGWAM AND THE CABIN. BY W. GIL-
            <br>MORE SIMMS
            <br>AG ABFL AND THE LITTLE MANHATTAN,
            <br>BY CORNELIUS MATHEWS.
            <br>WANDERINGS OF THE PILGRIM UNDER THE
            <br>SHADOW OF THE JUNGFRAU, BY GEORGE
            <br>B, CHEEVER, D. D—Just Ready.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">The following are in press:—Western Clearings,
            <br>by Mary Clavers (Mrs Kirkland): Wanderings
            <br>of a Pilgrim under tl«e Shadow of the Jungfrau, by
            <br>George B. Cheever; Views and Reviews in Ame-
            <br>rican History, Literature, and Fiction, a Miscellany,
            <br>by W. Gilmore Simms; The Forest and the Prairie,
            <br>by James Hall, author of the Border Talcs; a new
            <br>volume, by Nathaniel Hawthorne; The Old Eng-
            <br>lish Library, by W. N Jones; and other productions
            <br>of American authors.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">MESSRS. HARPER &amp; BROTHERS
            <br>PUBLISH THIS DAY,
            <br>Elements of Morality and Polity.
            <br>BY PROF. HEWELL.
            <br>THIS valuable new production, from the pen of
            <br>one cf the most eminent scholars of the age,
            <br>exhibits, in a most lucid, exact, and elegant state,
            <br>the great principles of moral, political, and ecclesi-
            <br>astical science in a far more complete and methodi-
            <br>cal manner than has ever yet been presented to the
            <br>public. In offering this great work to the American
            <br>reader, the publisher begs leave to introduce it as
            <br>the commencement, of a new and attractive series
            <br>of sterling books, to be is used by them, under the
            <br>general designation of
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">HARPER’S NEW MISCELLANY;
            <br>the volumes of winch will be legibly printed, in
            <br>duodecimo, on fine paper, and
            <br>Bound in extra Muslin Gilt—Price
            <br>Fifty Cents a Volume,
            <br>and issued at short intervals. To render accessible
            <br>to the million, the fullest advantage' of popular in-
            <br>struction in the various divisions of human know-
            <br>ledge, is the design of the above series. It is appar-
            <br>ent in the present day, that books of intrinsic value
            <br>are demanded by the people. Formerly the popu-
            <br>lar taste preferred mainly works of mere amusement
            <br>the great body of readers now seek them as vehi-
            <br>cles of general knowledge books of a more per-
            <br>manently valuable caste—devoted to some of the
            <br>departments of science, or general literature. A
            <br>new race has sprung up, glowing with the first 
            <br>energies of youth, requiring more expanded ideas
            <br>of the word in which they live, and a more reliable
            <br>and well-digested knowledge of the men. and the
            <br>events of other times and countries. A class of
            <br>books expressly adapted to this demand, it is the
            <br>aim of the publishers to supply; and at a price so
            <br>exceedingly cheap that every person of ordinary
            <br>taste and advantages may thus become possessed
            <br>of a
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">Complete Library of the Best Litera-
            <br>ture of the Age.
            <br>In this collection it is intended to include the best
            <br>productions in every department of knowledge;
            <br>popular philosophical treatises on topics of t univer-
            <br>sal interest; the most compact and brilliant histori-
            <br>cal books; valuable biographical memo&gt;rs ; modern
            <br>voyages and travels, &amp;c., together with scientific
            <br>and other collateral divisions; in the selection of
            <br>all which, the most careful discrimination will be
            <br>observed A mere glance over the wide domain of
            <br>our English literature will exhibit much yet unex-
            <br>plored and uncultivated, from which might be ga-
            <br>thered the fruits of a rich, luxuriant harvest. besides
            <br>which, the ever-teeming issues of the European
            <br>press open a vast revenue of literary wealth, from
            <br>which the above collection may be literally suppli-
            <br>ed. Original productions from American writers
            <br>will also occasionally be introduced In submitting,
            <br>therefore, the esteemed work of Prof. Wrewell
            <br>as a kind of first-fruits of their “New Miscellany,”
            <br>the publishers deem it only necessary to add, that
            <br>their arrangements for carrying forward the enter-
            <br>prise being of the most complete and efficient kind,
            <br>they confidently rely upon their efforts being met
            <br>with a ready response from the entire reading com-
            <br>munity.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">This, they venture to believe, will be insured to
            <br>the r Miscellany, no less from the intrinsic value
            <br>of the collection, than from its unparalleled econ-
            <br>my: each volume being elegantly produced, bound
            <br>IN HANDSOME AND SUBSTANTIAL STYLE. FITTED WITH-
            <br>OUT FARTHER EXPENSE FOR PERMANENT PRESERVA-
            <br>TION in the libraky; the whole series being issued
            <br>in uniform binding, while the press of each volume
            <br>will be only Fiety Cents—far below the cost of
            <br>are vary similar series of books yet published in this,
            <br>or, it is believed, any other country.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO-FORTES CHEAP FOR CASH.—THE
            <br>subscribers have on hand a handsome assort-
            <br>ment, 6, 6 1/2 and 7 octave, mahogany and rosewood
            <br>pianos, which they will warrant and sell low for 
            <br>cash or approved paper.
            <br>GLENN, ROGERS &amp; CO., Manufacturers,
            <br>152 Fulton street, East of Broadway.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page202"></div>
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">J. F. BROWNE &amp; CO.
            <br>-MANUFACTURER OF THE
            <br>IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION HARP,
            <br>By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years with Erard.
            <br>JF. BROWNE respectfully 'informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has established
            himself for the manufacture
            <br>and importation of these very beautiful instruments, at
            <br>281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET.
            <br>His arrangements are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices,
            thereby saving purchasers the high duties
            <br>imposed by Tariff on these Instruments.
            <br>J. F. Browne would observe, these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
            with all the modern improvements of 
            <br>London and Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy of tone, fineness of touch, and perfectness
            of mechanism. Particular care is taken
            <br>to fit them for the extremes of climate in this country, in which respect they will
            be found far superior to any of European manufac-
            <br>ture, imported in the usual way.
            <br>These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and professional talent in
            Europe; among the latter, he would mention
            <br>N. C. Boscha, who invariably selects from this establishment.
            <br>J. F. Browne begs to offer the opinions of some of the first professional talent in
            this country.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making
            a professional use of your Harps, and of
            <br>testing their qualities, it affords me pleasure to certify, that in point of tone,
            workmanship, and above all, a solidity that stands proof
            <br>against the inconstancy of our trying climate, they have in all cases given me the
            most entire satisfaction.
            <br> January, 1845.		I am yours, CHARLES THIBAULT, No. 40 Beach St., N. Y.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Dear Sir :—I write to express the delight I experienced in performing on one of your
            Harps at Sig. Casella’s Concert in this city.— 
            <br>The mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly superior to any harp I
            have heard for many years. I remember my old
            <br>Master, Boscha, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no
            other. Yours, most truly, H. G. TRUST.
            <br>Philadelphia, March 4th, 1844.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make
            I performed on at the St. George’s Society
            <br>Concert, is, in brilliancy of tone, touch, and elegance of workmanship, the finest
            I ever played on. This will apply to all your Harps.
            <br>The grand six and a half Gothic Double action, is a most splendid instrument. Yours,
            with respect, ELIZABETH SLOMAN.
            <br>New York, January 16th, 1845.	A pupil of N. C. Boscha.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir :—Having at your request closely scrutinized your double-action
            Harps, I find they possess the best quali-
            <br>ties of the first makers in Europe combined. That in the ease of touch, by which the
            most brilliant tone is obtained, in perfection and
            <br>ease of modulation, they are superior to any I have used; their elegance of exterior
            must gratify the most refined taste. Your new
            <br>Grand Gothic six and a half octave, is the most splendid effort of art yet produced
            in the musical world; it will give me great pleasure
            <br>in recommending your Harps at every opportunity.	Yours Truly, HENRY HORN.
            <br>January 12th, 1845.	An eminent professor, and Member of the Royal Academy.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
            show the estimate of persons every way capable of
            <br>making a correct decision. J. F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the
            Society of Arts, Philadelphia, for his splendid
            <br>improvements in this delightful Instrument.
            <br>Harps from 300 to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div>
         <div class="ab">The southern literary messenger.
            <br>B.B MINOR, Proprietor. Pub island monthly,
            <br>at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            <br>The MESSANGER has been established since
            <br>1835, has a large subscription list, and is the princi-
            <br>pal organ of Southern opinion.
            <br>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office
            <br>of the  "Broadway Journal," 135 Nassau street.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">JUST PUBLISHED BY H. G. DAGGERS, 30 Ann 
            <br>Streep New York.
            <br>THE COTTON LORD. By Mrs. Stone A Ro-
            <br>mance of the Rich and Poor, written by a lady of
            <br>brilliant talents 25 Cents.
            <br>FRANKENSTEIN, by Mrs. Mary W. Shelley,
            <br>wife of the illustrious poet. “It is among the most
            <br>exciting and terrible of modern roinancos.’’—TRI
            <br>BUNE. 25 Cents.
            <br>LAWRIE TODD, by John Galt, with an original
            <br>preface by the original Lawne Todd viz Grant
            <br>Thorburn, Esq. “Mr. Thorburn’s Preface is worth
            <br>more than the price asked for the novel.” 25 Cents
            <br>THE NUN; or, Life in a Convent. By one of
            <br>the Sisterhood “A terrible exposition of the secret
            <br>practices of Roman Catholics.” 25 Cents.
            <br>POOR JACK. By Captain Martyatt, author of
            <br>Midshipman Easy, Peter Simple, &amp;c. 25 Cents 
            <br>N. B. All of the above will be sent for One DOL
            <br>LAR to any person ordering them through Postmas-
            <br>ters. who are by law authorized to remit money to
            <br>publishers. Any Postmaster ordering the above
            <br>shall be presented with either novel he may select.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">ÆOLIAN attachment.
            <br>Hermann S. SARONI, Professor of Music, 116 
            <br>Leonard street, New York, leaches the Piano
            <br>Forte, with or withoi t Coleman a celebrated At 
            <br>tachment.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO-FORTES—H. WORCESTER, NO. 139
            <br>THIRD AVENUE, Corner of 14th Street, res 
            <br>pectfully informs his friends and the public, that he
            <br>has a good assortment of Piano Fortes, in Rosewood,
            <br>and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons
            <br>wishing to purchase will find it to their advantage
            <br>to call and examine before purchasing elsewhere.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div>
         <div class="ab">BEETHOVEN’S MOUNT OF OLIVES AND
            <br>the SEVEN SLEEPERS—During the week of
            <br>the American Musical Convention.—The sublime
            <br>Oratorio the Mount of Olives, by the immortal
            <br>Beethoven, and the Seven Sleepers, by Dr. Lowe,
            <br>will he performed at the Tabernacle, on Thursday
            <br>evening, the 9th October next, under the direction of
            <br>MR GEORGE LODER
            <br>The Chorus and Orchestra will be full and effect-
            <br>ive, and the solo parts will be sustained by resident
            <br>talent
            <br>Mr. H. C- TIMM will preside at the Organ.
            <br>Tickets, 50 cents each, mav be obtained on and
            <br>after Thursday next, at the principal music stores
            <br>Subscribers will receive three tickets for one dollar 
            <br>as usual.
            <br>HENRY MEIGGS, 446 Broadway.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">G. H. DERWORT, PROFESSOR OF SINGING
            <br>Guitar and Piano Forte, has opened a class
            <br>for Young Ladies, from 7 to l0 years of age, among
            <br>whom are three of his own daughters, whom he
            <br>proposed to thoroughly Instruct in toe art of Singing
            <br>Mr Derwort’s system is the result of many years'
            <br>observation and expericnce, during which he has
            <br>successfully taught in Germany, London, and New
            <br>York. His method cannot fail to impart to his pu-
            <br>pils a clear perception and a thorough knowledge
            <br>of the grammatical principles of music with the
            <br>ability to  harmonize any simple given melody.
            <br>Parents and guardians are invited to call at his
            <br>Rooms, 427 Broadway, when every inquiry will be
            <br>answered.
            <br>Terms $20 per annum, payable quarterly in ad-
            <br>vance. Lessons three tunes a week.
            <br>Private instruction as heretofore.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER-JAMES 
            <br>PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near
            <br>Kim. A Large Stock of the finest instruments al
            <br>ways on hand Terms moderate FOR SALE-A
            <br>Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be told at a great
            <br>bargain for cash.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">WEDDING, VISITING, &amp; PROFESSIONAL 
            <br>CARDS, engraved and printed at VALEN-
            <br>TINE’S, 1 Beekman street— Lovrjoy’s Hotel
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div>
         <div class="ab">J BALLARD. PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR,
            <br>Singing, and Flute, No. 135 Spring street.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">CARD OF REMOVAL-MR. W. A. KING.
            <br>Professor of Music and Teacher of the Piano-
            <br>Forte and Organ, has Removed lo the First House 
            <br>above Twenty Fifth Street on the Rail-Road (4th 
            <br>Avenue)
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">Our First Volume.—A few copies of
            <br>the first volume of the Broadway Jour-
            <br>nal are for sale at the office, either in
            <br>numbers or neatly bound.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">AGENTS.
            <br>Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass.
            <br>R. G. H Huntington, Hartford, Ct.
            <br>M. Baullemet, Mobile, Ala.
            <br>Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O.
            <br>D. M. Dewey, Rochester, N. Y. 
            <br>J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.
            <br>W. E. Russell, Schenectady, N. Y. 
            <br>Levi Willard, Troy, N. Y.
            <br>G. Jones, Albany. N. Y.
            <br>S. F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y.
            <br>Shurtz it Wilde, Baltimore, Md.
            <br>Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.
            <br>Thos. H. Pease, New-Haven, Ct.
            <br>J. C. Morgan, New-Orleans.
            <br>W. W. Kingslev, New-London, Ct.
            <br>G. N. Beesley, Utica, N Y.
            <br>H. B. Strang, Peekskill, N. Y.
            <br>Haliburton &amp; Dudley Boston, Mass.
            <br>S. Thompson, Worcester, Ma s.
            <br>Peter Cooke, Hartord, Ct.
            <br>H. Esten, Providence, R. I.
            <br>Salford &amp; Park, Norwich. Ct.
            <br>John Tomlin, P. M. Jackson, Tenn.
            <br>S. Hart, Sen., Charleston, S C.
         </div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      <a href="#a001"> Link </a><div class="note" id="n001">Moraux is here derived from mæurs and its meaning is "fashionable," or, more strictly, "of manners."</div>
      <a href="#a002"> Link </a><div class="note" id="n002">Speaking of the tides, Pomponius Mela, in his treatise De Situ 
         Orbis," says “either the world is a great animal, or" &amp;c.
      </div>
      <a href="#a003"> Link </a><div class="note" id="n003">Florem putares nare per liquidum æthera.
         P. Commire.
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>