<div>
   <div class="issueId">18450510</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 1.     NEW YORK,  SATURDAY, MAY 10, 1845.     NO. 19.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum. Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>C. F. BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C, WATSON, EDITORS.
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau St. By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div class="figure">
         
         <div class="head">GLIMPSES OF BROADWAY. NO. I. FROM UNION SQUARE LOOKING DOWN BROADWAY</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Rushten's Apothecary's Shop     Houses of-- C.V.S. Roosevelt,     James Phalen,  
            J.F. Penniman.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">The National Academy</div>
         <div class="biblPage">289</div>
         
         <div class="head">THE NATIONAL ACADEMY.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">PORTRAITS.</div>
         
         
         <p>Every year upon the opening of the exhibition, we hearthe senseless cry repeated
            from shallow-thoughted writers,"too many portraits--who wants to see men's faces--why
            don't they give us more historical works?" as if historicalpictures were
            anything but groups of men's faces. A portraitis to a historical composition what a
            biography is to history,or a legend to a novel. For ourselves, we prefer portraiture
            to historical compositions; and we regard a good portrait asthe very highest
            reach of art: and so does the world at largeregard it. The most valuable paintings in the world are portraits; they sell at higher prices than any other
            pictures, andgive the highest degree of pleasure. Even the gross beauties 
            of Rubens are valued more highly than any other of hispaintings, and the portraits of
            Van Dyke and Titian are themost esteemed of their productions. Take the portraits
            fromthe list of Reynolds' works, and there would be nothing left worth having.
            Among our own painters, Copley, Stewart,Trumbull, and Alston's portraitures comprise
            the best andmost numerous of their productions. Perhaps the finest collection of pictures in the country, is the Portrait Gallery of Harvard College, which contains some of the finest of Copley's and Stuart's heads. A bad
            portrait of a bad subjectis certainly not a pleasant thing to contemplate; but a
            fineportrait of a fine head, is one of the most charming and profitable objects in Art. A portrait of 
            <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> by such an artist as Van Dyke, would be worth more than all the historical pictures painted in his
            century. It is the true object of 
             Art to counterfeit Nature, and preserve the forms whichwould be forever
            obliterated without its aid. We would byno means discourage historical composition,
            but then wewould have each century paint its own history. It is veryobvious that
            no painter can give us a reflection of a past age.We do not want mockeries in a
            picture, but realities. Themodest sculptures on the ruins of Palenque, give a more
            vividimpression of the life of the Mexicans, than such pictures asthat by Mr.
            Rothermel in the present exhibition can do. Thetwo little pictures by Mr. Mount,
            numbers 145, 242, willconvey to our descendants a better idea of their ancestors,
            than the most learned composition by one of themselves evercan. If we must paint
            historical pictures, let us paint ourown history, which we thoroughly understand, and
            leavethe dead to paint themselves. We want no masquerades on canvas, but living
            men and women in their real characters.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our exhibition is rich in portraits, and particularly poorin history pieces, which
            we are extremely happy to see; andwe draw more hopeful auguries for the Arts among
            us, thanif the case were reversed.
         </p>
         
         <p>We miss from the walls of the Academy the perfect portraits of Page,
            which for many years were its chief glory inportraiture. It is a puzzling anomaly that one of the greatest artists in the country should be compelled to
            leave themetropolis, and seek for employment in a provincial town.But such is
            the truth, and a mortifying truth it is, for itproves that there is a want of
            appreciation of the highestorder of talent in the community, or at least it seems to
            proveit, for we do not believe that there is any lack of enthusiasmfor high Art, although fortuitous circumstances may sometimes defeat its
            manifestation.
         </p>
         
         <p>New York has just cause to feel pride in her portrait painters, for she
            monopolizes nearly all the talent of the countryin this department of Art. And we
            doubt whether any schoolin Europe can produce so large a number of good portrait
            painters in the same number of artists.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have already given the post of honor in the presentexhibition to Wenzler, a young German artist, who has heretofore given his attention to
            miniatures. The defect of hisportraits is their color, which is harmonious, but cold
            andleaden. It must be owing, we think, to his painting in anorthern light. The
            portraits of Hugh Maxwell and Mr.Furness are among the very best examples of
            portraits thatwe have ever seen, but they are hung in a very bad position,and it is not easy to pronounce very clearly upon their technical merits;
            yet they appear perfect in drawing, and onlylacking in a little warmth of tone. Next
            to these portraitswe must place No. 119, a portrait of Captain Erricsson, by
            Elliott, a young artist, who exhibited his first picture, a portrait of Governor Seward, last year. Mr. Elliott is a nativeof the western part of
            the State, Syracuse; he is destined tooccupy a very high position among the artists
            of the NewWorld. His great danger is facility of execution; he paintswith great rapidity, and rarely or never fails in the likeness of his subject. The portrait of the celebrated engineer is one of the most
            pleasing in the exhibition. We lookat it in vain, seeking for a fault, for it is
            very perfect in itskind, harmonious in color, correct in drawing, free in execution, and altogether a most life-like, speaking portrait. Weare loth
            to qualify our praise, but it is the least degree in theworld sketchy. However, it
            gains in grace what it lacks insolidity and finish. It is truly an admirable
            picture. No. 220,a portrait of Horace Kneeland, is a stronger head and more
            substantial, and quite as good as a likeness, but it lacks thedignified repose
            indispensable in a portrait. No. 190, thehead of an old man with a flowing black beard, is an admirable study, painted with surprising freedom and truth.
            No.128, a Portrait of Mr. Spencer the artist, is a good sober picture. No. 200 is a sweet face--the position exceeding graceful and
            unaffected. It is the least like a portrait, and themost like nature, of any one in
            the room. It is a dewy rose,compared with some of the artificial flowers near
            it.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>No. 199. Portrait of T. Hicks--painted by himself. Law- yers say that the advocate
            who
            pleads his own cause has a fool for his client, and the artist who paints his
            own portraitis sure of satisfying his sitter. Perhaps this is the reasonwhy
            artists are so fond of painting themselves. We believethere are few painters who
            have not multiplied their ownfaces. The Academy has an absurd rule, requiring its associates to present their own portraits to he hung on its walls.
            They could not have hit upon a better plan for securing acollection of bad
            pictures. At the top of the great stairway,as the visiter mounts into the
            sky-parlor, where, for someinscrutable reason, the Academy holds its exhibitions,
            maybe seen the best collection of caricatures in the city. Oneof the greatest
            curiosities among them is a head labelled"Bryant," which nobody would suspect was
            meant for thepoet of that name. Mr. Hicks's portrait, though painted by
            himself, is very like him, but it is not equal to some of hisother
            portaits.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>No. 23. Portrait of Col. Thayer--R. W. Weir, N. A. Afull length portrait in regimentals. The position is exceedingly bad. A suspended action in a
            single figure produces avery unpleasant sensation. The head is better painted than
            any that we have seen by this artist before. The legs areadmirably
            foreshortened, but if they had been shortened stillmore by being left off altogether, it would have been a better picture. There cannot possibly
            be a more uninterestingsight than a pair of long legs covered with white linen trowsers sticking out of a portrait. The accessories in this portrait
            are finished with great care, but they are just the parts ofthe picture which
            are of not the least consequence. It is theonly picture that Mr. Weir has in the
            exhibition.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 27. Portrait of Dr. Macready--J. J. Mapes, H. Weknew that Professor Mapes was
            master of an infinite varietyof accomplishments, but we were not prepared to see so
            gooda portrait as this from his easel. It is a speaking likeness.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 36. Portrait of a Child--J. H. Lazarus. A very sweetpicture, but it is so badly
            hung that it can hardly be seen toadvantage.
         </p>
         
         <p>No 48. Portrait of D- Bryson--E. Mooney, N. A. A sobertruthful portrait. No. 55, W.
            Rowell, by the same artist, isequally good. These pictures only lack a little warmth
            ofcolor to render them among the best in the exhibition. Theircoldness must be
            owing to the light in which the artistworks, for some of his portraits are almost
            hot in color.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 54. Portrait of Mrs. H. Shelton--F. Boyle. An admirable portrait;
            well drawn and well colored, excepting asooty hue which Mr. Boyle contrives to
            invest all his pictureswith. The position is graceful, the arms well disposed, and
            the drapery elaborated with great care. Mr. Boyle is apainter.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 67. Portrait of Captain Cropper--C. C. Ingham.If Mr. Ingham will do himself the
            harm to paint portraits ofmen, we hope for his own sake that he will eschew sailors.
            He cannot put the rough externals of a weather-beaten faceupon canvass. 169 and
            184, two portraits of young ladies,are in his happiest manner. The shotted silk in
            169 is amiracle, and the gauze scarf might deceive one of Stuart'sclerks. The
            ladies themselves appear to be made of finestclay--porcelain.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 69. Portrait--E. H. May. This young artist has twoother portraits in the
            exhibition; the best of the three, andindeed among the best portraits in the room,
            is No. 130; it isaltogether a most admirable portrait, modest, substantial,and
            fleshly.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 83. Brig. Gen. Roumfort, of the Second Brigade,Philadelphia.--W. E. Winn. We are very happy to perceive that this is a production of the right-angled
            city. Whyit was sent here for exhibition we are at a loss to conceive.Gen.
            Roumfort may be a brave man and good citizen, foraught we know to the contrary, but
            the artist appears tohave tried hard to make him look like the reverse. Not
            content with giving him all the swagger possible, he hasmade the gallant
            General's sword several inches longerthan its scabbard. It is a woful picture, and
            it brings tomind most woful events, which the Philadelphians should be
            ambitious to forget.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 158. Portrait of a Gentleman.--T. H. Smith. Thereis nothing in this modest
            picture, excepting the markedcharacter of the subject, to attract attention, and the position in which it is hung not being a favorable one. we should
            hardly have noticed it had we not known the painter to beone of the most
            industrious, most enthusiastic, and most 
            promising of all our young artists. No. 221, another head ofan old
            gentleman, is a very truthful, unpretending portrait.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>No. 165. A Greek.--By F. Fink. This portrait attracts agood deal of attention, and
            is universally admired. Thehands are exquisitely painted, and the whole picture
            reflectsgreat credit on the artist. But it is not the portrait of aGreek; it
            is a gentleman in a greek costume, and so it shouldhave been called.
         </p>
         
         <p>No. 172. Portrait of Jacob Barker.--By H. Inman, N. A.This is the only portrait by this gentleman in the exhibition; but this is one of the best that he
            has ever painted. Itis a good likeness and a very pleasing picture. Considering
            that it was painted from three sittings, and those short ones,it must be
            regarded among this distinguished artist happiestefforts. It is somewhat slight and
            sketchy, but we see thatit is just what the artist aims at in painting. The resemblance of the head to the portraits of Doctor Franklin is very
            remarkable.
         </p>
         
         <p>Bust of J. J. Mapes. By H. Kneeland. It is to the disadvantage of this excellent bust that it is the only one in the exhibition, for it is so true to nature, so finely and purely modeled that it requires to be seen
            by the side of ordinary worksto make its superiority apparent. It is admirably
            chiseled,and makes the nearest approach to the perfection of Power'sbusts of
            any that we have seen in any previous exhibition.There are many portraits still left
            of real merit which weshall notice hereafter.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Enigma</div>
         <div class="biblPage">291</div>
         
         <div class="head">ENIGMA.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>INFLUX of Eternal Mind,
            
            <br></br>Nameless, formless, undefined;
            
            <br></br>Image of all things that be,--
            
            <br></br>Mirror of Eternity;
            
            <br></br>Ether, betwixt earth and heaven;
            
            <br></br>Deathless, though to mortals given;
            
            <br></br>Sphere of knowledge, soul of things,
            
            <br></br>Parent of imaginings;
            
            <br></br>Fluctuous vehicle of shape,
            
            <br></br>Nature's idol, Reason's ape;
            
            <br></br>Master of the hand and eye,
            
            <br></br>Forerunner of destiny;
            
            <br></br>Dual Essence! at thy birth
            
            <br></br>Sprang the masters of the earth;
            
            <br></br>Eros, lord of golden life,--
            
            <br></br>Passion, mingling all in strife,--
            
            <br></br>Prudence, wisdom's early friend,--
            
            <br></br>Fancy, earning but to spend;
            
            <br></br>Last, not least, thou sawest light;--
            
            <br></br>Name thyself, O subtile sprite!
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">HORUS.</span>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">On Writing for the Magazines</div>
         <div class="biblPage">291</div>
         
         <div class="head">ON WRITING FOR THE MAGAZINES.</div>
         
         <p>Before the days of magazines, wit and mirth, and quibsand jests, and glorious
            outbursts of temperament, must havelost half their relish without the after
            enjoyment of beingproduced in the magazines--if indeed they could ever existin
            any conversational perfection without the suggestions andstimulus of the press. It
            is notorious now-a-days, or if not,it may be very readily observed that men talk to
            write, andwrite to talk--that the mutual collision of the babble of theclub room and the soiree with the silence of the writing table, broken only
            by the music of the pen on paper, makesthem perfect in both. One never talks with
            any knowledgetill he writes, travelling into the secret labyrinths of thought,
            or writes with feeling till he has been warmed by the countenance and sympathy of the living eye and voice. Our antemagazinists had none
            of this; they left few records to theirchildren of their swift passing moments; they
            appeared onlyin state, on special occasions in print, and handed down history to us as little better than a Parish Register.
         </p>
         
         <p></p>
         
         <p>Negligence and ease, with enthusiasm and refinement, arethe charms of a magazine.
            No one should care what awriter is deficient in, for this purpose, if he only excite
            oursympathy and awaken our enjoyment. Who is the prince ofthe magazinists but
            
            <span class="person" id="jwilson">Christopher North</span>, the careless slipshodenthusiast, a glowing Sun breaking upon us
            all the brighterout of the polar austerities of Scotland? It was a merciful
            dispensation which sent this tropical genius to a climewhich might naturally
            produce only Chamber's Journals and  Information for the people. Soul, soul,
            soul are the threerequisites for the great magazine. We like the dishabilleair
            and demi-toilette of authorship, for we feel, where theseare worn, the surrounding
            atmosphere is warm and genial.Here we prefer sensibility to sense. Political economy
            maytake care of the pocket elsewhere, and the didactic play onsome other
            instrument of its own. Our organ shouldbreathe only the heart-stirring symphonies of
            Beethoven.We would have one shelf or more in our library for solid
            Encyclopedias and books of business, and another distinct where the eye may
            catch the golden lettering of the poets,and those prose legers of the heart where
            the best affectionsare entered up monthly, and an open account kept against
            Time to the end. What a good round balance there will bein favor of 
            <span class="person" id="jwilson">John
               Wilson
            </span>, 
            <span class="person" id="jhlhunt">Leigh Hunt</span>, and 
            <span class="person" id="thood">Thomas Hood</span> forinstance, when three score and ten brings its
            settlement!
         </p>
         
         <p>It will be seen that we restrict the magazine article proper to but one species of writing, or rather one way of thinking or feeling, for the illustrations of the faculty may be various, ranging through all the
            wide world of fancy, humor,pathos, not forbidding satire--for satire, when it is not purely malevolent, may be enjoyable, bringing us into closer companionship with our fellows. The rough points of a satirist's
            temperament may be the cog-wheels which link us in moreclosely with the general
            movement from which we mightelse be separated and unhappy.
         </p>
         
         <p>Above all things the magazine must depend upon its interest to us for
            its contemporary matter. It must talk of theday and the hour, the whim or philosophy
            of the moment,it must be immediate and local. It must discourse readilyupon
            the fashionable notoriety of the time, or read its homilyfor the benefit of the
            newest politician, or satirize the latestfolly, and turn round to put us in conceit again with its conveniences and virtues. Its great aim is to make us
            pleasedwith the world as it is, its praise must be the very otto ofegotism and complacency, its "feigned abuse such as perplexed lovers use." It should
            purify the soiled temple of theworld, by causing us to forget all the evil and
            reminding usof all the good, removing the mildew of weariness and disgust from its shrines and altars, that the spirit may returnand worship again pure and undismayed. Life would sometimes pall upon us,
            were it not relieved by the playful gracesof the essayist. In this day no one can be
            insensible to thebenefits of literature. The most heroic act is incomplete till
            it receive the welcome, the All Hail! of the orator and poet.Fame dwells in
            books. The guardian being wanting, thevirtue becomes extinct. If the magazines had
            more power itwould be better for the state. We know not what cultivation our statesmen, for instance, might receive if their measures were
            ably reviewed by faithful writers, and theirspeeches commented upon by a body of
            critics who wouldbe the protectors of manly eloquence. No one will longwaste intellect where it is unheeded. "Do not use fulminating gold when common
            gunpowder will do the same," wrote
            <span class="person" id="tmoore">Moore</span> to 
            <span class="person" id="jhlhunt">Leigh Hunt</span>, when 
            <span class="person" id="tmoore">Moore</span> thought his friend
            wuswriting too well in the pages of the Reflector. Our politicians are in little danger of resorting to such a costly alchymy. It is
            different abroad. Pulic men approach the publicwith the fear of the press before their eyes. An English debater rounds his periods by the music of the
            eloquent Timesor Examiner, as by the flute of Gracchus. Our orators, withno
            such clarifying medium, speak direct to Bunkum. It isby the support and influence of
            the best men that the bestthings are done, the best words spoken, and the best books
            written. 
            <span class="person" id="apope">Pope</span> has explained this in his courtly graceful way:
         </p>
         
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>"But why then publish? 
            <span class="person" id="ggranville">Granville</span> the polite,
            
            <br></br>And knowing 
            <span class="person" id="wwalsh">Walsh</span>, would tell me I could write; 
            
            <br></br>Well-natured 
            <span class="person" id="sgarth">Garth</span> inflamed with early praise,
            
            <br></br>And 
            <span class="person" id="wcongreve">Congreve</span> lov'd, and Swift endur'd my lays!
            
            <br></br>The courtly Talbot, Somers, 
            <span class="person" id="jsheffield">Sheffield</span> read,
            
            <br></br>E'en mitred Rochester would nod the head,
            
            <br></br>And St. John's self, great 
            <span class="person" id="jdryden">Dryden</span>'s friend before,
            
            <br></br>With open arms receive one poet more."
            
         </div>
         
         
         <p>There is nothing more delightful in authorship, than anunchecked genial strain of
            friendly altercation, a rivalry inthe appreciation of one another's qualities, where
            it takesplace between men who possess something in themselvesworth eulogizing,
            and are of sufficient importance for theworld to take an interest in the matter. We
            know what amuch dreaded word egotism is in society and among critics,and how instinctively alarm is taken by a class of very sensitive persons at the
            slightest approach to personality; how 
            many very careful guardians there are in the world with thezeal of duennas, whose prudish, nicely-educated souls are offended at an
            improper exhibition of self, and we appreciatevery kindly the good taste which would reduce men and women to a vapid state of insipidity, by closing the
            mouths ofeverybody to anything which might prove hazardous to thepersonal
            comfort of--fools. Yet in spite of all this, we areadvocates of plain speaking,
            downright thinking, egotism,personality, and any other terror "within the limits of becoming mirth," and guarded by a never to be relinquishedspirit
            of honest dealing. So long as fair play is shown, letus have the game out, come the
            good or ill fortune of itwhere it may.
         </p>
         
         <p>One large class of objectors to the egotism of authors isthat numerous body who are not authors, and who sometimes affect to be superior to the supposed
            vanity which,they imagine, is at the bottom of these exhibitions in print.Let
            us look into the matter. Waiving, for a moment, allquestions of the kind of
            notoriety, in the case of the author,it may be, as it very often is, that the name
            of a fault-finder,if he be a merchant, for instance, is a hundred times in the
            paper to the author's once. The most greedy, carnivorouscandidate for fame, who
            bites with the avidity of a pike at anewspaper puff, and urges his literary wares upon the public, amid the general laughter, and particular contempt of
            his own class, is not half so industrious as the tradesmanwith his signs, bill-heads, check-books, agencies, correspondences, runners, gazetteers,
            advertisements, with his nameon every packing box, placarded on every dead wall,
            runningabout the streets on carts, labelled on sloops, making thetour of
            rivers on steamboats, from the broad bunting to thevery plates and dishes in cabin,
            and the last pewter spoon,or reaching that apotheosis of reputation, the figure head
            and bow of a ship ploughing the ocean. A prolific literaryrabbit keeps before
            the people with some diligence, but notwith half the success of the last pill
            manufacturer. But, itwill be said, the fact is nothing, the motive is everything.
            The merchant pursues notoriety purely as an affair of business, of
            dollar and cents, and, when these are attained, hisown private character, his
            domestic interests, his heart andsoul, are his own uncorrupted, while the author is
            makingtrade and merchandize of all that a man should hold mostdear and secret, of his affections, his sensibilities, the pretended goodness of his
            heart, and nicety of his feelings. Isthe merchant so entirely uncorrupted as he represents himself? Is there nothing involved in his notoriety-seeking
            butmatters of interest and profit? Is it all outward, material,separable from
            the man? No, his good name stands for athousand things besides his dollars and
            cents. Go into theinterior of the country, and see the fluttering which the presence of a man whose name has stood a quarter of a century,with honor,
            in Pearl Street, creates. He may be courted forhis wealth, but he is respected for
            all that stands behind it,the probity, the self-denial, the industry, the talent, the energy, which have made him celebrated. Is name, is notoriety nothing? Why, without any impeachment to his modesty,
            he goes up to the desk of the hotel, and writes hisautograph, in the traveller's
            book, with the air of a mandrawing a check on the spectators for an unlimited amount
            of respect, attention and deference, with the certainty of itsbeing honored.
            The merchant seeks notoriety for the sameends, and as nearly as he can, with the
            same means as theauthor. Talk not of the vanity of authors, and the love of
            puffs and notoriety, ye merchants, before editors. As soothing to
            the soul of the ship-owner in South st., or the Captainon the seas, is a few inches
            of type, eulogistically arranged,as to the glistening eyes of the most
            self-idolatrous youngster,who ever perpetrated rhyme or prose.
         </p>
         
         <p>We see that the merchant, in his own argument, does notstand quite clear of the suspicions he urges against the author. He is very righteously and commendably strengthening his own convictions and deference to duty by
            the voiceof public opinion. And he is by no means necessarily making sale of his virtues, because he is prosperous by the credithe gets for them.
            The author assuredly goes further in thevoluntary exhibition of himself,--in his
            egotism,--to admitthe point at once. It is his vocation. To find fault withhim
            for this is to beg the whole question. It is his businessto write out what he knows,
            thinks and feels, that other menmay learn to know, think and feel. If he were to do otherwise, and cease to exhibit, directly or indirectly, his own
            personal character on the page, biography would soon be an enumeration of
            mere platitudes, and would fall into the verypretence and puffery sought to be
            avoided; ignorance wouldbe unquestioned, folly respected, and vice unscathed; there
            would be one biographical formula, something like that inthe ladies' magazines,
            where character and reputation aredispensed as freely as tin money on the stage,
            where genius,that century-blooming aloe, blooms as rankly as the "dandelion in the field, and Shakspeares and Miltons go staggeringabout in
            bibs and petticoats. What a blessed uniformity ofpraise there would be!--what charity, what kind-heartedness!--how perfect a Utopia, how benevolent a
            Millennium,if heroes of various kinds could have it all their own way,
            unchallenged by the occasional impertinence of interferingsensibility and
            justice. What is genius but this secretspring of egotism, everywhere giving life to
            books as thewater to the landscape which is sometimes hidden deep beneath the surface, at others half concealed by foliage, thenplaying, laughing and
            rejoicing in a thousand streams andrivulets in the full blaze of day? Egotism will be valued always in proportion to the character of the author, as a soil
            that betrays a vein of gold is worth more than one of coal orslate. That it may
            become a nuisance, is undoubted; butin its annoying forms, it carries its own
            antidote in its verybarefacedness. But even in its coarser and common forms,it
            has its value, as in the autobiography of 
            <span class="person" id="bcellini">Benvenuto Celli-ni</span>, while no
            passages of the great authors are treasuredmore than those in which they pause,
            parenthetically, toconvey some allusion to themselves. Who would lose the
            supposed personal reference to the blind bard in Homer, orthe passage on Light
            in 
            <span class="person" id="jmilton">Milton</span>? and, in spite of what isgenerally said to the contrary, who does not fancy Shakspeare, probably with justice, a thousand times interposing
            his own sentiments?
         </p>
         
         <p>We have certainly "fetched a compass" to get to our portof magazine writing, and
            vindicate its personalities. Arenot our American writers, lecturers, preachers,
            politicians,editors, actors and other publicans, enough talked about? Itmay be
            that they are too much talked about, and too little--that their names are better
            known than their actions--thatthey are often heard of, but poorly understood. We want
            the niceties of knowledge: all is nothing, mere barrenness,till we find out or
            are taught the peculiar secret principlewhich constitutes their vitality. We do not
            know anythingof the men till we know that. We must have a niche forour
            writers, in the gallery of the mind, otherwise they areso much lumber thrown
            together at the threshold. No man'sknowledge is to be valued till he offers you
            something of hisown, which is not to be picked up on the highway, or towhich
            has been added some value from use or keeping. Weget this rarely. Every one knows everything about our public men, few know anything. How little of all
            that hasbeen written can we refer a stranger visiting the country tofor a
            keen, just, appreciative character of our worthies!The magazines should be looked to
            for its criticism. Hereis a field where the genuine writers of the country should
            come to one another's help, and not leave the best characters of
            our authors and statesmen, as is the fact at present,to be written abroad. If we
            wish to learn anything of ourgreat men, beyond, of course, the fact that they are
            great,we must go to Miss 
            <span class="person" id="hmartineau">Martineau</span> and the foreign reviews.
         </p>
         
         <p>Authors have always been a generous body of men to oneanother in dedications,
            compliments, reviews, &amp;c., and thereis nothing more graceful or valuable than
            these things, whenthey are conscientiously bestowed by good and true men.The
            old scholarship of the Continent, the verses prefixed tothe Elizabethan editions,
            the tributes in the writings of
            <span class="person" id="whazlitt">Hazlitt</span> and his friends, are so many well remembered instances among others. It was a peculiarity of the old English authors--insomuch that 
            <span class="person" id="jhlhunt">Leigh Hunt</span> in his new work onImagination
            and Fancy, has gone somewhat at length andapologetically into the matter, in
            reference to 
            <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>,who mentions none of his contemporaries. "Has any body,''
            says he, "discovered the reason why he never noticed a living
            contemporary, and but one who was dead? and this too,in an age of great men, and
            when they were in the habit ofacknowledging the pretensions of one another."
         </p>
         
         <p>How necessary this spirit of appreciation is among others,where literature is an
            affair sustained and defended by thefew, is a point only to be suggested. In the
            present state ofour literature it is of the next importance to being true to
            themselves, that literary men should be true to one another.Short as our
            history has been, and comparatively few as 
            have been our men of letters, there has been time to forgetand neglect
            some of the best spirits among them. Americancriticism has yet many a genial hour's
            delightful toil tocome, in making the acquaintance of the inner life of many
            who are but little understood.--Dem. Review.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Aurora Agricultural Institute</div>
         <div class="biblPage">293</div>
         
         <div class="head">AURORA AGRICULTURAL INSTITUTE.</div>
         
         
         <p>A circular has been issued by several gentlemen of this County,for the
            establishment of an Institute at Aurora, in which young menmay become thoroughly acquainted with "the principles of Agricultural Science, and their
            application to Practical Husbandry."The plan is one which received the fullest
            approval of the late JudgeBuel; and the arrangements made, are such as cannot fail
            to offerevery desirable inducement to those interested. The farm chosen
            consists 212 acres, adjoining the beautiful village of Aurora, which iswell
            fitted by soil, location, improvement, &amp;c., for such purpose. Nopupils under 14
            years of age received. Charles C. Young, A. M. isProprietor and principal; A.
            Thompson, A. M., M. D. Lecturer onBotany, Geology, Agricultural Chemistry, &amp;c.,
            and David Thomas,Visitor and Adviser.--Auburn Journal.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Some of our readers may smile at seeing the announcement of an
            "Agricultural Institute" made the subject of anarticle in the "Broadway Journal,"
            but we trust that thosewho have had their eyes filled with the dust of Broadway
            since the breath of Spring has swept our streets, (the onlysweeping by the way
            that they get,) will pardon us if wecarry their mind's eyes to the contemplation of
            green fieldsand budding flowers. We are not without precedent, too,for
            introducing rustic themes even into "Broadway," forwhich we cite the display of huge
            squashes and mammothturnips at Niblo's Saloon every autumn, to say nothing of
            that learned body of citizens called "The Farmer's Club,"who meet weekly in the Park to discuss soils and fertilizing powders.
         </p>
         
         <p>Our readers must not suppose that we intend to cut Broadway; we have no
            such cruel design. We confess too muchattachment to city life, to its libraries, and lectures, its societies of learned men and its social advantages; we are
            notyet tired of even coal fires and gas lights; we still love tocontemplate
            the various phases of human nature only to befound in a large city. Yet with all
            this admiration for the"town," we are troubled at times with the "spring fever."
         </p>
         
         <p>No sooner does the Battery become green, or the trees inthe Park unfold their leaves, than we feel an instinctive longing to look at the country. We yearn to pluck the first hyacinth of the garden, the earliest blue
            violet of the field, orthe first trilium erectum of the woods. We attribute this inclination to the fact of our having spent some portion of ourearly
            life in the country, a pleasure which we sincerely wishmany of the young people we
            meet in our walks could enjoy,while their hearts are fresh, and their tastes
            unformed bythe conventional standards of town life.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is not our purpose to discourse at length on the importance of an
            institute founded on the plan above stated itsbenefits to our youth, and especially
            to the young men of ourcities, must be apparent to all. Farming, as a learned profession, (we mean a profession that requires learning,) is becoming more and more popular; as an accomplishment, it islikely soon
            to become fashionable, and we think the soonerthe better; as an occupation, it has
            charms and advantagesto which no other pursuit can lay claim.
         </p>
         
         <p>A well ordered school of Agriculture, we conceive to be agreat desideratum; and we are pleased to see public attention directed to the subject. The day
            seems to have goneby, when education consisted only in learning words, and the
            whole youthful life must be spent on a form, torturing thebrain and destroying
            the body. It has been discovered thatphysical as well as mental training is
            necessary to the fulldevelopment of our nature. The philosophy of Socrates and
            Plato--the philosophy of words has long since given way tothe philosophy of
            Bacon--the philosophy of works. To those boys who have for years been poring
            over dullpages of Greek and Latin, whose eyes have become weakand weary with much study--whose brains have been puzzled with irregular verbs and
            heathen Mythology, and theirbodies enervated by the confinement of the
            school-room,--how delightful must be the change, to the pure fresh air of the fields
            and the invigorating labor of practical husbandry.
         </p>
         
         <p>The situation of the Aurora Institute is peculiarly favorable to the
            objects for which it is established. The easternbank of the Cayuga Lake, the site of
            the beautiful village ofAurora, is in the centre of the famous wheat growing district of this State; for beauty of scenery, fertility of soil, and
            salubrity of climate it is not surpassed by any section of ourcountry.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the capacity of Visitor and Adviser, this institute willhave the services of one
            of the most competent men in theState. There are many men better known to the public
            than David Thomas, but none more esteemed by the largenumber of scientific men
            who rejoice in his acquaintance.Well versed in the natural sciences, and peculiarly
            giftedwith the faculty of imparting his knowledge to others, he ismost fitly
            chosen for his office.
         </p>
         
         <p>Whatever advantages this institution may possess, nonewill be more truly appreciated by the youth who resort thither, than the society and
            instruction of this learned and goodman.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="biblTitle">Three Sundays in a Week</div>
         <div class="biblPage">293</div>
         
         <div class="head">THREE SUNDAYS IN A WEEK.</div>
         
         
         <p>"You hard-hearted, dunder-headed, obstinate, rusty,crusty, musty, fusty, old savage!" said I in fancy, one afternoon, to my grand uncle Rumgudgeon--shaking
            my fist athim in imagination.
         </p>
         
         <p>Only in imagination. The fact is, some trivial discrepancy did exist,
            just then, between what I said and what I hadnot the courage to say--between what I
            did and what I hadhalf a mind to do.
         </p>
         
         <p>The old porpoise, as I opened the drawing-room door,was sitting with his feet upon the mantel-piece, and a bumper of port in his paw, making strenuous efforts to accomplish the ditty,</p>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br> Remplis ton verre vide! 
            
            <br></br> Vide ton verre plein! 
            
         </div>
         
         <p>"My dear uncle," said I, closing the door gently, and approaching him
            with the blandest of smiles, "you are alwaysso very kind and considerate, and have evinced your benevolence in so many--so very many ways--that--that I feel I
            have only to suggest this little point to you once more tomake sure of your
            full acquiescence."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Hem!" said he, "good boy! go on!" </p>
         
         <p>"I am sure, my dearest uncle [you confounded old rascal!]that you have no design
            really, seriously, to oppose my unionwith Kate. This is merely a joke of yours, I
            know--ha! ha!ha!--how very pleasant vou are at times."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Ha! ha! ha!" said he, "curse you! yes!" </p>
         
         <p>"To be sure--of course! I knew you were jesting. Now,uncle, all that Kate and myself
            wish at present, is that youwould oblige us with your advice as--as regards the time--
            you know, uncle--in short, when will it be most convenientfor yourself, that the
            wedding shall--shall--come off, youknow?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"Come off, you scoundrel!--what do you mean by that?Better wait till it goes on." </p>
         
         <p>Ha! ba! ha!--he! he! he!-- hi! hi! hi!--ho! ho! ho!--hu!hu!hu!--oh, that's good!--oh,
            that's capital--such awit! But all we want, just now, you know, uncle, is that
            you would indicate the time precisely."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Ah!--precisely?"</p>
         
         <p>"Yes, uncle--that is, if it would be quite agreeable toyourself." </p>
         
         <p>"Would'nt it answer, Bobby, if I were to leave it at random--some time
            within a year or so, for example?--must Isay precisely?"
         </p>
         
         <p>"If you please, uncle--precisely.</p>
         
         <p>"Well, then, Bobby, my boy--you're a fine fellow, are'nt 
            you?--since you will have the exact time, I'll--why, I'lloblige you for
            once."
         </p>
         
         <p>"Dear uncle!" </p>
         
         <p>"Hush, sir!" [drowning my voice]--"I'll oblige you foronce. You shall have my
            consent--and the plum, we mus'ntforget the plum--let me see! when shall it be?
            To-day'sSunday--is'nt it? Well, then, you shall be married precisely--precisely, now mind!--when three Sundays come together in a week! Do
            you hear me, sir! What are you gapingat? I say, you shall have Kate and her plum
            when threeSundays come together in a week--but not till then--youyoung
            scapegrace--not till then, if I die for it. You knowme--I'm a man of my word--now be off!" Here he swallowed his bumper of port, while I rushed from the room
            indespair.
         </p>
         
         <p>A very "fine old English gentleman," was my granduncle Rumgudgeon, but
            unlike him of the song, he had hisweak points. He was a little, pursy, pompous,
            passionate,semicircular somebody, with a red nose, a thick scull, a longpur e,
            and a strong sense of his own consequence. With thebest heart in the world, he
            contrived, through a predominantwhim of contradiction, to earn for himself, among
            those whoonly knew him superficially, the character of a curmudgeon.Like many
            excellent people, he seemed possessed with aspirit of tantalization, which might
            easily, at a casual glance,have been mistaken for malevolence. To every request, a
            positive " No!" was his immediate answer; but in the end--in the long, long
            end--there were exceedingly few requestswhich he refused. Against all attacks upon
            his purse hemade the most sturdy defence; but the amount extorted fromhim, at
            last was, generally, in direct ratio with the length ofthe siege and the
            stubbornness of the resistance. In charityno one gave more liberally or with a worse
            grace.
         </p>
         
         <p>For the fine arts, and especially for the belles lettres heentertained a profound contempt. With this he had been inspired by Casimir Perier, whose pert
            little query "A quoi unpoete est il bon?" he was in the habit of quoting, with a
            verydroll pronunciation, as the ne plus ultra of logical wit. Thusmy own inkling for the Muses had excited his entire displeasure. He assured me
            one day, when I asked him for anew copy of 
            <span class="person" id="horace">Horace</span>, that the translation of "Poeta
            nasciturnon fit" was a nasty poet for nothing fit"--a remark whichI took in high dudgeon. His repugnance to "the humanities had, also, much
            increased of late, by an accidental biasin favor of what he supposed to be natural science. Somebody had accosted him in the street, mistaking him for no
            less a personage than Doctor Dubble L. Dee, the lecturerupon quack physics.
            This set him off at a tangent; and justat the epoch of this story--for story it is
            getting to be afterall--my grand uncle Rumgudgeon was accessible and pacific only upon points which happened to chime in with thecaprioles of the hobby he was riding. For the rest, he laughed with his arms and
            legs, and his politics were stubborn andeasily understood. He thought, with Horsley,
            that "thepeople have nothing to do with the laws but to obey them."
         </p>
         
         <p>I had lived with the old gentleman all my life. My parents, in dying,
            had bequeathed me to him as a rich legacy.I believe the old villain loved me as his
            own child--nearlyif not quite as well as he loved Kate--but it was a dog's existence that he led me, after all. From my first year untilmy fifth,
            he obliged me with very regular Hoggings. Fromfive to fifteen, he threatened me,
            hourly, with the House ofCorrection. From fifteen to twenty, not a day passed in
            which he did not promise to cut me off with a shilling. Iwas a sad dog, it is true--but then it was a part of my nature--a point of my faith. In Kate,
            however, I had a firmfriend, and I knew it. She was a good girl, and told me
            very sweetly that I might have her (plum and all) wheneverI could badger my grand uncle Rumgudgeon, into the necessary consent. Poor girl!--she was barely fifteen, and without this consent, her little amount in the funds was not comeat-able until five immeasurable summers had "dragged their
            slow length along." What, then, to do? At fifteen, or evenat twenty-one [for 1
            had now passed my fifth olympiad] fiveyears in prospect are very much the same as
            five hundred.In vain we besieged the old gentleman with importunities.Here was a piece de resistance (as Messieurs Ude and Careme would say) which
            suited his perverse fancy to a T. Itwould have stirred the indignation of Job
            himself, to see howmuch like an old mouser he behaved to us two poor wretched little mice. In his heart he wished for nothing more ardently than our union. He had made up his mind to this  all along. In fact,
            he would have given ten thousand poundsfrom his own pocket (Kate's plum was her own)
            if he couldhave invented anything like an excuse for complying withour very natural wishes. But then we had been so imprudent as to broach the
            subject ourselves. Not to oppose itunder such circumstances, I sincerely believe was
            not in hispower.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have said already that he had his weak points; but, inspeaking of these, I must
            not be understood as referring tohis obstinacy: that was one of his strong points--"assurement ce n'etait pas sa foible." When I mention his
            weaknessI have allusion to a bizarre old-womanish superstition whichbeset him.
            He was great in dreams, portents, et id genusomne of rigmarole. He was excessively
            punctilious, too, uponsmall points of honor, and, after his own fashion, was a man
            of his word, beyond doubt. This was, in fact, one of hishobbies. The spirit of his vows he made no scruple of setting at naught, but the letter was a
            bond inviolable. Nowit was this latter peculiarity in his disposition, of which
            Kate's ingenuity enabled us, one fine day, not long after ourinterview in the dining room, to lake a very unexpected advantage; and, having thus, in
            the fashion of all modern bardsand orators, exhausted, in prolegomena, all the time
            at mycommand, and nearly all the room at my disposal, I will sumup in a few
            words what constitutes the whole pith of thestory.
         </p>
         
         <p>It happened then--so the Fates ordered it--that amongthe naval acquaintances of my betrothed, were two gentlemen who had just set foot upon the shores of
            England, aftera year's absence, each, in foreign travel. In company withthese
            gentlemen, my cousin and I preconcertedly, paid uncleRumgudgeon a visit on the
            afternoon of Sunday, October thetenth--just three weeks after the memorable decision
            whichhad so cruelly defeated our hopes. For about half an hourthe conversation
            ran upon ordinary topics; but at last, wecontrived, quite naturally, to give it the
            following turn:
         </p>
         
         <p>Capt. Pratt. "Well, I have been absent just one year.-Just one year to-day,as I live--let me see! yes!--this is October the tenth. You remember, Mr.
            Rumgudgeon, I called,this day year, to bid you good-bye. And by the way, it does
            seem something like a coincidence, does it not--that ourfriend Captain
            Smitherton, here, has been absent exactly ayear also--a year to-day?"
         </p>
         
         <p>Smitherton. "Yes! just one year to a fraction. You willremember, Mr. Rumgudgeon,
            that I called with Capt. Pratolon this very day, last year, to pay my parting
            respects."
         </p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "Yes, yes, yes--I remember it very well--veryqueer, indeed! Both of you gone
            just one year. A very strangecoincidence, indeed! Just what Doctor Dubble L. Dee
            woulddenominate an extraordinary concurrence of events. DoctorDub--"
         </p>
         
         <p>Kate. (Interrupting.) "To be sure, papa, it is somethingstrange; but then Captain
            Pratt and Captain Smithertondidn't go alttogether the same route, and that makes a
            difference, you know."
         </p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "I don't know any such thing, you huzzey! Howshould I? I think it only makes
            the matter more remarkable.Doctor Dubble L. Dee"--
         </p>
         
         <p>Kate. "Why, papa, Captain Pratt went round Cape Horn,and Captain Smitherton doubled
            the Cape of Good Hope."
         </p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "Precisely!--the one went east and the other wentwest, you jade, and they
            both have gone quite round theworld. By the bye, Doctor Dubble L. Dee"--
         </p>
         
         <p>Myself, (hurriedly.) "Captain Pratt, you must come andspend the evening with us
            to-morrow--you and Smitherton--you can tell us all about your voyage, and we'll have a
            gameof whist, and"--
         </p>
         
         <p>Pratt. "Whist, my dear fellow--you forget. To-morrow will be Sunday. Some other
            evening''--
         </p>
         
         <p>Kate. "Oh no, fie!--Robert's not quite so bad as that.To-day's Sunday."</p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "To be sure--to be sure!''</p>
         
         <p>Pratt. "I beg both your pardon's--but I can't be so muchmistaken. I know to-morrow's
            Sunday because"-- 
         </p>
         
         <p>Smitherton, (much surprised.) "What are you all thinking about? Was'nt
            yesterday Sunday, I should like toknow?"
         </p>
         
         <p>All. "Yesterday, indeed! you are out."</p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "To-day'a Sunday, I say--don't I know?"</p>
         
         <p>Pratt. Oh no!--to-morrow's Sunday."</p>
         
         <p>Smitherton. "You are all mad--every one of you. I am 
            as positive that yesterday was Sunday as I am that I sit uponthis
            chair."
         </p>
         
         <p>Kate, (jumping up eagerly.) "I see it--I see it all. Papa,this is a judgment upon
            you, about--about you know what.Let me alone, and I'll explain it all in a minute.
            It's a verysimple thing, indeed. Captain Smitherton says that yesterday was Sunday: so it was; he is right. Cousin Bobby, anduncle and I, say that
            to-day is Sunday: so it is; we are right.Captain Pratt maintains that to-morrow will
            be Sunday; soit will; he is right too. The fact is, we are all right, andthus
            three Sundays have come together in a week."
         </p>
         
         <p>Smitherton, (after a pause.) "By the bye, Pratt, Kate hasus completely. What fools
            we two are! Mr. Rumgudgeon,the matter stands thus: the earth, you know, is
            twenty-fourthousand miles in circumference. Now this globed the earthturns
            upon its own axis--revolves--spins round--thesetwenty-four thousand miles of extent,
            going from west toeast, in precisely twenty-four hours. Do you understand,Mr.
            Rumgudgeon?"
         </p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "To be sure--to be sure--Doctor Dub"-- </p>
         
         <p>Smitherton, (drowning his voice.) "Well, sir: that is atthe rate of one thousand
            miles per hour. Now suppose thatI sail from this position a thousand miles east. Of
            course, Ianticipate the rising of the sun here at London, by just onehour. I see the sun rise one hour before you do. Proceeding, in the same direction, yet another thousand miles, I anticipate the rising by two
            hours--another thousand, and Ianticipate it by three hours--and so on, until I go
            entirelyround the globe, and back to this spot, when, having gonetwenty-four
            thousand miles east, I anticipate the rising ofthe London sun by no less than
            twenty-four hours; that is tosay, I am a day in advance of your time. Understand, eh?"
         </p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "But Dubble L. Dee"-- .</p>
         
         <p>Smitherton, (speaking very loud.) "Captain Pratt, onthe contrary, when he had
            sailed a thousand miles west ofthis position, was an hour, and when he had sailed twentyfour thousand miles west, was twenty-four hours, or one day,
            behind the time at London. Thus, with me, yesterday wasSunday--thus, with you,
            to-day is Sunday--and thus, withPratt, to-morrow will be Sunday. And what is more,
            Mr.Rumgudgeon, it is positively clear that we are all right; forthere can be
            no philosophical reason assigned why the ideaof one of us should have preference
            over that of the other.
         </p>
         
         <p>Uncle. "My eyes!--well, Kate--well, Bobby!--this isa judgment upon me, as you say. But
            I am a man of myword-- mark that! you shall have her, boy (plum and all,)when
            you please. Done up, by Jove! Three Sundays all ina row! I'll go,and take Dubble L.
            Dee's opinion upon that.
         </p>
         
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE.</span>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         <div class="biblTitle">To One in Paradise</div>
         <div class="biblPage">295</div>
         
         <div class="head">TO ONE IN PARADISE.</div>
         
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>Thou wast all that to me, love,
            
            <br></br>For which my soul did pine--
            
            <br></br>A green isle in the sea, love,
            
            <br></br>A fountain and a shrine,
            
            <br></br>All wreathed with fairy fruits and flowers,
            
            <br></br>And all the flowers were mine.
            
            <br></br>Ah, dream too bright to last!
            
            <br></br>Ah, starry Hope! that didst arise But to be overcast!
            
            <br></br>A voice from out the Future cries,
            
            <br></br>"On! on!"--but o'er the Past
            
            <br></br>(Dim gulf!) my spirit hovering lies Mute, motionless, aghast!
            
            <br></br>For, alas! alas! with me The light of Life is o'er!
            
            <br></br>(Such language holds the solemn sea To the sands upon the shore)
            
            <br></br>Shall bloom the thunder-blasted tree,
            
            <br></br>Or the stricken eagle soar!
            
            <br></br>And all my days are trances,
            
            <br></br>And all my nightly dreams 
            
            <br></br>Are where thy dark eye glances,
            
            <br></br>And where thy footstep gleams--
            
            <br></br>In what ethereal dances,
            
            <br></br>By what eternal streams.
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Reviews</div>
         
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">The First Three Books of Homer's Iliad</div>
            <div class="biblPage">295</div>
            
            <p>The first Three Books of Homer's Iliad, according to the Ordidinary
               Text, and also with the restoration of the Digamma, towhich are appended English
               Notes, critical and explanatory, aMetrical Index, and Homer's Glossary. By 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Charles
                  Anthon
               </span>,L.L. D., Jay Professor of the Greek and Latin Languages in Columbia College, New York, and Rector of the Grammar School. NewYork:
               Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is one of the series of "School and College Classics"which have attracted so
               general an attention, first, from theircomprehensiveness, and admirable adaptation to their objects, and, secondly from their punctilious accuracy and beauty of typographical execution. We have seen richer, gaudier,
               but never more truly beautiful books. The Greek text, inthis Homer, with the
               frequent digammas, is certainly themost graceful and picturesque specimen of
               printing we everbeheld.
            </p>
            
            <p>The volume contains all of the Iliad which is usually readat school, as
               preparatory to a collegiate course--sufficientto furnish the student with the principles of Homeric translation and analysis. The text is, in the
               main, that of 
               <span class="person" id="spitzner">Spitz-ner</span>, which is now generally regarded as the
               best;--althoughon some occasions, alterations have been adopted, and the
               reasons given in a note. Besides the regular text of 
               <span class="person" id="spitzner">Spitzner</span>,there is that
               of 
               <span class="person" id="rpknight">Richard Payne Knight</span>, with the digammarestored according to his views. In fact,
               it is by no meansimprobable that this secondary text is at least a close approximation to the ancient orthography of Homer--althoughmany
               discrepancies might be pointed out, going to show thatin many cases the learned
               commentator could not have beenotherwise than wrong in his conjectures. The work
               ofKnight is extremely rare in this country, and even as a merematter of
               curious speculation, Dr. 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Anthon</span> has rendered apublic service by introducing the
               restorations in question.
            </p>
            
            <p>The commentary, as in all this series of classics, is peculiarly full
               and explicit--proceeding on the sole ground whichis admissible in matters of
               scholastic instruction--the groundthat the scholar is absolutely ignorant, and has need of information at all points, however seemingly trivial. No error
               ismore fatal in tuition, than that of taking it for granted thatthe student
               knows any thing at all. The materials of theNotes are derived, chiefly, from 
               <span class="person" id="fawolf">Wolf</span>,
               
               <span class="person" id="cbheyne">Heyne</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="buttman">Buttman</span>, 
               <span class="person" id="nagelsbach ">Na-gelsbach</span>, and 
               <span class="person" id="stadelmann">Stadelmann</span>, and the Commentary
               includesevery thing that is really valuable in the works of theseeminent
               scholars. The Glossary is separated from the Notes,--a very judicious
               arrangement--and contains a great dealof novel information in regard to the parsing
               of the HomericGreek. It is distinguished, also, from every Homeric Lexicon
               which has preceded it (in English) by its introduction andapplication to the Homeric text, of the Sanscrit and Linguistic Etymologies:--an Index to
               the Glossary is subjoined.The Metrical Index has been constructed with especial reference to the doctrine of the digamma and its bearing uponthe
               Homeric versification.
            </p>
            
            <p>Upon the whole, this edition of Homer is not only one ofthe most valuable of the series, but one of the most important additions to classical
               literature which this country orany other has produced.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">Letters from New York.</div>
            <div class="biblPage">295</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Letters from New York. Second Series. By 
               <span class="person" id="lmchild">L. M. Child</span>. New 
               
               <br></br>York. C. S. Francis, &amp; Co. 1845.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>The great popularity of the first series of Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lmchild">Child</span>'s letters from
               New York, will insure a hearty welcome and alarge sale for this new volume.
               Without possessing any ofthe charms which private epistles derive from their confidential revelations and bits of private scandal that all people love, the letters of Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lmchild">Child</span> make a direct appeal to 
               every human heart and cause the reader to feel as thoughthey had been
               addressed to himself personally. It is becausethe author opens her own heart that
               she gains admission tothe hearts of others so rapidly. Nothing will so disarm reserve as confidence; ice can alone be melted by heat; hatredand
               anger must be overcome by love and kindness. Bitter,sarcastic writers can never
               hope for popularity, or at leastlove. We rarely see one of 
               <span class="person" id="jswift">Swift</span>'s essays carried
               about as apocket companion, but the good natured genial writings of
               <span class="person" id="ogoldsmith">Goldsmith</span>
               are oftener bound up as pocket volumes than theworks of any other author. The
               popularity of Mrs. 
               <span class="person" id="lmchild">Child</span>'sletters must be attributed to a similar cause; and to
               the factthat they treat of human beings and things that interest humanity. The sympathies of men are more wide than weare apt to believe. The stories of washerwomen, of streetsweepers and little
               beggar children, interest us beyond themost elaborate histories of merely official
               personages. Mrs.
               <span class="person" id="lmchild">Child</span> instinctively seizes upon subjects which are interesting
               to all classes, to men and women rather than to statesmen,or ladies and
               gentlemen. The present volume of her lettershas a most taking table of contents.
               'Christmas,' 'Ole Bul,''New Year's Festivities,' 'Valentine's Day,' 'Fourth of
               July,''Children in Union Park,' 'Genius and Skill,' 'GreenwoodCemetery,'
               'The Violin,' 'Autumn Woods,' The Spirite ofTrade,' 'Sir Harry Falkland;' these
               are some of the titlesto the letters; suggestive of charming reading and delightful heart-touching subjects.
            </p>
            
            <p>We make an extract from the last letter. </p>
            
            <p>Rapid approximation to the European style of living is more andmore observable in this city. The number of servants in livery visibly increases every
               season. Foreign artistic upholsterers assert thatthere will soon be more houses in
               New York furnished according tothe fortune and taste of noblemen, than there are
               either in Paris orLondon; and this prophesy may well be believed, when the (act
               is considered that it is already not very uncommon to order furniturefor a
               single room, at the cost of ten thousand dollars. There wouldbe no reason to
               regret this lavishness, if the convenience and beautyof social environment were really increased in proportion to the expenditure, and if there were a
               progressive tendency to equality in thedistribution. But, alas, a few moments'
               walk from saloons superblyfurnished in the style of Louis 14th, brings us to
               Loafer's Hall, adreary desolate apartment, where shivering little urchins pay a
               centapiece, for the privilege of keeping out of watchmen's hands, bysleeping
               on boards ranged in tiers.
            </p>
            
            <p>But the effects of a luxurious and artificial life are sad enough onthose who
               indulge in it, without seeking for painful contrast amongthe wretchedly poor.
               Sallow complexions, feeble steps, and crookedspines, already show an obvious
               deterioration in beauty, grace, and jvigor. Spiritual bloom and elasticity are
               still more injured by modesof life untrue to nature. The characters of women
               suffer more than jthose of men, because their resources are fewer. Very many
               thingsare considered unfeminine to be done, and of those duties which are
               feminine by universal consent, few are deemed genteel by the upperclasses. It
               is not genteel for mothers to wash and dress their ownchildren, or make their
               clothing, or teach them, or romp with themin the open air. Thus the most beautiful
               and blessed of all humanrelations performs but half its healthy and renovating
               mission. Thefull, free, joyful growth of heart and soul is everywhere impeded by
               artificial constraint, and nature has her fountains covered by vanityand
               pride. Some human souls, finding themselves fenced within suchnarrow limits by
               false relations, seek fashionable distinction, or theexcitement of gossip,
               flirtation, and perpetual change, because theycan find no other unforbidden
               outlets for the irrepressible activity ofmind and heart. A very few, of nature's
               noblest and strongest,quietly throw off the weight that presses on them, and lend a comparatively true life in the midst of shams, which they reprove
               onlyby example. Those who can do this, without complaint or noise,and
               attempt no defence of their peculiar course, except the dailybeauty of their
               actions, will work out their freedom at last, in themost artificial society that
               was ever constructed; but the power todo this requires a rare combination of
               natural qualifier. For the fewwho do accomplish this difficult task, I even feel
               more respect thanI do for those who struggle upward under the heavy burden of
               earlypoverty. "For wealth bears heavier on talent, than poverty. Undergold
               mountains and thrones, who knows how many a spiritual giantmay lie crushed down
               and buried?" I once saw a burdock shoot upso vigorously, that it threw off a piece
               of board in the platform,which covered it front light and air. I had great respect
               for the braveplant, and even carried my sympathy so far, as to reproach myself
               for not haring lifted the board it was trying to bard to raise, insteadof
               watching it curiously, to see how much it could do. The pressureof artificial
               life, I cannot take off from souls that are born in themidst of it; and few have
               within themselves such uplifting life as theburdock.
            </p>
            
            <p>It is one of the saddest sights to see a young girl, born of wealthy and wordly parents, full of heart and soul, her kindly impulses continually checked by etiquette, her noble energies repressed by genteel limitations. She must not presume to love any body, till fatherand mother
               find a suitable match; she must not laugh loud because itis vulgar; she must not
               walk fast because it is ungenteel; she mustnot work in the garden, for fear the
               sun and wind may injure hercomplexion; she must sew nothing but gossamer, lest it
               mar thedelicacy of her hands; she must not study, because gentlemen donot
               admire literary ladies. Thus left without ennobling objects ofinterest, the feelings and energies are usually concentrated on frivolous and
               unsatisfactory pursuits, and woman becomes a by-word anda jest, for her giddy
               vanity, her love of dress and beaux.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Pencil of Nature</div>
            <div class="biblPage">296</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Pencil of Nature. By H. Fox Talbot: London, 1844. Imported 
               
               <br></br>by Wiley &amp; Putnam, 161 Broadway. Nos. 1
               and 2.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>This is the first attempt to publish a series of pictures, madeentirely by Nature herself. They are produced by the photographic process, and are of course as true, excepting in color, as truth herself. These
               reflections of Nature are fixedupon sensitive paper instead of metal plates, as in the Daguerrian process; and each picture is an original work. The
               "Pencil of Nature" is a somewhat fanciful term, and not avery correct one, for these impressions partake of the character of a medallion more
               than of painting. But we are notdisposed to pick differences about terms, the work
               itself isentitled to the highest consideration, and every one who inspects it will draw his own auguries of its influence on the
               imitative Arts. The author gives a very full and lucid statement
               of the first discovery of his art, and of the process bywhich it has been carried
               to its present high condition. Bypure chance, Monsieur Daguerre has reaped nearly
               all thehonors of the discovery which Mr. Fox Talbot made simultaneously with him. There are twelve plates in the twonumbers of Mr. Talbot's publication, which very satisfactorily prove the importance of the art
               in giving actual views ofalmost any kind of still life. In making copies of architectural ornaments and pictures, it must be found of very great
               advantage; and even in copying curious manuscripts and rareold books, it is
               found of great service, as may be seen froma fac-simile of a page of an old Norman-French book, containing the statutes of Richard the Second.
            </p>
            
            <p>The view on the Boulevard at Parts, taken from one of theupper windows of the
               Hotel de Douvres on the corner of theRue de la Paix, is a most delightful picture
               which transportsthe spectator in a visit to the French Capital. It has nothing of the doubtful aspect or indistinctness of a painting, butis
               indeed. Paris itself. The street has just been watered andis under repair, as seen
               by a couple of wheel-barrowswhich stand in the fore ground. By the road side a row
               ofCittadines and Cabriolets are waiting, and a carriage is standing in the distance. It is the Broadway, as much as this isBroadway which we
               look into when we raise our head.But, goodness, what a range of fantastic chimney-pipes borders the horizon, forest of flues of all conceivable
               shapes.The corner house on the right hand is a bathing house, with"Bains"
               painted on the wall. Saving the mansion with arailing in front it looks for all
               the world like a New Yorkhouse; we can look into the garret window and almost discern a Grisette at her employment. It is a cheap view of
               Paris.
            </p>
            
            <p>The most charming of all the impressions however is thereflection of an English
               haystack, which brings us an Englishmarket scene as truly as though we were
               looking out of anEnglish window upon an English farm-yard. The sunshinewhich
               falls upon it is English sun-shine; it has lighted upan object three thousand
               miles away, and now shines asbrightly on our desk as it did a year ago in
               Somersetshire,or in pleasant Kent, for the locality of the haystack is not
               given. The book itself, considered merely as a book, is arare specimen of
               luxurious publishing, and the ornament onthe cover is worth to an ornamental
               artist, for a study, morethan its contents
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">Saul, A Mystery</div>
            <div class="biblPage">296</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Saul, A Mystery. By the Author of "Christian Ballads," "Athan- 
               
               <br></br>asion," etc. etc. etc. New York: D. Appleton, &amp; Co.
            </div>
            
            <p>This poem was announced as about to be published in thefall of 1842, but withheld for private reasons. It is the longest dramatic work ever written, we believe, by an American,--occupying more than 280 pages, large
               duodecimo. Thehistory on which it is founded, is contained in the Books of
               Samuel, commencing with the twentieth chapter of the firstbook, and ending
               with the first chapter of the second. "Itmay be proper to say," says the author in
               a note, "that I amnot acquainted with any other poem in the language plotted 
               on the same incidents. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="wsotheby">Sotheby</span>'s Epic, which veryprobably occupies
               the same ground, I believe I have neverseen, and am sure that I never read."
            </p>
            
            <p>This we look upon as a very remarkable thing. How apoet, writing a Jong dramatic
               poem on the same theme, andwith the same title and hero which have been already employed by another, could have forborne (at least after the completion of his own work) to peruse the work of his fellow-laborer in the field, is to our apprehension, we say, a eery remarkable thing, and plainly shows Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="accoxe">Coxe</span> to be a very remarkable man.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have no faith in dramatic poems--they are paradoxical.What is poetical is not
               dramatic--what is dramatic is neverpoetical. "Saul," however, is not entitled a
               "DramaticPoem," but a "Mystery"--and if there is any thing in theWorld we
               detest, it is a mystery of any kind. We confess,therefore, that we proceed to the
               perusal of this book witha host of prejudice. We do not think we shall like it,
               andif we do not, we shall endeavor to say so, in the plainest ofall possible
               terms.
            </p>
            
            <p>In our next "Journal," we shall review the poem in full.At present, we have time
               only to extract a peculiar passage,--the whole of the first scene of the fourth
               act.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               Merodach. 
               
               <br></br>There crashed an avalanche,
               
               <br></br>From highest Libanus:
               
               <br></br>And ho! another falls a-near,
               
               <br></br>Glancing a thousand moonbeams,
               
               <br></br>As the crystal rocks of ice,
               
               <br></br>Go thundering down below.
               
               <br></br>And hark! it is the mother-eagle screams,
               
               <br></br>As snaps the high branched pine,
               
               <br></br>And her nest and her brood are buried.
               
               <br></br>Far, far, in the valley below,
               
               <br></br>The peasant awakes in fear,
               
               <br></br>As he hears the alarum on high,
               
               <br></br>And the booming destruction comes down!
               
               <br></br>He wakes, and he prayeth his prayers;
               
               <br></br>The prayers that he prayeth are vain.
               
               <br></br>A mountain is piled on his roof and his home,
               
               <br></br>And the cry, and the crashing are still.
               (Climbs higher.)
               
               <br></br>Earth, in these solitudes,
               
               <br></br>Makes bold to talk with God,
               
               <br></br>And lifts her head sublime to heaven,
               
               <br></br>Where breaks no mortal voice On the long Sabbath of her quietness.
               
               <br></br>But spirits, where are ye In icy fetters pining;
               
               <br></br>Ye who once chained the soul of Saul;
               
               <br></br>Ye whom the harp disarmed,
               
               <br></br>When David rallied his good angels,
               
               <br></br>To drag ye hither through the viewless? Spirits, say where!
               (Pauses.)
               
               <br></br>If such the might of song;
               
               <br></br>Ye too shall have enchanters Mimicking once more The spell of Moses' rod:
               
               <br></br>And Pytho shall be praised upon the lyre,
               
               <br></br>Loud as the Hebrew's Lord.
               
               <br></br>A blind old man shall be To roam the sunny islands,
               
               <br></br>That float upon the sea,
               
               <br></br>And on their hills, and on their valleys,
               
               <br></br>Forever, shall his song enshrine A fair idolatry.
               (Climbs higher.)
               
               <br></br>Enchantress hear'st me not,
               
               <br></br>That calledst me afar?
               
               <br></br>I come to bid the spirits back again,
               
               <br></br>And seven beside, more strong.
               
               <br></br>Their harper foe is gone forever,
               
               <br></br>And Saul is thine once more.
               
               <br></br>Say witch, where art thou?
               Voice.
               
               <br></br>Come on!
               Merodach.
               
               <br></br>Ah, Magdiel, art thou there?
               Voice.
               
               <br></br>Ay, teaching the new seven. Did ye hear
               
               <br></br>The snowballs that we bowled upon your head?
               
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">Never too Late</div>
            <div class="biblPage">297</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Never too Late. By 
               <span class="person" id="cburdett">Charles Burdett</span>. New York. D. Appleton, &amp; Co. Be-
               
               <br></br>ing of a second series of tales for the people.
            </div>
            
            <p>One of those simple little tales of every day life, written to enforce apious
               lesson, which always proves popular, and is doubtless foundconducive to the object
               aimed at. Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="cburdett">Burdett</span> is already favorablyknown as the author of two or three
               other books of the same class.It is published in a neat style, uniform with the
               well known "series offor the people," issued by the same publishers.
            </p>
            
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Magazines</div>
         
         <div class="head">THE MAGAZINES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Knickerbocker</div>
            <div class="biblPage">297</div>
            <div class="ab">The Knickerbocker.
               <br></br>Democratic Review.
               <br></br>Hunt's Merchant's Magazine.
               
               <br></br>American Review and Whig Magazine.--(
               <span class="person" id="ghcolton">Colton</span>.)
            </div>
            
            <p>The Knickerbocker presents its customary variety in itstable of contents besides a grand piece de resistance, composed of 
               <span class="person" id="apike">A. Pike</span>, and its Editor's
               table the usual variety ofpleasant gossip. We are sorry to see that Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="lgclark">Clark</span> has involved himself in a quarrel with Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>, and more sothat
               he should have found anything in our own columns thatby transplanting will wear an
               appearance of hostility to thatgentleman. Our remarks, which the Editor of the Knickerbocker has quoted, were meant to apply solely to Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>'s manner, and not to his matter, for we had notheard enough of his
               lectures to enable us to form an opinionof his views of his subject; but we were
               strongly impressedwith a feeling of respect for Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>'s opinions, from the
               little that we did hear.
            </p>
            
            <p>The feature of the Democratic Review is an essay oneducation by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>, from
               which the public may forma correct idea of his style and thoughts. Many who have
               long been in the habit of calling all New-Englanders reformers and transcendentalists, will be struck with his strong Conservatism.
               Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span> has constantly an eye to thefuture, like the majority of his
               countrymen, but he also keepsan eye fixed steadily upon the past. He believes in
               the goodold times. The Democratic has several admirable articlesbesides Mr.
               
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span>'s. The Essayist on English letter writersfrom the time of 
               <span class="person" id="jhowell">Howell</span> to 
               <span class="person" id="clamb">Lamb</span>,
               makes a very singularomission in leaving 
               <span class="person" id="hwalpole">Horace Walpole</span> out of his Catalogue.
               This is like leaving 
               <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span> out of the list of EnglishDramatists, or
               Fielding from the Catalogue of Novelists.Walpole is the only Englishman whose
               letters form thecirculating portion of his works. We read the letters of other
               authors on account of their other productions: but we read
               <span class="person" id="hwalpole">Walpole</span>'s works,
               because we have read his letters. Wehave extracted a good part of the Essay on
               writing for theMagazines, for its genial humor and magazinity, into another part of our columns. The portrait of the Democratic forthis month is a striking likeness of McDuffie, of South Carolina, copied
               from a daguerreotype.
            </p>
            
            <p>Hunt's Magazine has a translation from 
               <span class="person" id="coquelin">M. Coquelin</span>,by 
               <span class="person" id="hccarey">Henry C. Carey</span>, of
               Philadelphia, on the CommercialAssociations of France and England, a paper on the
               ErieCanal Enlargement, by 
               <span class="person" id="jbjervis">J. B. Jervis</span>, of New-York, on theCorn Trade of the
               United Stales, by 
               <span class="person" id="chudson">Charles Hudson</span>, ofMassachusetts, a review of the Exploring
               Expedition, anda great amount of of statistical matter.
            </p>
            
            <p>The American Review, Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="ghcolton">Colton</span>'s Whig Magazine,is almost a duplicate of the
               Democratic Review exceptingthe complexion of its politics. The first article, by
               Dr.
               <span class="person" id="dfbacon">Bacon</span> "The Mystery of Iniquity," is forcibly written, andinfinitely more
               exciting than any of the 'mysteries', notexcepting Saul, that have recently been
               published. It readsvery much like a chapter from the mysteries of Paris. The
               paper by Mr. 
               <span class="person" id="hnhudson">Hudson</span> "on reading" will do very well as a Seqaul to
               one on Education in the Democratic. It is worthan infinite number of such Essays
               as that by 
               <span class="person" id="jpycroft">Pycroft</span>, a cheapedition of which has recently been published. The
               reviewof the ' Vestiges of Creation,' is the most vigorous attackthat has yet been made on that much abused and much bepraised work. The
               embellishment of the Whig Review, isa portrait of John Quincy Adams, neither very commendable as a portrait or as a work of art. The biographical sketch of the old-man-eloquent, as the country newspapers will persist in calling the venerable ex-President,contains an extract
               from his diary when he was twenty-fiveyears old, which will let him down in the
               eyes of goodpeople several rounds on the ladder of fame.
            </p>
            
            <p>Taking them together, these four works exhibit a higherreach in the department of
               magazine literature, than thecountry has ever offered before. While the three
               dollarmagazines, cheap and flashy, flourish best in Philadelphia,the five
               dollar ones thrive best in New York; indeed it isthe only place, except Richmond,
               Va., where one has everthrived at all. But there is still room for another to
               administer 
               to tastes and preserve interests, which the others neglect.No magazine
               in this country has yet done anything for theinterests of art, but there is a growing appetite in tne American people for works of artistic
               excellence, which we trustthat some intelligent publisher will before long turn to
               aprofitable account.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">Blackwood</div>
            <div class="biblPage">298</div>
            <p>BLACKWOOD.--Mess. Leonard, Scott &amp; Co. have issued the Aprilnumber of
               Blackwood. It contains eight papers of varied excellence,but all good. "Ping-Kee's
               view of the stage" is piquant exceeding,ly, and 
               <span class="person" id="jwilson">North</span>'s Account of 
               <span class="person" id="jdryden">Dryden</span>(although disfigured with the usual carelessness and rant of 
               <span class="person" id="jwilson">Wilson</span>) is an admirable essay. The continuation of the papers called "
               Confessions of an Opium Eater" isbetter, we think, than the original--which was a
               lie throughout.There is yet room for a book on opium eating, which shall be the
               most profoundly interesting volume ever penned. It would be written,however,
               by no 
               <span class="person" id="tdequincey">De Quincy</span>.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p14">
         <div class="biblTitle">New Works in Press</div>
         <div class="biblPage">298</div>
         
         <div class="head">NEW WORKS IN PRESS.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">London, April 1, 1845.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Sybil, a novel. By 
            <span class="person" id="bdisraeli">D'Israeli</span>, author of "Coningsby."
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Life of the late Lord Hill. By the 
            <span class="person" id="esidney">Rev Edwin Sydney</span>. 8vo.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Travels in North America, with Geological Observations. By
            <br></br>
            <span class="person" id="clyell">Charles Lyell</span>, F. R.
            S., with plates.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Naval Worthies of the Reign of Queen Elizabeth. By 
            <span class="person" id="jbarron">John Barron</span>,
            <br></br>Esq.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">The Tree Rose, Practical Instructions for its formation and Culture.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">The Literature of Political Economy. By 
            <span class="person" id="jrmcculloch">J. R. Mc. Culloch</span>, Esq.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Physical Condition of New South Wales and Van Dieman's Land.
            <br></br>8vo.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">The Lady's Country Companion. By Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="jcloudon">Lowdon</span>.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Richard the Third; a poem. By 
            <span class="person" id="sturner">Sharon Turner</span>, Esq.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">A Dictionary of Greek and Roman Biography and Mythology. Edi
            <br></br>ted by
            Dr. 
            <span class="person" id="wsmith">William Smith</span>,Editor of the Dictionary of Greek and
            <br></br>Roman Antiquities--to be
            completed in 3 vols. 8vo.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Overland Sketches of the Pyramids, Cataracts, Deserts, Mosques,
            <br></br>etc. By Lieut. 
            <span class="person" id="cbyoung">C.
               B. Young
            </span>.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Finden's Beauties of the Poets--a series of their principal female
            <br></br>characters. To
            be issued monthly.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Parrot's Ascent of Mount Ararat: being the first vol. of 
            <span class="person" id="wdcooley">Cooley</span>'s
            <br></br>"World
            Surveyed."
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p15">
         <div class="biblTitle">Eothen</div>
         <div class="biblPage">298</div>
         
         <div class="head">EOTHEN</div>
         
         <p>The editor of the Buffalo Journal has started an ingeniousthought in respect to
            this brilliant book of travel, which willnot in the smallest degree diminish its
            value, even thoughhis thought should prove a fact. He thinks that Eothen was
            composed upon the plan of the Amber Witch and Lady Wil-,loughby's Diary, and
            that the success of the former work ledto the composition of Eothen. We copy a part
            of his re-;marks, which are certainly very plausible.
         </p>
         
         <p>We are more than half inclined to suspect that the success of theAmber Witch has
            provoked the really clever writer of Eothen to test,by a like experiment, the boasted infallibility of the English Reviewers. Sparkling as most of the
            sketches in Eothen are, there is notfrom beginning to end a single passage that could not have been written by a man of vivid imagination--such as the writer evidently possesses__without removing from his library. Hundreds
            of writers ofworks, avowedly fictitious, display quite as much of graphic fidelity
            to nature in describing scenery, costumes and manners, with whichthey have no
            other acquaintance than through books.
         </p>
         
         <p>The reader of Eothen will note that the author carefully avoids allticklish ground,
            and never ventures upon any description the fidelityof which can be tested by actual
            observation. Thus his journey fromBelgrade to Constantinople, his residence in that
            city, his visit to theplain of Troy, his description of Smyrna, &amp;c., although
            specimens ofvery beautiful writing, are yet so vague, shadowy, and indistinct, that
            of the thousands who have visited the same places none can say thatthis is
            true, this false, except in the general way that every well readman can make the
            same averment--We see the writer and read hisreflections, but we see nothing of the
            East.
         </p>
         
         <p>His visit to Lady Hester Stanhope is described with more particularity of detail, for the reason that on such a theme the writer felt himself
            on safe ground. Lady Hester is dead, and so cannot contradictany statement he may
            make, and besides, she was so eccentric, sawso few travellers, and her mood so
            changed from time to time, thatthe writer of Eothen might let his fancy run riot in
            description, andnone could convict him of fiction. His adventures in Palestine, with 
         </p>
         
         <p>descriptions of what he saw, could easily have been made up frombooks, and the
            hints derived from the conversation of friends whohad actually visited the Holy
            Land. The whole of that portion lookslike patch-work, made brilliant by the glow of
            a fervid imagination.
         </p>
         
         <p>But we are willing to stake the whole argument on the chapter of"Cairo and the
            Plague." If any one can read that and verily believethe writer ever witnessed and
            passed through what he professes, heneed not stagger at any thing. The same is true
            of what he saysrespecting the Pyramids, and that incredible, solitary ride on a dromedary, in the night, across the desert, to Suez.--Look, too, at
            Baalbec,despatched, literally, in a dozen lines of dreamy mystification, containing not one definite idea. We might go on with particulars, but
            these are enough to direct inquiry to the point we wish. The mocking tone in which much of the book is written, gives piquancy to it,while at the same time it suggests that the wicked writer was chuckling over the
            success of his scheme to mystify the Aristarchuses of thereviews. The view we have
            taken of the book in no way detracts fromits literary merits, which are of a very
            high order; but what fun itwill be to the writer to have so effectually mystified the erudite, elaborate, and solemn Quarterly, the keen, critical acumen
            of Blackwood,and the very respectable reading public generally? We should like
            to have the opinions of our critical friends of the Mirror and the Broadway Journal upon this matter.
         </p>
         
         <p>If the travels of 
            <span class="person" id="jbruce">Bruce</span>, published with his own name, andaccompanied by numerous
            original drawings of the objectsthat he saw in his journeyings, were looked upon as apocryphal, it would not be a strange matter if a book like Eothen,
            which has been published anonymously, should be regardedas a fiction. But its
            authenticity has never been doubted inEngland, where the author must be well known. Its authorship has been attributed to a barrister named Trevilian, and
            we have no doubt that it is a perfectly true book. The beauty of
            the style, the light-hearted novelesque manner of thenarrative, and the absence of
            such statistical matter as wegenerally find in books of travel, all help to give it
            an air ofromance. But these are just the points which a good artist,like the
            author of Eothen, would have regarded, and to makehis book appear true, he would
            have introduced some of thecharacteristics of other true books; as the author of the Amber Witch has done. But its originality is one of the strongest evidences of its genuineness. Nothing could be moreeasy than to
            get up, without leaving one's library, a book ofEastern travel that would thoroughly
            deceive the public; butonly a very great artist could have hit upon the novel idea
            of practising a deception by framing a work unlike any otherthat had ever
            appeared on the same subject, and instead ofusing the same materials which others
            had brought fromthe east, to reject them altogether. But it would be impossible for the author to take his reader to a region which hehad never
            visited himself. Eothen brings the east to usmore vividly than any other eastern
            traveller has done; suchspots as Baalbec are hurriedly and dreamily sketched, because other travellers had described them minutely. Thereis a
            minuteness of honesty in many parts of Eothen, whichappears exceedingly like the work of an ingenious artist rather than the effect of an ingenuous mind; but they are few,and the marks of sincerity and honesty are many. We readthe
            work with entire faith, satisfied that if the author werenot a true traveller, he
            was in the highest degree a trueartist.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p16">
         <div class="biblTitle">Bobus Smith</div>
         <div class="biblPage">298</div>
         
         <div class="head">BOBUS SMITH.</div>
         
         <p>It is not generally known to American readers, that the Rev. 
            <span class="person" id="ssmith">Syd-ney
               Smith
            </span> had a brother who was nearly as bright a genius as thegreat wit himself.
            Robert Smith, commonly called Bobus by hisfriends, died just a fortnight after the decease of his elder and more famous brother. We find the following
            biographical notice in the lastnumber of the London Critic, the new weekly review
            which defends thecause of Young England:
         </p>
         
         <p>"It has very recently fallen to our lot to attempt some commemoration
            of the life, character, and genius of the late Rev.
            <span class="person" id="ssmith">Sydney Smith</span>. We little
            apprehended at the time that weshould so soon afterwards be called upon to record
            the deathof his brother, elder by one year, Robert Smith, Esq., whichtook
            place on the day fortnight after the other. These twomost remarkable men had always
            entertained a strong degreeof reciprocal attachment and admiration for each other;
            butthe life of the elder had, especially of late years, been so comparatively withdrawn from the more prominent scenes ofbusiness and society, that
            we have little doubt that we shallsurprise the larger proportion of our readers by
            affirming that,while the younger justly attracted an ampler share of thepublic
            notice by the more active part he bore in questions and measures affecting
            the public welfare, and while in aspecies of inspiration which he imparted to mirth
            and wit,though by no means his most valuable characteristic, he,among the men
            of his own, and perhaps of any time, maywith truth be pronounced inimitable; at the
            same time, webelieve that the most discerning of the contemporaries whowere
            happy enough to enjoy the friendship of both--we aresure that the lamented Sydney
            himself--would in extent ofacquirement, in original force of thought, in mastery of
            mind,have given the palm to Robert, or to call him by the namehe inherited
            from the happy familiarity of early days, BobusSmith.
         </p>
         
         <p>"We cannot pretend to give a full or accurate account of hislife. He was born iu
            1770. At Eton he was the intimateassociate of Canning, 
            <span class="person" id="jhfrere">Frere</span>, and Lord Holland, and a contributor to the Microcosm. At Cambridge he materially addedto
            the reputation for scholarship and classical compositionwhich he had established at school; and if the most fastidious critic of our day would diligently
            peruse the threeTriposes which he composed in Lucretian rhythm, on thethree
            systems of Plato, Descartes, and Newton, we believethat we should not run the least
            risk of incurring the chargeof exaggeration, in declaring our belief that these compositions in Latin verse have not been excelled since Latin was
            a living language. Be this said with the peace of 
            <span class="person" id="jmilton">Milton</span> and
            <span class="person" id="acowley">Cowley</span>--with the
            peace of his fellow Etonians, 
            <span class="person" id="tgray">Grey</span> andLord Wellesley.
         </p>
         
         <p>"We are not aware that we can refer to any subsequentcompositien by Mr. Smith which
            could be put on a level withthese youthful effusions. We should, indeed, imagine
            thatno person with his powers of intellect had ever published solittle. Nor
            were his achievements in active public life, fromthe same fastidious aversion to
            display, though by no meanswanting in usefulness, at all commensurate with the ideas
            conceived of him by every one that approached him. He wasnine years in Bengal as Advocate General, and one short extract from Sir 
            <span class="person" id="jmackintosh">James Macintosh</span>'s
            Diary may show the valueentertained for him there:--"I hear frequently of Bobus; always merry and always kind. Long live Bobus!" 
         </p>
         
         <p>We believe his acquaintances were disposed to form brilliant auguries
            of what he was likely to effect as a speaker inParliament. His first essay, in 1812,
            is supposed not to havecome up at least to the mark of his own fastidious judgment,
            and he seldom afterwards addressed the House at any length,or upon subjects
            which excited the contest and passions ofparties. He rendered, however, really
            eminent services asa most diligent and pains-taking member of committees,which
            might have put many an idle mediocrity to the blush.He finally retired from Parliament in 1826. He spent the remainder of his life in comparative
            retirement, in the sereneenjoyment of the various literature he loved, and the cheerful intercourse of the restricted society that delighted him.
            Nothing can be imagined more rich and racy in its varietyof material, and in its force of reflection, than his conversation. "Pourquoi ne parlez-vous comme-ca dans la Chambre des Communes?" said Madame de Stael to him one
            day,after listening for some time to its eloquent flow; thoughthere was in it
            nothing of the harangue, in its manly easeand simplicity it partook of his
            character; there was muchin him of the sturdy Saxon combined with the refined and
            thoroughly finished scholar. No one was ever so clear of allfrippery, and the
            only thing for which he probably felt notoleration was a prig. Of his conversation
            Mr. Canning said"Bobus's language is the essence of English."
         </p>
         
         <p>In his inner domestic life he was full of gentle and attaching
            qualities. He married Caroline Vernon, daughter ofRichard Vernon, esq. and Evelyn,
            Countess of Upper Ossory.He lost a son and a daughter in their prime of youth, each
            ofmost rare promise. His eldest son, and only survivingchild, is the Right Hon. R. Vernon Smith, M. P. for Northampton.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p17">
         <div class="biblTitle">Professor Gouraud</div>
         <div class="biblPage">299</div>
         
         <p>Professor 
            <span class="person" id="ffgouraud">Gouraud</span>.--The following extract from theProfessor's lecture on Memory, is
            a remarkable instance offluent writing in a foreigner, who, three or four years
            since,was almost ignorant of our languge. 
            <span class="person" id="ffgouraud">M. Gouraud</span>'s styleis somewhat too
            luxuriant for these days of classic severity,but it has wonderful ease as the
            production of a foreigner.
         </p>
         
         <p>Already have the birds of night, preceded by the white-winged owl,who seems to
            serve them as a warning beacon, begun to regain theirobscure retreats in the shadowy
            depths of the forests: the timid hare  and cautious deer have already left the
            open fields for the more propi- 
         </p>
         
         <p>tious shadow of the woods. At their return, the implacable eagle andthe voracious
            hawk begin to prepare anew their sharp talons for themorning's hunt; while,
            disengaging their heads from underneath thewarm wings which covered them during the
            night, the birds of dayamong whom they must soon choose again their prey, little
            foreseeingthe cruel fate which may and which must before long overtake them,
            open their eyes, shuffle their glossy feathers, and begin to hop frombranch to
            branch, as if to stretch their little limbs, and prepare theirlight wings for
            flight.
         </p>
         
         <p>All at once, the air rings with a melodious sound, which causes theatmosphere to
            vibrate afar, with a sweet and tremulous thrill; theecho, hitherto silent, repeats
            it in successive adulations to the distantstreamlet of the valley. Immediately cadencing a harmonious roulade, which seems to run over a thousand
            varied notes at once thefairy voice which produced these ravishing sounds awakens
            all thesurrounding echoes, and they repeat it in chorus--while the voice itself
            seems to pause, as if, submerged in the torrent of harmonies withwhich she has
            filled the atmosphere, she were listening to herself inrapturous astonishment. At
            these enchanting accents, the joyoustroop are suddenly arrested, as if under the
            infatuation of a spell tolisten also; for they have recognised the harmonious
            ringing notes ofthe lyric enchantress of the groves, the morning leader of the songsters of the forest--the melodious nightingale! who, already preluding at her morning concerts, offers thus abruptly her first salutations
            to Aurora, always attentive to her songs. It would seem indeed thather
            melodious notes had been carried by the surrounding echoes evento the carminated
            gates of the horizon, and were understood by theelements; for Aurora at the moment
            seems to have redoubled herpace. The birds, preluding already to the harmonies of
            their matinhymns, seem to prepare themselves for singing her triumphs. Attheir
            head is the rustic cuckoo, the gay linnet, the lively red-breastand the sensitive
            turtle-dove. The nightingale by their side, presidingt over the concert, redoubles
            her harmonious cadences, as the Goddessof the dawn approaches. Most of the stars
            have vanished from thefirmament; the heavens now appear like an ocean of shining
            gold andliquid gems of a thousand hues. And now Aurora reigns in undisputed
            sovereignty. But, alas! "a natural image of pleasure: as nothing ismore
            beautiful than her reign, so nothing is shorter than its duration."
         </p>
         
         <p>The god of day follows her with hasty steps; she must soon resignher empire, like
            the night, which just now fled so rapidly before her. In vain the hours, with
            redoubled energy, scatter in precipitated floodstheir bouquets of roses beneath her
            steps; she must finally yield--thegod of day has almost overtaken her! Already he is
            announced bythe more vivid tints which he pours around him. The glowing rays
            but just precede the dazzling glare; the east seems on fire: it appearssuddenly
            all in flames. At their effulgency, the burning disc is eachmoment expected; at
            every instant he seems about to appear--at lasthe rises majestically from the liquid
            abyss! A brilliant pencil offlame, starting forth like a flash of lightning, and
            suddenly filling allspace, seems, like the bow of a celestial orchestra, to have
            given thelast signal for the awakening of all nature. It is the Sun, who has
            just touched upon the horizon with the edge of his inflamed disc.-Red as a
            purpuereal sphere of gleaming Vermillion, and at first of animmense size, he
            gradually ascends from behind a wide-spreadingcurtain of clouds, which he soon
            pierces with a thousand pencils oflight, forming a gigantic glory, whose superior
            rays curve themselvesinto an immense arch, which reaches to the zenith. "Then the
            veilof darkness being entirely effaced, man is again permitted to recognise his abode, which he finds everywhere beautified and embellished.
            The verdure has taken during the night fresh vigor and renewed freshness; the new-born day which shines upon it, the first rays which gildit display
            it covered with a brilliant net-work of dew, which reflectsto the eye the light and
            the colors of the rainbow!"
         </p>
         
         <p>The merry troop is again arrested to contemplate with ecstatic feelings
            the glorious spectacle, which has been thus gradually developedbefore them. Meanwhile all nature has been awakened, at that sublime moment,--when the
            disc of the sun touched lightly upon thehorizon--the birds were re-united in chorus,
            and now they cause allthe echoes of their melodious warblings to resound in concert.
            Notone remains silent; their musical songs, feeble at first, are more tender and sweet than during the remainder of the day--they seem as if
            tinged with the softness and mellow ness of a languid awakening.-Imitating
            their merry concerts, the insects hum beneath the grass;the fishes in the streams
            dart along the surface of the water, and leapwith jov, sparkling in the light with
            their silver scales; the reptilescrawl from their dark and humid holes, and come to
            bask in the warmsun-light; and even the serpent himself, raising up his hideous head
            above his spiral coils, and darting out his scarlet longue, unable to sing
            praises hisses forth bis ceaseless curse! Every thing, finally, is excited and moved throughout all nature; every thing breathes joy and
            happiness at the first rays of the rising Sun--and the planets themselves do they not bound forward in their empyreal course morerapidly and more
            animatedly as they approach him nearer and nearerin their perihelion? . . . . . 
         </p>
         
         <p>But to speak only of things more accessible to the observer; athis appearance the
            camel of the desert is said to kneel while turninghimself towards the east; the
            eagle stretches broad his extendedwings, while fixing his piercing eye upon his
            burning disc; and theelephant salutes him with his flexible proboscis: or rather, do
            notall the animals salute in his image, by an irresistible impulse, in this
            universal concert and by these testimonials of respect and gladness,HIM of whom
            the Sun is but the shadow?-the universal Father andBenefactor, above all empyreal suns! And yet, "although the concourse of all these objects carries to the sense an impression of freshness which seems to penetrate even to
            the soul," man alone, of allcreated beings, almost always forgets himself in presence of a spectacle so majestic and sublime! . . . . . . .
         </p>
         
         <p>Soon the laborers resume their wonted toils; the flocks and herdsare reconducted to
            the fields; the butterflies begin to flit from flower 
            to flower, the bees of the neighbouring trees come to dispute withthem for the sweet ambrosia of their streaming nectaria; the ladybirds leave their rosy couches; the gilded day-beetles quit their protecting
            recesses, while those of the night regain their mossy cells.The nocturnal flowers
            fold their humid petals, while the blossoms ofthe day unfold their fresh corollas.
            The dew evaporates beneaththe increasing heat of the Sun, whose vivifying influence,
            animatingall nature, infuses life, vigor, and gladness into every particle of
            matter, into every sensitive bosom.......
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p18">
         <div class="biblTitle">Anniversary Week</div>
         <div class="biblPage">300</div>
         
         <div class="head">ANNIVERSARY WEEK.</div>
         
         <p>In addition to the usual religious societies which hold theiranniversaries in this
            city during the second week in May,we have this season a convention of Infidels,
            whose meetingsare held in a small brick building in Broadway called the
            Coliseum. The city was startled at the sight of placards onthe corners of all the principal streets, headed Infidel Convention, notifying the people
            that a meeting of infidels wouldbe held at certain hours during Sunday. We like the honesty of these people, in proclaiming their Infidelity, although
            it appears that the great man among them, Mr. Owen, objected to the term, and preferred being called, a "friend of universal freedom and unlimited charity," which is a very comprehensive designation, but not a
            very forcible one. TheTribune makes some strange comments upon this convention,
            which we do not fully comprehend, but they appear to ushighly commendatory. "
            Saying nothing of the influence ofbelief," says the paper, "who can doubt that the isolated condition of all infidels, their independence of the restraining influence of sympathy and fellowship are clearly unfavorable
            tohigh moral attainments? We rejoice, then, that they haveresolved to know
            each other, and fix upon some definite andendearing plan of organization and
            action."
         </p>
         
         <p>This is surely very distinct and unequivocal. A paperpossessing the immense
            circulation of the Tribune, which istaken in many pious families for the reason that
            it excludestheatrical advertisements, and other wicked matter from itscolumns,
            is rejoiced that the infidels in this country have hadthe shrewdness to adopt the machinery by which other classes of men contrive to strengthen
            themselves in their errors,and trusts that they may fix upon some plan for rendering
            their infidelity enduring. The want of "high moral attainments"
            among infidels, the Tribune attributes to theisolated manner in which they have
            heretofore lived, andthinks that by meeting together frequently, and adopting the
            machinery of a party, whereby they may become more thoroughly imbued with infidelity, that their morals will be improved. The morality
            and the reasoning of the Tribune aredecidedly original, and we would advise the
            proprietors toget out a patent for them.
         </p>
         
         <p>It appears that Mrs. Rose, the somewhat celebrated clairvoyante, a
            Polish lady, who resides in this city, was amongthe speakers at the Coliseum, and
            that Judge Herttell wasappointed chairman. The Tribune says that Robert Owen
            addressed the meeting briefly and sensibly, and of the convention
            it expresses the belief that "an elevation of the aimsand an improvement of the morals of many will be the consequence." The Tribune, according to its manner of reasoning in the premises, would be rejoiced to see a
            convention ofcounterfeiters or pickpockets, or horse thieves, for the isolated
            manner in which these people live is very destructive to thesocial sympathies, and "devotion to their party or sex, solicitude for us welfare, and
            pride in its respectability wouldmake them behave better than they otherwise
            would."
         </p>
         
         <p>The wisdom of conventions, even for professedly benevolent purposes, is very questionable, but there can be no question of the evil which must
            result from party machinery,being adopted by men whose sole object is to bind themselves in a compact of infidelity.
         </p>
         
         <p>No less than twenty-three different associations, mostlyreligious, have held their
            anniversaries during the week.Among the societies, we perceive one of a winning
            title, the"National Reform Association." We should suppose thateverybody would
            be anxious to enrol themselves among itsmembers; yet it appears that only
            twenty-five personsgathered together at its anniversary, which, after all, is
            about the number of men in the country who are favorableto National Reform. The
            Foreign Evangelical Society cannumber its thousands of members. Our Charity is not
            one  of the domestic virtues; she begins abroad, and, in manycases ends
            there.
         </p>
         
         <p>In New Haven there has been a grand gathering of ScientificGentlemen during the last week, and much important information has been disseminated, and
            many curious discoveriesmade public. One of the members discovered a fossil pun,
            which seemed to afford the association a vast amount ofpleasure, it being
            probably the first discovery of the kindever made.
         </p>
         
         <p>Somebody gave an account of marks which had beenfound on a rock, resembling the
            human foot without toes, or afoot with the toes frozen off. Professor Silliman, junior remarked that it had long been a no-toe-rious fact.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p19">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Crossing's Sweeper</div>
         <div class="biblPage">300</div>
         
         <div class="head">THE CROSSING'S SWEEPER.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>With unkempt hair, and shoeless feet,
            
            <br></br>The untitled sov'reign of the street,
            
            <br></br>With broom in hand,
            
            <br></br>Of charity may crave a mite,--
            
            <br></br>Pass him not by, it is a sight He may command.
            
            <br></br>Pass him not by without a sign,
            
            <br></br>You recognize the shape divine In him, though poor;
            
            <br></br>Kind words, if not a coin, will soothe,
            
            <br></br>And make his rugged pathway smooth,
            
            <br></br>More than before.
            
            <br></br>Pass him not by! Ye know not men,
            
            <br></br>But God with his omniscient ken Has placed him there,
            
            <br></br>To make his country's annals bright,
            
            <br></br>When the plebeian claims his right And spurns despair.
            
            <br></br>Ay! 'neath that tattered, brimless hat,
            
            <br></br>May rest a spirit great as that Which shook the world,
            
            <br></br>And bent all Europe to its rod,
            
            <br></br>While kings who ruled by grace of God,
            
            <br></br>From thrones were hurled.
            
            <br></br>A time may come when 'neath a sky,
            
            <br></br>Brighter than that dark canopy,
            
            <br></br>That shades him now;
            
            <br></br>He yet may stand to clear your way,
            
            <br></br>And pointing out a brighter day,
            
            <br></br>Enwreathe his brow.
            
            <br></br>The head now pillowing on a stone,
            
            <br></br>Despised, uncared for, and lone,
            
            <br></br>May one day rise,
            
            <br></br>High plumed on its eagle wings,
            
            <br></br>To sit above your sceptred kings,
            
            <br></br>Eloquent, wise!
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">S. A. W.</span>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Musical Items</div>
         
         <div class="head">MUSICAL ITEMS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Boehm Flute</div>
            <div class="biblPage">300</div>
            
            <p>The Bcehm Flute.--We rarely have the good fortune tobe able to chronicle one really useful improvement in musical instruments; numberless modern
               inventions come underour notice daily, but they are, for the most part, if not entirely, valueless--of but little practical advantage.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Boehm Flute is, however, a noble exception; welook upon it as the most
               valuable improvement ever effectedin this instrument; and we believe, although
               there is nolimit to the ingenuity of the human intellect, that it bringsthe
               flute as near perfection as it ever will be. It not onlyrenders every scale of the
               instrument comparatively easy,but it ensures, beyond every contingency, that every
               scaleshall be in perfect tune. It renders also the upper and thelower tones
               very easy to produce, while it improves andequalizes the tone throughout. Passages
               which were impracticable upon the old flute can be played with perfect fa 
               cility upon the Boehm flute, while, added to all these advantages, and many more advantages which we shall take anearly opportunity of pointing out to amateur and professional players, the exterior appearance of the flute is much improved and beautified.
            </p>
            
            <p>A strong feeling of prejudice was exhibited against theBoehm innovation, as it was arrogantly called, by professional players, both here and in Europe; but its striking advantages and sterling excellence silenced
               them one by one, andthe Boehm flute is now universally adopted.
            </p>
            
            <p>To Mr. W. J. Davis, the talented flutist, every honor mustbe given as the first
               man who had the boldness to introduceit into this country; and to Mr. Larrabee, the ingenious maker, the public and the professors owe a debt of
               gratitude forhis sacrifice of self-interest, in substituting the new for the
               old flute.
            </p>
            
            <p>We hope that all who are interested in this subject, andhave not yet examined the
               Boehm flute, may be induced byour notice to visit Mr. Larrabee's factory, 110
               Fulton street.We have examined the instrument thoroughly, and can vouchfor
               its excellence in every way.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <div class="biblTitle">Grand Sacred Concert at St. Peter's Church.</div>
            <div class="biblPage">301</div>
            
            <p>Grand Sacred Concert at St. Peter's Church.
               --We call theattention of our readers to the advertisement of this Concert in our
               present number. It will be seen that a truly classical and yet popular programme is offered on this occasion. The selections are fromthe finest
               composers, ancient and modern. Mozart, Handel, Hayden,Mendelssohn, Rossini and
               other names of note, give warranty of theexcellence of the selection. The solos
               and chorusses from St. Paulwill be new to most of our readers. As an entire work,
               Paulus is un'doubtedly the greatest work that Mendelssohn has yet produced; for,
               lofty sentiment, profound thought, and exquisite melody, no recentcomposition
               has approached it. The Loblgesang has also, only oncebeen produced in this
               country, and the selections from it cannot fail toadd the charm of novelty to the
               programme.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mrs. Edward Loder, Miss De Luce, Miss Schmidt, Miss Watson,and Mr. Masset sustain the principal parts, while the chorus, composed principally of the
               members of the New-York Vocal Society, sofavourably known to the public, is
               announced to be full and effective.It will be under the direction of Mr. H. C.
               Watson.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. William A. King, organist of St. Peter's, whose reputation inthat department
               is widely spread throughout the States, is engagedto get the concert up. Mr. H. C.
               Timm performs with Mr. W. AKing a four-handed piece for the organ.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Concert is for the benefit of the Funds of the Church, which,independent of
               the musical attraction will doubtless be sufficient tofill the Church.
            </p>
            
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p22">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Broadway Theatre</div>
         <div class="biblPage">301</div>
         
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY THEATRE.</div>
         
         <p>Mr. Hamblin has made a very touching appeal to the citizens of New
            York, and proposes borrowing one hundredthousand dollars, in the ridiculously
            small sums (as Mr. Tiggwould say) of one dollar, from the same number of individuals, for which he will issue scrip entitling subscribers to a
            dollar's worth of admissions to his theatre when it shall befinished. This is certainly a very ingenious scheme for raising a hundred thousand
            dollars; but without a particle of illwill towards Mr. Hamblin, whom we have not
            the pleasureof knowing, we cannot say that we wish he may get it. Forwe
            should regret exceedingly to see a theatre erected inBroadway, more especially
            such a theatre as Mr. Hamblinwould probably put up. Considering the effect which theatres invariably have in the neighborhood where they havebeen
            built, we should expect that the owners of property inBroadway would protest
            against the erection of one in thatnoble thoroughfare. The little Olympic is
            probably the bestconducted theatre in the city; but we see it surrounded by
            dram shops, billiard rooms, and other equivocal resorts for the
            profligate and idle. We see no necessity of making atheatre a drinking house, a
            gambling house, and a somethingelse house, as well as a play house, but there
            seems to be thereal unities of the drama, and pea-nuts and punch are as essential concomitants to the acting drama as tin foil and rouge.It is
            one of the strangest things in life, that every institutionhas been modified by
            time excepting the theatre. It is justas dissolute now as it was in the days of
            Charles the Second.Though governed by no laws, and its professors reckoned as
            vagrants, it is one of the most conservative institutions amongus. Quakers
            and Jews change, but the theatre holds to itsold usages. Mr. Simpson is the only
            man in New York whohas remained unchanged during the past twenty years, and
            his theatre is the only building in the city which has notbeen renovated. All
            the churches have been remodeled;preachers have changed their style, their
            theology, and theirhabits; society has suffered a dozen revolutions; the whole
            order of living has been reversed; we have altered our food,drink, habits,
            and even our speech; cotillions have gone out,and the Polka has come in; finger
            glasses and silver forkshave become common in hotels; drunkenness has grown
            unfashionable; the national name has been changed; newstreets have been
            built; Texas has been annexed; cheapbooks have been invented; hanging is almost
            abolished; theCroton river runs through the streets;--but Mr. Simpson andthe
            Park remain the same, as unchangeable as the eternalsphinx of the desert. He looks
            as gloomy and saturnine ashe used to look when he played Charles Surface in a
            claretcolored coat and straw colored shorts; and his theatre is asdingy, as English, and as expensive as ever. The filthy saloons, with their red
            moreen curtains and yellow refreshmentsellers remain unchanged, and probably will
            remain so forthe next century; and the same plays are presented on thestage
            that were witnessed by our grandmothers and ourgrandmothers' grandmothers. There is no church in Christendom half so conservative as the theatre: there
            are ismsin every thing but the drama, which has never known aschism. Mr.
            Dinneford, to be sure, got up a Greek tragedythe other day, which was stepping
            backward a thousandyears or two, instead of moving forward, as any one must
            do who would produce a sensation in the drama; and it appears
            that he lost twenty-five hundred dollars by his devotionto the classics, which
            should be a caution to other managersto let the classics alone.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have no reason to believe that Mr. Hamblin wouldbreak adrift from the
            legitimate drama, or that he would doany better in Broadway than he has heretofore
            done in theBowery; and therefore we would rather see him fail thansucceed in
            his present undertaking; not that we wish himany ill as an individual, but as a
            manager he cannot but doharm in the community. He has had a large theatre under
            his control for many years, but he has done nothing to elevate
            the drama or correct the corrupt tastes of his audiences.If Mr. Hamblin must have
            a theatre, let him by all meansstick to the Bowery. He would be a fish out of
            water inBroadway, and his theatre would mar the beauty of our magnificent thoroughfare.
         </p>
         
         <p>We shall have a theatre in New York by and by, we haveno doubt, that will reflect
            the manners of the people andsatirise their vices, but it must be under the
            control of amanager to the manor born.
         </p>
         
         <p>We are sorry for Mr. Hamblin's misfortunes, and wouldnot put the slightest obstacle in his way to retrieve his losses; and our remarks are only intended to apply to the erection of a theatre in Broadway.</p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p23">
         <div class="biblTitle">Fact and Fiction</div>
         <div class="biblPage">302</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Fact and Fiction.
            --From Thoughts on Reading, in 
            <span class="person" id="ghcolton">Colton</span>'s Mag-
            <br></br>azine,
            by 
            <span class="person" id="hnhudson">H. N. Hudson</span>, the Lecturer on Shakspeare:
         </div>
         
         <p>"Good people often seem laboring under a great mistakein regard to works of
            fiction. They appear to think of truthas synonymous with matters of fact, and of fiction as synonymous with falsehood. Now, there is probably nothing that
            lies so frequently or so abominably as narratives of facts.Why, if a man
            wants to make any falsehood go down, healways sweetens it with some "fact whch
            came under hisown observation." Facts, indeed, we know to be the readiest vehicle of lies in the world: and whenever one undertakes to
            inflict them on us, we take for granted that there isno truth in him; or that, if
            there be, it is not coming outthis time. On the other hand, as some one has said,
            thepurest fictions often contain more of truth than many histories and scientific theories. In 
            <span class="person" id="espenser">Spenser</span> or 
            <span class="person" id="mcervantes">Cervantes</span>, forexample, perhaps you
            shall not find a single falsehood, or asingle fact; in a Gibbon or a Paley, you
            shall scarcely find asingle fiction or a single truth. In the former, all shall be
            true but the names; in the latter all but the names shall befalse. Take, for
            example, 
            <span class="person" id="jaddison">Addison</span>'s Cato and Sancho Panza.Now, Cato is unquestionably a real name;
            nobody doubtsthe existence of such a man; or that he was a genuine old,
            eating, breathing, thinking and speaking Roman, of thestaunchest and noblest
            make. But 
            <span class="person" id="jaddison">Addison</span>'s Cato is one ofthe sheerest falsehoods that ever was
            perpetrated; such abeing never did exist, and never could exist; all the princi-
            ples of human nature must be changed before his existencewere possible.
            Sancho Panza, on the contrary, is doubtlessa fictitious name; nobody pretends that
            a real man ever borethat name; but the character is a perfect form of truth; is
            as real as the old Roman Cato was, whom 
            <span class="person" id="jaddison">Addison</span> meant togive us, but could
            not; wants, in short, all that 
            <span class="person" id="jaddison">Addison</span>'sCato has, and has all that 
            <span class="person" id="jaddison">Addison</span>'s Cato
            wants. And thusit is, that, in the hands of an artist, a fiction becomes the
            truest of realities, while, in the hands of a bungler, a factbecomes the
            emptiest of falsehoods.
         </p>
         
         <p>Again; take 
            <span class="person" id="espenser">Spenser</span>'s Una and 
            <span class="person" id="sjohnson">Johnson</span>'s 
            <span class="person" id="jmilton">Milton</span>. Now,Una is a mere personification of truth--one of the purest abstractions which the mind can frame, and
            with which, assuch, we could no more sympathize, than with a triangle oran
            octagon. And yet, in Spenser's hands, it has turned outa fair humanity, breathing
            and blushing before us, like lifeitself. Uniting all the purity of an abstraction,
            with theflesh-and-blood reality of an actual person, we at once revereher as truth, and feel for her as the real subject of sympathies and
            affections answering to our own. Here, then, is agenuine character; a pure
            abstraction has come out a livingperson; a perfect fiction has become a perfect
            truth. Thisis the miracle that genius performs. 
            <span class="person" id="jmilton">Milton</span>, on the contrary, is an actual person; nay, he has stamped his individuality, as a full length portrait, on every page of his works, sothat
            he who runs may read, provided he have eyes. In
            <span class="person" id="sjohnson">Johnson</span>'s hands, however, he
            becomes a mere abstraction;no longer he, but it; or rather, a bundle of the mo t inconsistent and irreconcilable abstractions. You could no more
            mould such elements into the same living character, thanyou could mix fire and water, without destroying either.-Here is a genuine fact turned into a perfect
            falsehood. Thisis the miracle that genius does not perform. We couldmultiply instances beyond either our time or the reader's patience. It is
            truth, in this sense, that forms the substanceand the soul of all true books; and
            we care not what formyou give it, it is as genuine and as indestructible as the
            eyeof God.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p24">
         <div class="biblTitle">Miscellany</div>
         <div class="biblPage">302</div>
         
         <div class="head">MISCELLANY.</div>
         
         <p>IT IS AN ILL WIND THAT BLOWS NOBODY GOOD.--The frosthas been so intense on the
            Danube, that rocks which for centuries hadobstructed the navigation near Lintz,
            suddenly burst, and thus openedthe bed of the river.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>BURSTING OF BEER.--The famous brewers of Burton Ale,Messrs. Alsopps, whose names should be written Allslops, have recently failed for the moderate sum of one million and a half of dollars.</p>
         
         <p>Mr. Murdoch, who has been successfully lecturing inthis city upon the Drama and
            
            <span class="person" id="wshakespeare">Shakspeare</span>, will make his re-appearanceupon the stage in September. He has an
            engagement at the Park for12 nights.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>THREE FACES UNDER A HOOD, viz. PALMO-HOOD.--The newopera house in Chambers street
            was first occupied by the Italians, thenthe Greeks, but now, it appears from the following notice, it is occupied by the Ethiopians.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Mr. Dumbleton has at length succeeded in obtaining possessionfrom Palmo, of the
            Opera House, and will this evening open it withthe Ethioipan Serenaders.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Henry Phillips gave his farewell concert at Niblo'sSaloon last Tuesday evening; it was well attended, and the performances gave great
            satisfaction. Mr. Phillips sang twelve differentballads, scenas, &amp;c., many of
            which were encored, and all were wellreceived. If he should repeat his visit to
            this country he would meetwith better encouragement in the large cities on the
            Atlantic than hehas done. His indifferent success has resulted mainly from an injudicious beginning in the manner of giving his concerts.
         </p>
         
         <p>HISTORICAL SOCIETY.--At a very crowded meeting of thissociety on Wednesday
            evening, the Rev. 
            <span class="person" id="rwgriswold">Rufus W. Griswold</span> read along and interesting paper in reference
            to the intellectual history ofthe country--with criticisms on the works of several
            of our most notedauthors. He did not conclude the essay.
         </p>
         
         <p>MR. ALPERS, THE MUSICIAN.--We had an interesting article on theburial of this
            excellent musician, which is crowded out of this week'sJournal. He died last
            Saturday at the house of his friend Mr. Timm,and was buried from the Tabernacle
            Tuesday morning. The housewas nearly filled by the members of the Philharmonic
            Society ofwhich he was a member, and by his personal friends and pupils. The
            funeral ceremonies, of which we shall give the particulars, were highly impressive, and admirably adapted to the occasion.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Mirror of last week contains a poem of much merit,entitled "The Gazelle.'' It is the composition of a mere boy of fifteen, 
            <span class="person" id="cccooke">C. C. Cooke</span>, and,
            although professedly an imitation of "TheRaven," has a very great deal of original
            power.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p25">
         <div class="biblTitle">New Publications</div>
         <div class="biblPage">302</div>
         
         <div class="head">NEW PUBLICATIONS.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">THOSE MARKED + ARE RE-PRINTS.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">+ Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="dwjerrold">Candle</span>'s Curtain Lectures. By Punch; with illustrations.]
            <br></br>+Martin's
            Illustrated Bible, No. 4 (steel plates).
            <br></br>+
            <span class="person" id="smaunder">Maunder</span>'s Treasury of History, No. 5.
            
            <br></br>+Copland's Dictionary of Practical Medicine. Edited by Dr. 
            <span class="person" id="calee">C. A. Lee</span>. No. 6.
            
            <br></br>+Encyclopedia of Domestic Economy. By 
            <span class="person" id="twebster">T. Webster</span> and Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="fbparkes">Parkes</span>. No. 2.
            <br></br>Plato
            Against the Atheists. With Critical Notes. By 
            <span class="person" id="tlewis">Taylor Lewis</span>, LL. D.
            <br></br>Dr. 
            <span class="person" id="canthon">Anthon</span>'s
            System of Latin Versification: with specimens of translations
            <br></br>from English and
            German Poetry into Latin Verse. 12mo.
            <br></br>Notes on the Ephesians, by Dr. 
            <span class="person" id="abarnes">Barnes</span>. 12mo.
            
            <br></br>The Dutchman's Fireside; a novel. By 
            <span class="person" id="jkpaulding">J. K. Paulding</span>: new edition.
            <br></br>Harper &amp;
            Brothers' Pictorial Bible, No. 26.
         </div>
         
         
         <p>By the arrival of the Hibernia, we have London dates to 19th ultimo,
            by which we learn that the following new works have been issued:
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Lives of Men of Letters and Science, in the Reign of Geo. III. By Lord
            <br></br>
            <span class="person" id="hpbrougham">Brougham</span>.
            8vo.; with steel portraits. 21s.
            <br></br>Peninsular Sketches. By Actors of the Scenes.
            Edited by 
            <span class="person" id="whmaxwell">W. H. Maxwell</span>.
            <br></br>Elements of Physics. By 
            <span class="person" id="cfpeschel">C. F. Peschel</span>, Principal of the
            Royal Military Col
            <br></br>lege, Dresden. Translated from the German, with
            Notes, by 
            <span class="person" id="ewest">E. West</span>. One
            <br></br>vol. 8vo., with diagrams and wood cuts.
            <br></br>Texas and the
            Gulf of Mexico. By Mrs. 
            <span class="person" id="mchoustoun">Houston</span> (?) 2 vols. 8vo.
            <br></br>Education the Birthright of every
            human being. By Rev. 
            <span class="person" id="bparsons">B. Parsons</span>.
            <br></br>Female Characters of Holy Writ. By Rev. 
            <span class="person" id="hhughes">H. Hughes</span>.
            
            <br></br>Autobiography of 
            <span class="person" id="jbwhite">J. Blanco White</span>--with his Correspondence.
            <br></br>The Wandering Jew.
            By 
            <span class="person" id="esue">Eugene Sue</span>. Vol. 11. 7s.
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">IN PRESS.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Dalekarlien, a new novel by Miss 
            <span class="person" id="fbremer">Bremer</span>.
            <br></br>
            <span class="person" id="fvraumer">Raumer</span>'s Letters on North America.
            
            <br></br>Essays Biographical and Literary. By 
            <span class="person" id="whprescott">William H. Prescott</span>, Esq., author of
            <br></br>the
            Conquest of Mexico.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p26">
         <div class="biblTitle">Notice to Publishers</div>
         <div class="biblPage">302</div>
         
         <div class="head">NOTICE TO PUBLISHERS.</div>
         
         <p>We shall furnish in our columns hereafter, a weekly list ofnew works published in the U. S. and in London. Publishers in New-York, Boston, Philadelphia,
            and other cities,are requested to send us lists of their new works, and of
            works in press, in order to make our publication as full aspossible.
         </p>
         
         <p>To booksellers at a distance, and to professional men generally, as
            well as readers at large, this occasional list will beinteresting and valuable. We
            propose to make it complete,so that it shall be a full index to alt the operations
            of the"Press" in the English language.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">303</div>
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">BOARD IN BROOKLYN.</div>
            
            <p>--A Single Gentleman,who is partial to Chess and Music, can be provided with a
               furnishedroom, and breakfast and tea, in a private family, residing near Fulton
               street,Brooklyn, in one of its most pleasant streets.
            </p>
            
            <p>Address W. S. Office of Broadway Journal: or enquire at said office.</p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">GRAND SACRED CONCERT.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">At St. Peter's Church, Barclay St.
               <br></br>FOR THE BENEFT OF THE CHURCH.
            </div>
            
            <p>ON SUNDAY EVENING, MAY 18th, 1845. Onwhich occasion the performances will consist of selections from Mendelssohn's Oratorio of St. Paul,
               Haydn's Creation, Handel's Messiah, Rossini'sStabat Mater, and Mendelssohn's
               latest composition--the Lobegesang, or Hymnof Praise."
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">PRINCIPAL PERFORMERS.</div>
            
            
            <p>Mrs. Edward Loder, Miss De Luce, Miss Schmitt, Miss Watson, Mr. Massett. Mr. H. C. Timm, and Mr. W. A. King, (organ.)</p>
            
            
            <p>The chorus will be most carefully selected, consisting chiefly of membersof the
               celebrated New York Vocal Society, under the direction of Mr. H. C.Watson.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The whole performance will be under the direction of Mr. W. A. King, organist of the church.</p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">Tickets 50 cents.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">To commence at eight o'clock.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DESIGNING AND ENGRAVINGON WOOD.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">SAMUEL E. BROWN, 70 Nassau Street, Corner of
               <br></br>John, New York.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Portraits, Views of Buildings, Scenery. Original Designs, &amp;. &amp;. furnished
               
               <br></br>at this establishment.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">MR. AND MRS. KIRKLAND'SSCHOOL FOR YOUNG LADIES,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 255 Greene Street,
               <br></br>One door above Waverly Place, New York.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>THIS School differs essentially from most others inthis city, in one
               particular: the number admitted is so limited that eachscholar receives the
               personal attention and instruction of the principals.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>Mr. Kirkland resided some years in Europe for the express purpose ofqualifying
               himself as an instructor.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The French language is taught by an approved master, a native of France,and
               every facility is afforded for practice, both in the school and in the family.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The plan of instruction embraces three divisions. The Initiatory Course includes Grammar, Geography, American History, Writing and Arithmetic,
               with Composition. Reading aloud, Spelling and Definition, form part of the
               daily exercises of the whole school.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The Second continues the above-named studies, with the addition of Ancient and Modern History and the French Language.</p>
            
            
            <p>In the higher or AEsthetic course all the usual branches of a thorough English course of education are included, with French, German, Latin and
               Greek, according to the wish of the parent and the capacity of the scholar. 
            </p>
            
            
            <p>Pupils in this course pay particular attention to Poetry, to the art of Composition, and to the Philosophy of History. Moral Philosophy is taught
               from
               <span class="person" id="jdymond">Dymond</span>, as abridged and prepared for schools by Mrs. Kirkland. Lectures
               on various subjects are delivered by Mr. and Mrs. Kirkland, and others; and
               the general course of study is advanced and rendered interesting by copious
               illustrations from French and English Literature.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Primary Course, - - - - $12.50 Per Quarter.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Second "(including French, &amp;c.) 18 00 " </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Third, or highest course, - - - 25 00 "</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Music-Piano Forte, - - - 15 00 "</div>
            
            <div class="ab"> " Singing, - - - 15 00 "</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Drawing, - - - - 10 00 "</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Dancing, - - - - 12 00 "</div>
            
            <div class="ab">For Board, (payable Quarterly in advance,) $175 per Annum.</div>
            
            
            <div class="ab">Board during vacations at the same rate.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The young ladies are required to bring towels, spoons, fork and napkin
               
               <br></br>ring--every article fully marked,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washing $7 50 per Quarter.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">No Extras--whether for fuel, use of instruments, or any thing not here
               
               <br></br>specified.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Pupils received at any time, and charged in proportion only.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">References to parents and guardians given if desired.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE BOEHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">(NEW INVENTION.)
               <br></br>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the
               Conservatorie at
               <br></br>Paris, and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
            </div>
            
            <p>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the "BoehmFlute," 110 Fulton St. N. Y., anxious
               to introduce to the Amateurs ofthe cities the above lmportant Intention, which
               has been so enthusiasticallyreceived end generally used by the most
               distinguished European Artists, feelshappy in being able to place before them
               the following testimonial to itsmerit, signed by two of the most distinguished
               of our resident Artists. 
            </p>
            
            
            <p>We hereby certify to the the excellence of Boehm Flute as manufacturedby Mr.
               J.D. Larrabee; to the beauty of its tone, the perfection of its tune,and the
               simplicity of its fingering, which renders a brilliant executioncomparatively
               easy.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">PHILIP ERNST (who has already introduced it successfully among his pupils.
               <br></br>JOHN
               A. KYLE, Principal flute of the Philhar
               <br></br>-monic Society and Italian
               Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm Flute,
               <br></br>41 Forsyth street, New
               York.
            </div>
            
            
            <div class="ab">Amateurs and Professors a re requested to call at the manufactory, 110
               <br></br>Fulton
               at. and judge for themselves.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">JOHN DOUGLAS,BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">No. 106 FULTON STREET.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO-FORTES.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">--A. H. GALE &amp; CO.'S WARE-
               <br></br>Rooms, No. 289 Broadway--Manufactory Third Avenue,
               corner of 13th
               <br></br>street.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assortment of
               Rosewood and Mahogany Piano-Fortes, with from six to seven octaves embracing ever variety of patterns, made in their well known substantial manner, under their immediate and personal superintendence, by
               skillful andexperienced mechanics, from the best seasoned materials.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>These instruments embrace many important improvements, which will re-commend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of perfection, with
               the best French grand action, warranted in every respect by the manufacturer.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, (formerly Conductor toDubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the latest approved
               Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most superiorquality; such as he is prepared
               to guarantee for their excellence of Tone,Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices.
               Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. PianoFortes aways on hire.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to theirnumerous friends, and to the public, would, at the same time, call attention to their Stock of
               Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, inelegant Rosewood and
               Mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of thebusiness,
               have been enabled to add several important improvements to theaction, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, upon examination,
               equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNHAM.
               <br></br>361 Broadway.
               <br></br>Manufactory 13th St., between 3d and
               4th Avenues.
               <br></br>N.B.--A good second-hand Piano Forte for sale.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">--V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as iron frames,
               &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the
               result of23 years experience in the business.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">F. RILEY &amp; CO.,</div>
            
            <p>No. 297 Broadway,(betweenReade and Duane streets,) New York, Publishers of Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and
               retail. In addition to theirown catalogue, (one of the largest in the United
               States,) they keep on handhe publications of all the principal Music houses.
               They are erecting a largeSaloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes
               of a superior quality,will be constantly kept on hand.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">PIANO - FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>--JOHN PETHICK,(formerlyMundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to the elegant and varied aesortment he now has at
               his Old Establisment, Corner ofCottage-place and Bleecker Street, which he will
               sell at prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twentyyears, and for a large portion of that time manufacturer for two of the largest Music Stores in this city, feels warranted in saying that his instruments
               will bear a favorable chmparison with those of the best makers in this coun
               try or Eurepe, and that they contain all the real improvements of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and Repaired.New
               York, April 23d. 1845.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">88, 90, &amp;92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">A large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
               <br></br>TERMS MODERATE.
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">BERTINI</span>'S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressivework yet published in this
               country. Where pupils here used this methodthe most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is
               that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies, aregiven in such progressive
               order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, andcarry them almost
               imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,otherwise, are too
               often made irksome in other instruction books. The timehas arrived when a
               superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,and it is only by
               the study of such methods as Bertini's that pupils will be enabled to READ music with facility, and at the same time become good musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the rudments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and each lessonis
               fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest reccommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of 
               <span class="person" id="hjbertini">Bertini</span>'s
               Methodover all others yet published in this country, most of them having used
               theforeign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
               names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">BOSTON
               <br></br>Messrs. G. J. Webb.
               <br></br>J. G Maedar.
               <br></br>H. T. Hach.
               <br></br>E. L. White.
               
               <br></br>David Paine.
               <br></br>A. Kurek.
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.
               <br></br>NEW YORK.
               <br></br>Messrs. H. C.
               Timm.
               <br></br>W. Alpers.
               <br></br>U. C. Hill.
               <br></br>F. H. Brown.
               <br></br>PHILADELPHIA.
               <br></br>B. C.
               Cross.
               <br></br>Joseph Duggan.
               <br></br>ALBANY--O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197, Washington
               street, Boston.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">WORKS IN PRESS.BY HARPER AND BROTHERS, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            
            <p>ENCYCLOPAEDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY:Comprising such Subjects as are connected with
               Housekeeping. By 
               <span class="person" id="twebster">Tho-mas Webster</span>, F. G. S., &amp;c., and the late Mrs.
               
               <span class="person" id="fbparkes">Parks</span>. With Additions andImprovements, by an AmericanPhysician. With nearly
               1000 Engravings.To be published in parts, at 25 cents each.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>MEMOIRS OF THE STATESMEN OF THE COMMONWEALTH OFENGLAND. By 
               <span class="person" id="jforster">John Foster</span>. Edited
               by the Rev. 
               <span class="person" id="iocharles">I. O. Charles</span> of Boston. Five Steel Engravings.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>A DICTIONARY OF PRACTICAL MEDICINE. By 
               <span class="person" id="jcopland">James Copland</span>, M.D., F. R. S. Edited by
               
               <span class="person" id="calee">Charles A. Lee</span>, M. D., in numbers, at 50 centseach.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>A NEW GREEK AND ENGLISH LEXICON, including 
               <span class="person" id="hgliddell">Liddle</span> and 
               <span class="person" id="rscott">Scott</span>'senlarged Translation of Pascow's Greek and German Lexicon, with Additions and
               Improvements, by 
               <span class="person" id="hdrisler">Henry Drisler</span>, A. M., under the supervisionof Professor 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Anthon</span>.
               8vo.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>THE FARMER'S DICTIONARY; being a Compendious Account of everything
               relating to the Produce and management of Farms in this Country,and an
               Explanation of Technical Terms. By 
               <span class="person" id="dpgardner">D. P. Gardner</span>, M. D.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>PLATO AGAINST THE ATHEISTS; or, the Tenth Book of the Dialogueon Laws, accompanied with Critical Notes, and followed by extended Dissertations on some of the main points of the Platonic Philosophy and Theology, especialy as compared with the Holy Scriptures. By 
               <span class="person" id="tlewis">Taylor Lewis</span>, LL. D.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>THE TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO, greatly amended and enlarged fromvaluable Early
               Manuscripts recently published by the French Society ofGeography, and in Italy
               by Count 
               <span class="person" id="gbbaldelliboni">Baldelli Boni</span>. With copious Notes. By
               <span class="person" id="hmurray">Hugh Murray</span>, F. R. S. E.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>LIFE OF PAUL JONES. By 
               <span class="person" id="asmackenzie">Alex. Slidell Mackenzie</span>, U. S. Navy. 2 vols.12mo.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>THE ECLOGUES AND GEORGICS OF VIRGIL. With English Notes,&amp;c., by 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">Charles
                  Anthon
               </span>. LL. D.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE ANABASIS OF 
               <span class="person" id="xenophon">XENOPHON</span>. With English Notes, &amp;c., by 
               <span class="person" id="canthon">CharlesAnthon</span>, LL.
               D.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">HARPER &amp; BROTHERS.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">SHEPARD</div>
            
            
            <p>Is SELLING BOOKS AND STATIONARY AScheap as ever.</p>
            
            
            <p>He has added a large assortment of Books bought atvery low prices at the late
               trade sale.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="bgniebuhr">Niebuhr</span>'s Rome, just published at $5, he will sell far below that price. 
            </p>
            
            
            <p>Encyclopedia Americana, in 13 vols., he will sell low enough.</p>
            
            
            <p>He has also added a beautiful assortment of Gold Pencils--some of whichhe will
               sell as low as $1,87 1-2 cents, warranted.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>Another lot of that beautiful Letter Paper at $1,50 per ream--well
               worth$2,25.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">Please call and see if you cannot buy to suit you at
               <br></br>SHEPARD'S, 191
               Broadway,
               <br></br>opposite John str[eet]
            </div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">UNITED STATES EXPLORING EXPEDITION.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">CHEAP EDITION.</div>
            
            <p>NARRATIVE OF THE U. S. EXPLORING EXPEDITION, during the years 1838,
               39, 40, 41, 41. By 
               <span class="person" id="cwilkes">Charles Wilkes</span>,U. S. Navy, Commander of the Expedition. With
               Illustration. and Maps. InFive Volume. Vol. 1, 2 00.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>This edition contains, precisely the same type, page, and readingmatter, as the
               one in imperial octavo; the difference between them being inthe quality and size
               of the paper, and the omission of the steel plates, andsome of the maps. The
               number of wood illustrations in this edition is nearly three hundred. A volume will be published about every two weeks, until the whole
               work shall be completed. For sale by
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">NOW READY, (Gratis,) WILEY &amp; PUTNAM'SLITERARY NEWS LETTER FOR MAY,
               containing--
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">1. --Foreign Literary Intelligence.
               <br></br>2. --American Literary Intelligence.
               
               <br></br>3.--Important English Works in press.
               <br></br>4.--List of new English Work, just
               published.
               <br></br>5.--New American Work, published in April.
               <br></br>6.--Works recently
               imported, with the prices.
               <br></br>7.--W. &amp; P.'s recent Publications, with Critical
               Notices.
               <br></br>8. --Books which are Books: Library of Choice Reading.
               <br></br>9. --The United
               States' Exploring Expedition,
               <br></br>WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway,
            </div>
            
            <p>This News-Letter will be distributed gratuitously to all who willleave their address with the publishers. Single copies of English books imported
               to order per steamer or packet.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">my 10</div>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="note" type="headnote">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.The first Premium awarded fire years
               by the American Institute for thebest Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH'S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing,
               guaranteed to all (old and young)in 10 lessons of one hour each. TERMS Reduced to
               TWO DOLLARSAND A HALF.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thoroughcourse of instruction,
               including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks andStationery. Payable at the
               commencement.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>CLASS Hours-- 9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemenand from 11 to 1
               o'clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>For sale "
               <span class="person" id="obgoldsmith">Goldsmith</span>'s Gems OF PENMANSHIP," elegantly bound.Price Five
               Dollars.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">THE 
               SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab"> B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               <br></br>Published Monthly at Richmond, Va.; price
               Five Dollars per Year.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835,has a large subscription list
               among the elite of the Southern Aristocracy,and is the principal organ of
               Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the "Broadway Journal," 153 Broadway.</p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">IMPORTANT WORKS FOR PUBLIC LIBRARIES.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">FOR SALE BY
               <br></br>BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, NEW YORK.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>THE TRANSACTIONS OF THE ROYAL SOCIETY OF LONDON, or Philosophical
               Transactions, from thecommencement, in 1665 to 1800. By Drs. 
               <span class="person" id="chutton">Hutton</span> and
               
               <span class="person" id="tshaw">Shaw</span>;in 18 vols. 4 to., and from 1600 to 1835, in 36 vols., together54 vols.
               royal, 4 to. uniformly bound in half calf. $250 00
            </p>
            
            
            <p>THE ARCHAEOLEGIA; or Miscellaneous Tracts, relating toAntiquity, by the Society
               of Antiquaries of Sweden, completefrom the beginning in 1770 to 1843, in 30 vols.
               uniformlybound in half russia. 225 00
            </p>
            
            
            <p>THE DELPHIN EDITION OF THE LATIN CLASSICS; byValpy, with various notes, the best
               edition, (published at 150sterling) in 142 vols. 8 vo. boards. 200 00
            </p>
            
            
            <p>PINKERTONS' COLLECTIONS OF VOYAGES AND TRAVELS in various parts of
               the world, 17 large vols., 4 to. halfbound in calf. 70 00
            </p>
            
            
            <p>
               <span class="person" id="pbayle">BAYLE</span>'S GREAT HISTORICAL AND CRITICAL DICTIONARY; by 
               <span class="person" id="pdesmaizeaux">Des Maizeaux</span>,
               best edition, 5 vols. folio, bound incalf. 30 00
            </p>
            
            
            <p>ANDERSONS' BRITISH POETS; from 
               <span class="person" id="gchaucer">Chaucer</span> to 
               <span class="person" id="twarton">Warton</span>; 14vols. royal 8 vo. bound in
               calf extra. 40 00
            </p>
            
            
            <p>COLONEL 
               <span class="person" id="rwhvyse">VYSE</span>'S ACCOUNT OF OPERATIONS CARRIEDON IN EXPLORING THE PYRAMIDS OF
               EGYPT; withnumerous plates; 3 vols. 4 to. 14 00
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">REPUBLICATION OF THE FOREIGN MAGAZINES.</div>
            
            <p>LONDON, EDINBURGH, FOREIGN, and WESTMINSTER QUARTERLY REVIEWS, and BLACKWOOD'S MAGAZINE.</p>
            
            
            <p>The above Periodicals are reprinted in New-York, immediately on theirarrival by
               the British steamers, in a beautiful clear type, on fine white paperand are faithful copies of the originals--Blackwood's Magazine being an exact
               fac-simile of the Edinburgh Edition.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The wide spread fame of these splendid Periodicals renders it needless tosay
               much to their praise. As Literary organs, they stand far in advance ofany works
               of a similar stamp now published, while their political complexionis marked by a
               dignity, candor, and forbearance not often found in works ofa party
               character.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>They embrace the views of the three great parties in England, Whig, Tory,and
               Radical. "Blackwood" and the "London Quarterly" are Tory; the"Edinburgh Review" Whig; and the "Westminster" Radical. The "Foreign Quarterly" is
               purely literary, being devoted principally to criticisms onforeign Continental
               Works.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The prices of the Re-Prints are less than one third of those of the
               foreigncopies; and while they are equally well got up, they afford all that advantage to the American over the English reader.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">TERMS.--Payment to be made in Advance.
               <br></br>For the four Quarterly Reviews, $8.00 per
               annum.
               <br></br>For any three " " 7.00 "
               <br></br>For any two " " 5.00 "
               <br></br>For any one " "
               3.00 "
               <br></br>For Blackwood, Monthly, 3.00 "
               <br></br>For 4 Reviews &amp; Blackwood, 10.00
               "
            </div>
            
            
            <div class="ab">CLUBBING</div>
            
            
            <p>Four copies of any or all the above works will be sent to one address, onpayment
               of the regular subscription for three--the fourth copy being gratis.Remittances
               and communications (post-paid or franked) should be made toLEONARD SCOTT &amp;
               CO., Pub's, 112 Fulton st., N.Y.
            </p>
            
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF The TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much sufferingand regret, and should
               not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
            </p>
            
            
            <p>The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow'sprofessional
               skill, and believing him well qualified in the science ofDental Surgery, and an
               accomplished and skillful operator, we mostcheerfully certify to the ease and
               safety with which Dr. B. performsthe various and important operations, so
               essential to the usefulness,durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="ab">Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo.
               <br></br>Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
               <br></br>Joshua Herrick,
               Me.
               <br></br>John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               <br></br>James Irvin, Pa.
               <br></br>J. Thompson, Miss.
               <br></br>Dr. A.
               G. Bigelow's Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.
            </div>
            
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p27">
         <div class="biblTitle">Agents for the Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">304</div>
         
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL,</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co., - - - - Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance, - - -Philadelphia, Pa.
            
            <br></br>R. G. H. Huntington, - - - - Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>George Jones, - - - - Albany, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Thomas H. Pease, - - - - New Haven, Ct.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div>
         
         <p>John Douglas, Printer, 106 Fulton street.</p>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>