<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            vol. I. no. 13. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, MARCH 29, 1845.
            Three Dollars per Annum.
            Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
            C. F, BRIGGS, EDGAR A. POE, H. C. WATSON, EDITORS,
            
         </p>
         <p>Published at
            153 BROADWAY, by
            John Bisco.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Truth. whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding ; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse,</p>
         <p>Locke.
            REVIEWS.
            The Amber Witch. No 2, of Wiley &amp; Putnam’s Library of Choice Read-
            ing. Price 37 1-2 cents.
            
         </p>
         <p>It was a piece of rare good luck that the projectors of this
            praise-worthy series of choice books could begin their library
            with two works, so perfect in their kind as Eӧthen and the
            Amber Witch ; and it will be a piece of luck still more rare,
            if the works which come alter, do not suffer by comparison
            with them. The British press has given so wide a currency
            to laudatory criticisms on the Amber Witch, that we are deprived of the pleasure of uttering any thing new in the way of
            praise on the same subject. Any thing savoring of dispraise
            in respect of this beautiful work, would be entirely new
            and startling ; for we believe that no critic has yet had the
            temerity to risk his own reputation by undervaluing a production whose merits will be appreciated as readily by the
            unlearned as the learned reader. Although it is, probably,
            as truthful a romance as ever has been written, that is, makes
            as near an approach to the thing it pretends to be, a true
            history, it is a matter of surprise that the author did not render
            it more truthful than it is, by suffering the witch to be burned.
            Not only is the moral of the narrative destroyed by the denouement, but the moment we begin to suspect that she
            will be rescued from the flames, the conviction that we are
            reading a true narrative begins to be shaken. It is, unquestionably, a more delightful romance for ending as it does,
            but if it be true, that Dr. Meinhold published it as an experiment upon the critical powers of the Tubingen reviewers,
            we wonder as much at his giving the story an ending so
            purely artificial, as we do at the obtuseness of the critics who
            are reported to have received it as a genuine chronicle.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Although a cheaper edition of the Amber Witch has already been published, we are sure that even those who may
            possess it in a homelier form, will be glad to have it in the
            elegant shape in which it is now presented.
         </p>
         <p>The Children or Mount Ida. By Mrs. Child.
            
         </p>
         <p>This classic tale, by Mrs. Child, is the most simple and
            Perfect story that any American woman has yet produced.
            Were it not for a superlative adjective, here and there, and
            sometimes a magazine platitude, it might be passed off for
            an old Greek legend. It has much of the sweet simplicity
            and touching passion of the story of Cupid and Psyche, and
            in purity of thought and elevated imagination, we have read
            no composition of late years that equals it. We trust that
            those who have been in the habit of representing Mrs. Child
            as a writer of extravagant fancies, will read this simple and
            chaste production. A story like this could only come from a
            mind the reverse of extravagant. Its faults are those which
            must always mar the productions of an imagination teeming
            with rich fancies,—faults that appear like beauties in the
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>writings of a less gifted mind. Mrs. Child has, unconsciously
            we suspect, drawn the portrait of a perfect woman, a wife and
            mother, in Œnone, a very different being from the Glumdalclitches who form the ideal of Miss Fuller’s women. Corythus is, too, we fear, almost as near an approach to as perfect a man as our imperfect nature has yet developed.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The story of Œnone and Corythus however, is something
            more than a simple Greek legend ; in the disguise of a fiction Mrs. C. has introduced one of the marvelous psychological developments, which have become too common in our
            day, to be laughed out of countenance by our wise men who
            will receive no truths less than a century old. The clairvoyance of Œnone is not in the least startling on Mount Ida;
            it harmonises with the old Greek legends, as naturally as
            though it had sprung from Greece, proving that the fables
            of her mythology had a deeper foundation to rest upon than
            the chimeras of barbarous ignorance. Œnone hastening her
            own calamities by her unconscious revelations, made while
            in the sleep that the unconscious powers of Corythus had
            produced, is so pure and tragic, that it hardly reads like a
            new invention. There cannot be a finer incident for the
            uses of tragedy ; the clap-traps of poisoned bowls and daggers
            are mere gewgaws compared with this terrible power by
            which Fate compels her victims to be the instruments of
            their own ruin.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mrs. Child is too pure and gentle a spirit to harrow the
            soul by pictures of remorse and suffering, but she has employed an incident of daily occurrence, (at least of reported
            daily occurrence, and for the uses of fiction, it is immaterial
            whether the reports be true or false,) to produce a catastrophe as purely tragical in its developement as any in the
            range of fiction.
         </p>
         <p>The I.ibrary of Commerce: Practical, Theoretical, and Historical. By
            Freeman Hunt, Editor of the Merchants’ Magazine. Vol. 1. 142 Fulton
            street. 1845.
            
         </p>
         <p>This is the first number of “ Hunt’s Library of Commerce,”
            an important and much needed series of books, which the
            well known editor of the Merchants’ Magazine has undertaken to publish.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The present volume contains a sketch of the commercial intercourse of the world with China; a history of the
            British Corn laws; and Memoirs of Commercial Delusions:
            embracing sketches of the Mississippi scheme and the South
            Sea bubble. The first article, we presume to be from the
            pen of the editor; the others are republications from English
            works. The most valuable part of the book is that which
            relates to Commercial Delusions, because it shows, in a manner which cannot be misunderstood, the disastrous effects
            which must always follow all commercial speculations, when
            they are carried to excess. There are speculations of daily
            occurrence in our community, based upon no surer ground
            than those projected by Law and Scraggs, which do not
            create as much distress, only because they are not as widely
            spread as were the operations of those arch-financiers. A
            company was projected in Wall street, the past winter, in
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page194"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>which several men of capital embarked, which was hardly
            more explicit in its objects than one started by a great genius
            in the time of the South Sea Bubble, entitled “ A Company
            for carrying on an Undertaking of Great Advantage, but Nobody to know what it is.” The projector of this surprising
            adventure is said to have gained two thousand pounds in
            instalments of 5 per cent, from subscribers to shares. The
            profits, of course, were nothing to nobody, excepting himself.
            If the mania for “companies” to do every thing, should ever
            return to this city, we hope to see a company started for
            keeping the streets free from mud. We think that if any
            enterprising genius should open the books for subscription to
            such stock even now, he could not fail to receive a very great
            number of subscriptions.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Library of Commerce is published in a very neat form,
            and handsomely printed, it will, of course, be a prominent
            volume on every merchant’s book-shelves.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Popular LECTURE on Astronomy. By M. Arago, with additions and corrections by Dionysius Lardner, L.L. D. Greeley &amp; McElrath, Tribune
            Buildings. 1645. Price 25 cents.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If M. Arago should ever chance to see a copy of this work,
            it would, probably, cause him as much surprise as the last
            comet did, which caught him napping. It is, unquestionably,
            a very excellent book for popular reading, and to those who
            know nothing about Astronomy, it will, as any work on Astronomy could not fail to do, convey many great truths which
            they will be the better for knowing. Nearly one half of the
            book has been contributed by Dr. Lardner, and the balance is
            ascribed to M. Arago, but as it was published from notes
            improperly taken, to which he never gave his consent, it is
            hardly doing him justice to pass it off as his work. The
            publishers give a perfectly satisfactory account of the manner
            in which it was obtained, and excuse themselves for republishing it by urging a plea very common with certain kinds
            of people, “ if they did not, somebody else would.” Perhaps
            we are a little too strict in regard to the publication of other
            people’s property without their permission, but there are so
            few in the country who err in this manner, that we may be
            forgiven for erring on the same side.
         </p>
         <p>M. Arago asks two questions in his lecture on comets, only
            one of which he answers.
            “ If the Moon is an old comet, what has she done with
            her hair!”
            “ What would be the consequence if the Earth should ever
            become the satellite of a comet ?”
            
         </p>
         <p>In reply to this last supposition, M. Arago quiets the fears
            of the Earthites, by a very ingenious theory, from which it
            appears, that instead of the Earth being alternately vitrified,
            liquified, and congealed as it approached and receded from
            the sun, its condition would not very materially be changed,
            and that at its aphelion and perihelion, its temperature would
            not vary much more than it does now. “There is nothing,
            therefore, to prove,” M. Arago is made to say, and perhaps did
            say; “ that in the hypothesis that the Earth should become
            the satellite of a comet, the human race must necessarily perish from thermometric changes." An exceedingly consoling
            theory; for although we Earthites might not altogether be satisfied with so secondary a position in the Universe, as that of a
            satellite to a vagabond comet, still we need entertain no
            harassing fears of danger to life and property in the case of
            such an event taking place. But we trust it will be a long
            time before any comet shall think of annexation with an eye
            to our own planet; and we have no doubt that even our friends
            at the south, as zealous they are for annexation of another
            kind, would sturdily oppose this.
         </p>
         <p>The World in a Pocket-Book. Geo. S. Appleton, Philadelphia, and Apple-
            ton ic Co., New York. 3d edition.
            
         </p>
         <p>An exceedingly neat pocket volume, the contents of which
            fulfill the promise of the title, imposing as it is. One of
            the chapters, “ The Genius of the World,” is quite novel in
            its way. The time from Moses to 1840, is compressed into
            five pages; all the genius of the world in so small a space !
            Alas for genius!
         </p>
         <p>Imitation—Plagiarism—The conclusion of Mr. Poe’s reply to
            THE LETTER OF OUTIS.
            
         </p>
         <p>“I have written what I have written,” says Outis, “from
            no personal motives, but simply because, from my earliest reading of reviews and critical notices, I have been disgusted
            with this wholesale mangling of victims without rhyme or
            reason.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I have already agreed to believe implicitly every thing asserted by the anonymous Outis, and am fully prepared to admit, even, his own contradictions, in one sentence, of what
            he has insisted upon in the sentence preceding. I shall assume it as indisputable, then, (since Nobody says it) that,
            first, he has no acquaintance with myself and “ some acquaintance with Mr. Longfellow,” and secondly, that he has
            “ written what he has written from no personal motives
            whatever.” That he has been disgusted with “ the mangling of victims without rhyme or reason,” is, to be sure, a
            little unaccountable, for the victims without rhyme or reason are precisely the victims that ought to be mangled; but
            that he has been disgusted “ from his earliest reading” with
            critical notices and reviews, is credible enough if we but imagine his “ earliest reading” and earliest writing to have taken
            place about the same epoch of time.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But to be serious ; if Outis has his own private reasons for
            being disgusted with what he terms the “ wholesale mangling of victims without rhyme or reason,” there is not a man
            living, of common sense and common honesty, who has not
            better reason (if possible) to be disgusted with the insufferable cant and shameless misrepresentation practised habitually by just such persons as Outis, with the view of decrying by sheer strength of lungs—of trampling down—of rioting down—of mobbing down any man with a soul that bids
            him come out from among the general corruption of our public press, and take his stand upon the open ground of rectitude and honor.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Outises who practise this species of bullyism are, as
            a matter of course, anonymous. They are either the “ victims without rhyme or reason who have been mangled by
            wholesale,” or they are the relatives, or the relatives of the
            relatives of the “ victims without rhyme or reason who have
            been mangled by wholesale.” Their watchwords are “ carping
            littleness,” “ envious malignity,” and “personal abuse.” Their
            low artifices arc insinuated calumnies, and indefatigable whispers of regret, from post to pillar, that “ Mr. So-and-So, or Mr.
            This-and-That will persist in rendering himself so dreadfully
            unpopular”—no one, in the meantime, being more thoroughly
            and painfully aware thau these very Outises, that the unpopularity of the just critic who reasons his way, guiltless of
            dogmatism, is confined altogether within the limits of the
            influence of the victims without rhyme and reason who
            have been mangled by wholesale. Even the manifest injustice of a Gifford is, I grieve to say, an exceedingly popular thing; and there is no literary element of popularity more
            absolutely and more universally effective than the pungent impartiality of a Wilson or a Macaulay. In regard to
            my own course—without daring to arrogate to myself a single other quality of either of these eminent men than that
            pure contempt for mere prejudice and conventionality which
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page195"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>actuated them all, I will now unscrupulously call the attenJ
            tion of the Outises to the fact, that it was during what they
            (the Outises) would insinuate to be the unpopularity of my
            “ wholesale mangling of the victims without rhyme and
            reason” that, in one year, the circulation of the “Southern
            Messenger” (a five-dollar journal) extended itself from seven [
            hundred to nearly five thousand,—and that, in little more
            than twice the same time, “ Graham’s Magazine” swelled
            its list from five to fifty-two thousand subscribers.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I make no apology for these egotisms, and I proceed with
            them without hesitation—for, in myself, I am but defending
            a set of principles which no honest man need be ashamed of
            defending, and for whose defence no honest man will consider an apology required.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The usual watchwords of the Outises, when repelling a
            criticism,—their customary charges, overt or insinuated, are
            (as I have already said) those of “personal abuse” and
            “ wholesale (or indiscriminate) mangling.” In the present
            instance the latter solely is employed—for not even an Outis
            can acuse me, with even a decent show of verisimilitude, of
            having ever descended, in the most condemnatory of my reviews, to that personal abuse which, upon one or two occasions, has indeed been levelled at myself, in the spasmodic
            endeavours of aggrieved authors to rebut what I have ventured to demonstrate.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I have then to refute only the accusation of mangling by
            wholesale—and I refute it by the simplest reference to fact.
            What I have written remains ; and is readily accessible in any
            of our public libraries. I have had one or two impotent enemies, and a multitude of cherished friends—and both friends
            and enemies have been, for the most part, literary people;
            vet no man can point to a single critique, among the very
            numerous ones which I have written during the last ten
            years, which is either wholly fault-finding or wholly in approbation ; nor is there an instance to be discovered, among
            all that I have published, of my having set forth, either in
            praise or censure, a single opinion upon any critical topic of
            moment, without attempting, at least, to give it authority by
            something that wore the semblance of a reason. Now, is
            there a writer in the land, who, having dealt in criticism
            even one-fourth as much as myself, can of his own criticisms,
            conscientiously say the same? The fact is, that very many
            of the most eminent men in America whom I am proud to
            number among the sincerest of my friends, have been rendered so solely by their approbation of my comments upon
            their own works—comments in great measure directed
            against themselves as authors—belonging altogether to that
            very class of criticism which it is the petty policy of the Outises to cry down, with their diminutive voices, as offensive
            on the score of wholesale vituperation and personal abuse.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If, to be brief, in what I have put forth there has been a preponderance of censure over commendation,—is there not to
            be imagined for this preponderance a more charitable motive
            than any which the Outises have been magnanimous enough
            to assign me—is not this preponderance, in a word, the natural and inevitable tendency of all criticism worth the name
            in this age of so universal an authorship, that no man in his
            senses will pretend to deny the vast predominance of good
            writers over bad ?
         </p>
         <p>"And now," says Outis," [and now too, say I] “ for the matter of
            Longfellow's imitations--in what do they consist? The critic is not
            very specific in this charge. Of what kind are they? Are they imi-
            tations of thought? Why not call them plagiarisms then, and show
            them  up? Or are they only verbal imitations of style? Perhaps this
            is one of them, in his poem on the "Sea Weed,"
            -------------------------------------------------------------"drifting, drifting,
            drifting,
            On the shifting
            Currents of the restless main.
            resembling in form and collocation only, a line in a beautiful and very
            
         </p>
         <p>powerful poem of Mr. Edgar A. Poe. (Write it rather Edgar a
            Poet, and then it is right to a T.) I have not the poem before me
            and have forgotten its title. But he is describing a magnificent intellect in ruins, if I remember rightly—and, speaking of the eloquence
            of its better days, represents it as	
         </p>
         <p>----- “flowing, flowing, flowing,
            Like a river.”
            
         </p>
         <p>Is this what the critic means ? Is it such imitations as this that he
            alludes to ? If not, I am at fault, either in my reading of Longfellow,
            or in my general familiarity with the American Poets. If this be the
            kind of imitation referred to, permit me to say, the charge is too paltry for any man, who valued his reputation either as a gentleman or a
            scholar.”
         </p>
         <p>Elsewhere he says:—
            
         </p>
         <p>Moreover, this poem contains an example of that kind of repetition
            which I have supposed the critic meant to charge upon Longfellow as
            one of his imitations—
         </p>
         <p>Away—away—away—&amp;c.
            
         </p>
         <p>I might pursue it farther, but I will not. Such criticisms only make
            the author of them contemptible, without soiling a plume in the cap
            of his victim.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The first point to be here observed is the complacency
            with which Outis supposes me to make a certain charge and
            then vituperates me for his own absurd supposition. Were
            I, or any man, to accuse Mr. Longfellow of imitation on the
            score of thrice employing a word in consecutive connexion,
            then I, (or any man) would only be guilty of as great a sotticism as was Outis in accusing me of imitation on the score
            of the refrain. The repetition in question is assuredly not
            claimed by myself as original—I should therefore be wary
            how I charged Mr. Longfellow with imitating it from myself. It is, in fact, a musical effect, which is the common
            property of all mankind, and has been their common property for ages.
         </p>
         <p>Nevertheless the quotation of this
            “drifting, drifting, drifting”
            
         </p>
         <p>is on the part of Outis, a little unfortunate. Most certainly
            the supposed imitation had never been observed by me—nor
            even had I observed it, should I have considered it individually, as a point of any moment;—but all will admit, (since
            Outis himself has noticed the parallel,) that, were a second
            parrallel of any obviousness to be established from the same
            brief poem, “The Sea-Weed,” this second would come in
            very strong corroboration of the first. Now, the sixth stanza
            of this very “Sea-Weed” (which was first published in
            “Graham’s Magazine” for January 1845) commences with
         </p>
         <p>“ From the for off isles enchanted
            
         </p>
         <p>and in a little poem of my own, addressed “ To Mary,” and
            first published at page 636 of the first volume of the “ Southern Literary Messenger,” will be found the lines:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>„ And thus thy memory is to me
            Like some enchanted far off isle
            In some tumultuous sea.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But to show, in general, what I mean by accusing Mr. Longfellow of imitation, I collate his “ Midnight Mass for the Dying
            Year” with " The Death of the Old Year” of Tennyson.
         </p>
         <p>MIDNIGHT MASS FOR THE DYING YEAR.
            Yes, the Year is growing old,
            
         </p>
         <p>And his eve is pale and bleared,
            Death, with frosty hand and cold,
            Plucks the old man by the beard,
            Sorely,—sorely !
         </p>
         <p>The leaves are falling, falling,
            Solemnly and slow;
            Caw, caw, the rooks are calling;
            It is a sound of woe,
            A sound of woe!
            
         </p>
         <p>Through woods and mountain-passes
            The winds, like anthems, roll;
            They are chanting solemn masses,
            Singing, Pray for this poor soul,
            Pray,—pray!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>And the hooded clouds, like friars,
            Tell their beads in drops of rain,
            And patter their doleful prayers ;
         </p>
         <p>Put their prayers are all in vain,
            All in vain!
            There he stands in the foul weather,
            The foolish, fond Old Year,
            Crowned with wild flowers and with
            heather,
            Like weak, despised Lear,
            A king,—a king !
            Then comes the summer-like day,
            Bids the old man rejoice!
            His joy! his last! O, the old man
            gray,
            Loveth her ever soft voice
            Gentle and low.
            To the crimson woods he saith—
            To the voice gentle and low,
            Of the soft air like a daughter’s breath,
            Pray do not mock me so !
            Do not laugh at me !
            And now the sweet day is dead ;
            Cold in his arms it lies;
            No stain from its breath is spread
            Over the glassy skies,
            No mist nor stain !
            Then, too, the Old Year dieth,
            And the forests utter a moan,
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page196"></div>
            Like the voice of one who crieth
            In the wilderness alone,
            Vex not his ghost!
            Then comes, with an awful roar,
            Gathering and sounding on,
            The storm-wind from Labrador,
            The wind Euroclydon,
            The storm-wind!
            Howl! howl! and from the forest
            Sweep the red leaves away !
            Would, the sins that thou abhor-
            rest,
            O soul! could thus decay,
            And be swept away !
            For there shall come a mightier blast,
            There shall be a darker day ;
            
         </p>
         <p>And the stars, from heaven down-cast,
            Like red leaves be swept away !
            Kyrie Eleyson !
         </p>
         <p>Christie Eleyson !
            THE DEATH OF THE OLD YEAR.
            Full knee-deep lies the winter snow,
            And the winter winds are wearily sighing;
            Toll ye the church-bell sad and low,
            And tread softly, and speak low,
            For the Old Year lies a-dying.
            Old Year, you must not die,
            You came to us so readily,
            You lived with us so steadily.
            Old Year, you shall not die.
            He lieth still: he doth not move ;
            He will not see the dawn of day ;
            He hath no other life above—
            He gave me a friend, and a true, true love.
            And the New Year will take ’em away.
            Old Year, you must not go,
            So long as you have been with us,
            Such joy as you have seen with us,
            Old Year, you shall not go.
            He frothed his bumpers to the brim;
            A jollier year we shall not see ;
            But though his eyes are waxing dim,
            And though his toes speak ill of him,
            He was a friend to me.
            Old Year, you shall not die ;
            We did so laugh and cry with you,
            I’ve half a mind to die with you.
            Old Year, if you must die.
            He was full of joke and jest,
            But all his merry quips are o’er;
            To see him die, across the waste
            His son and heir doth ride post haste,
            But he ’ll be dead before.
            Every one for his own ;
            The night is starry and cold, my friend,
            And the New Year, blithe and bold, my friend,
            Comes up to take his own.
            How hard he breathes ! Over the snow
            I heard just now the crowing cock.
            The shadows flicker to and fro :
            The cricket chirps : the light bums low:
            ’Tis nearly one o’clock.
            Shake hands before you die ;
            Old Year, we ’ll dearly rue for you,
            What is it we can do tor you ?
            Speak out before you die.
            His face is growing sharp and thin—
            Alack ! our friend is gone !
            Close up his eyes; tie up his chin ;
            Step from the corpse and let him in
            That standeth there alone,
            And waiteth at the door.
            There’s a new foot on the floor, my friend,
            And a new face at the door, my friend,
            A new face at the door.
            
         </p>
         <p>I have no idea of commenting, at any length, upon this
            imitation ; which is too palpable to be mistaken ; and which
            belongs to the most barbarous class of literary piracy ; that
            class in which, while the words of the wronged author are
            avoided, his most intangible, and therefore his least defensible and least reclaimable properly, is appropriated. Here,
            with the exception of lapses, which, however, speak volumes,
            (such for instance as the use of the capitalized “ Old Year,”
            the general peculiarity of the rhythm, and the absence of
            rhyme at the end of each stanza,) there is nothing of a visible or palpable nature by which the source of the American
            poem can be established. But then nearly all that is valuable
            in the piece of Tennyson, is the first conception of personifying
            the Old Year as a dying old man, with the singularly wild
            and fantastic manner in which that conception is carried out.
            Of this conception and of this manner he is robbed. What
            is here not taken from Tennyson, is made up mosaically,
            from the death scene of Cordelia, in “Lear”—to which I refer the curious reader.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In “ Graham’s Magazine" for February 1843, there appeared a poem, furnished by Professor Longfellow, entitled “The
            Good George Campbell,” and purporting to be a translation
            from the German of O. L. B. Wolff. In “ Minstrelsy An-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>cient and Modern by William Motherwell, published by John
            Wylie, Glasgow 1827,” is to be found a poem partly compiled and partly written by Motherwell himself. It is entitled
            “ The Bonnie George Campbell.” I give the two side by
            side:
         </p>
         <p>MOTHERWELL.
            Hie upon Hielands
            And low upon Tay,
            Bonnie George Campbell
            Rade out on a day.
            Saddled and bridled
            And gallant rade he ;
            Hame cam his gude horse,
            But never cam he.
            Out cam his auld mither
            Greeting fu’ sair,
            And out cam his bonnie bride
            Rivin’ her hair.
            Saddled and bridled
            And booted rade he ;
            Toom harae cam the saddle,
            But never cam he.
            “My meadow lies green,
            And my corn is unshorn;
            My barn is too big,
            And my baby’s unborn.”
            Saddled and bridled
            And booted rade he;
            Toom hame cam the saddle,
            But never cam he.
            LONGFELLOW.
            High on the Highlands,
            And deep in the day,
            The good George Campbell
            Rode free and away.
            All saddled, all bridled,
            Gay garments he wore ;
            Home came his gude steed,
            But he nevermore.
            Out came his mother,
            Weeping so sadly ;
            Out came his beauteous bride
            Weeping so madly.
            All saddled, all bridled,
            Strong armor he wore ;
            Home came the saddle,
            But he nevermore.
            My meadow lies green,
            Unreaped is my corn,
            My garner is empty,
            My child is unborn.
            All saddled, all bridled,
            Sharp weapons he bore:
            Home came the saddle,
            But he nevermore!
            
         </p>
         <p>Professor Longfellow defends himself (I learn) from the
            charge of imitation in this case, by the assertion that he did
            translate from Wolff, but that Wolff copied from Motherwell.
            I am willing to believe almost anything rather than so gross
            a plagiarism as this seems to be—but there are difficulties
            which should be cleared up. In the first place how happens
            it that, in the transmission from the Scotch into the German,
            and again from the German into the English, not only the
            versification should have been rigidly preserved, but the
            rhymes, and alliterations ? Again ; how are we to imagine
            that Mr. Longfellow with his known intimate acquaintance
            with “ Motherwell’s Minstrelsy” did not at once recognize so
            remarkable a poem when he met it in Wolff? I have now
            before me a large volume of songs, ballads, etc. collected by
            Wolff; but there is here no such poem—and, to be sure, it.
            should not be sought in such a collection. No collection of
            his own poems has been published, and the piece of which
            we are in search must be fugitive—unless, indeed, it is included in a volume of translations from various tongues, of
            which O. L. B. Wolff is also the author—but of which I am
            ! unable to obtain a copy.* It is by no means improbable that
            here the poem in question is to be found—but in this case it
            must have been plainly acknowledged as a translation, with
            its original designated. How, then, could Professor Longfellow have translated it as original with Wolff? These
            are mysteries yet to be solved. It is observable—peculiarly
            ! so—that the Scotch “ Toom” is left untranslated in the version of Graham’s Magazine. Will it be found that the same
            omission occurs in Wolff’s version ?
         </p>
         <p>In “ The Spanish Student” of Mr. Longfellow, at page 80,
            will be found what follows:
            
         </p>
         <p>Scene IV.—Preciosa's chamber. She is sitting with a book in her hand
            near a table, on which are flowers. A bird singing in its cage. The
            Count of Lara enters behind, unperceived.
         </p>
         <p>Preciosa reads.
            All are sleeping, weary heart!
            Thou, thou only sleepless art!
            Heigho ! I wish Victorian were here.
            I know not what it is makes me so restless! [The bird sings.
            Thou little prisoner with thy motley coat,
            That from thy vaulted, wiry dungeon singest,
            Like thee I am a captive, and, like thee,
            I have a gentle gaoler. Lack-a-day !
            All are sleeping, weary heart !
            Thou, thou only sleepless art !
            All this throbbing, all thia aching,
            Evermore shall keep thee waking,
            For a heart in sorrow breaking
            Thinketh ever of its smart !
            
         </p>
         <p>Thou speakest truly, poet! and methinks
            More hearts are breaking in this world of ours
            Than one would say. In distant villages
            And solitudes remote, where winds nave wafted
            The barbed seeds of love, or birds of passage
            Scattered them in their flight, do they take root,
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>• Sammlung vorzuglicher Volkalieder der bekanntesten Nationen,
            grostentheils run ersten male, metrisch in das Deutche ubertragen.
            Frankfurt, 1837.
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page197"></div>
            And grow in silence, and in silence perish.
            Who hears the falling of the forest leaf?
            Or who takes note of every flower that dies ?
            Heigho ! I wish Victorian would come.
            Dolores! [ Turns to lay down her book, and perceives the Count.
            Ha!
            Lara. Senora, pardon me.
            Preciosa. How’s this? Dolores!
            Lara.	Pardon me—
            Preciosa.	Dolores!
            Lara. Be not alarmed ; I found no one in waiting.
            If I have been too bold----
            Preciosa [turning her back upon him]. You are too bold !
            Retire ! retire, and leave me !
            Lara.	My dear lady,
            First hear me ! I beseech you, let me speak !
            'Tis for your good I come.
            Preciosa [turning toward him with indignation].
            Begone ! Begone i
            
         </p>
         <p>You are the Count of Lara, but your deeds
            Would make the statues of your ancestors
            Blush on their tombs ! Is it Castilian honor,
         </p>
         <p>Is it Castilian pride, to steal in here
            Upon a friendless girl, to do her wrong?
            O	shame ! shame ! shame ! that you, a nobleman,
            Should be so little noble iu your thoughts
            As to send jewels here to win my love,
            And think to buy my honor with your gold I
            1	have no words to tell you how I scorn you.
            Begonel The sight of you is hateful to me!
            Begone, I say!
            
         </p>
         <p>A few passages farther on in the same scene we meet the
            following stage directions:—“He tries to embrace her, she
            starts back and draws a dagger from her bosom." A little
            farther still and “ Victorian enters behind.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Compare all this with a " Scene from Politian, an unpublished Tragedy by Edgar A. Poe,” to be found either at page
            13, or at page 106, of the second volume of the “ Southern
            Literary Messenger.”
         </p>
         <p>The scene opens with the following stage directions:
            
         </p>
         <p>A lady's apartment, with a window open and looking into a garden.
            Lalage in deep mourning, reading at a table, on which lie some
            books and a hand mirror. In the back ground, Jacinta leans
            carelessly on the back of a chair.
         </p>
         <p>Lalage reading. " It in another climate, so he said,
            Bore a bright golden flower but not i’ this soil.
            [Pauses, turns over some leaves, and then resumes.
            No ling’ring winters there, nor snow, nor shower,
            But ocean ever, to refresh mankind,
            Breathes the shrill spirit of the western wind.”
            Oh, beautiful! most beautiful! how like
            To what my fever’d soul doth dream of Heaven !
            O happy land ! [pauses] She died—the maiden died—
            O still more happy maiden who couldst die !
            Jacinta!
            [Jacinta returns no answer, and Lalage presently resumes.
            Again a similar tale,
            Told of a beauteous dame beyond the sea!
            Thus speaketh one Ferdinand i' the words of the play,
            ** She died full young”—one Bossola answers him
            u I think not so ; her infelicity
            Seemed to have years too many.” Ah luckless lady !
            Jacinta!  [Siill no answer.] Here’s a far sterner story,
            But like, on very like in its despair,—
            Of that Egyptian queen, winning so easily
            A thousand hearts, losing at length her own.
            
         </p>
         <p>She died. Thus endeth the history, and her maids
            Lean over her and weep—two gentle maids
            With gentle names, Eiros and Charmion.
         </p>
         <p>Rainbow and Dove—Jacinta!
            
         </p>
         <p>[Jacinta finally in a discussion about certain jewels, insults
            her mistress, who bursts into tears.
            Lalage. Poor Lalage ! and is it come to this?
         </p>
         <p>Thy servant maid !---but courage !—’tis but a viper
            Whom thou hast cherished to sting thee to the soul !
            [ Taking up the mirror.
            Ha ! here at least’s a friend—too much a friend
            Iu earlier days—a friend will not deceive thee.
            Fair mirror and true ! now tell me, for thou canst,
            A tale—a pretty tale—and heed thou not
            Though it be rife with woe. It answers me.
            It sneaks of sunkeu eyes, and wasted cheeks,
            And beauty long deceased—remembers me
            Of Joy departed—Hope, the Seraph Hope
            Inurned and entombed !—now, in a tone
            Low, sad, and solemn, but most audible
            Whispers of early grave untimely yawning
            For ruined maid. Fair mirror aud true ! thou liest not.
            Thou hast no end to gain—no heart to break.
            Castiglione lied who said he loved—
            Thou true—he false !—false !—false !
            [ While she speaks a Monk enters her apartment, and approach-
            es unobserved.
            Monk.	Refuge thou hast
            Sweet daughter ! in Heaven. Think of eternal things !
            Give up thy soul to penitence, and pray.
            Lalage. I cannot pray!-- soul is at war with God !
            [Arising hurriedly.
            The frightful sounds of merriment below
            Disturb my senses—go, I cannot pray !
            The sweet airs from the garden worry me !
            
         </p>
         <p>Thy presence grieves me—go !—thy priestly raiment
            Fills me with dread—thy ebony crucifix
            With horror and awe !
         </p>
         <p>Monk.	Think of thy precious soul!
            
         </p>
         <p>Lalage. Think of my early days !—think of my father
            And mother in Heaven ! think of our quiet home
            And the rivulet that ran before the door !
         </p>
         <p>Think of my little sisters l—think of them !
            
         </p>
         <p>And think of me !—think of my trusting love
            And confidence—his vows—iny ruin—think—think
            Of my unspeakable misery !—begone !
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Yet stay ! yet stay ! what was it thou saidst of prayer
            And penitence ? Didst thou not speak of faith
            And vows before the throne ?
         </p>
         <p>Monk.	I did.
            Lalage.	’Tis well.
            There is a vow were fitting should be made—
            A sacred vow, imperative, and urgentt—
            A solemn vow.
            Monk.	Daughter, this zeal is well.
            J.alage. Father ! this zeal is any thing but well.
            Hast thou a crucifix fit for this thing ?
            A crucifix whereon to register
            A pious vow ? 	[He hands her his own.
            Not that—oh ! no !—no ! no ! [Shuddering.
            Not that ! not that ! I tell thee, holy man,
            Thy raiments and thy ebony cross affright me :
            Stand back! I have a crucifix myself—
            I have a crucifix ! Methinks ’twere fitting
            The deed—the vow—the symbol of the deed—
            And the deed’s register should tally, father !
            Behold the cross wherewith a vow like mine
            Is written in Heaven !
            [Draws a cross-handled dagger and raises it on high.
            Monk.	Thy words are madness, daughter !
            And speak a purpose unholy—thy lips are livid—
            Thine eyes are wild—tempt not the wrath divine—
            Pause ere too late !—oh ! be not—be not rash !
            Swear not the oath—oh ! swear it not!
            Lalage.	’Tis sworn!
            The coincidences here are too markedly peculiar to be
            gainsayed. The sitting at the table with books, etc.—the
            flowers on the one hand, and the garden on the other_________the
            
         </p>
         <p>presence of the pert maid—the reading aloud from the book
            —the pausing and commenting—the plaintiveness of what
            is read, in accordance with the sorrow of the reader—the abstraction—the frequent calling of the maid by name—the refusal of the maid to answer—the jewels—the “ begone”—the
            unseen entrance of a third person from behind—and the drawing of the dagger—are points sufficiently noticeable to establish at least the imitation beyond all doubt.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Let us now compare the concluding lines of Mr. Longfellow’s “ Autumn” with that of Mr. Bryant’s “ Thanatopsis:”
            Mr. B. has it thus:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>So live, that when thy summons comes to join
            The innumerable caravan that moves
            To that mysterious realm where each shall take
            His chamber in the silent halls of Death,
         </p>
         <p>Thou go not, like the quarry slave at night,
            Scourged to his dungeon ; but, sustained and soothed]
            
         </p>
         <p>By an unfaltering trust, approach thy grave
            Like one who wraps the drapery of his couch
            About him, and lies down to pleasant dreams.
         </p>
         <p>Mr. L. thus:
            To him the wind, aye and the yellow leaves
            Shall have a voice and give him eloquent teachings.
            
         </p>
         <p>He shall so hear the solemn hymn that Death
            Has lilted up for all, that he shall go
            To his long resting-place without a tear.
         </p>
         <p>Again, in his “Prelude to the Voices of the Night” Mr.
            Longfellow says:—
            Look then into thine heart and write !
            Sir Philip Sidney in the “ Astrophel and Stella” has:
            Foole, said my Muse to me, looke in thy heart und write !
            Again—in Longfellow’s “ Midnight Mass” we read:
            And the hooded clouds like friars.
            The Lady in Milton’s “ Comus” says:
            When the grey-hooded even
            Like a sad votarist in palmer’s weeds.
            And again:—these lines by Professor Longfellow will be
            remembered by every body:
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page198"></div>
            Art is long and time is fleeting,
            And our hearts, though stout and brave,
            Still like muffled drums are beating
            Funeral marches to the grave.
            
         </p>
         <p>But if any one will turn to page 66 of John Sharpe’s edition
            of Henry Headley’s Select Beauties of Ancient English Poetry, published at London in 1810, he will there find an Exequy on the death of his wife by Henry King, Bishop of Chichester, and therein also the following lines, where the author
            is speaking of following his wife to the grave :
         </p>
         <p>But hark ! my pulse, like a soft drum,
            Beats my approach—tells thee I come !
            And slow howe’er my marches be,
            I shall at last sit down by thee.
            
         </p>
         <p>Were I disposed indeed, to push this subject any farther,
            I should have little difficulty in culling, from the works of
            the author of “ Outre Mer,” a score or two of imitations
            quite as palpable as any upon which I have insisted. The
            fact of the matter is, that the friends of Mr. Longfellow,
            so far from undertaking to talk about my “ carping littleness”
            in charging Mr. Longfellow with imitation, should have
            given me credit, under the circumstances, for great moderation, in charging him with imitation alone. Had I accused
            him, in loud terms, of manifest and continuous plagiarism,
            I should but have echoed the sentiment of every man of letters in the land beyond the immediate influence of the Longfellow coterie. And since I, “ knowing what I know and
            seeing what I have seen”—submitting in my own person to
            accusations of plagiarism for the very sins of this gentleman
            against myself—since I contented myself, nevertheless, with
            simply setting forth the merits of the poet in the strongest
            light, whenever an opportunity was afforded me, can it be
            considered either decorous or equitable on the part of Professor Longfellow to beset me, upon my first adventuring an infinitesimal sentence of dispraise, with ridiculous anonymous
            letters from his friends, and moreover, with malice prepense,
            to instigate against me the pretty little witch entitled Miss
            Walter; advising her and instructing her to pierce me to
            death with the needles of innumerable epigrams, rendered
            unnecessarily and therefore cruelly painful to my feelings by
            being first carefully deprived of the point ?
         </p>
         <p>E. A. P.
            A COMMISSION OF LUNACY.
            
         </p>
         <p>I was once called to decide upon the case of a person who
            was thought by his friends to be insane. He had been sent
            to a mad house, and in one of his lucid intervals had demanded a trial of the county judge, and a trial was granted.
            A jury of six men, of whom I was one, were to decide upon
            his case. He was a healthy looking gentleman, with nothing unusual in his appearance excepting a restlessness of
            his eyes, which might not have been observed had he not
            been accused of insanity. The proofs of his madness were
            very clear, but he showed so much coolness and clear thinking in his cross-questioning of witnesses, that I felt some
            hesitation in pronouncing him unsound of mind. His case
            was a very sad one, and he melted the hearts of all who
            heard him when he appealed to the jury.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ I deny that I am insane, gentlemen,” he said, when the
            judge gave him leave to speak, “ but that is a matter of course.
            No man ever thought himself insane; neither can any man
            ever think himself so; for, having no standard of soundness
            but what exists in his own mind, he cannot be unsound to
            himself though he may be manifestly so in the mind of another. But who shall determine what is madness and what
            is not ? Be careful, gentlemen, how you pronounce me mad,
            lest to-morrow I be called to pronounce you so. The proofs
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>that have been offered to you of my madness are to me proofs
            of entire soundness of mind. I would be mad were I anything different from what I have been represented. They
            have brought three physicians, who all say that I am mad.
            Yet I will compel you to admit that the madness is in them
            and not in me. I was sick, very sick, sick at heart, for you
            must know that I had lost my Bessy and my little boy, my
            little boy.” Here the unfortunate hesitated and seemed to
            lose himself entirely. “ I said that I was sick, but it was
            Bessy. But it must have been me. Yes, I was sick, very
            sick, sick at heart, for my little boy and Bessy. Bessy again.
            Yes, Bessy had been sick but now it was I. I was sick, and
            they brought me a physician. He felt my pulse, he looked
            upon me with his cold gray eyes, and then reached me a
            tumbler half full of a nauseous liquid which he said would
            quiet me, and do me good. But all the while I was quieter
            than a rock, and colder, and harder. I thought that he
            needed the stuff more than myself, so I caught his head between my knees, and though he struggled hard yet I poured
            it down his throat, gentlemen, and he was glad enough to escape. Then they brought another to me, who gave me a
            little globule of sugar, a pin’s head was a cannon ball beside
            it, and told me that it would cure my fever. Do you blame
            me for thrusting the madman out of my chamber ? Then they
            brought me another, who would give me no medicine at all,
            but ordered them to swathe me in wet sheets. Him too I
            drove from my presence, the lunatic. Yet these are the men
            who come here to swear to my insanity. Ah, gentlemen, I
            am not mad, but I wonder that I am not. The combined
            powers have taken away my Bessy and my little boy, and I
            shall never, never, never see them more. Never.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It was a perfectly clear case of lunacy, and a pitiable one.
            But when we retired to the jury-room, one of the jurors
            would not agree with the other five. He stretched himself
            upon a bench, threw a handkerchief over his head, and requested us to wake him when we had come over to his way
            of thinking. For myself, I was not disposed to be bullied
            out of my opinion, so I too lay down upon a bench, determined not to yield an inch of my right to think for myself,
            and in a few minutes fell fast asleep ; but I had better have
            kept awake, for the moment that my eyelids fell I had to
            perform the part of a juror again.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It was the same ill-lighted room, the same dull judge who
            slept through half the trial, the same clownish spectators,
            the same everything, except the defendant, who yet seemed
            to be the same person in a different habit.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>He was a good looking youth, indeed, I had never seen a
            finer; his dark chesnut hair and sandy beard were equal to
            a patent of nobility, for they proclaimed his Saxon blood,
            and proved him of a race that came upon the earth to conquer
            it. His eyes were grey and his complexion fair. But, poor man!
            he was out of his mind. His father was a merchant, and he
            wept while he gave evidence to his son’s insanity. He, the
            son, would wear his beard, and this was the proof of his
            madness. In spite of the jeers, the sneers, and the laughter
            of the world, he would let his beard grow as nature intended. Poor fellow! We all pitied him. So intelligent, so
            gentle in his manners, so happily circumstanced, and yet
            mad ! He had the hardihood to declare in open court, that
            he saw no reason why he should deprive his face of the covering which God had put upon it.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>"No reason!” cried his mother, “ O my son, does not your
            father shave, your uncle, your brother, all the world shave
            but yourself? No reason for shaving ? O! my son !”
         </p>
         <p>“ True,” replied the unfortunate youth as he stroked his
            beard with ineffable content, “ true, but they are all mad or
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page199"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>they would not. I need my beard to protect my face and
            throat from the wet and cold. It helps to hide the sharp
            angles of my jaws, it makes me more comely, adds to my
            strength and keeps me in health. Do I not look more like a
            man than my father, with his smooth, pale face, who has nothing but his clothes to distinguish him from a woman ?
            Look at him, he has scraped all the hair off' his chin and
            placed another man’s hair on his head. Beautiful consistency. To shave his chin and put false hair on his head! What
            a mad outrage upon nature. Hair is not always necessary to
            the head for it often falls off as we grow old, but it never
            drops from the chin. I appeal to this honorable court—”
         </p>
         <p>“ Silence !” cried the honorable court, who at that moment
            woke up.
            “ Justice never sleeps, excepting on the bench,” observed
            the youth in a low voice.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Go on,” said the honorable court, whose business, when
            out of court, was horse dealing, which fitted him in an eminent degree for the responsibilities of his office.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“I appeal to this honorable court,” continued the insane
            youth, “ I appeal to you, gentlemen of the jury, and I would,
            if 1 were permitted, appeal to these fair ladies (there were
            several old gossips in the room) to say whether I am not
            more sane than my father.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ I can’t allow such audacious remarks as those in this
            place,” said the honorable court, rising and wiping its honorable face with a dingy handkerchief. “ This thing mustn't
            proceed no further. 1 don’t know, gentlemen of the jury,
            as I have ever been more seriously affected in my life, than
            I have been by this melancholy trial.”
         </p>
         <p>“ Probaby not,” said the maniac.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ The court will allow no interruption from no one,” said
            the honorable court, fixing its dreadfully stern eyes on the
            madman and stretching out its stumpy fore-finger in a threatening manner. “ My heart has been melted by the scene we
            have witnessed.”	
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ A very little heat will melt ice,” said the mad youth.
            “My feelings is too much for me to proceed,” continued
            the honorable court, “ I resign the case into your hands,
            gentlemen of the jury, only remarking that the young man is
            mad, and so you must give in your werdick.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The poor youth was immediately put into a strait-jacket
            and dragged away, yet he still seemed to stand at the bar,
            but his appearance was changed. He wore a broad brimmed hat made of oaten straw, a linen blouse which reached
            below his knees, and a shirt of snowy whiteness open at the
            throat, so that his manly neck was fully exposed. His complexion was brown, his eye clear and bright, his laughing
            mouth displayed teeth of a pearly lustre, and he appeared to
            receive great pleasure in snuffing the fragrance of a bunch of
            field flowers which he held in his hand. I thought, as I looked at him, that I had never seen a youth who bore so many
            marks of unequivocal soundness of mind and body. But he
            was mad, notwithstanding all. His own father was the first
            witness examined. Poor old man ! he could hardly articulate the words which a sense of duty to his child compelled
            him to utter.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Nothing but a hope that judicious medical treatment
            may restore my son to his senses, could induce me to this
            dreadful alternative,” said the old man after he had been
            sworn. “ My poor son has been afflicted with his disorder
            for two years. We have tried all gentle means to cure him,
            but he grows worse and worse. The proofs of his madness
            are so glaring that he cannot be kept from the mad-house.
            He is now in his twenty-fifth year; he has had a good education, the best that money could procure; he has made the
            tour of Europe ; he has had all the advantages which my extensive business connexions could give him, and yet, gentlemen, regardless of my wishes and his own welfare, he has
            married a poor young woman and gone to bury his splendid
            accomplishments on a farm. Is it not dreadful, gentlemen,
            to witness such a sacrifice ? I offered him a share in my
            business, I proposed to establish him in a splendid distillery,
            but such was the poor creature's derangement of intellect that
            even this brilliant offer could not draw him from the obscurity of the country. Look at his dress, gentlemen ; if the court,
            please, is not that prima facie evidence of his insanity ?"
            The court thought it was, but would not give a decided
         </p>
         <p>opinion without first looking into somebody’s reports.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Look at him, gentlemen, would any body believe that he
            was the son of a rich merchant ? That disgraceful blouse
            like a common laborer’s. That coarse straw hat! O, genmen, pardon a father’s weakness ! I can say no more.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The mother of the insane man appeared next, but her distress was too great to admit of her giving her evidence in a
            straight forward manner.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>She believed her son to be crazy. Had first suspected
            it on his return from Paris on account of his plain clothes ; he
            had left off coffee and tea and drank nothing but cold water;
            he talked strangely about the country; quite unlike her
            other children, who were fond of style and lived respectably ;
            insanity not peculiar to the family ; was not influenced by
            her husband; had seen her son laugh with the coachman ;
            had opposed his marriage; thought it a decided proof of insanity to marry out of one’s own circle ; had been the first
            to propose sending her son to the insane retreat.
         </p>
         <p>After the witnesses delivered their testimony, the court
            told the maniac that he might address the jury.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ I have nothing to say in regard to the testimony,” said
            the youth, “ but that it is all true. I prefer the sweets of a
            country life to the bitter toils of business. I have a wife
            whom I love ; she brought me no fortune, it is true, but she
            helps me, daily, to earn one. I have a little farm which
            yields more than I need; I have good health, a quiet conscience, and two lovely children whose minds and bodies I
            am striving to rear in conformity with the dictates of nature.
            For these I prefer a moderate fortune in the country to an
            immodedrate one in the city. Besides, I look upon the judgment pronounced upon Adam in the light of a command, and
            I was never happy until the sweat of my own brow seasoned
            my daily food.”
         </p>
         <p>The jury pronounced him mad without leaving their seats.
            “ A righteous werdick!” said the honorable court.
            He was led from the court-room, and yet he still stood
            there, such are the inconsistencies of dreams.
            
         </p>
         <p>He was now dressed in rusty clothes; his countenance was
            subdued by thought; he was unhappy but not uneasy ; his
            eyes were cast down, his lips were more closely pressed together, and the vigorous look of youth was changed for a
            gravity of demeanor that sat upon him well, though it seemed too grave for his years. There was literally a cloud of
            witnesses to his insanity. He had been heard to pity a condemned felon ; he had said irreverend things of the law; he
            had spoken against the clergy; he had abused physic;
            he had given his money to vagabonds; he laughed at the
            fashions; he had cried at a wedding; he was opposed to war;
            he had been struck without returning the blow ; he had pitied a slave holder ; he had——. But the jury would hear no
            more. They pronounced him mad with one voice. All Bedlam seemed now broken loose. No sooner was one maniac
            pronounced upon than another occupied the stand. The obscure little court-room began to look like the ante-room of
            the revolutionary tribunal. To expedite business a whole lot
            of maniacs were put up together and judged in a lump.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>One was a young girl of eighteen who had married her
            father’s poor clerk whom she loved, when she might have
            married her father’s rich partner whose money her friends
            loved ; a Wall-street broker who had refused usury on a note ;
            a grocer who had recommended a customer not to buy his
            sugar because he could buy cheaper elsewhere ; a man who
            corrected a post office error when his letter had been undercharged; a political orator who had refused an office because
            he did not think himself entitled to one ; a lawyer who refused to advocate the cause of a rogue on the pretence of
            conscientious scruples ; a critic who doubted his own infallibility; a lieutenant of marines who gave up his commission
            and earned his bread by his own labor; an editor of a newspaper who had never called names; an English traveller
            without national prejudices; a midshipman who never
            damned the service; an artist who painted from nature; an
            author who was satisfied with a review of his book; a young
            lady who was offended at being told that she was pretty ;
            a poet who considered himself inferior to Shakspeare. These
            were all pronounced mad. But the noise of their removal
            woke me, and finding that the other jurors had gone over to
            the one who was for rendering a verdict of not insane, I too,
            instructed by my dream, concluded to coincide with them,
            lest I should establish a precedent by which I might at some
            future day be pronounced mad myself.
         </p>
         <p>HARRY FRANCO.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page200"></div>
            PORTRAIT OF AN ANNEXATIONIST.
            
         </p>
         <p>It has not been for lack of interest, or of opinion, that we have kept silent on the
            important subject of annexation. But
            seeing that the thing was determined upon, we saw no good in wasting our little space
            in the reading world by fretting
            and fuming to no purpose. The deed has been done, and the whole country has been standing
            with open mouth ever since
            it was done, waiting to see how it would affect the various powers,—England, France,
            and Mexico; but no intelligence has
            yet been had from either. There is one great power, however, a crowned head, of whom
            nobody seems to have had a
            thought, who has felt more interest in the matter than any other potentate, and from
            whom we have heard by mesmeric express. To him the news of the joint resolutions came like a cool wind in summer, bracing
            up his nerves and giving him a
            sensation of ineffable satisfaction. His imperial majesty, Satan the first, received
            the intelligence with unbounded and inexpressible delight, inexpressible at least in words. To give the public some idea
            of his content, our artist has furnished us
            with a fac simile of his serene highness as he appeared while listening to the joint
            resolutions which were read to him, by
            his private Secretary, with all their amendments.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The likeness is indisputable, and the satisfaction immense; though commonly of a lean
            habit, it will be seen that he
            has grown fat upon it; his fancy is tickled to a degree past bearing, with visions
            of prospective fields of carnage, of an extended area of--------Freedom; of battles by sea; of captives in prison; of broken-hearted
            widows; of weeping orphans;
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>of national debts ; of privateers ; of pirates; of burning villages; sinking ships
            ; heroes; chieftains; gold lace ; epaulettes,
            cripples, drunkards, idlers, ruined cities, and innumerable other delights which he
            feels sure will follow on the heels of annexation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But, hold! The intended annexees refuse to be annexed. His majesty is more displeased
            than any holder of scrip ; he
            fumes and scolds ; he drives even his favorites from him in his wrath. It is not to
            be wondered at; he has not had a taste of
            his favorite pastime, war, in so long a time, that he cannot quietly pocket a disappoinment
            like this. Our artist has
            sketched him again ; but he looks like another personage though he is the same.
         </p>
         <p>He has put on his crown of iron horns to give intensity to his anger. He will play
            the-------with those foolish annexees
            who will not accept the terms of denationalization which have been offered to them.
            But his majesty will again be satisfied :
            there is little doubt of the work being done to his mind by and by.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page201"></div>
            THE ART OF THE USE OF COLOR IN IMITATION IN PAINTING,
            NO. VI.
            REYNOLDS, ALSTON, STUART.
            
         </p>
         <p>To the method recommended by me in an earlier article,
            for painting a head, I propose now to add another hint, which
            I think will not be lost, the more so as I shall be able to
            bring authority, besides its own self-evident truth.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the picture, such as it was when we left it some weeks
            back, perhaps some greater purity of complexion might be
            desired ; if so, take a very little white in your brush together
            with drying oil, and scumble it thinly over all your flesh, and
            if the reds were of sufficient strength to bear this slight
            weakening, it will be as pure as a white lily. This comes
            naturally after what I have said of this mode, and perfectly
            harmonises with it; where this has been done, should it not
            answer the expectations or wishes of the painter, let him
            begin it all over again, and do it more thoroughly from the
            beginning; and the end will not disappoint him if he be reasonable. If there is any thing in it, it cannot be perfected at
            one trial, but should not, therefore, discourage those who have
            for years, it may be, made vain efforts to satisfy themselves by
            the ordinary means.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A gentleman of Boston, who was well acquainted with
            Gilbert Stuart, was invited by him to look at a picture,
            which he had just finished, and whilst they were looking at
            it, Mr. S. told my informant, as something worth knowing,
            “ that a wonderful effect could sometimes be produced in
            flesh by passing white all over it.” But this was all—there
            seemed to have been no system, or thorough knowledge of the
            principle, so as to make any thing certain of it, so far as he
            disclosed it. And, indeed, his pictures sufficiently testify to
            the truth of this supposition—for though his heads of aged
            persons, particularly old men with ruddy-veined complexions,
            are often as fine as could be desired, it is a well-known fact,
            that those of young women of delicate color, or children, are
            greatly inferior, bearing no comparison with the former;
            whereas, had he been thoroughly grounded in this mode,
            there would have been no disparity in his more careful pictures, at least not in favor of the coarser subject, but rather,
            on the other hand. But if a general principle for the painting of flesh be a true one, and such as is to be depended upon,
            it will meet all cases, and be as applicable to the one as the
            other.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Reynolds, too, in some notes of his written for the guidance
            of his pupils, and now to be found in Taylor’s translation of
            Mérimée, on Oil Painting, [page 334,] says:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ In respect to painting the flesh tints, after it has been finished
            with very strong colors, pass white over it very thin with oil. I believe it will have a very wonderful effect”—“ or paint carnation too
            red, and then scumble over it with white and black.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This, too, shows how indefinite his knowledge of the cause
            must have been, for it is evident from some of his works that
            I have inspected, that he did not so build up his picture from
            dark to light as I have described.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In a portrait of Charles Carroll, painted by Sir Joshua,
            when our revolutionary hero was a young man, it had been
            reduced by time to a state of the first painting, having been
            thickly impasted with white lead, and the shadows laid
            in gray and solid—the glazings, most likely, of carmine
            and lake, had entirely flown, except in inconsiderable
            streaks here and there; and these washes of fleeting colors
            were probably all that he depended on for his imitations of
            nature. His methods must have been various, throughout
            his life, for some of his pictures are said to retain all their
            color; but he never arrived at what he considered the true
            way, or he would certainly have continued to use it, and he
         </p>
         <p>is known to have kept changing, to the end of his life, seeking
            what he could not find.
            
         </p>
         <p>More than six years since, in conversation with the late
            Washington Alston, I took occasion to speak to him in general terms of this theory of the use of colors, which then, as
            now, interested me very much; he said, that in theory it
            seemed very clear and satisfactory, and admitted that in his
            younger days, twenty or thirty years before, he had himself
            made many experiments of a somewhat similar kind, and did
            not doubt but that it would be as good in practice as in
            thought, if it could be carried out; but he had his doubts
            that light colors so passed over darker ones, as I have described, “ would have the look of a white veil.” The conversation was never renewed, and as I was then too modest
            to point to any of my own pictures where I had made a feeble
            attempt to do the thing I preached, and was not then aware
            of what I have given above in favor of passing white over
            the surface of flesh, from Reynolds or Stuart, I had nothing
            to offer in defence but the simple question, “ well, is not the
            skin actually in some degree a veil ?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Now I have heard it argued by some persons, who doubt
            every thing when they first hear it, “if this theory is true,
            why did not Alston know it ? and Stuart ?” and so they reject
            it;—“ can any thing be more absurd ?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>With great respect for the memory of Mr. Alston, and admiration for many of his works, yet I cannot bv any means
            subscribe to their perfection in color, particularly his latter;
            the best color that I have ever seen of his, must have been
            produced at least twenty years before, and perhaps when he
            was yet endeavoring to attain the right way. Many seem to
            think that the works of Titian are scarcely finer in color than
            those of Alston ; if so, I have greatly overrated the works of
            the former master, and should never despair of the genius of
            our people in renewing the old Venetian glory. The pictures
            of Alston are low in tone, which to my mind constitutes their
            chiefest merit so far as their coloring is concerned ; hut to
            look upon this as his chief excellence does him great injustice. It is the delicacy of his taste in design for which he
            must be wisely distinguished. I do not mean to be understood to say that he had not also a fine eye for color, but that,
            considered as imitations of nature, his flesh wants depth, as
            well as clearness or transparency, being often foxy—and
            when cool, having something of leaden solidity.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If I have offended any one of the innumerable admirers of
            this most distinguished painter by these remarks, let them
            believe, which is true, that I would much rather have left unsaid any unfavorable word of his pictures, than have utterred
            one syllable which I did not most conscientiously believe.
            Moreover, people are so disposed, when they have once set
            up their idol, to attribute to it not only all the knowledge they
            themselves possess, but all they have not, that to have said
            at least as much as this seemed to me a duty. If he had not
            the knowledge of the best means of using his materials, as I
            am quite certain he had not, the fact that thus crippled he
            has done so much better than others, only argues his more
            extraordinary abilities, and it would not be detracting too
            much from any mere man, to say that there are some things
            that he does not know. I could find it in my heart to say
            that even Raffaelle was ignorant on some points where the
            whole strength of others was to be found. No one, I believe,
            has ever attributed to him what is known to have been well
            understood by Paul Veronese, and others of his school.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>To any one acquainted with Alston’s method of painting,
            it will be apparent that he more nearly approached that which
            I have endeavored to set forth, than most of the other painters about. He alternated the three primitive colors all through
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page202"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>his flesh, solidly to he sure, and on the surface instead of
            laying them over each other, and often mixed them all together, producing a sort of neutral olive tint, and passed this
            mixture thinly over all his masses, for unity, and again
            touched into this with red yellow and blue; but reason will
            teach us that this is but a small approach to the system of
            Nature, and had it been so used by Titian, it might very
            safely be doubted—no name being a sufficient authority for
            what reason rejects as inconsistent with its teachings, at
            least if we except Revelation ; and an ingenious painter may
            so use a wrong method, like a skillful lawyer making the
            worse appear the better side, that it will need a jury of more
            than ordinary penetration to detect the error.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As to light passed over a darker color “ appearing like a
            veil,” as supposed by Mr. A., what Reynolds says in its favor,
            will be deemed a fair offset.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Most of the better of our painters who have travelled
            abroad, and copied from the pictures of this greatest of all
            colorists, (Titian) agree that where they had done their best
            to imitate them, an impenetrable mystery seemed to hang
            over his flesh that nothing but nature could parallel—looking, as I have heard it somewhat coarsely expressed, “as if
            it could sweat." When any of Alston’s pictures call forth
            such significant remarks from those who contemplate them,
            it may be time to doubt our eyes and look again.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I should like well to end this article with an urgent recommendation to those who have read what I have written
            with any fixed attention, if they have not already done it, to
            look up the essays of William Hazlitt on Art, particularly one
            first published, I believe, in the Edinburgh Encyclopædia under the title of “ The Fine Arts,” and since republished in
            the same covers with some nonsense, by Haydon on Painting,
            and read them with the attention which the best writings on
            the subject in the English language demand. For in theory,
            they say all that need be said, and had the practical knowledge of their author kept pace with his clear profound
            thoughts and perceptions, the world would not now, perhaps,
            lack at least one modern example of a painter worthy to
            stand beside the great departed ones of old. As it is, we
            have gained a critic of unequalled excellence, who needs first
            to be fairly accepted, to prepare the way for the practical
            talent that will inevitably, soon or late, bring into use what
            he has so ably prepared for the painter who can put his truths
            into his pictures.	william page.
         </p>
         <p>THE GREAT TOWER OF TARUDANT.
            (Concluded from page 171.)
            
         </p>
         <p>At the dawn of day next morning, King Abdallah was
            roused from sleep by a strain of solemn music, that sent a
            thrill of joy and gratitude through his frame, and gave unusual fervency to his sunrise prayers. When he had bathed
            and breakfasted, the same emir who had received him into
            the city, came to conduct him to the royal palace. They proceeded through several noble streets, crowded with animated
            but orderly multitudes, and soon reached the queen’s palace,
            which stood upon a slightly elevated platform in the centre
            of the city. This edifice was not of great extent, but its
            beauty anil splendor excited the king's admiration more than
            anything he had yet beheld. It was a glowing mass of precious stones; the foundations were of emerald, the walls of
            beryl, the roof of amethyst, supported by lofty and elegant
            columns of topaz, while the doors and windows were set with
            diamonds, pearls, and other gems of richest worth. A beautiful garden environed it, whose plants and flowers were
            scarcely more numerous than the brightly plumaged birds
            that sang and sported amidst them.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>On the terrace before the palace the king was met by the
            fairy who had guided him through the desert. She said,
            “ King of Tarudant, my sister awaits your arrival in the
            great hall of audience ; I will conduct you to her presence."
            Taking Abdallah's hand, she led him through apartments
            whose magnificent beauty baffles description ; they were full
            of what seemed to them on entering, to be martial looking
            guards, but as he passed through their bending ranks, they
            changed into beautiful boys, holding olive branches and
            wearing white garments.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The king of Tarudaut entered the audience chamber with
            a throbbing heart, for a mysterious impression in the depths
            of his soul assured him that his destiny depended on the fairy
            queen, and that even more than the recovery of his kingdom
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>was involved in the events that were about to occur. As he
            passed the arched and lofty portal, which was cut through
            one enormous sapphire, his eager eyes glanced rapidly over
            the brilliant throng of courtiers, guards, and emirs, till they
            rested on the person of the sovereign herself. He had expected to behold a grave and majestic figure, but he saw instead
            a form delicate even to slightness, so exquisitely moulded,
            that not the countenance alone but every visible part possessed a defined expression of beauty and goodness. The
            loveliness of her face was radiant like a star; it shone with
            such sweetness and simplicity, that the tender woman, the
            pitying angel and the sinless child seemed combined in its
            gracefully animated lineaments. While the king’s eyes drank
            in these wondrous charms, their fascinating influence glided
            onwards to his heart, and there stamped an impression that
            nor time nor eternity could ever efface.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Still holding the hand of his guide, whose form and features seemed almost unlovely contrasted with those of her
            sister, the king walked slowly onwards amid the murmuring salutations of the multitude that filled the hall. As he
            approached, the queen arose from the throne of pure gold
            whereon she had been seated, and descending its steps of
            sardine stone, came towards him, with a group of beautiful
            young girls bearing up the train of her flowing purple robe.
            When within a few steps she stopped, and the king was
            about to speak, when at that moment the fairy, whose hand
            he held, withdrew it, and moving forward met her sister
            with a warm embrace. While the kiss of greeting yet lingered on their lips, the two forms mingled into one ! By a
            sudden, almost imperceptible transition, the sisters became
            before the eyes of Abdallah, a single being, possessing the
            traits of both, and yet not wholly like either. The stately
            elegance of one was subdued and softened by the graceful
            beauty of the other. The rich carnation that had glowed
            in the cheeks of the mountain queen, was visible beneath the
            pale complexion of the fairy from the well, whose clear blue
            eyes shone brightly as ever, but with a deep tenderness that
            added to their charms a thousand fold. In the smile that
            dwelt upon those ruby lips the king could recognise familiar
            lines, but the gentle sweetness to which his heart responded,
            awoke no echo in his memory. The raiment, too, of the sisters, had combined in the garments that covered the newformed person—the blue, star-spangled dress of the desert
            fairy appearing above the queenly purple robe.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>While the king vet stood gazing in amaze at this transfigured being, she addressed him in a voice of most melodious
            sweetness. “ Be not alarmed, O king of Tarudant, at beholding your friend and guide thus merged into another. Though
            much has been added to me, nought has been taken away.
            My sister and I were one from the beginning. How we were
            separated, you shall be informed ; know now, that by your
            means alone, through the sufferings of your kingdom, and
            through your steadfast faith, could we be reinstated. It is at
            length accomplished, Bright is the future that awaits you.
            I know the thought that fills your mind, the cherished hope
            that glows in your heart. I have not witnessed your courage
            and your constancy with an unmoved soul; they deserve and
            shall receive the highest reward that I can bestow.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The king sank upon his knees before the beautiful fairy,
            and fervently kissed her hand ; she gently bade him rise, and
            when he stood once more upon his feet, behold, the multitude that but now had filled the hall, had vanished every
            one. Silence reigned within those royal walls, and there
            was none to break it save the king and the glorious being
            whom his soul adored. Then, unseen by mortal eye, unheard
            by mortal ear, the vows of everlasting love and faith were
            breathed; the kiss of plighted troth exchanged, and side by
            side the fairy Queen and King Abdallah knelt down to ask a
            blessing on their union from the Giver of all good.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>That same night the blaze of torches and bonfires, the
            shouting and dancing of the people announced and celebrated
            throughout the airy kingdom, the nuptials of its queen.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>After a week, a brief, brief week of enjoyment and festivity, King Abdallah and his bride descended from the mountain capital, determined to recover the kingdom of Tarudant
            and overthrow the Egyptian magician and his thrice accursed tower. They were accompanied by a numerous train of
            gay and beautiful youths and maidens, who, to distant lookers-on, exhibited all the appearance of a powerful army
            marching to meet some formidable foe.
         </p>
         <p>As they passed across the desert, the blessed influence of
            the fairy was exerted with such strength that springs of wa-
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page203"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>ter burst from the sand wherever site pointed the golden
            sceptre which she carried; while along the line of march as
            soon as her train had passed, flowers and plants sprung up;
            so that when they had reached the borders of Tarudant,'
            there was a broad belt of rich vegetation extending across
            the deserts, and uniting the two kingdoms.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>About noon, on the third day (for the fairy caused the cavalcade to proceed with more than morbid speed) they came
            in sight of the great tower, standing in its solitary magnificence, amid a desolation more terrible than that of the desert, in whose monotonous sands there was nothing to remind
            the beholder of former animation or prosperity, while here
            on every side were strewed the wrecks of recent life and happiness. Drawing nigh, they perceived that the edifice, though
            still glittering with gems and gold, with silver, brass and
            ivory was much dilapidated, and stained and weather-beaten,
            as though a thousand years had beheld it instead of a few
            short weeks. The smoke, too, which yet gushed from its
            summit, was thin and pale, and swayed about uncertainly,
            as if scarcely able to rise through the atmosphere. Of the
            monstrous green birds, two alone were left, who were perched upon the top of the tower, feebly flapping their wings,
            seemingly too weak to fly.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>They halted before the great gate of the tower, and the queen
            directed Abdallah to take a bow and three arrows from one
            of the youths in her train. With one arrow he pierced one
            of the birds which fell back dead upon the tower. Its companion uttering a low shriek, attempted to fly away, but after vainly fluttering its wings in the air for a moment, it
            slowly fell to the ground, and lay there gasping in the last
            extremity.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The king shot a second arrow at the centre of the tower,
            which caused the edifice to reel to and fro, as though rocked
            by an earthquake. A third bolt directed at the great gates,
            sent the tower tumbling to the ground with a thunderous
            shock that might have been heard half-way to Mount Atlas.
            For a minute all was darkness, so filled was the air with
            dust and smoke ; then there was the rushing of innumerable
            wings, as the genies who had filled the lower fled affrighted
            away—those only remaining who were too much bruised to
            escape.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Presently there emerged from the ruins, crawling on his
            hands and knees amid the rubbish, a little deformed figure,
            which none could ever have believed to be the haughty Arphaxad, who had known him only in the days of his grandeur. Yet he it was, in his true natural shape, such as he
            wore on his first appearance in Tarudant. He crept humbly
            towards the king, and lifted up his hands imploring pardon.
            Abdallah drew his sword, and would have cutoff the wretch’s
            head, but the fairy stayed his arm, saying, “Suffer him to
            live—revenge does not become a king. He may repent him
            of his evil deeds, and grow a better man. Besides, he hath
            great and wondrous skill, which, rightly directed, will restore
            the kingdom even with more speed than it was destroyed.
            Spare him, therofore, and use him, but trust him not, he is a
            good servant but a terrible master.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Abdallah hearkened to the voice of the queen. The magician was spared, and, controlled by the wisdom of the fairy,
            and the firmness of the king, exerted his vast powers, through
            many years as successfully for good purposes as he formerly
            had for evil. Tarudant recovered and indeed excelled its former prosperity, and when at the end of a lengthened reign,
            Abdallah was summoned to his fathers, he left the most
            flourishing kingdom of the Moslem world to a son who inherited much of the goodness and wisdom of his fairy mother, and left the kingdom unimpaired to a long line of
            equally fortunate successors.
         </p>
         <p>ROBERT OLIVER.
            THE UNIVERSALITY OF HUMAN EMOTIONS.
            
         </p>
         <p>Ralph Waldo Emerson says in one of his essays, “what
            one man has felt all men may feel.” It is a simple truth
            which any body might utter, although, simple as it is, there
            are but few who seem to know it. Grave men spend years
            of their lives ; many, all their lives, in the study of human
            nature as it is revealed in history, when they have only to
            study themselves, to know all of their kind, that they are
            capable of knowing. A man may comprehend the feelings
            of all other men who have capacities like his own, but he
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>can neither go a step above or below his own level. An angel and a devil, are alike incomprehensible to him. He
            must be a strangely organized being who can find no second
            self. In reading Eӧthen I was startled to discover that the
            author of that pleasant book had once experienced a sensation which had troubled me at the same period of life, and
            which I had never been able to make any body comprehend.
            Perhaps another, in reading his description of his feelings,
            may not comprehend them as I do, unless he has himself
            experienced them. He is speaking of the effect of the great
            pyramid on his mind.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ When I was very young, between the ages of three and
            five years, being then of delicate health, I was often in time
            of night the victim of a strange kind of mental oppression; I
            lay in my bed perfectly conscious, and with open eyes, but
            without power to speak, or move, and all the while my brain
            was oppressed to distraction by the presence of a single and
            abstract idea, the idea of solid immensity. It seemed to me
            in my agonies that the horror of this visitation arose from its
            coming upon me without form or shape ; the close presence
            of the direst monster ever bred in Hell, would have been a
            thousand times more tolerable than that simple idea of solid
            size; my aching mind was fixed, and riveted down upon the
            mere quality of vastness, vastness, vastness: and was not
            permitted to invest it with any particular object. If I could
            have done so the torment would have ceased. When at
            last I was roused from this state of suffering, I could not of
            course in those days, knowing no metaphysical distinctions except by the dreadful experience of an abstract idea, find
            words to express the nature of my sensations, and even now
            I cannot explain why it is that the forced contemplation of
            a mere quality, distinct from matter, should be so terrible.
            Well, now my eyes saw and knew, and my feet informed
            my understanding that there was nothing abstract about the
            great Pyramid; it was a big triangle, sufficiently concrete,
            easy to see, and rough to the touch ; it could not, of course,
            affect me with the peculiar sensation which I have been talking of, but yet there was something akin to the old nightmare agony in the terrible completeness with which a mere
            mass of masonry could fill and load my mind.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Not only did I suffer the same unspeakable agonies in my
            early childhood, but often since, my mind has been oppressed
            by the contemplation of a solid mass of masonry, and the sufferings of my early years recalled vividly to my recollection,
            in the same manner that the author was affected by a sight
            of the Pyramid of Ghizeh. There is nothing oppressive in
            the sight of a well proportioned building, or in a high mountain, but such heaps of granite and marble as the Exchange
            and Custom-House, in Wall-street, seem to weigh upon the
            mind like a nightmare.	H. F.
         </p>
         <p>
            the theatre.
            THE NEW COMEDY BY MRS. MOWATT.
            
         </p>
         <p>The plot of “ Fashion” runs thus : Adam Trueman, a blunt, warmhearted shrewd, irascible, wealthy, and generous old farmer of Cattaraugus county, N. Y., had a daughter, (Ruth) who eloped with an
            adventurer. The father forgave the daughter, but resolving to disappoint the hopes of the fortune hunter, gave the couple a bare subsistence In consequence of this, the husband maltreated, and finally
            abandoned the wife, who returned, broken-hearted, to her father’s
            house and there died, after giving birth to a daughter, Gertrude.
            That she might escape the ills of fortune-hunting by which her mother
            was destroyed, Trueman scat the child, at an early age, to be brought
            up by relatives in Geneva ; giving his own neighbours to understand
            that she was dead. The Geneva friends were instructed to educate
            her in habits of self-dependence, and to withold from her the secret
            of her parentage, and heirship ;-the grandfather’s design being to se
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page204"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>cure for her a husband who will love her solely for herself. The
            friends by advice of the grandfather, procured for her when grown up
            to womanhood, a situation as music teacher in the house of Mr. Tiffany, a quondam foot-pedlar, and now by dint of industry a dry-goods
            merchant doing a flashy if not flourishing business; much of his success having arisen from the assistance of Trueman, who knew him
            and admired his honest industry as a travelling pedlar.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The efforts of the dry goods merchant, however, are insufficient to
            keep pace with the extravagance of his wife, who has become infected
            with a desire to shine as a lady of fashion, in which desire she is seconded by her daughter, Seraphina, the musical pupil of Gertrude.
            The follies of the mother and daughter so far involve Tiffany as to
            lead him into a forgery of a friend’s endorsement. This crime is suspected by his confidential clerk, Snobson, an intemperate blackguard,
            who at length extorts from his employer a confession, under a promise of secresy provided that Seraphina shall become Mrs. Snobson.
            Mrs. Tiffany, however, is by no means privy to this arrangement:
            she is anxious to secure a title for Seraphina, and advocates the
            pretensions of Count Jolimaitre, a quondam English cook, barber,
            and valet, whose real name was Gustave Treadmill, and who, having
            spent much time at Paris, suddenly took leave of that city, for that
            city’s good, and his own; abandoning to despair a little laundress
            (Millinette) to whom he was betrothed, but who had rashly entrusted
            him with the whole of her hard earnings during life.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Gertrude is beloved (for her own sake) by Colonel Howard “ of the
            regular army,” and returns his affection. The Colonel, however
            makes no proposal, because he considers that his salary of “fifteen
            hundred a year” is no property of his own, but belongs to his creditors. He has endorsed for a friend to the amount of seven thousand
            dollars, and is left to settle the debt as he can. He talks, therefore,
            of resigning, going west, making a fortune, returning, and then offering his hand with his fortune, to Gertrude.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>At this juncture, Trueman pays a visit to his old friend Tiffany!
            and is put at fault in respect to the true state of Gertrude’s heart (and
            indeed of every thing else) by the tattle of Prudence, Mrs. Tiffany’s
            old-maiden sister. She gives the old man to understand that Gertrude
            is in love with T. Tennyson Twinkle, a poet who is in the sad habit
            of reading aloud his own verses, but who has really very respectable
            pretensions, as times go. T. T. T. nevertheless, has no thought of
            Gertrude, but is making desperate love to the imaginary money-bags
            of Seraphina. He is rivalled, however, not only by the Count, but
            by Augustus Fogg, a gentleman of excessive haut ton, who wears
            black and has a general indifference to every thing but hot suppers.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Millinette, in the mean time, has followed her deceiver to America,
            and happens to make an engagement as femme de chambre and general
            instructor in Parisian modes, at the very house (of all houses in the
            world) where her Gustave, as Count Jolimaitre, is paying his addresses to Miss Tiffany. The laundress recognizes the cook, who, at first
            overwhelmed with dismay, fiually recovers his self-possession, and
            whispers to his betrothed a place of appointment at which he promises to “ explain all.” This appointment is overheard by Gertrude,
            who for some time has had her suspicions of the Count. She resolves
            to personate Millinette in the interview, and thus obtain means of exposing the impostor. Contriving therefore to detain the femme de
            chambre from the assignation, she herself (Gertrude) blowing out the
            candles and disguising her voice, meets the Count at the appointed
            room in Tiffany’s house, while the rest of the company (invited to a
            ball) are at supper. In order to accomplish the detention of Millinette, she has been forced to give some instructions to Zeke (re-bap
            tized Adolph by Mrs. Tiffany) a negro footman in the Tiffany livery.
            These instructions are overheard by Prudence, who mars everything
            by bringing the whole household into the room of appointment before
            any secret has been extracted from the Count. Matters are made
            worse for Gertrude by a futile attempt on the Count’s part to conceal
            himself in a closet. No explanations are listened to. Mrs. Tiffany
            and Seraphina are in a great rage—Howard is in despair—and Trueman entertains so bad an opinion of his grandaughter that he has an
            idea of suffering her still to remain in ignorance of his relationship.
            The company disperse in much admired disorder, and everything is at
            odds and ends.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Finding that she can get no one to hear her explanations, Gertrude
            writes an account of all to her friends at Geneva. She is interrupted
            by Trueman—shows him the letter—he comprehends all—and hurries
            the lovers into the presence of Mr. and Mrs. Tiffany, the former of
            whom is in despair, and the latter in high glee at information just received that Seraphina has eloped with Count Jolimaitre.
         </p>
         <p>While Trueman is here avowing his relationship, bestowing Ger-
            
         </p>
         <p>trude upon Howard, and relieving Tiffany from the fangs of Snobson
            by showing that person that he is an accessary to his employer’s forgery, Millinette enters, enraged at the Count’s perfidy to herself, and
            exposes him in full. Scarcely has she made an end when Seraphina
            appears in search of her jewels, which the Count, before committing
            himself by the overt act of matrimony, has insisted upon her securing.
            As she does not return from this errand, however, sufficiently soon,
            her lover approaches on tip-toe to see what has become of her; is
            seen and caught by Millinette ; and finding the game up, confesses
            every thing with exceeding nonchalance. Trueman extricates Tiffany
            from his embarrassments on condition of his sending his wife and
            daughter to the country to get rid of their fashionable notions ; and
            even carries his generosity so far as to establish the Count in a restaurant with the proviso that he, the Count, shall in the character and
            proper habiliments of cook Treadmill, carry around his own advertisement to all the fashionable acquaintances who had solicited his
            intimacy while performing the role of Count Jolimaitre.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We presume that not even the author of a plot such as this, would
            be disposed to claim for it any thing on the score of originality or invention. Had it, indeed, been designed as a burlesque upon the arraut conventionality of stage incidents in general, we should have regarded it as a palpable hit. And, indeed, while on the point of absolute unoriginality, we may as well include in one category both the
            events and the characters. The testy yet generous old grandfather,
            who talks in a domineering tone, contradicts every body, slaps all
            mankind on the back, thumps his cane on the floor, listens to nothing,
            chastises all the fops, comes to the assistance of all the insulted women, and relieves all the dramatis personae from all imaginable dilemmas:—the hen-pecked husband of low origin, led into difficulties by
            his vulgar and extravagant wife :—the die-away daughter aspiring to
            be a Countess :—the villain of a clerk who aims at the daughter’s hand
            through the fears of his master, tome of whose business secrets he
            possesses :—the French grisette metamorphosed into the dispenser of
            the highest Parisian modes and graces :—the intermeddling old maid
            making bare-faced love to every unmarried man the meets :—the stiff
            and stupid man of high fashion who utters only a single set phrase :—
            the mad poet reciting his own verses:—the negro footman in livery
            impressed with a profound sense of his own consequence, and obeying
            with military promptness all orders from every body:—the patient,
            accomplished, and beautiful governess, who proves in the end to be
            the heiress of the testy old gentleman :—the high-spirited officer, in
            love with the governess, and refusing to marry her in the first place
            because he is too poor, and in the second place because she is too rich:
            and, lastly, the foreign impostor with a title, a drawl, an eye-glass,
            and a moustache, who makes love to the supposititious heiress of the
            play in strutting about the stage with his coat-tails thrown open after'
            the fashion of Robert Macaire, and who, in the end, is exposed and
            disgraced through the instrumentality of some wife or mistress w hom
            he has robbed and abandoned:—these things we say, together with
            such incidents as one person supplying another’s place at an assignation, and such equivoques as arise from a surprisal in such cases—the
            concealment and discovery of one of the parlies in a closet—and the
            obstinate refusal of all the world to listen to an explanation, are the
            common and well-understood property of the play-wright, and have
            been so, unluckily, time out of mind.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But, for this very reason, they should be abandoned at once. Their
            hackneyism is no longer to be endured. The day has at length arrived when men demand rationalities in place of conventionalities. It
            will no longer do to copy, even with absolute accuracy, the whole tone
            of even so ingenious and really spirited a thing as the “ School for
            Scandal.” It was comparatively good in its day, but it would be positively bad at the present day, and imitations of it are inadmissible at
            any day.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Bearing in mind the spirit of these observations, we may say that
            “ Fashion” is theatrical but not dramatic. It is a pretty well-arranged
            selection from the usual routine of stage characters, and stage manoeuvres—but there is not one particle of any nature beyond greenroom nature, about it. No such events ever happened in fact, or ever
            could happen, as happen in“ Fashion.” Nor arc we quarrelling, now,
            with the mere exaggeration of character or incident—were this all,
            the play, although bad as comedy might be good as farce, of which
            the exaggeration of possible incongruities is the chief element.
            Our fault-finding is on the score of deficiency in verisimilitude—In natural art—that is to say, iu art based in the natural laws of man’s
            heart and understanding.
         </p>
         <p>When, for example, Mr. Augustus Fogg (whose name by the bye
            has little application to his character) says, in reply to Mrs. Tiffany’s
            THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            
         </p>
         <p>invitation to the conservatory, that he is “ indifferent to flowers,” and
            replies in similar terms to every observation addressed to him, neither
            are we affected by any sentiment of the farcical, nor can we feel any
            sympathy in the answer on the ground of its being such as any human
            being would naturally make at all times to all queries—making no
            other answer to any. Were the thing absurd in itself, we should laugh,
            and a legitimate effect would be produced ; but unhappily the only absurdity we perceive is the absurdity of the author in keeping so pointless a phrase in any character’s mouth. The shameless importunities
            of Prudence to Trueman are in the same category—that of a total deficiency in verisimilitude, without any compensating incongruousness—
            that is to say, farcicalness, or humor. Also in the same category we
            must include the rectangular crossings and recrossings of the dramatis
            personas on the stage ; the coming forward to the foot-lights when any
            thing of interest is to be told; the reading of private letters in a loud
            rhetorical tone ; the preposterous soliloquising; and the even more
            preposterous “asides.” Will our play-wrights never learn, through
            the dictates of common sense, that an audience under no circumstances
            can or will be brought to conceive that what is sonorous in their own
            ears at a distance of fifty feet from the speaker cannot be heard by an
            actor at the distance of one or two?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>No person of common ingenuity will be willing to admit that even
            the most intricate dramatic narrative could not be rendered intelligible
            without these monstrous inartisticalities. They are the relics of a day
            when men were content with but little of that true Art whose nature
            they imperfectly understood, and are now retained solely through that
            supine spirit of imitation which grows out of the drama itself as the
            chief of the imitative arts, and which has had so much to do in degrading it, in effect, by keeping it stationary while all of its sisters have
            been making rapid progress. The drama has not declined as many
            suppose : it has only been left out of sight by every thing else. We
            must discard all models. The Elizabethan theatre should be abandoned. We need thought of our own—principles of dramatic action
            drawn not from the “ old dramatists” but from the fountain of a Nature that can never grow old.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It must be understood that we arc not condemning Mrs. Mowatt’s
            comedy in particular, but the modern drama in general. Comparatively, there is much merit in “ Fashion,” and in many respects (and
            those of a telling character) it is superior to any American play. It
            has, in especial, the very high merit of simplicity in plot. What the
            Spanish play-wrights mean by dramas of intrigue are the worst acting
            dramas in the world:—the intellect of an audience can never safely
            be fatigued by complexity. The necessity for verbose explanation on
            the part of Trueman at tne close of “ Fashion” is, however, a serious
            defect. The denouement should in all cases be full of action and nothing
            else. Whatever cannot be explained by such action should be communicated at the opening of the play.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The colloquy in Mrs. Mowatt’s comedy is spirited, generally terse,
            and well seasoned at points with sarcasm of much power. The management throughout shows the fair authoress to be thoroughly conversant with our ordinary stage effects, and we might say a good deal in
            commendation of some of the “ sentiments” interspersed :—we are
            really ashamed, nevertheless, to record our deliberate opinion that if
            "Fashion” succeed at all (and we think upon the whole that it will)
            it will owe the greater portion of its success to the very carpets, the
            very ottomans, the very chandeliers, and the very conservatories that
            gained so decided a popularity for that most inane and utterly despicable of all modem comedies—the “ London Assurance” of Bourcicault.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The above remarks were written before the comedy’s representation at the Park, and were based on the author’s original MS., in which
            some modifications have been made—and not at all times, we really
            think, for the better. A good point, for example has been omitted,
            at the denouement. In the original, Trueman (as will be seen in our
            digest) pardons the Count, and even establishes him in a restaurant,
            on condition of his carrying around to all his fashionable acquaintances
            his own advertisement as restaurateur. There is a piquant, and dashing deviation, here, from the ordinary routine of stage “poetic justice,
            which could uot have failed to tell, and which was, perhaps, the one
            original point of the play. We can conceive no good reason for its
            omission. A scene, also, has been introduced, to very little purpose.
            We watched its effect narrowly, and found it null. It narrated nothing; it illustrated nothing; and was absolutely nothing in itself.
            Nevertheless it might have been introduced for the purpose of
            giving time for some other scenic arrangements going on out of
            sight.
         </p>
         <p>The comedy was thus cast:
            Adam Trueman.......................Mr. Chippendale.
            Count de Jolimaitre....................W. H. Crisp.
            Colonel Howard .	•	•	•	• Dyott.
            Mr. Tiffany ................................Barry.
            Mr. T. Tennison Twinkle .	. De Walden.
            Mr. Augustus Fog .	.	.	.	• Bridges.
            Mr. Pnobson ..... Fisher.
            Zeke, a colored servant	.	.	• Skerrett
            Master of the ceremonies .	.	.	. Gallot.
            Mrs. Tiffany.............................Mrs. Barry.
            Gertrude ...	. Miss Clara Ellis.
            Seraphina Tiffany .	.	. Miss Kate Horn.
            Prudence ..... Mrs. Knight.
            Millinette..................................Dyott
            
         </p>
         <p>A well written prologue was well delivered by Mr. Crisp, whose action is far better than his reading—although the latter, with one exception, is good. It is pure irrationality to recite verse, as if it were
            prose, without distinguishing the lines :—we shall touch this subject
            again. As the Count, Mr. Crisp did every thing that could be done
            his grace of gesture is preeminent. Miss Home looked charmingly as
            Seraphina. Trueman and Tiffany were represented with all possible
            effect by Chippendale and Barry and Mrs. Barry as Mrs. Tiffany
            was the life of the play. Zeke was caricatured. Dyott makes a bad
            colonel—his figure is too diminutive. Prudence was well exaggera-
         </p>
         <p>ted by Mrs. Knight—and the character in her hands, elicited more ap-
            plause than any one other of the dramatis personae.
            
         </p>
         <p>Some of the author’s intended points were lost through the inevitable inadvertences of a first representation—but upon the whole, every
            thing went off exceedingly well. To Mrs. Barry we would suggest
            that the author’s intention was, perhaps, to have élite pronounced
            ee-light, and bouquet, bokett;—the effect would be more certain. To
            Zeke we would say, bring up the table bodily by all means (as originally designed) when the fow tool is called for. The scenery was very
            good indeed—and the carpet, ottomans, chandelier, etc. were also excellent of their kind. The entire “ getting up” was admirable.
            “ Fashion,” upon the whole, was well received by a large, fashionable,
            and critical audience ; and will succeed to the extent we have suggested above. Compared with the generality of modern dramas, it is a
            good play—compared with most American dramas it if? a very good
            one—estimated by the natural principles of dramatic art, it is altogether unworthy of notice.	P.
         </p>
         <p>THE CONCERT ROOM.
            
         </p>
         <p>Signor Sanquirico’s Concert.—The Opera House was well filled
            on Monday evening, on the occasion of the artist’s benefit. Signora
            Pico, Madame Otto, Mesdames Desjardines and Felicia, Signors Antognini, De Begnis, Meyer, and Messrs. Grœneveldt, Kyle, &amp;c. &amp;c.,
            assisted him in his endeavors.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The two first pieces we were fortunate enough to miss. No. 3, Grand
            Duo, Convcnienze Teatrali, Donizetti, sung by Pico and Sanquirico, is
            a dashing, sparkling, frothy sort of composition, and was executed
            with less spirit than these artists usually display. No. 4 of the first
            act, was, according to the programme, No. 5 of the third act. It was
            a duett for the flute and clarionette by Messrs. Kyle and Grœneveldt.
            It was the best thing of the evening. The composition was very
            pleasing, but somewhat commonplace. The execution generally was
            admirable, although there were some parts which might have gone
            much better. Mr. Kyle has one very great fault—we allude to his
            want of accentuation in his rapid passages, which frequently renders
            his brilliant execution crowded and confused. If Mr. Grœneveldt has
            a fault, it is in the exact opposite of this—viz., too much accentuation ;
            the too great use of which renders the style hard, pedantic, and inelegant. This fault is, however, but rarely observed in Mr. Grœneveldt.
            No. 5, Aria Finale, from Bctley, Se Crudele, by Madame Otto. Whenever we hear this lady’s beautiful voice, we feel a regret that her musical education has not been more carefully attended to. She always
            reminds us of a lady we knew in Baltimore, who sang just like a bird,
            so freely, so entirely without effort did the rich volume of sound roll
            from her parted lips. Madame Otto’s defects in style, and the imperfectness of her execution, must necessarily preclude the possibility
            that she should do any justice to the higher walks of Italian or German vocal music. In the national Tyrolean ballads, her voice is wonderfully effective, and as friends to her and to her talent, we should advise her, for the sake of keeping up her popularity, to sing such songs
            only as are within the compass of her execution. In Ocean, thou
            mighty monster ! from Weber’s Oberon, Madam Otto sang out of tune,
            so much so, and so continually out of time, os to distress the orchestra and to ruin the scena. The practice which Madame Otto continually exhibits, both in her Italian and English singing, of taking breath
            audibly between the syllables of words, is quite fatal to effect, and its
            correction should occupy her attention most earnestly.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>No. 6 was Rossini's Duo, I Marinari, sang by Signor Antognini and
            executed by Signor Sanquirico. We are not behind the curtain in the
            affairs of Italian artists, but if ever one man evidenced a determination
            to sacrifice another, Sanquirico did on Monday last. This beautiful
            duett is familiar to every one ; it is among the happiest of Rossini’s
            later compositions, and requires to be sung con amore, with vigor and
            with spirit. Signor Sanquirico drawled it out like a country psalmsmiter ; and he drawled it out of tune, and the more he was urged onward by Antognini and the band, the more cool and determined he
            seemed, and the more he would not go. We do not know the reason
            for this conduct, but be it what it may, it was disrespectful in the
            highest degree to the public, and ungenerous, nay, unjust to Antognini. The duett was of course hissed, although the hissing was meant
            for Sanquirico, and Signor Antognini as soon as he sung the last note
            turned his back upon the company and bounced off the stage, dashing
            his music on the floor. Now the public had done nothing to ofl'end
            the Signor; he might at least have made the usual obeisance, before
            exhibiting his anger. Verily, these Italian artists are models for amiable temper, brotherly love, good will and charity to all!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The orchestral arrangements of this duett by Signor Milon, were, as
            far as we could judge from the imperfect way in which they were
            played, very clever, clear, effective, and well conceived. The brass
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page206"></div>
            instruments, particularly, were well treated. We should like to hear
            it done justice to.
            
         </p>
         <p>The dancing was dreadful. Md’lle Desjardines has but a very imperfect idea of the meaning of the word grace; her “ toe” is neither
            “ light” nor “ fantastic,” and her “ motion” is the most prosaic we
            ever witnessed.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A poor little girl was discovered in an attitude, to reproduce which
            would make the fortune of a sculptor; so peculiar and so original was
            its character. Children so young should not be brought before the
            public.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The third part consisted chiefly of selections from Il Barbiere. We
            have noticed this opera so frequently that any remark at the present
            time would be superfluous.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Signor De Beguis was the Figaro, and we never were more pleased
            with his performance ; it was subdued and in perfect keeping. Pico
            sang her music charmingly ; her execution was distinct and rapid, and
            her ornaments, generally, in good taste. But her acting is devoid of
            grace or originality, and she is more the country hoyden than the refined Rosina.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Sanquirico sang his Scena Manca un foglie, with a great deal of
            spirit, but his performance was by no means equal to many of his
            previous performances of the same scena.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. P. Meyer sang Doniz tti’s Ft Raviso. He has a very fine Baritone voice, but he does not seem to know much about the art. He
            sings without style, just as one untaught would sing. He appears to
            be perfectly at home before the public, which is a great advantage to
            a young artist. We think that Mr. Meyer would find it worth his
            while to study diligently, for we are sadly in want of such a voice at
            our concerts, and he might reap a rich harvest of professional engagements during many months of the year.
         </p>
         <p>The duett between De Begnis and Sanquirico was well acted and
            well sung, and gave much satisfaction to the audience.
            
         </p>
         <p>When we left Pico, Sanquirico and De Begnis had been called out.
            and we have every reason to believe, from the severe enthusiasm of the
            audience, that every person concerned in the concert, even the gentleman who so kindly and so gracefully draws up the curtain when the
            bell rings, shared the like honor.
         </p>
         <p>N. Y. VOCAL SOCIETY.
            Mr. Editor:
            
         </p>
         <p>Sir—Being one of the numerous and delighted auditory at this
            Concert last. Saturday evening, I take the liberty of offering a few remarks on the performances thereof.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>	It was a rich repast to the unprejudiced amateur, being strictly
            classical, and at the same time performed by the very “elite” of the
            musical residents in the city, in a manner worthy of, and only to be
            executed by the N. Y. Vocal Society—in a word, this society stands
            in the same relationship to the admirers of the highest class of vocal
            music as the Philharmonic does to the instrumentalists.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The first act consisted of a liberal gleaning from the ever beautiful
            opera of “ Semiramide,” in which Mrs. Loder sang to the admiration
            of every one, and proved, (if proof were necessary) that she, being an
            educated vocalist, is as equal to the classical music of one school as
            another. The chorusses went with a precision and an unity of effect
            so indispensable to the proper performing of the chromatic intricacies
            with which Rossini’s concerted music abounds. I would suggest that
            if the pianos and fortes were even more strictly observed than they
            were, the effect would be still nearer to perfection. The rendition of
            the beautiful quartette and chorus “ Di Tanti Regi,” conceived in
            Rossini’s happiest mood, was greatly impaired by Mr. Watson’s singing flat almost entirely throughout the quartette—the result I believe
            of severe cold. Miss De Luce gave her cavatina, “ Ah ! quel Giorao”
            in a highly creditable manner. With a fine rich voice, all she has to
            do is to get schooled—or in other words, to gain style and expression,
            by practice and example, without which the finest voice will fail to
            make the artiste. Miss Watson’s quiet and well conceived singing in the
            aria and chorus “ In si barbara,” gives great promise for the future.
            It was a pleasing and very chaste performance, and shows what she
            will do when more experienced. Mr. Timm conducted the first part
            and presided at the Piano as Mr. Timm always docs preside! Mr.
            Kyle performed a solo on the flute with great eclat, although at a concert of that kind I could have wi hed the subject chosen had been a
            little more of the legitimate order,—the arrangement of the two airs,
            “ Rory O’More” and the “ Angel’s Whisper,” is however exceedingly
            clever. The second part ol the concert was conducted by Mr. G. Lo.
            der in admirable style, an 1 consisted of a feast, to be enjoyed only at
            this society, where the immortal compositions of the fine English writers of the “Madrigal” and “Glee” are alone to be heard to the best
            advantage. They were all performed in admirable style, and but for
            the lateness of the hour, and length of the programme, there would
            have been several encores—the satisfaction evinced by the audience,
            consisting of most of our musical connoisseurs and amateurs, and a
            very large portion of the leading professors, gives evidence that the
            N. Y. Vocal Society is looking up.	K.
         </p>
         <p>MUSICAL REVIEW.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Avezzana’s Quick Step.” Performed by the American Brass Band
            and dedicated to Captain Avezzana, and the officers and members of
            the New York Italian Guard, by C. Chianei.
         </p>
         <p>“ My Bark which o’er the tide.” Barcarole, from the new Opera of
            the Daughter of St. Mark ; composed by M. W. Balfe.
            The above are published by Millett at his Music Saloon, 329 Broad-
            way.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Farewell, farewell, we meet no more below.” Sung by Mrs. E. Loder
            written by Alfred Wheeler, Esq., music arranged and dedicated to
            Mrs. J. S. Bennett of New York, by Austin Philips.
         </p>
         <p>“ Annerock Polka.” Composed and dedicated to his friend, Ferdi-
            nand Graubner,, by Charles Perabeau.
            The above are published by Firth, Hall &amp; Pond. 239 Broadway, and
            No. 1 Franklin Square.
            The Quick Step by Mr. Chianei, is very well adapted to the pur-
            pose, and must prove highly effective when played by the band.
            
         </p>
         <p>The song we noticed last week. It is the Barcarole from Balfe’s new
            Opera. It is more expensively got out than the Boston edition, having
            a full title, handsomely engraved.
         </p>
         <p>We understand that Mr. Millett has several other songs from the
            Daughter of St. Mark in advance of the publisher.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Austin Phillips always makes a pretty song. He has a happy
            vein of unfailing thought. Many of his compositions are exquisite in
            their sentiment, and always musicianlike in their arrangement, although we sometimes discover evidences of carelessness in the accompaniments. The song under notice is a sweet and plaintive melody in
            F, well suited to the melancholy sentiment of the poetry. It is a song
            well adapted for teaching, and doubtless Mr. Loder’s singing will render it popular.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Perabeau’s Polka is spirited and melodious. There is only one
            Polka in the world, and that is the first one—every other must perforce be a copy, for so peculiar and distinct is its character, that the
            fancy can have but little play. Mr. Perabeau’s Polka is certainly one
            of the best, and one of the most pleasing of the thousand and one
            which have come under our notice of late.
         </p>
         <p>STODART &amp; DUNHAM’S PIANO FORTE MANUFACTORY.
            
         </p>
         <p>Or the numerous articles of luxury with which our country abounds,
            the Piano Forte is, without doubt, the most interesting in its manufacture, the most universal in its adoption, and by far the most important in our social arrangements for innocent and refined enjoyment.
            Of its manufacture we shall speak at length below, as we feel assured
            that the subject will prove highly interesting to our readers.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As to the universality of its adoption, the fact is well accredited.
            We find it in every country of Europe ,in manyparts of Asia, (the firm
            of Stodart &amp; Co. have sent out many Pianos to China,) in Africa, in
            Australia, throughout the length and breadth of this vast continent—
            nay, even the very face of the ocean is dotted over with Piano Fortes.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Of its social importance every one can speak, for its benefits are
            not confined to one particular class ; it will be often found where the
            grosser luxuries of the palate and the vanities of dress have never intruded; and where it has found its way, it has always brought pleasure and frequently solace and consolation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It may not be generally known, that in this country, nay, in this
            city, the finest square Piano Fortes in the world are produced. We
            know that it has been the fashion until very lately, for all those who
            could afford such expensive luxury, to import from Europe their instruments, believing no article good, but such as bore the European
            stamp. But experience has fully demonstrated the absurdity of this
            practice, and justice has at length been reluctantly yielded to our own
            manufacturers.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Of the many admirable makers in this city, Stodart &amp; Dunham certainly rank among the very highest and best. Their name is known
            all over the country, and it is indeed, as natural to expect to see the
            name of Stodart upon a Piano, as that of Erard upon a Harp, for so
            many, many years has the name been associated with the manufacture of Pianos, both in this, and in the old country.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We will now conduct our readers to the factory of Messrs. Stodart
            and Dunham. It is situated in Thirteenth street, between the Third
            and Fourth avenues, directly opposite the Manhattan Reservoir. The
            length of the building is one hundred and forty feet, and it is four stories in height. We shall proceed regularly with the description of
            the manufacture, from the wood in the lumber-yard, to the elegantly
            finished instrument.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Lumber-Yard is the first point which demands attention.
            Around its spacious area, are stacked the various kinds of wood used
            in the manufacture of Pianos, such as pine, oak, ash, rosewood, ma-
         </p>
         <p>
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page207"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>hogany, holly, maple, &amp;c. &amp;c. Many thousand dollars worth of such
            stock will be found here, continually exposed to every change of weather—cold, heat, raiu, &amp;c., &amp;c., in order to inure it to all climates. The
            wood remains in this state two or three years; that which is nearest
            the drying-room is used first, the whole mass is then advanced forward
            and the new stock, as it arrives, is placed in the rear of all. So that
            it is all worked down in rotation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Veneer-Room is the next opened for inspection. Here are laid
            the finely cut veneers, pile upon pile, containing thousands of feet of
            the richest, rarest, and most expensive mahogany and rosewood. The
            room itself is perfumed with the luxurious odor from the wood, and it
            is truly a beautiful sight to observe the various and exquisite figures
            in the graining of the different sorts of wood. We can safely say that
            we never beheld more beautiful specimens of veneers, both as regards
            gorgeousness of color, and elegance of figure, than were shown to us by
            our frank and gentlemanly conductor, Mr. Dunham. The art of cutting up veneers, is that in which Mr. D. excels, and doubtless many
            thousands of dollars have been saved to the establishment by his
            steady hand, and his mathematically correct eye. The difficulty consists in cutting the figure to match, and at the same time avoiding all
            unnecessary waste. The wood used here is all of the best quality ;
            the finest Spanish mahogany, and the choicest rosewood from the
            Rio Janeiro market. The wood is grown in the interior west of Rio,
            and is brought to that port on the backs of mules, whence it is shipped to all parts of the world. We can scarcely judge of the value of
            the stock in this room, but we should it think about a thousand or fifteen hundred dollars.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Drying-Room comes next. Here the wood which is taken from
            the yard is piled up in layers, carefully divided, over and around a
            stove, by which the room is heated to an unbearable degree. A long
            hot pipe is carried the entire length of the room, over which the wood
            wanted for immediate use is placed. It is thoroughly dried, then taken
            out, cooled, and dusted, and after having undergone once more the same
            operation, it is conveyed through a trap-door to the case-room.
         </p>
         <p>We shall resume the notice of this establishment in our next.
            MISCELLANY.
            
         </p>
         <p>The recompense or English and American Artists.—The London Art Union in commenting upon a picture by Edwin Landseer, of
            a couple of spaniels, says :—
         </p>
         <p>“ Our readers will scarcely credit that which we can vouch for as a fact
            
         </p>
         <p>--the picture was begun and finished within two days .' It wilt be readily believed that the painter received a very large sum for the work; and it is notorious that his paintings are purchased not only as fast as, but faster than,
            they are produced. It is by no means unjust to infer, therefore, that in the
            nineteenth century an artist might, if he pleased, obtain by the work of bis
            own hands a fortune equal to that of the most fortunate of our “ Merchant
            Princes”— and far beyond that which any predecessor in Art achieved during
            the golden age of Leo X. It is known that one living painter has actually
            amassed a store of wealth that would make a Lombard-street banker stare—
            amassed It entirely by his own unaided labour. Such facts as these may not
            be forgotten by the historian of Art in Britain in the nineteenth century.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If the fortune amassed by a British artist would make a Lombardstreet banker stare, it would go well nigh to deprive an American artist of bis sight. Our artists consider it a privilege to be allowed to
            live at all; but in England, it appears that a great artist lives like a
            merchant prince. During the past year one of the best painters that
            America has yet produced, was forced to leave this city to seek employment in a provincial town, and another has been compelled to go
            to England for employment, two, in truth, Inman and Doughty; while
            another has found the patronage in Trance, which he tried after iu
            vain at home. Wilkie lived grandly and died rich, but Alston lived
            poorly and died in debt.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The English artists speak in very high terms of a landscape by
            Doughty, a snow scene in New Hampshire, in the last exhibition of
            the British Institution.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The celebrated Barberini Vase, was broken to pieces in the British
            Museum, by a drunken fellow who was moved by an ambition like that
            °f the incendiary of Ephesus.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The iconoclast was fined three pounds. The Museum possesses,
            however, a copy of the Vase, which was cast from a model produced
            at Rome.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A Mistake. The announcement, in several papers, that Edgar A. Poe
            is to become editor of “ The Aristidean” (the new Democratic five-dollar Monthly) is a mistake. The Aristidean” will continue to be
            edited, and no doubt well edited, by T. D. English.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Erratum. In our notice last week of a poem by Mrs. Nicholls, we
            spoke of her rhythm as anapœstic. We meant to say dactylic, of
            course.
         </p>
         <p>To Correspondents. A thousand thanks to Kate Carol.
            The capital essay of "R H.," will appear next week.
            Many thanks to “ Violet Vane,” and the “ Stranger.”
            
         </p>
         <p>Notices of "Human Magnetism," “ The Lady's Book," ” Graham’s
            Magazine," and several other works, are necessarily deferred until next
            week.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>F. RILEY &amp; CO., No. 297 Broadway, (between
             Reade and Duane streets) New York, Publishers ot Music, and Manufacturers of Musical Instruments, wholesale and retail. In addition to their
            own catalogue, (one of the largest in the United States,) they keep on hand
            the publications of all the principal Music houses. They are erecting a large
            Saloon in the rear of their store, where Piano Fortes of a superior quality,
            will be constantly kept on hand.	’
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES,
            THE Subscribers, while returning thanks to their
            
         </p>
         <p> numerous friends, and to the public, would, at the same time, call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and seven octaves, just finished, in
            elegant Rosewood and Mahogany cases.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Subscribers, from their long experience in every department of the
            business, have been enabled to add several important improvements to the
            action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove, upon examination, equal to any in the market.
         </p>
         <p>STODART &amp; DUNHAM.
            361 Broadway.
            Manufactory 13th St., between 3d and 4th Avenues.
            N.B.—A good second-hand Piano Forte for sale.
            PIANO FORTES.—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
            Street, N.Y.
            
         </p>
         <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as iron frames,
            &amp;c., with a compass of 6 1/2 and 7 octaves. They are made from choice materials and highly finished, with the most faithful workmanship, the result of
            23 years experience in the business.
         </p>
         <p>JAMES PIRSSON,
            PIANO-FORTE MANUFACTURER,
            88, 90, &amp; 92 WALKER STREET, NEAR ELM.
            A large stock of the finest Instruments always on hand.
            TERMS MODERATE.
            SINGING AT SIGHT.
            MR. WARNER, translator of Weber’s theoretical
            
         </p>
         <p>work, &amp;c., continues his course of Vocal Instruction at his rooms, 411
            Broad-Way. Mr. Warner’s new Illustrating Apparatus will also furnish
            very great facilities for a ready and full understanding of the subject preparatory to the study of Instrumental Music.
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
            THOMAS H. CHAMBERS, late Practical partner of
            
         </p>
         <p>the old established arm of 385 Broadway, will keep a complete assortmen of the larest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes, of the most superior
            quality ; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone
            Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired Piano
            Fortes aways on hire.
         </p>
         <p>BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.
            THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive
            
         </p>
         <p>work yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method
            the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases. The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies, are
            given in such PROGRESSIVE order, that they enlist the interest of pupils, and
            carry them almost imperceptibly through those mechanical difficulties which,
            otherwise are too often made irksome in other instruction books. The time
            has arrived when a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account,
            and it is only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will been
            abled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good musi-
         </p>
         <p>ians.
            
         </p>
         <p>      This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ; the rudments of music being given and illustrated at the same lime, and each lesson
            is fully explained by marginal notes on the same pace.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations from professional gentleman, who speak of the superior merits of Bertini’s Method
            over all others yet published in this country, most of them having used the
            foreign copies previously. It will only be necessary to give a few of the
            names in the principal cities.
         </p>
         <p>BOSTON	New York.
            Messrs. G. J. Webb.	Messrs. H. C. Timm.
            J. G Maedar.	W. Alpers.
            H.T. Hach.	U. C. Hill
            E. L.	While.	R. H. Brown.
            David Paine.	PHILADELPHIA
            A Kurek.	B. D. Cross.
            T.B Moses.	Joseph Duggan.
            Albany—0. J. Shaw.
            
         </p>
         <p>Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the work.
            American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H. OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston.
         </p>
         <p>MITCHELL’S OLYMPIC THEATRE
            PERFORMANCES EVERY EVENING. DOORS
            -open at Seven ; Curtain rises at half-past Seven.	
            Dress Circle, 50 Cents. Upper Boxes, 25 cents. Pit, 12 1-2 cents. Private
            Boxes, $3. Box Office open every day.
            JOHN DOUGLAS,
            BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            
         </p>
         <p>No. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every de scription of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
            with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, on terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
         </p>
         <p>January 16, 1845.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page208"></div>
            THIS DAY PUBLISHED,
            No. 1 of
            WILEY &amp; PUTNAM’S LIBRARY OF CHOICE READING,
            CONTAINING
            EOTHEN, OR TRACES OF TRAVEL BROUGHT HOME FROM THE EAST. 1 Vol. very beauti-
            fully printed on fine paper, in large clear type. 50 Cents.
            
         </p>
         <p>This is a real book—not a sham. It displays a varied and comprehensive power of mind,
            and a genuine mastery over the first and strongest of modern languages. The author has caught the character and humor of the eastern mind
            as completely as Anastasius, while in his gorgeous descriptions and
            power of sarcasm, he rivals Vathek. His terseness, vigor, and bold imagery, remind
            us of the brave old style of Fuller and of South, to which he adds a
            spirit, freshness, and delicacy all his own.”—Quarterly Review.
         </p>
         <p>No. 2.
            MARY SCHWEIDLER, THE AMBER WITCH. A Trial for Witchcraft. 1 vol. very beautifully
            printed
            on fine paper, in large clear type. 38 Cents.
            "We have read nothing in Fiction or in History which has so completely rivetted and
            absorbed our interest as this little volume. If it be a fiction, it
            is worthy—we can give no higher praise—of De Foe.”—Quarterly Review.
            	Published and for sale by
            _____________________________________WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            KEIGHTLEY’S HISTORICAL WORKS.
            THE HISTORY OF GREECE.—By Thomas Keight-
            ley, with notes and additions by G. Toulman Smith, in one volume.
            THE HISTORY OF ROME- By the same author, with notes and addi-
            tions in the same manner, in one volume.
            THE HISTORY OF THE ROMAN EMPIRE—Being a continuation of
            the History of Rome. By the same author. In one volume.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE HISTORY OF ENGLAND-From the Invasion of Julius Cæsar to
             the close of the reign of George IV. By the same author, with notes
            and additions as above. In two volumes. Published by
         </p>
         <p>TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John St.
            THE
            SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
            Published Monthly at Richmond, Va. ;  price Five Dollars per Year.
            THE MESSENGER has been established since 1835,
            has a large subscription list among the élitc of the Southern Aristocracy,
            and is the principal organ of Southern opinion.
            Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the " Broadway Jour-
            nal," 153 Broadway.
            REPUBLICATION
            OF THE
            FOREIGN MAGAZINES.
            LONDON, EDINBURGH, FOREIGN, and WEST-
            MINSTER QUARTERLY REVIEWS, and BLACKWOOD’S MAGA-
            ZINE.
            
         </p>
         <p>The above Periodicals are reprinted in New-York, immediately on their
            arrival by the British steamers, in a beautiful dear type, on fine white paper
            and are faithful copies of the originals—Blackwood’s Magazine being an exact fac-simile of the Edinburgh Edition.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The wide spread fame of these splendid Periodicals renders it needless to
            say much to their praise. As literary organs, they stand far in advance of
            any works of a similar stamp now published, while their political complexion
            is marked by a dignity, candor, and forbearance not often found in works of
            a party character.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>They embrace the views of the three great parties in England, Whig, Tory,
            and Radical. “ Blackwood” and the “ London Quarterly” are Tory ; the
            “ Edinburgh Review” Whig ; and the " Westminster” Radical. The “Foreign Quarterly” is purely literary, being devoted principally to criticisms on
            foreign Continental Works.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The prices of the Re-Prints are less than one third of those of the foreign
            copies ; and while they are equally well got up, they afford all that advantage to the American over the English reader.
         </p>
         <p>TERMS.—Payment to he made in Advance.
            For the four Quarterly Reviews, $8.00 per annum,
            For any three	"	"	7.00	"
            For any two	"	"	6.00	"
            For any one	"	"	3.00	"
            For Blackwood, Monthly,	3.00	"
            For 4 Reviews &amp; Blackwood, 10.00	"
            CLUBBING.
            Four copies of any or all the above works will be sent to one address, on
            payment of the regular subscription for three—the fourth copy being gratis.
            Remittances and communications (post-paid or franked), should be made to
            LEONARD SCOTT &amp; CO., Pub’s, 112 Fulton st, N. Y.
            DISEASES OF THE TEETH.
            Washington, D. C., May, 1844.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
            and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
            The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
            professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
            Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
            cheerfully certify to the case and safety with which Dr. B. performs
            the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
            durability, amt beauty of the Teeth.
         </p>
         <p>Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo. Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
            Joshua Herrick, Me.	John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
            James Irvin, Pa.	J. Thompson, Miss.
            Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.
            DISBROW’S RIDING SCHOOL,
            
            No. 408, BOWERY, near Astor and La Fayette
            Places. New York.
            Mr. D. has the honor to announce that his School is open Day and Even-
            ing, for Equestrian Tuition and Exercise Riding.
            TERMS:
            Lecture Lessons.
            16 Lessons......................$15 00
            10 " ............................10 00
            4	"	5 	00
            Single Lessons....................2 00
            Road "	................. 2 50
            Exercise Riding.
            1 Month..........................$12 ........................00
            20 Rides............................10......................... 00
            10 44 ........................... 6 00
            Single Rides..........................0	 75
            N. B.—Highly trained and quiet Horses for the Road or Parade, to let.
            Evening Class.
            12 Lessons.................................................$9 00  20 Rides $10 	00
            Single " •.......................1 00  Single Ride.................• ... 0 75
            RULES :
            1.	All Lessons or Rides paid for on commencing.
            2.	One hour allowed for each Lesson or Ride in the School.
            3.	One hour and a half for a Lesson on the Road.
            4.	Hours for Ladies, from 9 A. M. to 3 P. M.
            5.	Hours for Gnetlemen, from 3 to 4, and from 7 to 9 1-2 P. M.
            6.	No Gentlemen admitted during the hours appropriated to Ladles.
            A card of address is requested previous to commencing.
            N. B. Gentlemen keeping their horses at tills establishment, will have the
            privilege of riding them in the School gratis.
            
            GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
            The first Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for the
            best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
            NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
            
         </p>
         <p> tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
            in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms Reduced to TWO DOLLARS
            AND A HALF.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
            course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
            Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
         </p>
         <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen
            and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            Fur sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
            Price Five Dollars.	
            
         </p>
         <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27. 1S-14.
            Goldsmith’s Gems or Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
            much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, und
            Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
            volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
            of mauual dexteri'y than we have ever seen before.
         </p>
         <p>From the New York Express.
            
         </p>
         <p>Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship.—We have seen the original, as
            executed Mr his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
            wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
            to be “ more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
         </p>
         <p>PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY
            AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
            
         </p>
         <p> Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
            the Medal, four first Premiums, and two “ Highest Honors,” at the
            Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively’, for
            the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
            at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
            the score of economy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American In
            struments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polish
            ing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders receive
            promptly attended to.
         </p>
         <p>John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      
   </div>
</div>