<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 2.	     NEW YORK, SATURDAY, AUGUST 30, 1845.	     NO. 8.
         
         <br></br>Three Dollars per Annum.	
         
         <br></br>Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.
         
         <br></br>Edited by	
         
         <br></br>EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.	
         
         <br></br>Published at 135 Nassau St.
         
         <br></br>By JOHN BISCO.
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="head">Slander,</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>A whisper woke the air—
            
            <br></br>A soft light tone and low,
            
            <br></br>Yet barbed with shame and woe;—
            
            <br></br>Now, might it only perish there!
            
            <br></br>Nor farther go.
            
            <br></br>Ah me! a quick and eager ear
            
            <br></br>Caught up the little meaning sound!
            
            <br></br>Another voice has breathed it clear,
            
            <br></br>And so it wanders round,
            
            <br></br>From ear to lip—from lip to ear—
            
            <br></br>Until it reached a gentle heart,
            
            <br></br>And that—it broke.
            
            <br></br>It was the only heart it found,
            
            <br></br>The only heart ’t was meant to find,
            
            <br></br>When first its accents woke;—
            
            <br></br>It reached that tender heart at last,
            
            <br></br>And that—it broke.
            
            <br></br>Low as it seemed to other ears,
            
            <br></br>It came—a thunder-crash to hers,—
            
            <br></br>That fragile girl so fair and gay,—
            
            <br></br>That guileless girl so pure and true!
            
            <br></br>’Tis said a lovely humming bird
            
            <br></br>That in a fragrant lily lay,
            
            <br></br>And dreamed the summer mom away.
            
            <br></br>Was killed by but the gun’s report,
            
            <br></br>Some idle boy had fired in sport!
            
            <br></br>The very sound—a death-blow came!
            
            <br></br>And thus her happy heart, that beat,
            
            <br></br>With love and hope, so fast and sweet,
            
            <br></br>(Shrined in its Lily too
            
            <br></br>For who the maid that knew
            
            <br></br>But owned the delicate flower-like grace
            
            <br></br>Of her young form and face?)
            
            <br></br>When first that word
            
            <br></br>Her light heart heard,
            
            <br></br>It fluttered like the frightened bird.
            
            <br></br>Then shut its wings and sighed,
            
            <br></br>And, with a silent shudder,—died!
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">FRANCES S. OSGOOD</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="head">William Wilson.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>What say of it? what say conscience grim,
            
            <br></br>That spectre in my path?
         </div>
         
         <div class="ab">Chamberlain's Pharronida.</div>
         
         <p>Let me call myself, for the present, William Wilson. The
            fair page now lying before me need not be sullied with my
            real appellation. This has been already too much an object
            for the scorn—for the horror—for the detestation of my race.
            To the uttermost regions of the globe have not the indignant
            winds bruited its unparalleled infamy? Oh, outcast of all
            outcasts most abandoned!—to the earth art thou not forever
            dead? to its honors, to its flowers, to its golden aspirations?—
            
            and a cloud, dense, dismal, and limitless, does it not hang
            eternally between thy hopes and heaven?
         </p>
         
         <p>I would not, if I could, here or to-day, embody a record
            of my later years of unspeakable misery, and unpardonable
            crime. This epoch—these later years—took unto themselves a sudden elevation in turpitude, whose origin alone it
            is my present purpose to assign. Men usually grow base
            by degrees. From me, in an instant, all virtue dropped
            bodily as a mantle. From comparatively trivial wickedness
            I passed, with the stride of a giant, into more than the enormities of an Elah-Gabalus. What chance—what one event
            brought this evil thing to pass, bear with me while I relate.
            Death approaches; and the shadow which foreruns him has
            thrown a softening influence over my spirit. I long, in passing through the dim valley, for the sympathy—I had nearly
            said for the pity—of my fellow men. I would fain have
            them believe that I have been, in some measure, the slave
            of circumstances beyond human control. I would wish them
            to seek out for me, in the details 1 am about to give, some
            little oasis of fatality amid a wilderness of error. I would
            have them allow—what they cannot refrain from allowing—
            that, although temptation may have erewhile existed as
            great, man was never thus, at least, tempted before—certainly, never thus fell. And is it therefore that he has never
            thus suffered? Have I not indeed been living in a dream?
            And am I not now dying a victim to the horror and the mystery of the wildest of all sublunary visions?
         </p>
         
         <p>I am the descendant of a race whose imaginative and easily excitable temperament has at all times rendered them
            remarkable; and, in my earliest infancy, I gave evidence of
            having fully inherited the family character. As 1 advanced
            iu years it was more strongly developed; becoming, for many
            reasons, a cause of serious disquietude to my friends, and of
            positive injury to myself. I grew self-willed, addicted to the
            wildest caprices, and a prey to the most ungovernable passions. Weak-minded, and beset with constitutional infirmities akin to my own, my parents could do but little to check
            the evil propensities which distinguished me. Some feeble
            and ill-directed efforts resulted in complete failure on their
            part, and, of course, in total triumph on mine. Thenceforward my voice was a household law; and at an age when
            few children have abandoned their leading-strings, I was
            left to the guidance of my own will, and became, in all but
            name, the master of my own actions.
         </p>
         
         <p>My earliest recollections of a school-life, are connected
            with a large, rambling, Elizabethan house, in a misty-looking village of England, where were a vast number of gigantic and gnarled trees, and where all the houses were excessively ancient. In truth, it was a dream-like and spiritsoothing place, that venerable old town. At this moment,
            in fancy, I feel the refreshing chilliness of its deeply-shadowed avenues, inhale the fragrance of its thousand shrubberies, and thrill anew with undefinable delight, at the deep
            hollow note of the church-bell, breaking, each hour, with
            
            sullen and sudden roar, upon the stillness of the dusky atmosphere in which the fretted Gothic steeple lay imbedded
            and asleep.
         </p>
         
         <p>It gives me, perhaps, as much of pleasure as I can now in
            any manner experience, to dwell upon minute recollections
            of the school and its concerns. Steeped in misery as I am—
            misery, alas! only too real—I shall be pardoned for seeking
            relief, however slight and temporary, in the weakness of a
            few rambling details. These, moreover, utterly trivial, and
            even ridiculous in themselves, assume, to my fancy, adventitious importance, as connected with a period and a locality
            when and where I recognise the first ambiguous monitions
            of the destiny which afterwards so fully overshadowed me.
            Let me then remember.
         </p>
         
         <p>The house, I have said, was old and irregular. The
            grounds were extensive, and a high and solid brick wall,
            topped with a bed of mortar and broken glass, encompassed
            the whole. This prison-like rampart formed the limit of our
            domain; beyond it we saw but thrice a week — once every
            Saturday afternoon, when, attended by two ushers, we were
            permitted to take brief walks in a body through some of the
            neighbouring fields—and twice during Sunday, when we
            were paraded in the same formal manner to the morning and
            evening service in the one church of the village. Of this
            church the principal of our school was pastor. With how
            deep a spirit of wonder and perplexity was I wont to regard
            him from our remote pew in the gallery, as, with step solemn and slow, he ascended the pulpit! This reverend man,
            with countenance so demurely benign, with robes so glossy
            and so clerically flowing, with wig so minutely powdered,
            so rigid and so vast,—could this be he who, of late, with
            sour visage, and in snuffy habiliments, administered, ferule
            in hand, the Draconian laws of the academy? Oh, gigantic
            paradox, too utterly monstrous for solution!
         </p>
         
         <p>At an angle of the ponderous wall frowned a more ponderous gate. It was riveted and studded with iron bolts, and
            surmounted with jagged iron spikes. What impressions of
            deep awe did it inspire! It was never opened save for the
            three periodical egressions and ingressions already mentioned; then, in every creak of its mighty hinges, we found a
            plenitude of mystery—a world of matter for solemn remark,
            or for more solemn meditation.
         </p>
         
         <p>The extensive enclosure was irregular in form, having
            many capacious recesses. Of these, three or four of the
            largest constituted the play-ground. It was level, and covered with fine hard gravel. I well remember it had no trees,
            nor benches, nor any thing similar within it. Of course it
            was in the rear of the house. In front lay a small parterre,
            planted with box and other shrubs; but through this sacred
            division we passed only upon rare occasions indeed—such as
            a first advent to school or final departure thence, or perhaps,
            when a parent or friend having called for us, we joyfully
            took our way home for the Christmas or Midsummer holydays.
         </p>
         
         <p>But the house! — how quaint an old building was this! —
            to me how veritably a palace of enchantment! There was
            really no end to its windings — to its incomprehensible subdivisions. It was difficult, at any given lime, to say with certainty upon which of its two stories one happened to be.
            From each room to every other there were sure to be found
            three or four steps either in ascent or descent. Then the
            lateral branches were innumerable—inconceivable—and so
            returning in upon themselves, that our most exact ideas in
            regard to the whole mansion were not very far different from
            those with which we pondered upon infinity. During the
            five years of my residence here, I was never able to ascer
            
            tain with precision, in what remote locality lay the little
            sleeping apartment assigned to myself and some eighteen or
            twenty other scholars.
         </p>
         
         <p>The school-room was the largest in the house — I could
            not help thinking, in the world. It was very long, narrow,
            and dismally low, with pointed Gothic windows and a ceiling of oak. In a remote and terror-inspiring angle was a
            square enclosure of eight or ten feet, comprising the sanctum,
            “ during hours,” of our principal, the Reverend Dr. Bransby.
            It was a solid structure, with massy door, sooner than open
            which in the absence of the “ Dominie,” we would all have
            willingly perished by the peine forte et dure. In other angles were two other similar boxes, far less reverenced, indeed, but still greatly matters of awe. One of these was
            the pulpit of the “ classical ” usher, one of the “ English
            and mathematical.” Interspersed about the room, crossing
            and re-crossing in endless irregularity, were innumerable
            benches and desks, black, ancient, and time-worn, piled desperately with much-bethumbed books, and so beseamed
            with initial letters, names at full length, grotesque figures,
            and other multiplied efforts of the knife, as to have entirely
            lost what little of original form might have been their portion in days long departed. A huge bucket with water stood
            at one extremity of the room, and a clock of stupendous dimensions at the other.
         </p>
         
         <p>Encompassed by the massy walls of this venerable academy, I passed, yet not in tedium or disgust, the years of the
            third lustrum of my life. The teeming brain of childhood
            requires no external world of incident to occupy or amuse it;
            and the apparently dismal monotony of a school was replete
            with more intense excitement than my riper youth has derived from luxury, or my full manhood from crime. Yet I
            must believe that my first mental development had in it
            much of the uncommon — even much of the outré. Upon
            mankind at large the events of very early existence rarely
            leave in mature age any definite impression. All is gray
            shadow—a weak and irregular remembrance—an indistinct
            regathering of feeble pleasures and phantasmagoric pains.
            With me this is not so. In childhood I must have felt with
            the energy of a man what I now find stamped upon memory
            in lines as vivid, as deep, and as durable as the exergues of
            the Carthaginian medals.
         </p>
         
         <p>Yet in fact — in the fact of the world’s view — how little
            was there to remember! The morning’s awakening, the
            nightly summons to bed; the connings, the recitations; the
            periodical half-holidays, and perambulations; the playground, with its broils, its pastimes, its intrigues; — these,
            by a mental sorcery long forgotten, were made to involve a
            wilderness of sensation, a world of rich incident, an universe
            of varied emotion, of excitement the most passionate and
            spirit-stirring. “ Oh, le bon temps, que ce siecle de fer!"
         </p>
         
         <p>In truth, the ardor, the enthusiasm, and the imperiousness
            of my disposition, soon rendered me a marked character
            among my schoolmates, and by slow, but natural gradations,
            gave me an ascendancy over all not greatly older than myself;—over all with a single exception. This exception was
            found in the person of a scholar, who, although no relation,
            bore the same Christian and surname as myself;—a circumstance, in fact, little remarkable; for, notwithstanding a noble descent, mine was one of those every-day appellations
            which seem, by prescriptive right, to have been, time out of
            mind, the common property of the mob. In this narrative I
            have therefore designated myself as William Wilson,—a fictitious title not very dissimilar to the real. My namesake
            alone, of those who in school phraseology constituted “ our
            set," presumed to compete with me in the studies of the
            
            class—in the sports and broils of the play-ground—to refuse
            implicit belief in my assertions, and submission to my will—
            indeed, to interfere with my arbitrary dictation in any respect whatsoever. If there is on earth a supreme and unqualified despotism, it is the despotism of a master mind in
            boyhood over the less energetic spirits of its companions.
         </p>
         
         <p>Wilson’s rebellion was to me a source of the greatest embarrassment;—the more so as, in spite of the bravado with
            which in public I made a point of treating him and his pretensions, I secretly felt that I feared him, and could not help
            thinking the equality which he maintained so easily with
            myself, a proof of his true superiority; since not to be overcome cost me a perpetual struggle. Yet this superiority—even
            this equality—was in truth acknowledged by no one but myself; our associates, by some unaccountable blindness, seemed not even to suspect it. Indeed, his competition, his resistance, and especially his impertinent and dogged interference
            with my purposes, were not more pointed than private. He
            appeared to be destitute alike of the ambition which urged,
            and of the passionate energy of mind which enabled me to
            excel. In his rivalry he might have been supposed actuated
            solely by a whimsical desire to thwart, astonish, or mortify
            myself; although there were times when I could not help
            observing, with a feeling made up of wonder, abasement,
            and pique, that he mingled with his injuries, his insults, or
            his contradictions, a certain most inappropriate, and assuredly most unwelcome affectionateness of manner. I could only conceive this singular behavior to arise from a consummate self-conceit assuming the vulgar airs of patronage and
            protection.
         </p>
         
         <p>Perhaps it was this latter trait in Wilson’s conduct, conjoined with our identity of name, and the mere accident of
            our having entered the school upon the same day, which set
            afloat the notion that we were brothers, among the senior
            classes in the academy. These do not usually inquire with
            much strictness into the affairs of their juniors. I have before said, or should have said, that Wilson was not, in the
            most remote degree, connected with my family. But assuredly if we had been brothers we must have been twins; for,
            after leaving Dr. Bransby’s, I casually learned that my namesake was born on the nineteenth of January, 1813—and this
            is a somewhat remarkable coincidence; for the day is precisely that of my own nativity.
         </p>
         
         <p>It may seem strange that in spite of the continual anxiety
            occasioned me by the rivalry of Wilson, and his intolerable
            spirit of contradiction, I could not bring myself to hate him
            altogether. We had, to be sure, nearly every day a quarrel
            in which, yielding me publicly the palm of victory, he, in
            some manner, contrived to make me feel that it was he who
            had deserved it; yet a sense of pride on my part, and a veritable dignity on his own, kept us always upon what are
            called “ speaking terms,” while there were many points of
            strong congeniality in our tempers, operating to awake in me
            a sentiment which our position alone, perhaps, prevented
            from ripening into friendship. It is difficult, indeed, to define, or even to describe, my real feelings towards him.
            They formed a motley and heterogeneous admixture;—some
            petulant animosity, which was not yet hatred, some esteem, 
            more respect, much fear, with a world of uneasy curiosity, 
            To the moralist it will be unnecessary to say, in addition, 
            that Wilson and myself were the most inseparable of companions.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was no doubt the anomalous state of affairs existing between us, which turned all my attacks upon him, (and they 
            were many, eitlter open or covert) into the channel of banter
            or practical joke (giving pain while assuming the aspect of
            
            mere fun) rather than into a more serious and determined
            hostility. But my endeavours on this head were by no means
            uniformly successful, even when my plans were the most
            wittily concocted; for my namesake had much about him,
            in character, of that unassuming aDd quiet austerity which,
            while enjoying the poignancy of its own jokes, has no heel
             of Achilles in itself, and absolutely refuses to be laughed at.
            I could find, indeed, but one vulnerable point, and that, lying in a personal peculiarity, arising, perhaps, from constitutional disease, would have been spared by any antagonist
            less at his wit’s end than myself;—my rival had a weakness
            in the faucial or guttural organs, which precluded him from
            raising his voice at any time above a very low whisper. Of
            this defect I did not fail to take what poor advantage lay in
            my power.
         </p>
         
         <p>Wilson’s retaliations in kind were many; and there was
            one form of his practical wit that disturbed me beyond measure. How his sagacity first discovered at all that so petty
            a thing would vex me, is a question I never could solve;
            but, having discovered, he habitually practised the annoyance. I had always felt aversion to my uncourtly patronymic, and its very common, if not plebeian prӕnomen. The
            words were venom in my ears; and when, upon the day of
            my arrival, a second William Wilson came also to the academy, I felt angry with him for bearing the name, and doubly
            disgusted with the name because a stranger bore it, who
            would be the cause of its twofold repetition, who would be
            constantly in my presence, and whose concerns, in the ordinary routine of the school business, must inevitably, on account of the detestable coincidence, be often confounded with
            my own.
         </p>
         
         <p>The feeling of vexation thus engendered grew stronger
            with every circumstance tending to show resemblance, moral or physical, between my rival and myself. I had not then
            discovered the remarkable fact that we were of the same
            age; but I saw that we were of the same height, and I perceived that we were even singularly alike in general contour of person and outline of feature. I was galled, too, by
            the rumor touching a relationship, which had grown current
            in the upper forms. In a word, nothing could more seriously disturb me, (although I scrupulously concealed such disturbance,) than any allusion to a similarity of mind, person,
            or condition existing between us. But, in truth, I had no
            reason to believe that (with the exception of the matter of
            relationship, and in the case of Wilson himself,) this similarity had ever been made a subject of comment, or even observed at all by our schoolfellows. That he observed it in
            all its bearings, and as fixedly as I, was apparent; but that
            he could discover in such circumstances so fruitful a field of
            annoyance, can only be attributed, as I said before, to his
            more than ordinary penetration.
         </p>
         
         <p>His cue, which was to perfect an imitation of myself, lay
            both in words and in actions; and most admirably did he
            play his part. My dress it was an easy matter to copy; my
            gait and general manner were, without difficulty, appropriated; in spite of his constitutional defect, even my voice did
            not escape him. My louder tones were, of course, unattempted, but then the key, it was identical; and his singular
            whisper, it grew the very echo of my own.
         </p>
         
         <p>How greatly this most exquisite portraiture harassed me,
            (for it could not justly be termed a caricature,) I will not
            now venture to describe. I had but one consolation—in the
            fact that the imitation, apparently, was noticed by myself
            alone, and that I had to endure only the knowing and
            strangely sarcastic smiles of my namesake himself. Satisfied with having produced in my bosom the intended effect,
            be seemed to chuckle in secret over the sting he had inflict 
            
            ed, and was characteristically disregardful of the public applause which the success of his witty endeavours might have
            so easily elicited. That the school, indeed, did not feel his
            design, perceive its accomplishment, and participate in his
            sneer, was, for many anxious months, a riddle I could not resolve. Perhaps the gradation of his copy rendered it not
            so readily perceptible; or, more possibly, I owed my security to the masterly air of the copyist, who, disdaining the
            letter, (which in a painting is all the obtuse can see,) gave
            but the full spirit of his original for my individual contemplation and chagrin.
         </p>
         
         <p>I have already more than once spoken of the disgusting
            air of patronage which he assumed toward me, and of his
            frequent officious interference with my will. This interference often took the ungracious character of advice; advice
            not openly given, but hinted or insinuated. I received it
            with a repugnance which gained strength as I grew in years.
            Yet, at this distant day, let me do him the simple justice to
            acknowledge that I can recall no occasion when the suggestions of my rival were on the side of those errors or follies
            so usual to his immature age and seeming inexperience; that
            his moral sense, at least, if not his general talents and worldly wisdom, was far keener than my own; and that I might,
            to-day, have been a better, and thus a happier man, had I
            less frequently rejected the counsels embodied in those meaning whispers which I then but too cordially hated and too
            bitterly despised.
         </p>
         
         <p>As it was, I at length grew restive in the extreme under
            his distasteful supervision, and daily resented more and more
            openly what I considered his intolerable arrogance. I have
            said that, in the first years of our connexion as schoolmates,
            my feelings in regard to him might have been easily ripened
            into friendship; but, in the latter months of my residence at
            the academy, although the intrusion of his ordinary manner
            had, beyond doubt, in some measure, abated, my sentiments,
            in nearly similar proportion, partook very much of positive
            hatred. Upon one occasion he saw this, I think, and afterwards avoided, or made a show of avoiding me.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was about the same period, if I remember aright, that,
            in an altercation of violence with him, in which he was more
            than usually thrown off his guard, and spoke and acted with
            an openness of demeanor rather foreign to his nature, I discovered, or fancied I discovered, in his accent, his air, and
            general appearance, a something which first startled, and
            then deeply interested me, by bringing to mind dim visions
            of my earliest infancy—wild, confused and thronging memories of a time when memory herself was yet unborn. I
            cannot better describe the sensation which oppressed me
            than by saying that I could with difficulty shake off the belief of my having been acquainted with the being who stood
            before me, at some epoch very long ago—some point of the
            past even infinitely remote. The delusion, however, faded
            rapidly as it came; and I mention it at all but to define the
            day of the last conversation I there held with my singular 
            namesake.
         </p>
         
         <p>The huge old house, with its countless subdivisions, had
            several large chambers communicating with each other,
            where slept the greater number of the students. There
            were, however, (as must necessarily happen in a building so
            awkwardly planned,) many little nooks or recesses, the odds
            and ends of the structure; and these the economic ingenuity of Dr. Bransby had also fitted up as dormitories; although,
            being the merest closets, they were capable of accommodating but a single individual. One of these small apartments
            was occupied by Wilson.
         </p>
         
         <p>One night, about the close of my fifth year at the school,
            
            and immediately after the altercation just mentioned, finding every one wrapped in sleep, I arose from bed, and, lamp
            in hand, stole through a wilderness of narrow passages from
            my own bedroom to that of my rival. I had long been plotting one of those ill-natured pieces of practical wit at his
            expense in which I had hitherto been so uniformly unsuccessful. It was my intention, now, to put my scheme in operation, and I resolved to make him feel the whole extent
            of the malice with which I was imbued. Having reached
            his closet, I noiselessly entered, leaving the lamp, with a
            shade over it, on the outside. I advanced a step, and listened to the sound of his tranquil breathing. Assured of his
            being asleep, I returned, took the light, and with it again
            approached the bed. Close curtains were around it, which,
            in the prosecution of my plan, I slowly and quietly withdrew, when the bright rays fell vividly upon the sleeper,
            and my eyes, at the same moment, upon his countenance.
            I looked; — and a numbness, an iciness of feeling instantly
            pervaded my frame. My breast heaved, my knees tottered,
            my whole spirit became possessed with an objectless yet intolerable horror. Gasping for breath, I lowered the lamp
            in still nearer proximity to the face. Were these—these the
            lineaments of William Wilson? I saw, indeed, that they
            were his, but I shook as if with a fit of the ague in fancying
            they were not. What was there about them to confound me
            in this manner? I gazed; — while my brain reeled with a
            multitude of incoherent thoughts. Not thus he appeared—
            assuredly not thus — in the vivacity of his waking hours.
            The same name! the same contour of person! the same day
            of arrival at the academy! And then his dogged and meaningless imitation of my gait, my voice, my habits, and my
            manner! Was it, in truth, within the bounds of human
            possibility, that what I now saw was the result, merely, of
            the habitual practice of this sarcastic imitation? Awestricken, and with a creeping shudder, I extinguished the
            lamp, passed silently from the chamber, and left, at once, the
            halls of that old academy, never to enter them again.
         </p>
         
         <p>After a lapse of some months, spent at home in mere idleness, I found myself a student at Eton. The brief interval
            had been sufficient to enfeeble my remembrance of the events
            at Dr. Bransby’s, or at least to effect a material change in
            the nature of the feelings with which I remembered them.
            The truth — the tragedy — of the drama was no more. I
            could now find room to doubt the evidence of my senses;
            and seldom called up the subject at all but with wonder at
            the extent of human credulity, and a smile at the vivid force
            of the imagination which I hereditarily possessed. Neither
            was this species of skepticism likely to be diminished by the
            character of the life I led at Eton. The vortex of thoughtless folly into which I there so immediately and so recklessly
            plunged, washed away all but the froth of my past hours,
            engulfed at once every solid or serious impression, and left
            to memory only the veriest levities of a former existence.
         </p>
         
         <p>I do not wish, however, to trace the course of my miserable profligacy here—a profligacy which set at defiance the
            laws, while it eluded the vigilance of the institution. Three
            years of folly, passed without profit, had but given me rooted habits of vice, and added, in a somewhat unusual degree,
            to my bodily stature, when, after a week of soulless dissipation, I invited a small party of the most dissolute students
            to a secret carousal in my chambers. We met at a late hour
            of the night; for our debaucheries were to be faithfully protracted until morning. The wine flowed freely, and there
            were not wanting other and perhaps more dangerous seductions; so that the grey dawn had already faintly appeared
            in the east, while our delirious extravagance was at its
            
            height. Madly flashed with cards and intoxication, I was
            in the act of insisting upon a toast of more than wonted
            profanity, when my attention was suddenly diverted by the
            violent, although partial unclosing of the door of the apartment, and by the eager voice of a servant from without. He 
            said that some person, apparently in great haste, demanded
            to speak with me in the hall.
         </p>
         
         <p>Wildly excited with wine, the unexpected interruption
            rather delighted than surprised me. I staggered forward at
            once, and a few steps brought me to the vestibule of the
            building. In this low and small room there hung no lamp;
            and now no light at all was admitted, save that of the exceedingly feeble dawn which made its way through the 
            semi-circular window. As I put my foot over the threshold,
            I became aware of the figure of a youth about my own
            height, and habited in a white kerseymere morning frock, cut
            in the novel fashion of the one I myself wore at the moment. This the faint light enabled me to perceive; but the
            features of his face I could not distinguish. Upon my entering he strode hurriedly up to me, and, seizing me by the
            arm with a gesture of petulant impatience, whispered the
            words “ William Wilson! ” in my ear.
         </p>
         
         <p>I grew perfectly sober in an instant.</p>
         
         <p>There was that in the manner of the stranger, and in the
            tremulous shake of his uplifted finger, as he held it between
            my eyes and the light, which filled me with unqualified
            amazement; but it was not this which had so violently
            moved me. It was the pregnancy of solemn admonition in
            the singular, low, hissing utterance; and, above all, it was
            the character, the tone, the key, of those few, simple, and
            familiar, yet whispered syllables, which came with a thousand thronging memories of by-gone days, and struck upon
            my soul with the shock of a galvanic battery. Ere I could
            recover the use of my senses he was gone.
         </p>
         
         <p>Although this event failed not of a vivid effect upon my 
            disordered imagination, yet was it evanescent as vivid. For
            some weeks, indeed, I busied myself in earnest inquiry, or
            was wrapped in a cloud of morbid speculation. I did not
            pretend to disguise from my perception the identity of the
            singular individual who thus perseveringly interfered with
            my affairs, and harassed me with his insinuated counsel.
            But who and what was this Wilson? — and whence came
            he?—and what were his purposes? Upon neither of these
            points could I be satisfied; merely ascertaining, in regard to
            him, that a sudden accident in his family had caused his removal from Dr. Bransby’s academy on the afternoon of the
            day in which I myself had eloped. But in a brief period I
            ceased to think upon the subject; my attention being all absorbed in a contemplated departure for Oxford. Thither I
            soon went; the uncalculating vanity of my parents furnishng me with an outfit, and annual establishment, which
            Would enable me to indulge at will in the luxury already so
            dear to my heart,—to vie in profuseness of expenditure with
            the haughtiest heirs of the wealthiest earldoms in Great
            Britain.
         </p>
         
         <p>Excited by such appliances to vice, my constitutional temperament broke forth with redoubled ardor, and I spurned
            even the common restraints of decency in the mad infatuation of my revels. But it were absurd to pause in the detail
            of my extravagance. Let it suffice, that among spendthrifts
            I out-Heroded Herod, and that, giving name to a multitude
            of novel follies, I added no brief appendix to the long catalogue of vices then usual in the most dissolute university of
            Europe.
         </p>
         
         <p>It could hardly be credited, however, that I had, even
            here, so utterly fallen from the gentlemanly estate, as to 
            
            seek acquaintance with the vilest arts of the gambler by
            profession, and, having become an adept in his despicable
             science, to practise it habitually as a means of increasing
            my already enormous income at the expense of the weak minded among my fellow collegians. Such, nevertheless,
            was the fact. And the very enormity of this offence against
            all manly and honourable sentiment proved, beyond doubt,
            the main if not the sole reason of the impunity with which
            it was committed. Who, indeed, among my most abandoned associates, would not rather have disputed the clearest
            evidence of his senses, than have suspected of such courses,
            the gay, the frank, the generous William Wilson — the noblest and most liberal commoner at Oxford—him whose follies (said his parasites) were but the follies of youth and
            unbridled fancy—whose errors but inimitable whim—whose
            darkest vice but a careless and dashing extravagance?
         </p>
         
         <p>I had been now two years successfully busied in this way,
            when there came to the university a young parvenu nobleman, Glendinning — rich, said report, as Herodes Atticus —
            his riches, too, as easily acquired. I soon found him of weak
            intellect, and, of course, marked him as a fitting subject for
            my skill. I frequently engaged him in play, and contrived,
            with a gambler’s usual art, to let him win considerable sums,
            the more effectually to entangle him in my snares. At length,
            my schemes being ripe, I met him (with the full intention
            that this meeting should be final and decisive) at the chambers of a fellow-commoner, (Mr. Preston,) equally intimate
            with both, but who, to do him justice, entertained not even
            a remote suspicion of my design. To give to this a better
            coloring, I had contrived to have assembled a party of some
            eight or ten, and was solicitously careful that the introduction of cards should appear accidental, and originate in the
            proposal of my contemplated dupe himself. To be brief
            upon a vile topic, none of the low finesse was omitted, so
            customary upon similar occasions that it is a just matter for
            wonder how any are still found so besotted as to fall its victim.
         </p>
         
         <p>We had protracted our sitting far into the night, and I had
            at length effected the manoeuvre of getting Glendinning as
            my sole antagonist. The game, too, was my favorite écarté.
            The rest of the company, interested in the extent of our
            play, had abandoned their own cards, and were standing
            around us as spectators. The parvenu, who had been induced by my artifices in the early part of the evening, to
            drink deeply, now shuffled, dealt, or played, with a wild
            nervousness of manner for which his intoxication, I thought,
            might partially, but could not altogether account. In a very
            short period be had become my debtor to a large amount,
            when, having taken a long draught of port, he did precisely
            what I had been coolly anticipating—he proposed to double
            our already extravagant stakes. With a well-feigned show
            of reluctance, and not until after my repeated refusal had
            seduced him into some angry words which gave a color of
            pique to my compliance, did I finally comply. The result,
            of course, did but prove how entirely the prey was in my
            toils; in less than an hour he had quadrupled his debt. For
            some time his countenance had been losing the florid tinge
            lent it by the wine; but now, to my astonishment, I perceived that it had grown to a pallor truly fearful. I say to
            my astonishment. Glendinning had been represented to my
            eager inquiries as immeasurably wealthy; and the sums
            which he had as yet lost, although in themselves vast, could
            not, I supposed, very seriously annoy, much less so violently
            affect him. That he was overcome by the wine just swallowed, was the idea which most readily presented itself;
            and, rather with a view to the preservation of my own char
            
            acter in the eyes of my associates, than from any less interested motive, I was about to insist, peremptorily, upon a
            discontinuance of the play, when some expressions at my
            elbow from among the company, and an ejaculation evincing
            utter despair on the part of Glendinning, gave me to understand that I had effected his total ruin under circumstances
            which, rendering him an object for the pity of all, should
            have protected him from the ill offices even of a fiend.
         </p>
         
         <p>What now might have been my conduct it is difficult to
            say. The pitiable condition of my dupe had thrown an air
            of embarrassed gloom over all; and, for some moments, a
            profound silence was maintained, during which I could not
            help feeling my cheeks tingle with the many burning glances
            of scorn or reproach cast upon me by the less abandoned of
            the party. I will even own that an intolerable weight of
            anxiety was for a brief instant lifted from my bosom by the
            sudden and extraordinary interruption which ensued. The
            wide, heavy folding doors of the apartment were all at once
            thrown open, to their full extent, with a vigorous and rushing impetuosity that extinguished, as if by magic, every
            candle in the room. Their light, in dying, enabled us just
            to perceive that a stranger had entered, about my own height,
            and closely muffled in a cloak. The darkness, however,
            was now total; and we could only feel that he was standing
            in our midst. Before any one of us could recover from the
            extreme astonishment into which this rudeness had thrown
            all, we heard the voice of the intruder.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Gentlemen,” he said, in a low, distinct, and never-to-beforgotten whisper which thrilled to the very marrow of my
            bones, “ Gentlemen, I make no apology for this behaviour,
            because in thus behaving, I am but fulfilling a duty. You
            are, beyond doubt, uninformed of the true character of the
            person who has to-night won at écarté a large sum of money from Lord Glendinning. I will therefore put you upon
            an expeditious and decisive plan of obtaining this very necessary information. Please to examine, at your leisure, the
            inner linings of the cuff of his left sleeve, and the several
            little packages which may be found in the somewhat capacious pockets of his embroidered morning wrapper.”
         </p>
         
         <p>While he spoke, so profound was the stillness that one
            might have heard a pin drop upon the floor. In ceasing, he
            departed at once, and as abruptly as he had entered. Can
            I—shall I describe my sensations? — must I say that I felt
            all the horrors of the damned? Most assuredly I had little
            time given for reflection. Many hands roughly seized me
            upon the spot, and lights were immediately reprocured. A
            search ensued. In the lining of my sleeve were found all
            the court cards essential in écarté, and, in the pockets of my
            wrapper, a number of packs, fac-similes of those used at
            our sittings, with the single exception that mine were of the
            species called, technically, arrondées; the honors being
            slightly convex at the ends, the lower cards slightly convex
            at the sides. In this disposition, the dupe who cuts, as customary, at the length of the pack, will invariably find that
            he cuts his antagonist an honor; while the gambler, cutting
            at the breadth, will, as certainly, cut nothing for his victim
            which may count in the records of the game.
         </p>
         
         <p>Any burst of indignation upon this discovery would have
            affected me less than the silent contempt, or the sarcastic
            composure, with which it was received.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Mr. Wilson,” said our host, stooping to remove from beneath his feet an exceedingly luxurious cloak of rare furs,
            “Mr. Wilson, this is your property." (The weather was
            cold; and, upon quitting my own room, I had thrown a
            cloak over my dressing wrapper, putting it off upon reading the scene of play.) “ I presume it is supererogatory to
            
            seek here (eyeing the folds of the garment with a bitter
             smile) for any farther evidence of your skill. Indeed, we
            have had enough. You will see the necessity, I hope, of
            quitting Oxford — at all events, of quitting instantly my
            chambers.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Abased, humbled to the dust as I then was, it is probable
            that I should have resented this galling language by immediate personal violence, had not my whole attention been
            at the moment arrested by a fact of the most startling character. The cloak which I had worn was of a rare description of fur; how rare, how extravagantly costly, I shall not
            venture to say. Its fashion, too, was of my own fantastic
            invention; for I was fastidious to an absurd degree of coxcombry, in matters of this frivolous nature. When, therefore, Mr. Preston reached me that which he had picked up
            upon the floor, and near the folding doors of the apartment,
            it was with an astonishment nearly bordering upon terror,
            that I perceived my own already hanging on my arm, (where
            I had no doubt unwittingly placed it,) and that the one presented me was but its exact counterpart in every, in even
            the minutest possible particular. The singular being who
            had so disastrously exposed me, had been muffled, I remembered, in a cloak; and none had been worn at all by any of
            the members of our party with the exception of myself.
            Retaining some presence of mind, I took the one offered me
            by Preston; placed it, unnoticed, over my own; left the apartment with a resolute scowl of defiance; and, next morning
            ere dawn of day, commenced a hurried journey from Oxford to the continent, in a perfect agony of horror and of
            shame.
         </p>
         
         <p>I fled in vain. My evil destiny pursued me as if in exultation, and proved, indeed, that the exercise of its mysterious
            dominion had as yet only begun. Scarcely had I set foot in
            Paris ere I had fresh evidence of the detestable interest taken by this Wilson in my concerns. Years flew, while I experienced no relief. Villain!—at Rome, with how untimely, yet with how spectral an officiousness, stepped he in between me and my ambition! At Vienna, too—at Berlin—
            and at Moscow! Where, in truth, had I not bitter cause to
            curse him within my heart? From his inscrutable tyranny
            did I at length flee, panic-stricken, as from a pestilence;
            and to the very ends of the earth I fled in vain.
         </p>
         
         <p>And again, and again, in secret communion with my own
            spirit, would I demand the questions “Who is he?—
            whence came he?—and what are his objects?" But no answer was there found. And now I scrutinized, with a minute scrutiny, the forms, and the methods, and the leading traits
            of his impertinent supervision. But even here there was
            very little upon which to base a conjecture. It was noticeable, indeed, that, in no one of the multiplied instances in
            which he had of late crossed my path, had he so crossed it
            except to frustrate those schemes, or to disturb those actions,
            which, if fully carried out, might have resulted in bitter mischief. Poor justification this, in truth, for an authority so
            imperiously assumed! Poor indemnity for natural rights of
            self-agency so pertinaciously, so insultingly denied!
         </p>
         
         <p>I had also been forced to notice that my tormentor, for a
            very long period of time, (while scrupulously and with miraculous dexterity maintaining his whim of an identity of apparel with myself,) had so contrived it, in the execution of
            his varied interference with my will, that I saw not, at any
            moment, the features of his face. Be Wilson what he might,
            this, at least, was but the veriest of affectation, or of folly.
            Could he, for an instant, have supposed that, in my admonisher at Eton—in the destroyer of my honor at Oxford,—in
            him who thwarted my ambition at Rome, my revenge at
            
            
            Paris, my passionate love at Naples, or what he falsely termed my avarice in Egypt,—that in this, my arch-enemy and
            evil genius, I could fail to recognise the William Wilson of
            my schoolboy days,—the namesake, the companion, the rival,—the hated and dreaded rival at Dr. Bransby’s? Impossible!—But let me hasten to the last eventful scene of the
            drama.
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus far I had succumbed supinely to this imperious domination. The sentiment of deep awe with which I habitually
            regarded the elevated character, the majestic wisdom, the
            apparent omnipresence and omnipotence of Wilson, added to
            a feeling of even terror, with which certain other traits in
            his nature and assumptions inspired me, had operated, hitherto, to impress me with an idea of my own utter weakness
            and helplessness, and to suggest an implicit, although bitterly reluctant submission to his arbitrary will. But, of late
            days, I had given myself up entirely to wine; and its maddening influence upon my hereditary temper rendered me
            more and more impatient of control. I began to murmur,—
            to hesitate,—to resist. And was it only fancy which induced me to believe that, with the increase of my own firmness,
            that of my tormentor underwent a proportional diminution?
            Be this as it may, I now began to feel the inspiration of a
            burning hope, and at length nurtured in my secret thoughts
            a stern and desperate resolution that I would submit no longer to be enslaved.
         </p>
         
         <p>It was at Rome, during the Carnival of 18—, that I attended a masquerade in the palazzo of the Neapolitan Duke Di
            Broglio. I had indulged more freely than usual in the excesses of the wine-table; and now the suffocating atmosphere
            of the crowded rooms irritated me beyond endurance. The
            difficulty, too, of forcing my way through the mazes of the
            company contributed not a little to the ruffling of my temper; for I was anxiously seeking, (let me not say with what
            unworthy motive) the young, the gay, the beautiful wife of
            the aged and doting Di Broglio. With a too unscrupulous
            confidence she had previously communicated to me the secret of the costume in which she would be habited, and
            now, having caught a glimpse of her person, I was hurrying to make my way into her presence.—At this moment I
            felt a light hand placed upon my shoulder, and that ever-remembered, low, damnable whisper within my ear.
         </p>
         
         <p>In an absolute phrenzy of wrath, I turned at once upon
            him who had thus interrupted me, and seized him violently
            by the collar. He was attired, as I had expected, in a costume altogether similar to my own; wearing a Spanish cloak
            of blue velvet, begirt about the waist with a crimson belt sustaining a rapier. A mask of black silk entirely covered his
            face.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Scoundrel!” I said, in a voice husky with rage, while
            every syllable I uttered seemed as new fuel to my fury,
            “scoundrel! impostor! accursed villain! you shall not—you
            shall not dog me unto death! Follow me, or I stab you
            where you stand!”—and I broke my way from the ballroom into a small ante-chamber adjoining—dragging him
            unresistingly with me as I went.
         </p>
         
         <p>Upon entering, I thrust him furiously from me. He staggered against the wall, while I closed the door with an oath,
            and commanded him to draw. He hesitated but for an instant; then, with a slight sigh, drew in silence, and put himself upon his defence.
         </p>
         
         <p>The contest was brief indeed. I was frantic with every
            species of wild excitement, and felt within my single arm the
            energy and power of a multitude. In a few seconds I forced him by sheer strength against the wainscoting, and thus,
            
            getting him at mercy, plunged my sword, with brute ferocity, repeatedly through and through his bosom.
         </p>
         
         <p>At that instant some person tried the latch of the door. I
            hastened to prevent an intrusion, and then immediately returned to my dying antagonist. But what human language
            can adequately portray that astonishment, that horror which
            possessed me at the spectacle then presented to view? The
            brief moment in which I averted my eyes had been sufficient
            to produce, apparently, a material change in the arrangements at the upper or farther end of the room. A large mirror,—so at first it seemed to me in my confusion—now stood
            where none had been perceptible before; and, as I stepped
            up to it in extremity of terror, mine own image, but with
            features all pale and dabbled in blood, advanced to meet me
            with a feeble and tottering gait.
         </p>
         
         <p>Thus it appeared I say, but was not. It was my antagonist—it was Wilson, who then stood before me in the agonies of his dissolution. His mask and cloak lay, where he
            had thrown them, upon the floor. Not a thread in all his
            raiment—not a line in all the marked and singular lineaments of his face which was not, even in the most absolute
            identity, mine own!
         </p>
         
         <p>It was Wilson; but he spoke no longer in a whisper, and
            I could have fancied that I myself was speaking while he
            said:
         </p>
         
         <p>“ You have conquered, and I yield. Yet, henceforward
            art thou also dead—dead to the World, to Heaven and to
            Hope! In me didst thou exist—and, in my death, see by
            this image, which is thine own, how utterly thou hast murdered thyself."
         </p>	
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="head">Romance.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Romance, who loves to nod and sing,
            
            <br></br>With drowsy head and folded wing,
            
            <br></br>Among the green leaves as they shake
            
            <br></br>Far down within some shadowy lake,
            
            <br></br>To me a painted paroquet
            
            <br></br>Hath been—a most familiar bird—
            
            <br></br>Taught me my alphabet to say—
            
            <br></br>To lisp my very earliest word
            
            <br></br>While in the wild wood I did lie
            
            <br></br>A child—with a most knowing eye.
            
            <br></br>Of late, eternal Condor years
            
            <br></br>So shake the very Heavens on high
            
            <br></br>With tumult, as they thunder by.
            
            <br></br>I have no time for idle cares
            
            <br></br>Through gazing on the unquiet sky.
            
            <br></br>And when an hour with calmer wings
            
            <br></br>Its down upon my spirit flings—
            
            <br></br>That little time with lyre and rhyme
            
            <br></br>To while away—forbidden things!
            
            <br></br>My heart would feel to be a crime
            
            <br></br>Unless it trembled with the strings!
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p4">
            <p>Wiley and Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XIX.
               Prose and Verse. By Thomas Hood. Part II.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of this number of the Library we said a few words in our
               last, but we shall be pardoned for referring to it again, as it
               contains several of the most characteristic, as well as most
               meritorious compositions of one of the most remarkable men
               of his time.
            </p>
            
            <p>The quizzical Letters entitled “ Copyright and Copy
               
               wrong” should be read by all true friends and fair enemies
               of International Copyright. The strong points of the question of copyright, generally, were never more forcibly, if ever
               more ludicrously, put.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ The Bridge of Sighs” is, with one exception, the finest
               poem written by Hood. It has been much admired and often quoted—but we have no hesitation in complying with a
               friend’s request, to copy it in full. We must omit it, however, till next week.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ The Haunted House” we prefer to any composition of
               its author. It is a masterpiece of its kind—and that kind
               belongs to a very lofty—if not to the very loftiest order of
               poetical literature. Had we seen this piece before penning
               our first notice of Hood, we should have had much hesitation in speaking of Fancy and Fantasy as his predominant
               features. At all events we should have given him credit for
               much more of true Imagination than we did.
            </p>
            
            <p>Not the least merit of the work is its rigorous simplicity.
               There is no narrative, and no doggrel philosophy. The
               whole subject is the description, of a deserted house, which
               the popular superstition considers haunted. The thesis is
               one of the truest in all poetry. As a mere thesis it is really
               difficult to conceive anything better. The strength of the
               poet is put forth in the invention of traits in keeping with
               the ideas of crime, abandonment, and ghostly visitation.
               Every legitimate art is brought in to aid in conveying the
               intended effects; and (what is quite remarkable in the case
               of Hood) nothing discordant is at any point introduced. He
               has here very little of what we have designated as the phantastic—little which is not strictly harmonious. The metre
               and rhythm are not only, in themselves, admirably adapted
               to the whole design, but, with a true artistic feeling, the poet
               has preserved a thorough monotone throughout, and renders
               its effect more impressive by the repetition (gradually increasing in frequency towards the finale) of one of the most
               pregnant and effective of the stanzas:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>O’er all there hung a shadow and a fear;
               
               <br></br>A sense of mystery the spirit daunted,
               
               <br></br>And said, as plain as whisper in the ear,
               
               <br></br>The place is haunted!
            </div>
            
            <p>We quote a few of the most impressive quatrains:</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>The coot was swimming in the reedy pond,
               
               <br></br>Beside the water-hen so soon affrighted,
               
               <br></br>And in the reedy moat the heron, fond
               
               <br></br>Of solitude, alighted.
               
               <br></br>The moping heron, motionless and stiff,
               
               <br></br>That on a stone as silently and stilly
               
               <br></br>Stood, an apparent sentinel, as if
               
               <br></br>To guard the water-lily.
               
               <br></br>The vine unpruned, and the neglected peach
               
               <br></br>Drooped from the wall with which they used to grapple;
               
               <br></br>And on the cankered tree, in easy reach,
               
               <br></br>Rotted the golden apple.
               
               <br></br>Howbeit, the door I pushed—or so I dreamed—
               
               <br></br>Which slowly, slowly, gaped—the hinges creaking
               
               <br></br>With such a rusty eloquence, it seemed
               
               <br></br>That Time himself was speaking.
               
               <br></br>The startled bats flew out, bird after bird,
               
               <br></br>The screech-owl overhead began to flutter,
               
               <br></br>And seemed to mock the cry that she had heard
               
               <br></br>Some dying victim utter.
               
               <br></br>A shriek that echoed from the joisted roof
               
               <br></br>And up the stair and further still and further,
               
               <br></br>Till in some ringing chamber far aloof
               
               <br></br>It ceased its tale of murther.
               
               
               <br></br>Meanwhile the rusty armor rattled round,
               
               <br></br>The banner shuddered and the ragged streamer;
               
               <br></br>All things the horrid tenor of the sound
               
               <br></br>Acknowledged with a tremor.
               
               <br></br>The very stains and fractures on the wall,
               
               <br></br>Assuming features solemn and terrific,
               
               <br></br>Hinted some tragedy of that old hall,
               
               <br></br>Locked up in hieroglyphic.
               
               <br></br>Some tale that might, perchance, have solved the doubt
               
               <br></br>Wherefore amongst those flags so dull and livid,
               
               <br></br>The banner of the Bloody Hand shone out
               
               <br></br>So ominously vivid.
               
               <br></br>Those dreary stairs, where with the sounding stress
               
               <br></br>Of ev’ry step so many echoes blended,
               
               <br></br>The mind, with dark misgivings, feared to guess
               
               <br></br>How many feet ascended.
               
               <br></br>Yet no portentous shape the sight amazed;
               
               <br></br>Each object plain, and tangible, and valid;
               
               <br></br>But from their tarnished frames dark figures gazed,
               
               <br></br>And faces spectre-pallid.
               
               <br></br>Not merely with the mimic life that lies
               
               <br></br>Within the compass of Art’s simulation:
               
               <br></br>Their souls were looking through their painted eyes
               
               <br></br>With awful speculation.
               
               <br></br>On every lip a speechless horror dwelt;
               
               <br></br>On every brow the burden of affliction;
               
               <br></br>The old ancestral spirits knew and felt
               
               <br></br>The house's malediction.
               
               <br></br>Rich hangings, storied by the needle’s art,
               
               <br></br>With scripture history, or classic fable;
               
               <br></br>But all had faded, save one ragged part,
               
               <br></br>Where Cain was slaying Abel.
               
               <br></br>The death-watch ticked behind the panneled oak.
               
               <br></br>Inexplicable tremors shook the arras,
               
               <br></br>And echoes strange and mystical awoke,
               
               <br></br>The fancy to embarrass.
               
               <br></br>Prophetic hints that filled the soul with dread,
               
               <br></br>But through one gloomy entrance pointing mostly,
               
               <br></br>The while some secret inspiration said,
               
               <br></br>That chamber is the ghostly!
            </div>
            
            <p>Had Hood only written “ The Haunted House” it would
               have sufficed to render him immortal.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Reading. No. XX.
               The Indicator and Companion. By Leigh Hunt. Part II.
            </p>
            
            <p>This volume contains some two or three papers which are
               worth preserving—which have in them the elements of life
               —and which will leave a definite and perhaps a permanent
               impression upon every one who reads them In general,
               however, it is made up of that species of easy writing which
               is not the easiest reading. We find here too much of slipshodiness, both in thought and manner, and too little of determined purpose. The tone is not that of a bold genius
               uttering vigorous things carelessly and inconsiderately, with
               contempt or neglect of method or completeness, but rather
               that of a naturally immethodical and inaccurate intellect,
               making a certain air of ruggedness and insouciance the
               means of exalting the commonplace into the semblance of
               originality and strength. Hunt has written many agreeable
               papers, but no great ones. His points will bear no steady
               examination. The view at first taken of him by the public
               is far nearer the truth, perhaps, than that which seems to
               have been latterly adopted. His “Feast of the Poets ” is
               possibly his best composition. As a rambling essayist he
               has too little of the raw material. As a critic he is merely
               saucy, or lackadaisical, or falsely enthusiastic, or at best
               pointedly conceited. His judgment is not worth a rush —
               
               witness his absurd eulogies on Coleridge's “Pains of Sleep”
               quoted in the volume before us. In his “ Remarks upon (on)
               De Basso’s Ode to a Dead Body,” he has said critically some
               of the very best things it ever occurred to him to say; but
               if there be need to show the pure imbecility and irrelevancy
               of the paper as a criticism, let it only be contrasted with
               what a truly critical spirit would write. The highest literary quality of Hunt is a secondary or tertiary grade of Fancy. His loftiest literary attainment is to entertain. This is
               precisely the word which suits his case. As for excitement
               we must not look for it in him. And, unhappily, his books
               are not of such character that they may be taken up, with
               pleasure, (as may the “ Spectator,”) by a mind exhausted
               through excitement. In this condition we require repose—
               which is the antipode of the style of Hunt. And since for
               the ennuyé he has insufficient stimulus, it is clear that as an
               author he is fit for very little, if really for any thing at all.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <p>Introductory Lectures on Modern History, delivered in Lent
               Term, 1842, with the Inaugural Lecture delivered in December, 1841. By Thomas Arnold, D. D., Regius Professor of Modem History in the Univ rsity of Oxford, &amp;c.
               Edited from the Second London Edition, with a Preface
               and Notes, by Henry Reed, M. A., Professor of English
               Literature in the University of Pennsylvania. New-York:
               D. Appleton &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>We take it for granted that there are few of our readers unacquainted with the great celebrity of these Lectures, or
               with the high estimation in which they are held by the historical scholars of Europe. We feel called upon, therefore,
               to say only a very few words of the book. It would be difficult, indeed, to say too much, were we to discuss its excellences. Independently of his sterling worth as mere historian, Dr. Arnold must command the attention and respect of
               every American by his earnest and most influential zeal as
               an Apostle of Liberty. The Preface (by Dr. Reed) to this
               American edition, is an admirably written commentary on 
               the man.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Messrs. Appleton have recently published “ The Life
               and Correspondence ” and “ The Miscellaneous Works ” of
               Doctor Arnold, both edited by Arthur P. Stanley, M. A.
               These volumes are published uniformly with the one now
               before us; and all are in the beautiful style so usual with
               the Appletons.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <p>A Treatise on Domestic Economy, for the Use of Young Ladies at Home and at School. By Miss Catherine E. Beecher. Revised Edition, with Numerous Additions and Illustrative Engravings. New-York: Harper &amp; Brothers.</p>
            
            <p>This volume is so well known, and so thoroughly appreciated, that we need only call attention to the issue of an improved edition. It is very generally adopted as a text-book
               in female schools. It has been examined by the Massachusetts Board of Education, and by them deemed worthy of admission as a part of the Massachusetts School Library—an
               honor which speaks for itself.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <p>Simms’ Magazine,
               For August, is capital. It contains several of the finest kind
               of Magazine papers, and is as ably edited as any journal of
               its species in America—if not more ably edited than any. We
               invite attention to several Sonnets (anonymous,) and to the
               articles entitled “ The Epochs and Events of American History, as suited to the Purposes of Art in Fiction;" “The Subaltern’s Yarn;" “ Bayard the Chevalier;” and “A Foreigner’s First Glimpses of Georgia.”
            </p>
            
            <p>As a matter of course we find Mr. Simms agreeing with 
               
               ourselves, “ The Democratic Review,” and in fact with all
               the unprejudiced critics of the country, in condemning, nearly altogether, the very mediocres poems of Mr. Lord. We
               quote a sentence or two of Mr. Simms’ critique.
            </p>
            
            <p>Metaphysical poetry requires deep sedateness of mood, habitual
               contemplation, and much of that quieting sort of thought which a rare
               experience of the world alone can give. Wanting all this, the poems
               of Mr. Lord, which aim at this character, are vague, wordy, purposeless; without those leading views of his topic which alone can justify
               the author in attempting it. We see the fruits of his reading, not of
               his genius, in the poem called “ Worship.” Here is a little of Bryant,
               and here something more of Coleridge. Phrases from these and other
               poets are conspicuous upon every page—some of these strangely obtrusive, as at p. 8, the “ temple-hunting martlets” of Shakspeare.
               The ode “ To an American Statesman,” strikes us as a very decided
               imitation of that to the American flag, by Drake, and faint efforts in
               the way of Tennyson and Longfellow, are evident as we turn his
               pages.
            </p>
            
            <p>That Mr. Lord can think, and may, by severe training, and sometimes scourging, be made to think, we have proof in this little volume.
               We see here and there the head or tail of an idea, the wing or the
               pen-feathers of a fancy, which elaboration might have rendered legitimately his own. That he has a spiritual mood at work is apparent
               also. But there is no one piece in the collection, no, nor no one paragraph of any length, which may be considered tolerably perfect, and
               fit for selection.
            </p>
            
            <p>Simms' Magazine is published in Charleston, by Burges
               &amp; James.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <p>Harper’s Illuminated and Illustrated Shakspeare.</p>
            
            <p>Nos. 63 and 64 are issued; embracing “ The Tempest,” and
               some of the most exquisite specimens of wood engraving,
               and of design, which have ever been published in America.
               It is difficult to avoid enthusiasm while speaking of these
               admirable plates. The edition should be in the hands of every one who reads—or sees.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <p>The Mission, or Scenes in Africa. Written for Young People. By Capt. Marryat. New-York: D. Appleton &amp; Co.</p>
            
            <p>Captain Marryat is not surpassed by any writer of this age
               in the faculty of interesting the youthful mind. These two
               neat duodecimos are full of entertainment, and in point of
               moral purpose, not only unobjectionable, but commendable
               in the highest degree.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <p>The Abbey of Innismoyle: A Story of Another Century. By
               the author of “Father Clement,"  " """The Decision,” etc., etc.
               Philadelphia: James M. Campbell. New-York: Saxton
               &amp; Miles.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a handsome duodecimo—a republication from the
               English edition. The story is quite celebrated. It is full not
               only of romantic but of religious interest. An excellent gift
               book for the young.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <p>The Medici Series of Italian Prose. Nos. 2 &amp; 3. The Florentine Histories, by Niccolo Machiavelli. In 2 vols. Translated and Edited by C. Edwards Lester. New-York:
               Paine &amp; Burgess.
            </p>
            
            <p>Messrs. Paine &amp; Burgess are rendering good service to the
               cause of Letters in America by this series of translations
               from the Italian. The neatness of the mechanical execution deserves also high praise — although a little more margin might be desired.
            </p>
            
            <p>Neither “ The Florentine Histories ” nor Niccolo Machiavelli, need be commended by us. The author of “ The
               Prince ” was a man of profound thought, of great sagacity,
               of indomitable will, and unrivalled during his time if not in
               knowledge of the human, at least in knowledge of the Italian heart. He has been grossly maligned, not because misunderstood in himself, but in his relations to his age and
               
               countrymen. The “ Florentine Histories ” show his great
               powers—but not in their clearest light.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <p>A Latin Grammar, Comprising all the Rules and Observations necessary to an Accurate Knowledge of the Latin
               Classics. By James Ross, LL.D. With Latin Idioms,
               and a New Prosody, and Other Important Additions and
               Emendations. By N. C. Brooks, A. M., Principal of the
               Latin High School, Baltimore. Philadelphia: Thomas,
               Cowperthwait &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Brooks, one of the very best classical scholars in this
               country, has, in this edition of Ross, effected some important improvements of which we may take occasion to speak
               more fully hereafter:—as also of his
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <p>First Lessons in Latin: a Series of Exercises, Analytical
               and Synthetical, in Latin Syntax: designed as an Introduction to Ross' Latin Grammar, but suited to any other
               Grammar of the Language.
            </p>
            
            <p>This work is also published by Messrs. Thomas, Cowperthwait &amp; Co., of Philadelphia. </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <p>The History of The Volunteers of 1782. By Thomas Mc
               Nevin, Esq. New-York: R. Marlin &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>A pamphlet of about 120 pages duodecimo—full of interest
               to Americans as well as Irishmen.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <p>The Treasury of History. New-York: Daniel Adee.</p>
            
            <p>We have repeatedly called attention to this valuable work
               of Maunder. It will be completed in twelve numbers. No.
               VIII. is issued.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <p>Blackwood's Magazine,
               For August, has been republished by Messrs. Leonard Scott
               &amp; Co. in their usual prompt and accurate manner. The
               most interesting papers (at least to us) are No. 8 of “North’s
               Specimens of the British Critics,” and “A Letter from London by a Railway Witness.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <p>Godey's Lady's Book,
               For September, opens with a very fair engraving by Welch
               from one of the finest paintings ever done by Sully. It appears in the Magazine as a fancy piece — but the heads are
               those of his two beautiful and accomplished daughters. How
               much is lost in the absence of the artist’s inimitable color!
            </p>
            
            <p>Among the contributions we notice “ The Cheap Dress,”
               a very well narrated tale by Mrs. Annan. Mr. Simms has a
               Mesmeric Sketch, rather overstrained. Mrs. Hale and F.E.F.
               contribute to the number, which ends with a wood engraving from a sketch drawn by C.R. Leslie in the album of
               John Howard Payne. Mr. Godey maintains and will maintain his ground.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <p>The Edinburgh Review. No. CLXV. For July 1845.
               American Edition—Vol. XXIII, No. 1. New York: Leonard, Scott &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>The most interesting papers in this number are “ The Vestiges of Creation,” “ The Oregon Question,” and Mrs. Norton’s “ Child of the Islands.” “ The Vestiges of Creation”
               is slashingly condemned. The reviewer says:
            </p>
            
            <p>Everything is touched upon [what is the meaning of “ touched upon!" ] while nothing is firmly grasped. We have not the strong
               master-hand of an independent laborer, either in the field or closet,
               shown for a single instant. All in the book is shallow; and all is at
               second hand. The surface may be beautiful; but it is the glitter of
               gold-leaf without the solidity of the precious metal. The style is
               agreeable—sometimes charming; and noble sentiments are scattered
               here and there—but these harmonies are never lasting. Sober truth
               
               and solemn nonsense, strangely blended, and offered to us in a new
               material jargon, break discordantly on our ears, and hurt our better
               feelings.
            </p>
            
            <p>These opinions are just. The “ Vestiges” is merely a
               well-written and very suggestive romance;—but bad English
               does not look well in a Quarterly, and “hurts our better feelings.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <p>An Encyclopdia of Domestic Economy, comprising such
               subjects as are most immediately connected with Housekeeping, etc., etc. Illustrated with nearly 1000 engravings. To be completed in 12 numbers. New York: Harper and Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>Nos. IX &amp; X are issued. It is an invaluable work of reference.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <p>Cosmos: A Survey of the General Physical History of The
               Universe. By Alexander Von Humboldt. New York.
               Harper and Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Mess. Harper have issued the First Part of this
               renowned book, with the fame of which the whole literary
               world of Europe is now ringing. We shall speak of it, in
               detail, as it proceeds. Our readers will need no suggestion
               to procure the Parts as they come from the press. The price
               of each is one shilling.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22">
            <p>Graham's Magazine,
               For September, opens with decidedly the finest steel engraving ever published in this country — at least in a Magazine.
               It is the work of Smillie and Hinshelwood—subject, a lake
               and forest scene. There is also a really praiseworthy plate
               of fashions — well designed, well drawn, well colored, and
               we dare say as authentic as need be. It is French. The literary contents are nearly all good — although we are surprised to find a very indifferent poem by Mr. Longfellow.
               Mrs. Annan has here also the best tale of the number, “ The
               New Neighbourhood.” Fanny Forrester, Mrs. Butler, Mrs.
               Stephens, and Park Benjamin, are among the contributors.
               The Foreign Correspondence (literary) is very interesting—
               one of the best features of the Magazine.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <p>Arthur's Magazine,
               For September, was received at so late a day, that we are
               unable to do it justice this week. We shall recur to it. It
               looks well.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="head">The Fine Arts.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <p>Sale of Pictures at Bordentown.—We mentioned, a
               week or two since, that the remaining portion of Joseph
               Bonaparte’s collection of pictures was to be disposed of at
               public sale, at Bordentown, on the 17th and 19th of September, 1845. The gallery will be open for examination every
               day until the day of sale. For the information of those who
               intend to be present at the sale, but who may not be able to
               procure a catalogue previous to going on, we subjoin the
               Terms of Sale:
            </p>
            
            <p>1st. The sale will commence at 11 o’clock on each day,
               and proceed in regular order, according to the catalogue.
            </p>
            
            <p>2d. The purchasers to give their names and places of
               abode, and (if required by the auctioneer) to deposit part of
               the purchase money; in default of which, the lot so purchased to be immediately put up again and re-sold.
            </p>
            
            <p>3d. All bills to be settled in full within three days from
               the day of sale, (before delivery of the paintings,) otherwise
               they may be re-sold at the expense of the purchaser.
            </p>
            
            <p>The pictures will be sold by Thomas Birch, Jr., who, be
               
               ing himself a painter of merit, will, undoubtedly, do full
               justice to the beauty and the character of the works entrusted to his care.
            </p>
            
            <p>On looking through the catalogue we find the names of
               many eminent masters. Rubens has four pictures; subject,
               figures and animals—and a fifth, in which the figures are by
               Rubens, and the fruit and flowers by Sneyders. Rembrandt
               has two pictures; subject, Turkish heads. A. Carracchi has
               one; subject, Christ and his Disciples at Sea. Gaspar Poussin has one; a rich Landscape. Guercino has one; subject,
               Herod receiving the head of John the Baptist on a charger.
               The design embraces a group of ten figures. Canaletti has
               one; subject, view of London Bridge. Sneyders has several; subject generally, Birds, with Landscape, &amp;c. There
               are also many pictures by David Teniers, Berghem, Van
               Eyck, Ruysdael, Terburgh, Adriensen, Swebach, Vanderlinck, Bloemart, &amp;c. The Vernets have also many beautiful
               Landscapes and Marine views. Lebrun, Philip de Champagne, St. Denis, Laurent de la Hyre, &amp;c., are well represented. There are besides very many pictures in the various
               schools — the Italian, Dutch, Flemish, and French, ancient
               and modern.
            </p>
            
            <p>We had almost forgotten to state that there are many interesting pieces of sculpture, executed chiefly by Canova,
               Bartolini, and Rosio—marble busts of Napoleon’s sisters,
               Pauline and Eliza—his father, Charles Bonaparte, and his
               wife Maria Louisa — two splendid Medici Vases of Porphyry, three feet in height — one of them presented to Joseph
               Bonaparte by the King of Sweden—also some antique Bronze
               Castings from Pompeii, with other interesting items which
               we have not, at present, space to enumerate.
            </p>
            
            <p>From what we have said, it will be found that this collection is worthy the attention of connoiseurs in art, for
               though we do not claim for them the position of first class
               pictures, yet can we safely assert their general, and, in some
               cases, remarkable excellence. We shall probably refer to
               this collection previously to the day of sale.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p25">
            <p>One Thousand Pounds are hereby offered to the Artist who shall
               produce the best Oil Painting of the Baptism of Christ by immersion in the River Jordan, to illustrate the accounts of the Evangelists:—Matthew, 3d chapter, 13th to 17th verses; Mark, 1st chapter,
               9th to 11th verses; Luke, 3d chapter, 21st to 23d verses; and the following lines from the first book of Milton’s “ Paradise Regained.”
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>-------------------------------“ I saw
               
               <br></br>The prophet do him reverence, on him rising
               
               <br></br>Out of the voter, heaven above the clouds
               
               <br></br>Unfold her crystal doors," &amp;c.
            </div>
            
            <p>Lines 79 to 85; again, line 288:—</p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>—" As 1 rose out of the laving stream."
            </div>
            
            <p>It is required that the size of the work shall not be less than 12 feet
               by 10, nor greater than 10 feet by 12; that the two principal figures
               shall be at least as large as life; that the time shall be immediately
               before the immersion, while John is uttering the words of administration, or immediately after it, while John and Christ are standing in
               the water to the depth of about two-fifths of their height.
            </p>
            
            <p>Two years, from this date, will be allowed for the completion and
               sending in of the pictures. They must be forwarded—in frames not
               exceeding two inches in width—to a place in London hereafter to be
               advertised. The whole of the works will be publicly exhibited in the
               Metropolis, for a period of time, not exceeding two months, during
               which the competing Artists (being so far their own judges) shall by
               successive eliminations reduce the number of the paintings to five,
               out of which we will select the one to which the prize shall be awarded.
            </p>
            
            <p>With the view of obtaining suitable accommodation for the exhibition, it is requested that the names and addresses of all Artists intending to compete, together, if possible, with the size of their pictures,
               may be sent to either of our addresses by the 1st of January, 1846,
               when the precise mode of elimination will be advertised and the money
               funded for this specific object, in the names of three respectable
               individuals in London, whose names will be published: and, in the
               
               meantime, references will be given, if required, both in London and
               Edinburgh.
            </p>
            
            <p>The competition is open to Artists of all Nations.</p>
            
            <p>The ₤1000 will be paid to the successful competitor before the
               close of the exhibition; the picture and copyright to become our property.
            </p>
            
            <p>The utmost care will be taken of the paintings; but we cannot hold
               ourselves responsible in any case of injury or accident; nor can we
               defray any of the expenses of their conveyance or removal.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">THOMAS BELL,
               
               <br></br>Don Alkali Works, South Shields.
               
               <br></br>CHARLES HILL ROE,
               
               <br></br>Hermitage, Ashton Road, Birmingham.
               
               <br></br>April 3, 1845.
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p26">
         <div class="head">The City in the Sea.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Lo! Death has reared himself a throne
            
            <br></br>In a strange city lying alone
            
            <br></br>Far down within the dim West,
            
            <br></br>Where the good and the bad and the worst and the best 
            
            <br></br>Have gone to their eternal rest.
            
            <br></br>There shrines and palaces and towers
            
            <br></br>(Time-eaten towers that tremble not!)
            
            <br></br>Resemble nothing that is ours.
            
            <br></br>Around, by lifting winds forgot,
            
            <br></br>Resignedly beneath the sky
            
            <br></br>The melancholy waters lie.
            
            <br></br>No rays from the holy heaven come down
            
            <br></br>On the long night-time of that town;
            
            <br></br>But light from out the lurid sea
            
            <br></br>Streams up the turrets silently—
            
            <br></br>Gleams up the pinnacles far and free—
            
            <br></br>Up domes—up spires—up kingly halls—
            
            <br></br>Up fanes—up Babylon-like walls—
            
            <br></br>Up shadowy long-forgotten bowers
            
            <br></br>Of sculptured ivy and stone flowers—
            
            <br></br>Up many and many a marvelous shrine
            
            <br></br>Whose wreathed friezes intertwine
            
            <br></br>The viol, the violet, and the vine.
            
            <br></br>Resignedly beneath the sky
            
            <br></br>The melancholy waters lie.
            
            <br></br>So blend the turrets and shadows there
            
            <br></br>That all seem pendulous in air,
            
            <br></br>While from a proud tower in the town
            
            <br></br>Death looks gigantically down.
            
            <br></br>There open fanes and gaping graves
            
            <br></br>Yawn level with the luminous waves;
            
            <br></br>But not the riches there that lie
            
            <br></br>In each idol’s diamond eye—
            
            <br></br>Not the gaily-jewelled dead
            
            <br></br>Tempt the waters from their bed;
            
            <br></br>For no ripples curl, alas!
            
            <br></br>Along that wilderness of glass—
            
            <br></br>No swellings tell that winds may be
            
            <br></br>Upon some far-off happier sea—
            
            <br></br>No heavings hint that winds have been
            
            <br></br>On seas less hideously serene.
            
            <br></br>But lo, a stir is in the air!
            
            <br></br>The wave—there is a movement there!
            
            <br></br>As if the towers had thrust aside.
            
            <br></br>In slightly sinking, the dull tide—
            
            <br></br>As if their tops had feebly given
            
            <br></br>A void within the filmy Heaven.
            
            <br></br>The waves have now a redder glow—
            
            <br></br>The Hours are breathing faint and low—
            
            <br></br>And when, amid no earthly moans,
            
            <br></br>Down, down that town shall settle hence,
            
            <br></br>Hell, rising from a thousand thrones,
            
            <br></br>Shall do it reverence.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p27">
         <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
         
         <p>Mr. Sheppard, a Bass singer of considerable merit, as we
            have been told, who appeared at the Park Theatre four or
            five years since, has arrived in this city, and purposes giving
            a concert in the early part of the ensuing month. He has
            numerous warm and influential friends in New York, and will
            doubtless have a crowded room.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Frederick Horncastle has arrived at Boston, from London, and intends giving his highly popular entertainments
            founded on English character and Irish music.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Misses Bramson are giving concerts at New Haven.</p>
         
         <p>The French Opera Company opened at Niblo’s on Monday evening. We understand that they have met with remarkable success, but we have been unable to attend.</p>
         
         <p>Signor Antognini is in Canada, and is engaged to get up
            two grand musical entertainments for parties there. He has
            sent to New York lor Vocal and Instrumental music to be presented on each occasion.
         </p>
         
         <p>Signor Pico and Lycion De Begnis open the Royal Olympic Theatre at Montreal early in September.</p>
         
         <p>The little Misses Kilmiste, better known as the Infant
            Sisters, gave two concerts, or rather entertainments, at Palmo’s Theatre this week. The following announcement will
            be found curious and amusing.
         </p>
         
         <p>For Two Nights Only.—Fashionable and elegant performances of
            the little Misses Kilmiste, known as the Infant Sisters. Tuesday evening, Aug. 26th, will be performed the admired Burletta, called Disappointment. Principal characters by the Infant Sisters. Mr. Hyde,
            of London, will perform Overtures, Operatic Airs, and Brilliant Variations, upon a Penny Whistle. The whole concluding wixh the admired Burletta, called Papa Jerome, or Les Petites Amantes.
         </p>
         
         <p>A letter has been received in New Orleans from Mexico,
            dated July 22, giving an account of the reception of Mad.
            Borghese and other members of the Italian company, late of
            this city. It was enthusiastic in the extreme. They were
            in the finest health. The engagement will conclude about
            the last of November or the beginning of the following
            month, and then the company will return to New Orleans.
         </p>
         
         <p>A new song, rather popular, commences with the words,
            “Ha! ha! laughed the ivy!’’
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss Delcy and the rest of the English opera company
            will begin their engagement at the Park shortly. Mr. Raplino will direct the operas.
         </p>
         
         <p>We shall attend to the Musical Publications of Mess. E.
            Ferrett &amp; Co. very particularly in our next. We acknowedge the receipt of Strauss’ Waltzes—Beauties of La Norma
            —and Airs from The Bohemian Girl. Mess. Ferrett &amp; Co.
            publish this music at a wonderfully low price.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p28">
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>Under this head there is but little to observe. In NewYork, during the last fortnight, the theatres, without exception, have been unusually well attended. At the Park the
            present company is by no means strong. Mrs. Mowatt concluded a short engagement on the 23d; playing Pauline,
            Gertrude, in her own “ Fashion” and other róles. Her audiences were large and highly respectable. The enthusiasm
            
            was unabated. She is evidently improving, and that rapidly.
            We have no hesitation in prophesying for her a brilliant fu ture—if she be but true to herself. Her worst mannerism is
            an audible drawing in of the breath. Her action is uneqaulled in spirit and grace. Some of the intonations of her voice,
            are rich beyond expression, and have an obvious effect upon the finer spirits of an audience. Her elocution is of a noble order. She is much better supported than formerly by
            Mr. Crisp. He also, has improved. We noticed this, especially, in the greater dignity which he gives Melnotte while
            personating the Prince. It was his fashion, once, to play the
            part, at this point, as if a brainless coxcomb were the author’s
            intention. Mr. Bass is a great acquisition to any theatre,
            and we are surprised to see the coolness with which so truly
            admirable an actor has been received. His Damas was
            Nature herself. The part could not have been more truthfully done. Miss Fanny Gordon is a fifth or sixth rate performer, with whom we were not particularly pleased.
         </p>
         
         <p>On Monday last, Mr. Hackett made his bow to a Park audience as Falstaff. Of course he was warmly received.
            The boxes were thoroughly filled, and with a judicious audience.
         </p>
         
         <p>In looking over the play-bills of the Park for the coming
            season, we were surprised not to find the name of Mr. Murdoch. For several months it had been understood, through
            the city, that he was to perform here at a very early period.
            We now learn that he will not appear till towards the close
            of October—on account of Mr. Simpson's foreign engagements. Mr. Murdoch is an American, has noble views of his
            art, and has labored diligently in its acquisition. He has
            omitted nothing in the way of self-discipline, and will inevitably rank high.
         </p>
         
         <p>At the Bowery Mr. J. M. Scott has been playing his usual
            characters with success. This theatre has great capabilities
            which it is a pity were not improved. The stage appointments want richness, but we presume it is the intention to
            remedy this evil in the end. Much of the forest scenery is
            ill conceived. Light is undoubtedly wanting, on the audience, and color in the pannelings of the boxes, as well as the
            ceiling. The general coup d'œil of the theatre cannot be
            compared for an instant with that of the Park, yet its capabilities, we say, are greater. A trifling outlay would render it
            the handsomer theatre.
         </p>
         
         <p>At Niblo's the audiences have been, as usual, large and
            respectable. In the performances no particular variation.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Chatham Street has been doing very well with Mazeppa.</p>
         
         <p>Mr. Burton of the Walnut Street Theatre offers a premium of One Thousand Dollars for the best original American
            Comedy.
         </p>
         
         <p>Signora Suarez, one of the stars of the Teatro de Tacon,
            Havana, took a benefit on the 4th inst.
         </p>
         
         <p>S’ra Corcuera, another star, was to have hers on the 11th.</p>
         
         <p>Mr. Arrilla, director of the Equestrian company which arrived from France at Matanzas on the 30th July, died on the
            5th of August, of the yellow fever.
         </p>
         
         <p>The dramatic company of Senors Robunos gave a great
            representation in Puerto Principe, for the benefit of the sufferers by the last great fire in Matanzas.
         </p>
         
         <p>J. M. Scott, has the agency of the western theatrical circuit, which comprises some thirty or forty theatres. It is
            said that he will take about two hundred actors and actresses with him.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p29">
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>
         
         <p>Carey &amp; Hart will publish in October “ Literature and
            Art in America, with an Introductory Plea for Copyright,
            Universal and Perpetual: by Rufus W. Griswold ”—in one
            volume octavo.
         </p>
         
         <p>The first complete American edition of the Poems of
            James Montgomery, the chief of the religious poets of the
            nineteenth century, will be published in a few days by Louis
            &amp; Ball, of Philadelphia, in two volumes, demi octavo, with
            fine illustrations on steel.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Kennedy, author of “Horse-shoe Robinson,” &amp;c., has
            in preparation the Life of William Wirt; and the Poet Dana
            is advancing rapidly in his Memoirs of the Life and Works
            of Washington Allston.
         </p>
         
         <p>Longfellow and Bryant will soon have out illustrated edi-
            tions of their respective poems.
         </p>
         
         <p>It is remarkable that the sturdy republican and puritan
            Milton—the most American of all writers, in his theories
            and feelings—has never yet found a publisher in this country. We are glad to learn that H. Hooker, of Philadelphia,
            will in a few days issue, in two large and elegantly printed
            octavos, his Complete Prose Writings, with an Introduction
            by Rev. Dr. Griswold.
         </p>
         
         <p>A Professorship of English Literature and Belles Lettres
            has been established in the University of Vermont, and the
            Rev. Wm. Shedd, of Brandon, Vt., an Alumnus of the institution, has been chosen to fill it.
         </p>
         
         <p>We forgot to say, last week, that the “ Schnell Post,"
            published in New-York, has, by a ministerial edict, been
            forbidden to be taken at the Cabinets de Lecture, of Leipsic.
            The exact reason of the prohibition does not yet appear.
         </p>
         
         <p>Messrs. F. W. Thomas (author of “ Clinton Bradshaw”)
            and Judge A. B. Meek, of Tuscaloosa, Ala., (now at Washington,) are about to establish a Monthly Magazine. We
            know both parties as men of talent.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Kendall is proceeding with his Life of Jackson.</p>
         
         <p>Our friend of “ The Germantown Telegraph ” (a very
            excellent paper) asks us, with much pertinence, why we call
            our sheet “ The Broadway Journal ” when it is published in
            Nassau street. Be it known, that we originated in Broadway — were merely seduced by circumstances into Nassau
            street pro tem. Our destiny however is Broadway. It is
            Broadway to which we speak. We shall get back to Broadway at our earliest convenience.
         </p>
         
         <p>Talking of titles; — while the very respectable “Telegraph ” demurs to our “ Broadway ” moiety, two or three
            Prints not quite so respectable (at least in common sense) ob-,
            ject to the “Journal ” half. “ A journal,” say they, “is a
            daily, and nothing else.” The word "journal," to be sure,
            from the French journie, was a term originally applied to a
            daily record of events, and was precisely equivalent to “ diary ”—but in common with a multitude of words its primitive meaning gradually amplified itself, until it vanished altogether. A journal now is merely a record, generally speaking and for the primitive meaning we fall back upon “diary. 
            
            The argumentum ad absurdum will soon reduce our inquisi-
            tors to reason. If primitive meanings are to be adhered to,
            we might maintain that Mr. T-----is no sycophant merely
            because he is not in the habit of discovering figs.
         </p>
         
         <p>Some time ago we published, as the composition of William Gilmore Simms, a little poem called “ The Whippoorwill.” It belongs to Dr. Bird, of “ Calavar” memory.</p>
         
         <p>The Misses Sedgwick (nieces of the authoress) have established a school at 42 West Washington Place. Their accomplishments are well known, and of their capacity for the
            task assumed, no one acquainted with them can entertain a
            doubt. The Mirror says justly:
         </p>
         
         <p>The name of Sedgwick alone is a recommendation for a school: it
            is associated with candor, benevolence, and knowledge of the physical
            and moral laws, and we believe it is rarely in vain that one of a name
            should show such excellence; it kindles aspiration and imparts life to
            others who bear it.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Here the journeymen,” says the last number of Graham's Magazine, “ place two scales upon one another at
            right angles, thus X.” The sentence is a fine exemplification of the expediency of “ letting well alone.” It would
            have been wiser to stop at the “ right angles.”
         </p>
         
         <p>An exchange paper says:—</p>
         
         <p>“ In the United States Gazette of Friday last, we find, credited to
            the London World of Fashion for July, a story entitled ‘ Mary, or the
            Blighted Blossom.' It looked to us at once like an old acquaintance;
            and on turning to our files we found that on the 19th of February last
            was published in this paper, credited to the Buffalo Daily Gazette, a
            narrative headed ‘ Mary, or the Triumph of the Heart over Itself,’
            which is word for word, so far as we continued the examination, the
            same as the ‘ Mary’ first noticed, and which we have a dim recollection of having at the time copied from the U. S. Gazette. This is only
            one instance among many in which British periodicals have appropriated to themselves, without acknowledgement, the productions of
            American minds.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Very true:—and, what is more, it is astonishing to see
            how a Magazine article, like a traveller, spruces up after
            crossing the sea. We ourselves have had the honor of being
            pirated without mercy—but as we found our articles improved by the process (at least in the opinion of our countrymen)
            we said nothing, as a matter of course. We have written
            paper after paper which attracted no notice at all until it appeared as original in “ Bentley’s Miscellany” or the “ Paris
            Charivari.” The “ Boston Notion” once abused us very lustily for having written “ The House of Usher.” Not long
            afterwards Bentley published it anonymously, as original
            with itself,—whereupon “ The Notion,” having forgotten
            that we wrote it, not only lauded it ad nauseam, but copied
            it in toto.
         </p>
         
         <p>Robert Dale Owen, in a late letter to “ The Tribune,”
            fully exculpates himself from the charge of having plagiarzed a song, bodily. He says:
         </p>
         
         <p>I published in the year 1887, a historical drama, entitled “ Pocahontas,” indulgently noticed by the press at the lime, and in that drama,
            introduced the Song in question (at page 76.) To this drama notes
            were appended, and the note to page 74 read as follows;
         </p>
         
         <p>’ Tis home where'er the heart is, &amp;c.</p>
         
         <p>"	This Song is altered from some fugitive ballad that pleased me at
            the time that I read it, and has remained in my memory; though I
            have forgotten or never knew, the author’s name.”
         </p>
         
         <p>I need hardly add, that the lines appeared in the ' Chaplet of
            Mercy,’ as mine, equally without my consent or knowledge; sent
            thither, doubtless, by some friend who may have seen the Song in the
            little work in question, and had overlooked the disclaiming note.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>To those wishing a neat wedding, visiting, or business
            Card, we recommend Valentine's Card Engraving and Printing establishment, No. 1 Beekman street. His work is neatly, and even beautifully executed, and his charges are moderate.
         </p>
         
         <p>Strangers visiting New York will find at Johnson's (formerly Holt’s) Hotel—(the Pearl Street House)—as fine accommodations as at any in the city. The arrangements,
            throughout, are excellent—and we really can call to mind no
            similar establishment where as much true comfort is to be
            obtaided in conjunction with so much of respectability and
            economy. Mr. Johnson, the host, is one of the most gentlemanly men in the world.
         </p>
         
         <p>Messrs. Burges &amp; James, of Charleston, S. C., have in
            press the writings of Hugh Swinton Legaré,” to be prefaced
            by a sketch of his life. There will also be a portrait. The
            work will be in two volumes, containing Selections from
            Mr. L’s Contributions to the Southern and to the New York
            Review; Detached portions of his Diplomatic Correspondence; A Journal of the Rhine; Orations and other Miscellaneous Matter—together with Private Letters. The same
            publishers propose also to issue “ A Selection of Miscellanies
            in Criticism and Literature, by William Gilmore Simms”—
            in three handsome volumes duodecimo.
         </p>
         
         <p>“ Frederica Bremer,” says a late Liverpool Albion, “ will
            shortly pass through Liverpool, en route for the United
            States.”
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Mathews’ “Big Abel and Little Manhattan” will
            appear in September, as one of Wiley &amp; Putnam’s “ Library
            of American Books.”
         </p>
         
         <p>A very pretty poem, which (unfortunately for us) we did
            not write, appears in Wednesday’s “ Tribune” with the initials E. A. P. appended.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Baron Von Raumer has published his long promised
            work on the United States. An English translation will immediately appear.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. John Britton, the eminent antiquarian and topographer, has produced sixty-six volumes, containing 1866 engravings of noted accuracy, and costing in the outlay $50,000.
            A subscription has been opened for a memorial to be presented to the venerable topographer, and £300 have been collected.
         </p>
         
         <p>The commencement of Brown University is to be held on
            the first Wednesday of September. The oration before the
            Society of Undergraduates will be delivered by Rev. Mr.
            Lambert, of New Bedford, Mass., and a poem by R. S. S.
            Andros. Dr. Hawes, of Hartford, Ct., will deliver an address
            before the Society for Missionary Inquiry, and on the afternoon of Commencement day, an oration before the Phi Beta
            Kappa Society will be pronounced by Rev. William R. Williams, D. D., of New York city.
         </p>
         
         <p>We thank the New-York Correspondent of the “ Cincinnati Gazette,” for the gentlemanly tone of his reply to some
            late pettish comments of our own. We saw only a portion
            of one of his letters. Had we seen more, we should at once,
            through the precison and purity of his style, have recognised
            a friend.
         </p>
         
         <p>Hon. Edward Everett and family have taken passage in
            the Liverpool steamer for Boston of September 4th.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Mr. Henry Erben, who is building an organ for Trinity
            Church, says that thirty men can get inside one of the
            pipes.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Jocelyn is said to have completed a fine portrait of
            Gov. Baldwin, of Connecticut.
         </p>
         
         <p>Liberal Bequest.—The late Captain Joseph H. Dwight
            of Oxford, N. Y., bequeathed nearly all his estate to the Roman Catholic Church, for a new College. The bequest is
            supposed to be worth $15,000 or $20,000.
         </p>
         
         <p>To Correspondents—We are somewhat at a loss to comprehend A.
            M. J. of Attleboro’. To uhat previous poems does he allude? We thank
            him cordially for his last favor. It shall appear forthwith. The rhythmical information desired is unattainable in book form. See meanwhile one
            of the three numbers (we believe the third) of “ The Pioneer” published
            at Boston by Mr. Lowell.
         </p>
         
         <p>The length of “ Blanche,” excludes it for the present.</p>
         
         <p>“ Sleep” is on file.</p>
         
         <p>To D.N. of Utica—The address desired, is Boston, Mass.</p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div>
            <div class="head">WEDDING, VISITING, and PROFESSIONAL
               CARDS,
            </div>
            <div class="ab">engraved and printed at VALENTINE’S, 1 Beekman
               
               <br></br>Street—Lovejoy’s Hotel.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">TO TAILORS.</div>
            
            <p>SCOTT’S AMERICAN FASHIONS. Just published and for sale at 146 Broadway.</p>
            
            <p>The present Report for fall and winter, 1845-6, is moTe valuable to
               the Tailor, than was the one of last year, for which we were awarded
               a Diploma by the American Institute.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Terms.—Report of Fashion with Pattern-sheet and pamphlet, $1,50
               
               <br></br>         Do.    European,	            do.	         do.     1,00
               
               <br></br>         Mirror of Fashion—a monthly paper—per annum,      1,00
               
               <br></br>         Scott’s Tractate, a new work on Cutting Garments,   2,00
               
               <br></br>         Do.    Treatise on Cutting, 47 engravings—morocco
               
               <br></br>         bound,	                                          10,00
            </div>
            
            <p>The above works may be sent by mail to any place in the Union,
               for a few cents each.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MARTIN’S ILLUSTRATED FAMILY BIBLE.</div>
            
            <p>Part 8, of this truly magnificent work will be published on the
               1st of Sept. Price 25 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>I have examined, with considerable care, the "Devotional Family
               Bible,” now in course of publication by R. Marlin &amp; Co., 29 John St.,
               and regard it, in point of mechanical execution, among the most beautiful specimens of book making that I have ever seen. It possesses,
               at the same time, other and higher merits—a concise and instructive
               argument, prefixed to the several books, a lucid table of contents at the
               head of each chapter, a chronological index, a column of various readings, copious marginal references, and at the bottom of every page,
               comprehensive, judicious, and pious practical observations, by the
               Rev. Alex. Fletcher. In the midst of all, the text is left unembarrassed and clear. It will be one of the most beautiful, instructive, and
               valuable Family Bibles, any where to be found in the English language.
            </p>
            <div class="ab">	JOHN KNOX, D. D.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MEDICI SERIES OF ITALIAN PROSE.</div>
            
            <p>PAINE AND BURGESS, 62 JOHN ST., HAVE
               just published, Nos 2 and 3 of the Medici Series of ltalian Prose.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Florentine Histories. By Nicolo Machiavelli. In 2 vols.
               Translated by C. Edwards Lester, Esq. Price 60 cents per vol. pa
               per, 75 cents cloth.	
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">OPINION of JARED SPARKS, ESQ.</div>
            
            <p>“ With the Florentine Histories, I am well acquainted. Formed on
               the classical models of antiquity, it is executed with consummate skill,
               few historical compositions are so successful in attaining the two great
               ends of entertainment and instruction. The style is spirited, clear
               and vigorous, the narrative rapid and condensed, the reflections of the
               author, though brief and sententious, are always appropriate and often
               profound.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is probably no work within the same compass in which the
               instructive lessons of History can he studied with more profit and effect.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>The Subscribers, while returning thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at
               the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and
               seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood and mahogany cases.
            </p>
            
            <p>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
               the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
               to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
               upon examination, equal to any in the market.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway.
               
               <br></br>Manufactory, 13th st , between 3d and 4th Avenues.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
            
            <p>WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANOFORTE, ORGAN, &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street,
               where his terms for giving instruction can be ascertained. my17
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER.</div>
            <p>—JAMES
               PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near Elm. A
               Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms moderate. FOR SALE—A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a
               great bargain for cash.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <div class="ab">—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
               
               <br></br>Street, N. Y.
            </div>
            
            <p>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
               Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made
               from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful
               workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the busines
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ.</p>
            
            <p>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
               Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to
               the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establishment, corner of Cottage Place and Bleecker street, which he will sell
               at prices unusually low.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business for the last twenty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two
               of the largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that
               his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the
               best makers in this country or Europe, and that they contain all the
               real improvements of the day.
            </p>
            
            <p>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
               Repaired.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, April 23d, 1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            <p>—THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
               (formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway,
               will keep a complete assortment of the latest approved Grand Action
               Piano Fortes, or the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
               guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish,
               and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard
               prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on
               hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE BŒHM FLUTE.</div>
            
            <p>PHILIP ERNST, Teacher of the Flute and Guitar, would inform the lovers of Music that he has now for sale
               several of the above celebrated instruments, constructed in every respect in accordance with those now in use at the Paris and London
               Royal Academies. To be seen at PHILIP ERNST’S Music Saloon,
               395 Broadway, near Walker.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">MUSIC.</div>
            
            <p>A Rare Opportunity of Acquiring a Thorough Musical Education.</p>
            
            <p>G H. DERWORT, Professor of Singing, Guitar and
               Piano Forte, has opened a class for Young Ladies, from 7 to 10
               years of age, among whom are three of his own daughters, whom he
               proposes to thoroughly instruct in the art of Singing.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Derwort’s system is the result of many years’ observation and
               experience, during which he has successfully taught in Germany, London, and New York. His method cannot fail to impart to his pupils
               a clear perception, and a thorough knowledge of the grammatical
               principles of music, with the ability to harmonize any simple given
               melody.
            </p>
            
            <p>Parents and Guardians are invited to call at his Rooms, 427 Broadway, when every inquiry will bo answered.</p>
            
            <p>Terms $20 per annum, payable quarterly in advance. Lessons
               three times a week.
            </p>
            
            <p>Private instruction as heretofore.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THIS DAY IS PUBLISHED,</div>
            
            <p>VERSE AND PROSE, by Thomas Hood—Part I,
               forming No. 16 of the Library or Choice Reading, beautifully
               printed. Price 50 cents.
            </p>	
            
            <p>"Of all the humorists, Hood was the most poetical. When dealing with the most familiar subjects, whether it might be a sweep bewailing the suppression of his cry, or a mother searching through St.
               Giles’s for her lost infant, or a Miss Kilmansegg’s golden childhood—
               there was hardly a verse in which some touches of heart , or some play
               of fancy, did not beckon the laughing reader away into far other
               Worlds than the jester’s.”—London Athenӕum.
            </p>
            
            <p>" The smile and the sigh were ever blended together; the laugh at
               the grotesque idea and whimsical imagination, (rarely seeing objects
               as others saw them,) and the tear which must flow on such pathetic
               Narratives as Eugene Aram or the Old Elm Tree. Without a parallel
               and original as Hood was in the ludicrous, his more enduring fame
               will rest on the exquisitely humane and simply compassionate.”—Literary Gazette.	,
            </p>
            
            <p>” He was the inventer of a new sort of guano to fertilize men's
               minds, and to make them produce larger crops of good actions: or rather it was an intellectual compost that he invented, and the materials
               of which were satire softened by kindness, and ridicule tempered with
               good feeling.”—Hood's Magazine for June. Published and for sale
               by	WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">HARPER &amp; BROTHERS' LAST PUBLICATIONS.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">I.
               
               <br></br>HARPER’S ILLUMINATED BIBLE. No. 34.
               
               <br></br>Price Twenty-Five Cents,
            </div>
            
            <p>Comprising portions of the minor prophets to the 9th chapter of Amos.
               The embellishments to this number include some of unsurpassed beauty.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">II.
               
               <br></br>HARPER’S ILLUMINATED SHAKSPEARE,
               
               <br></br>Nos. 61 and 62. Price Twenty-Five Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes “ Measure for Measure” and the commencement of the “ Tempest”—with the eqquisite designs after Kenny Meadows, Weir, and others. It should be recollected that this edition of
               Shakspeare combines the best features of the two best London editions, by Charles Knight and Tyas—rendering it the most perfect ever
               presented to the public.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">III.
               
               <br></br>TRAVELS OF MARCO POLO,
            </div>
            
            <p>Newly collected from valuable MSS. in the Geographical Societies of
               France and Italy, with copious notes and illustrations by Hugh Murray, with Maps, &amp;c. 16mo. muslin. Price 50 Cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>This well-known production, which forms No. 173 of “ The Family
               Library,” has long been regarded as unique in geographical science.
               Marco Polo has justly been styled the “ Herodotus of the Middle
               Ages.” and the discoverer of the Asiatic continent; his explorations
               in the Chinese empire alone have never been exceeded, even to the
               present day.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IV.
               
               <br></br>THE SEERESS OF PREVORST. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ A work replete with startling new facts on Mesmerism: the most
               remarkable on the subject we have yet seen.”—Post.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">V.
               
               <br></br>JOHN RONGE AND THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES.
               
               <br></br>Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ A subject of the most absorbing interest throughout the whole
               whole European Continent.”
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VI.
               
               <br></br>DR. LEVER’S LATEST WORK-THE NEVILLES OF
               
               <br></br>GARRETSTOWN. Complete, price 12 1-2 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ Equal to the best works of the favourite author of Charles O'Malley ”</p>
            
            <div class="ab">VII.
               
               <br></br>JAMES’S NEW WORK—THE SMUGGLER. 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new production of Mr. James is founded on on some stirring
               incidents of past times on the Southern Coast of England; it is characterised by all the author’s peculiarities of style, the story being intersected by many episodical involutions, which impart to it additional
               interest.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VIII.
               
               <br></br>DE ROHAN. BY EUGENE SUE. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>“ Picturesque, bold, and highly dramatic—equal to any of his previous works.”—Sun.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">IX.
               
               <br></br>PRAISE AND PRINCIPLE—Or, For What shall I Live?
            </div>
            
            <p>By the author of “ Conquest and Self-Conquest,” “ Woman an Enigma,” &amp;c. I8mo. cloth gilt. Price 48 1-2 Cents. A charming volume,
               elegantly written, well sustained in its interest, and rife with excellent
               moral teaching.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">X.
               
               <br></br>CYCLOPEDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY. No. 8. Pr. 26 Cts.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">XI.
               
               <br></br>MISS BREMERs NEW WORK—THE PARSONAGE OF MO-
               
               <br></br>RA, OR LIFE IN DALECARLIA. Price One Shilling.
            </div>
            
            <p>In this new work Frederika Bremer presents many of her pretty and
               picturesque scenes, add introduces many of her high minded and romantic characters, with their spirit stirring colloquies; the story also
               includes interesting sketches of those Northern subterranean worlds—
               the copper mines of Fahlua.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XII.
               
               <br></br>EVELINA, by Miss Burney (since Madame D'Arblay). New
               
               <br></br>edition, 18mo. Price 25 Cents.
            </div>
            
            <p>This renowned production has long been considered as a classic of
               our language. The work appeared anonymously, the disclosure of
               the authorship of which, it will be remembered, led to the deeply interesting scene which ensued between the father and daughter—their
               mingled surprise and delight.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XIII.
               
               <br></br>DR. COPLAND’S MEDICAL DICTIONARY. No. 10. 60 Cts.
            </div>
            
            <p>This new issue includes a series of topics of vital interest to the
               Medical faculty of the country. The design and execution of this popular production, evince the most consummate skill and research; every person who desires a thorough digest of Medical Science, must appreciate its high value.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">XV.
               
               <br></br>PROF. LEWIS’S PLATO ON ATHEISTS. Price $1 5 .
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">J. F. BROWNE &amp; CO.
               MANUFACTURERS OF THE
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION HARP,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years with Erard,
               
               <br></br>J.F. BROWNE respectfully informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has established
               himself for
               
               <br></br>the manufacture and importation of these very beautiful instruments, at
               
               <br></br>281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET.
            </div>
            
            <p>His arrangements are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices,
               thereby saving purchasers the high duties imposed by
               Tariff on these Instruments.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. F. Browne would observe, these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
               with all the modem improvements of London and
               Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy of lone, fineness of touch, and perfectness of
               mechanism. Particular care is taken to fit them for the extremes of climate in this country, in which respect they will be found far superior
               to any of European manufacture, imported in the usual way.
            </p>
            <p>These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and professional talent in
               Europe; among the latter, he would mention N. C Bochsa,
               who invariably selects from this establishment.
            </p>
            
            <p>J. F. Browne begs to offer the opinions of some of the first professional talent in
               this country.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making
               a professional use of your Harps, and of testing
               their qualities, it affords me pleasure to certify, that in point of tone, workmanship,
               and above all, a solidity that stands proof against the inconstancy of our trying climate, they have in all cases given me the most entire satisfaction.
               I am yours, CHARLES THIBAULT,,
               January, 1845.	No. 40 Beach Street, N. Y.
            </p>
            
            <p>Dear Sir:—I write to express the delight I experienced in performing on one of your
               Harps at Sig. Casella’s Concert in this city. The
               mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly superior to any harp I have
               heard for many years. I remember my old Master,
               Bochsa, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no other.	Yours,
               most truly, H. G. TRUST.
               Philadelphia, March 4th, 1844.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make
               I performed on at the St. George’s Society Concert,
               is, in brilliancy of lone, touch and elegance of workmanship, the finest I ever played
               on. This will apply to all your Harps. The Grand six
               and a half Gothic Double action, is a most splendid instrument.	Yours, with respect,
               ELIZABETH SLOMAN. 
               A pupil of N. C. Bochsa.
               New York, January 16th, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir:—Having at your request closely scrutinized your double-action
               Harps. I find they possess the best qualities of the
               first Makers in Europe combined. That the ease of touch, by which the most brilliant
               tone is obtained, the perfection and case of modulation,
               they are superior to any I have used; their elegance of exterior must gratify the
               most refined taste. Your new Grand Gothic six and a half octavo, is the most splendid effort of art yet produced in the musical world; it will
               give me great pleasure in recommending your Harps at every
               opportunity.	Yours Truly, HENRY HORN.
               An eminent professor, and Member of the Royal Academy. 
               January 12th, 1854.
            </p>
            
            <p>These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
               show the estimate of persons every way capable of making a
               correct decision. J. F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the Society
               of Arts, Philadelphia, for his splendid improvements in
               this delightful Instrument.
            </p>
            
            <p>Harps from 300 to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE
               SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
               
               <br></br>Published monthly, at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.
            </div>
            
            <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since
               1835, has a large subscription list, and is the principal organ of
               Southern opinion.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the “ Broad-
               way Journal,” 133 Nassau streeet.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="ab">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.
               
               <br></br>THE FIRST PREMIUM AWARDED FIVE YEARS BY THE AMERICAN INSTI-
               
               <br></br>TUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
               
               <br></br>GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
               
               <br></br>No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            </div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course
               of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Stationery. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M., daily, for gentlemen,
               and from 11 to 1 o’clock, for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems or Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">NEW AND BRILLIANT ORATORIO.</div>
            
            <p>THE BEAUTIFUL AND EFFECTIVE ORATORIO of THE SEVEN SLEEPERS will be performed early
               in September next, at the Tabernacle, under the direction of Mr.
               GEORGE LODER.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Chorusses will he sustained by OVER ONE HUNDRED AND
               TWENTY-FIVE PERFORMERS, selected with particular reference 
               to their Musical Qualifications.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Solo parts (ten in number) will be WELL sustained by RESI
               DENT TALENT.
            </p>
            
            <p>A powerful Orchestra will be engaged for the occasion, and the public may confidently rely upon hearing a GOOD Oratorio WELL
               PERFORMED.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. H. B. TIMM will preside at the Organ.</p>
            
            <p>N.B. Persons leaving their names at the stores of Firth &amp; Hall;
               Firth, Hall, &amp; Pond. 239 Broadway; Atwill; Saxton &amp; Miles; Riley;
               Scharfenburgh &amp; Luis; G. F. Nesbitt, cor. Wall and Water; or with
               H. Meiggs, 446 Broadway, previous to first of September, will receive
               THREE TICKETS FOR ONE DOLLAR, payable on delivery of
               the tickets.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">BERTINl’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
            
            <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work
               yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this method, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
               The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exercises, scales and studies are given in such progressive order, that they
               enlist the interest of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly
               through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often
               made irksome in other instruction books. The time has arrived when
               a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is
               only by the study of such methods as Bertini’s that pupils will be enabled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good
               musicians.
            </p>
            
            <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner; the
               rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and
               each lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.
            </p>
            
            <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations
               from professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of
               Bertini’s Method over all others yet published in this country, most
               of them having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be
               necessary to give a few of the names in the principal cities.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Boston.	
               
               <br></br>Messr. G. J. Webb,	
               
               <br></br>J. G. Maeder,	
               
               <br></br>H. T. Hach,	
               
               <br></br>E. L. White,	
               
               <br></br>David Paine,	
               
               <br></br>A. Kurek,	
               
               <br></br>T. B. Moses.	
               
               <br></br>New-York.
               
               <br></br>Messrs. H. C. Timm,
               
               <br></br>W. Alpers,
               
               <br></br>U. C. Hill,
               
               <br></br>F. H. Brown,
               
               <br></br>Philadelphia.
               
               <br></br>B. C. Cross,
               
               <br></br>Joseph Duggan.
               
               <br></br>Albany—O. J. Shaw.
            </div>
            
            <p>Professors and Teachers arc respectfully invited to examine the
               work. American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H.
               OAKES, 197 Washington street, Boston 
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p30">
         <div class="note" type="headnote">Our First Volume.—A few copies of the first volume of the Broadway
            Journal are for sale at the office, either in numbers or neatly bound.
         </div>
         
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass.
            
            <br></br>R.	G. H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>M. Baullemet, Mobile, Ala.
            
            <br></br>Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O.
            
            <br></br>D. M. Dewey, Rochester, N.Y.
            
            <br></br>J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>W. E. Russell, Schenectady, N. T.
            
            <br></br>Levi Willard, Troy, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>G. Jones, Albany, N.Y.
            
            <br></br>S.	F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore, Md.
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.
            
            <br></br>Thos. H. Pease, New-Haven, Ct.
            
            <br></br>J. C. Morgan, New-Orleans.
            
            <br></br>W. W. Kingsley, New-London, Ct.
            
            <br></br>G. N. Beesley, Utica, N.Y.
            
            <br></br>H. B. Strang, Peekskill, N. Y.
            
            <br></br>Haliburton &amp; Dudley, Boston, Ms.
            
            <br></br>S. Thompson, Worcester, Mass.
            
            <br></br>Peter Cooke, Hartford, Ct.
            
            <br></br>H. Esten, Providence, R. I.
            
            <br></br>Safford &amp; Park, Norwich, Ct.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>