<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            VOL. 1.
            NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JANUARY 18, 1845.
            N° 3.
            
         </p>
         <p>Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the busness of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</p>
         <p>Locke.
            Reviews.
            Conversations on some of the Old Poets. By James Russell
            Lowell. Cambridge • Published by John Owen, 1845.
            
         </p>
         <p>A book is not worth much when its title page conveys a
            clear idea of its contents ; for the title of a book is like a
            man’s name, which only serves to distinguish him from other men, but gives no notion of his character. “Lowell’s
            Conversations” which is emblazoned on the illuminated cover
            of this little volume, is a much better title than the longer
            one. They are conversations, but not exclusively on the
            old Poets, as the title seems to promise; for of the whole
            constellation of Old Poets there are but three whose names
            are used by the author as pegs to hang his thoughts upon.
            Chaucer, Chapman and Ford, form the subjects of the three
            Conversations of which the volume is composed. The largest space is given, as it should be, to Chaucer, as possessing
            the most merit and being the least known. But whoever
            takes up these conversations expecting to encounter such
            criticism as he has been used to in reviews and magazines,
            will doubtless lay them down with such feelings of pleasurable disappointment as one experiences who bites a seckle
            pear for the first time, anticipating the flavor which other
            pears had yielded.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It would hardly be just to say that the great charm of this
            book is its sincerity, for that is the great charm of all good
            writing, but it is nevertheless so sincere that it seems like
            a peculiar merit. Mr. Lowell’s prose style is more his own
            than that of his poetry; it is more natural, clear, earnest,
            warm and unaffected; while it resembles the style of no other writer, it never startles
            you or impresses you with an
            idea that you have discovered something new. You seem
            to inhale it as you do the air—without an effort. Its sentences
            fall upon your mental ear like snow flakes upon water,
            and so noiselessly incorporate themselves into your own
            thoughts that you are unconscious of their increase until they
            begin to run over. It is the most readable style that we
            know, and the least cloysome : although like the air it is so
            light as never to weary ; yet, like the air, it has a terrible
            force when it is blown against you. Its gentlest whisper is
            as indicative of strength as its most terrible blast; because
            they are both caused by a power which we cannot discover.
            They come of themselves, and so seem fuller of might than if
            we saw the mechanism by which they are moved ; as the
            smallest insect that crawls contains within itself a more awe-inspiring power than the hugest steam engine that mortal
            hands ever framed. In the writings of most men we can
            discern the source of their style, we see how it was formed,
            what grammar aided in its construction, and what pedant
            moulded it, but in the writings of a man of genius, there is a
            breath which we have never felt before, a tone that no one
            beside has uttered, which we recognize as divine, because it
            is new. A somnambulist had one of Lowell’s manuscripts
            put into his hands and was asked how it impressed him; he
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>replied that it made him feel warm and comfortable. This we
            have no doubt will be the reply of nearly all who read these
            “Conversations.” They will be found warm and genial, except to a few, whom they will render hot and excited; for
            they contain certain expressions that will fall like molten
            lead upon the minds of some. We have no right, surely, to
            object to these, for if the author saw fit to put them forth it
            is an affair of his own; his purpose was to publish his
            thoughts and not to make friends. He knows what the
            world is composed of, and what he has to expect from it;
            there is not a sentence in the volume, nor, indeed, in any
            thing that he has written, which seems to say, “I hope I give
            no offence.” On the contrary, he seems to feel that offence
            is inevitable to all who speak the truth in the integrity of
            their hearts.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The conversations are between John and Philip, who have
            such a marvellous sympathy of tastes that we cannot easily
            discern, without looking, who it is that speaks. But for some
            reason John is not an abolitionist, while Philip is. And we
            may as well disburthen our mind of the feeling here, as to
            keep it encumbered, that Philip’s anti-slavery principles are
            somewhat too obtrusively put forth. There are other virtues
            than abolitionism: why not out with them? It smacks of
            generous bravery to confess to an unpopular virtue, but it is
            more brave not to confess at all. We should doubt the charity which boasted itself; or the chastity ; or piety. We see
            no need for an abolitionist to wear a badge, like one of Father
            Mathew’s disciples, to let the world know he is not what
            he once was. If every virtue must have its order of merit,
            our citizens will wear more decorations than the hero of
            Waterloo. It is an old saw that actions speak plainer than
            words. No man need fear but that he will be perfectly understood; whoever hates slavery will never be mistaken for
            one of its friends. There are a few ideas on art which break
            out in different parts of the conversations which are heterodox to our apprehensions: but this may be owing to a misconception of terms rather than to any difference of principles.
            Where there is so much to approve and admire we are not
            displeased to find something to condemn, for if it were not
            so, we should fear that our eyes were blinded by partiality.
            But it is a peculiarity with us, at least we have always
            thought so, to have a quicker eye for the faults of those we
            love than for others.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There are few readers who are not familiar with Leigh
            Hunt’s criticisms on Chaucer, and probably none more so than
            the author of these conversations; but we see nothing in his
            conversations to remind us of that daintiest of critics. Their
            styles and habits of thought are so dissimilar, that it could not
            well be otherwise. Hunt’s criticisms are neat and artist like,
            while Lowell’s are exceedingly free, and resemble criticisms
            as little as possible. They are loving comments, but so interspersed and enriched with other topics that they do not appear
            like comments upon Chaucer more than upon any thing else.
            We make a few extracts at random, which will hardly convey
            an idea of the book, which must be read entirely more than
            once to be justly appreciated.
         </p>
         <p>THE CONSCIOUSNESS OF GENIUS.
            “ I do not believe that Shakspeare never thought of posterity, nor
            that any man was ever endowed with marvellous powers, without be
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page34"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>ing conscious of it, and desiring to make them felt. No man of genius
            was ever so fully appreciated by contemporaries as to make him forget the future.
            A poet must needs be before his own age to be even
            with posterity.”
         </p>
         <p>CHAUCER.
            
         </p>
         <p>“There is in him the exuberant freshness and greenness of spring.
            Every thing he touches leaps into blossom. His gladness, and humor,
            and pathos, are irrepressible as a fountain. Dam them with a prosaic
            subject, and they overleap it with a sparkling cascade that turns even
            the hindrance to a beauty. Choke them with a tedious theological
            disquisition, and they bubble up forthwith, all around it, with a delightful gurgle. There is no cabalistic undine stone, or seal of Solo-mon that can
            shut them up forever. Reading him is like brushing
            through the dewy grass at sun-rise. Everything is new, and sparkling,
            and fragrant. He is of kin to Belphoebe, whose
         </p>
         <p>“Birth was of the womb of morning dew,'
            And her conception of the morning prime.”
            
         </p>
         <p>Nothing can be more unlike Leigh Hunt than this. Hunt
            is forever reminding you how charming the country is, but he
            never takes you there. Our author says nothing about the
            country, but you feel all the while as though you were treading on turf. The reason is that one was bred in the town, the
            other in the fields. “Reading him is like brushing through
            the dewy grass at sun-rise.” The sentence makes the air
            redolent of clover.
         </p>
         <p>BYRON.
            
         </p>
         <p>“It was not till our own day that the poets discovered what mystical significance had been lying dormant in a capital I. It seems
            strange that a letter of such powerful bewitchment had not made part
            of the juggling wares of the Cabalists and Theurgists. Yet we find
            no mention of it in Rabbi Akiba or Cornelius Agrippa. Byron wrought
            miracles with it. I fear that the noble Stylites of modem song, who
            from his lonely pillar of self, drew crowds of admiring votaries to Iis-ten to the
            groans of his self-inflicted misery, would have been left only
            to feel the cold and hunger of his shelterless pinnacle in Chaucer’s simpler day. Byron always reminds me of that criminal who was shut in
            a dungeon, the walls of which grew narrower and narrower every day,
            till they crushed him at last. His selfishness walled him in from the first ; so that
            he was never open to the sweet influences of nature, and
            those sweeter ones which the true heart finds in life. The sides of his
            jail were semi-transparent, giving him a muddy view of things immediately about him; but selfishness always builds a thick roof overhead to cut off the heavenward gaze of the spirit. And how did it squeeze the very
            life out of him in the end ! His spirit was more halt
            than his body. It had been well for him had he been as ashamed, or at least as conscious
            of one as the other. He should have been ba-nished, like Philoletes, to some isle
            of Lemnos, where his lameness
            should not have been affective and contagious. As it was, the world
            fell in love with the defect. Some malicious Puck had dropped the juice of 'Love in
            idleness’ upon its eyes, and limping came quite into fashion.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We do not agree with Mr. Lowell in all of what follows.
            If we have not the sky-lark and the nightingale, we think
            that no Eden could be complete without the Oriole and Bobo’link. And as for the nightingale, we have an owl in this lati-tude which makes a midnight
            plaint more dismal sweet, more
            touching, trembling, tear-compelling, than any that we ever
            heard made by the poets’ bird.
         </p>
         <p>THE NIGHTINGALE.
            "Let me read you an exquisite stanza from ‘ Troilus and Creseide.” It tells you how
            Creseide first avowed her love. There is nothing more
            tender in Coleridge’s Genevieve.
            ' And as the early bashful nightingale
            Doth hush at first when she begins to sing,
            If chance she heareth any shepherd’s tale,
            Or in the hedges any nestling,
            And then more boldly doth her voice outring;
            Cressid right so, when her first dread was spent,
            Opened her heart and gave her full love vent.'
            
         </p>
         <p>" I know not where the nightingale is more sweetly touched upon.
            Shakspeare has alluded to it once or twice, but not with enthusiasm.
            Coleridge, in one of his early poems, has given us a high strain of mu-sic about it.
            Milton’s sonnet is not so fine as most of his, though the
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>opening is exquisite. Keats has written, perhaps, the best ode in the
            language, upon the bird. Wherever the learned fix the site of Eden,
            it will never be in America, where we have neither the nightingale nor the
            sky lark. Yet we have the bob-o’-link and mocking bird in rich compensation. Nor are we wholly without music at night. I have often
            heard the song sparrow and robin at midnight, and what solitude
            would be quite lonely wanting the mournful plaint of the whippoorwill.”
         </p>
         <p>POETRY.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ The best poetry always comes to us leading by the hand the holy
            associations and tear-strengthened aspirings of youth, as Volumnia
            brought to Coriolanus his little children, to plead reproachfully with
            us, to be tender and meek, and patient. The passages I love in the
            poets give me back an hour of childhood, and are like a mother’s voice
            to me. They are as solemn as the rustle of the Bible leaves in the old family prayers. The noisy ocean of life hushes, and slides up his beach
            with a soothing and slumbering ripple. The earth becomes secluded
            and private to me as in early childhood, when it seemed but a little
            meadow green, guarded all round with trees for me to pick flowers
            in.”
         </p>
         <p>THE DIGNITY OF POVERTY.
            
         </p>
         <p>" Perhaps actual want maybe inconsistent with the serenity of
            mind which is needful to the highest and noblest exercise of the creative power, but I am not ready to allow that poverty is so. Few can
            dignify it like our amiable prose-poet, whose tales are an honor even
            to the illustrious language they are written in; but there is none for
            whom it has not some kind lesson. Poverty is a rare mistress for the
            poet. She alone can teach him what a cheap thing delight is—to be
            had of every man, woman, and child he meets; to be gathered from
            every tree, shrub, and flower ; nay, to be bought of the surly northwestern wind himself, by the easily paid instalments of a cheerful
            unhaggling spirit. Who knows the true taste of buns but the boy
            who receives the annual god-send of one with election day ? Who
            ever really went to the theatre but Kit Nubbles? Who feels what a
            fireside is, but the little desolate barefooted Ruths who glean the broken laths and waste splinters after the carpenters have had a full harvest ? Who believes that his cup is overflowing but he who has rarely
            seen anything but the dry bottom ! Poverty is the only seasoner of
            felicity. Except she be the cook, the bread is sour and heavy—the
            joint is overdone. As brisk exercise is the cheapest overcoat for the
            body, so is poverty for the heart. But it must be independent, and
            not of Panurge’s mind—that to owe is a heroic virtue. Debt is like
            the ingenious mechanical executioner I have read of somewhere, which
            presented the appearance of a fair woman standing upon a pedestal
            with three steps. When the victim mounted the first, she opened her
            arms ; at the second, she began to close them slowly around him ; at
            the third, she locked him in her iron embrace forever. On the other
            hand, however, poverty has its bad side. Poverty in one hour’s time
            shall transport a man from the warm and fruitful climate of sworn
            brotherhood with the world, into the bare, bleak, desert, and polar icefield of distant country-cousinship; and the world’s whole duty of
            man towards him, becomes on a sudden the necessity of staving off
            asking him to dinner.”
         </p>
         <p>Illustrated Works.
            “ Illustrated Genealogy of George Washington.” Published by W. A.
            Colman, 203 Broadway. (See Advertisement.)
            
         </p>
         <p>Heraldry, and Genealogy, have been slightly discouraged
            by many well intentioned citizens of this country, under the
            misapprehension that they tended to promote aristocratical
            distinctions, at variance with our Republican institutions,
            whereas they simply form symbols of a purely personal nature.
            The general use of heraldry, and the preservation of family
            records, have existed for centuries in the most jealous European
            Republics; and the historian and antiquary, can attest their
            usefulness in the elucidation of many important facts, which,
            without their aid, would never have been rescued from obscurity. There is a natural feeling in man, to ascertain the
            origin and history of his family, and the prevalence of this
            sentiment is shown by the universal custom in the parent
            state,—and as generally adopted here—of prefacing the memoirs of celebrated men with some account of their parents,
            and ancestors. When the public curiosity is thus conceived
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page35"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>worthy of satisfaction in relation to individuals of inferior
            merit, how much more gratifying it is to know the connexions and ancestors of the
            illustrious patriot, whose wisdom, courage, and energy, have nursed the infant liberties of his country
            in the full vigor of manly freedom and independence.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The work before us consists of the genealogical tree of the
            Washington family, the same as made out in the British Herald's college, for Augustine Washington, of Virginia, the father of our illustrious Patriot, and gives at one glance, their
            family history from the time of Richard III. up to the death of
            George Washington, a period exceeding 300 years. It is
            printed in gold and colors, with the blazonry of the Washingtons, and their alliances. As a work of art alone, it would be
            worthy a place in every parlor, did it not relate to one whose
            memory lives in the hearts of every lover of his country ; and
            we are pleased to see that Mr. Colman has published it at a
            price so low as to bring it within the easy acquisition of all
            our citizens.	(communicated.)
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship.—This is the most
            imdosing publication on the art of Hand Writing, that we
            have ever seen. Mr. Goldsmith has almost elevated his art
            into the upper region of the fine arts. His specimens are
            gems of neatness, grace and beauty. It is a thousand pities
            that all who write, and they include nearly all of the population of our country, could not make some approach to the
            perfection which Mr. Goldsmith has attained in the use of
            the pen.
         </p>
         <p>It is published by the author, at 189 Broadway.
            
         </p>
         <p>An Illustrated Edition of Bryant’s Poems.—An edition
            of Bryant’s Poems has been projected by some of the most
            eminent of our artists, to be illustrated by Wood Cuts, from
            original designs, after the manner of Hall’s Book of British
            Ballads. Nothing of this sort has ever been attempted among us, and the project is highly honorable to the gentlemen undertaking it. We have seen one of the designs, which
            we consider quite as good as many of the engravings in Mr.
            Hall’s book. If the work is to be got up in imitation of any
            other, the Niebelungen Lied offers a much finer example
            than the Book of British Ballads.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If it should be commenced, thore can be little doubt of its
            receiving ample support from the public ; and a fitter work
            for illustration could not be selected than the poems of Mr.
            Bryant.
         </p>
         <p>Literary and Learned Societies.
            
         </p>
         <p>The American Ethnolocical Society.—A Society with
            the above name has been in existence in this city, for
            the about two years, having for its object investigations into
            Physical History of Man. This interesting subject is absorbing
            much interest in Europe, and societies have lately been formed in London and Paris, having similar objects in view. In
            Germany, too, the Science has received a great impulse from
            the philological and antiquarian researches of Gesenius, Lepsius, Bopp, Ritter, and others. We are glad to hear of the interest awakened in our own city, on this subject, and that several of our distinguished Philologists, Antiquarians, and Geographers, among whom are Mr. Schoolcraft, Mr. Bartlett,
            and Alexander W. Bradford, the author of an able work on
            American Antiquities, have united in an association to promote
            the various branches of knowledge embraced in these heads.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This Society has just announced the first volume of its transactions, to be published by Bartlett &amp; Welford, Astor House.
            The Prospectus will be found in our advertising columns.
         </p>
         <p>The Drama.
            "OLD HEADS AND YOUNG HEARTS."
            
         </p>
         <p>A new Comedy, by the author of “London Assurance,”
            called “Old Heads and Young Hearts,” is now having a
            run at our Theatres. It was popular in London, after the
            first night, (when it was not very warmly received,) and of
            course is popular here. The success of a play like this,
            proves the truth of our views of the state of the stage.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The author of “Old Heads and Young Hearts,” may be
            presumed to know something about London society, and his
            representations of its phases should have some degree of
            vraisemblance. But if this Comedy represents any class of
            the English, it must be some one that is not composed of
            human beings. Even Earls and Countesses may be presumed to have some affinity with human nature, but the
            Earl of Pompion and his Countess are not even caricatures
            of any humanity that we have any knowledge of. There is
            a good deal of very lively dialogue, and one or two smart
            things, but not a particle of wit in the whole piece. All
            the characters say good things, without any reference to
            their appropriateness, and stand apart from each other without possessing any individuality. The most amusing character in the piece is a spaniel, who acts his part very naturally, and causes a good deal of merriment. The other
            actors should take a hint from the applause bestowed on his
            modest performance.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The first act opens with Littleton Coke, Esq., one of the
            legitimate rake-scrapes of the English stage, at his breakfast-table, in a Chintz morning gown. His valet is sitting
            on a stool, and Mr. Coke rises from his seat and lets us into
            some of the particulars of his good-for-nothing history,
            framed after the model of Charles Surface. Presently, Lord
            Charles Roebuck, son of the Earl of Pompion, comes in and
            informs him that his father has sent for him to marry his
            cousin, Lady Alice Hawthorn, and to stand for Closeborough,
            at the next election, but that he had fallen in love with Miss
            Kate Rocket, and begged that his friend would have the
            goodness to marry Lady Alice and go into parliament, in
            his stead. Mr. Coke is delighted at the proposition, as he
            is head over heels in debt, and Lady Alice has a fortune of
            five thousand a-year. While they are conversing his servant informs him that a bailiff and one of his creditors are
            at the door, upon which the two young men run off, and
            leave the valet to arrange matters with the harpies and
            body-snatchers, as he calls honest men who ask for their
            belongings. The bailiff and the creditor come in, and they
            prove to be a venerable clergyman, Jesse Rural, with long
            white hair, and Thomas Coke, Esq., M.P., the brother of
            the spendthrift Littleton. The valet, who has been pretty
            well used to bailiffs and tradesmen, never discovers from
            the appearance of these gentlemen, that they are not the
            persons he takes them for, and when they inquire for his
            master, salutes them with a torrent of vulgar abuse, which
            no bailiff even would take from a flunkey, or any body else.
            The two gentlemen, however, walk off with themselves,
            without demanding any explanation, and presently meet
            Littleton Coke, Esq. at the house of the Earl of Pompion,
            where all the dramatis personae are assembled, and where
            the most remarkable scenes occur—infinitely more gross and
            unnatural than any thing in Mr. Cooper’s “ Monnikins.’’
            The Countess of Pompion, when she first meets her son,
            after his long absence from abroad, sits caressing her lapdog ; and without either rising to salute him, or showing
            the smallest mark of pleasure, asks him whether he has
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page36"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>brought her any eau de Cologne, which must be a very great rarity with a Countess,
            and hopes he still uses the perfume
            des milles fleurs. As soon as she goes out, he and his cousin,
            Lady Alice, begin to make fun of her. Littleton Coke falls
            in love with Lady Alice ; so does his brother. She, however,
            only falls in love with Littleton, but flirts with Tom, who loves her to desperation,
            until the last scene, when he not
            only suddenly resigns her to his brother, but also resigns the
            bulk of his property to him, when a reconciliation takes
            place between them, which no entreaties on the part of Tom
            and his friends could effect before. Jesse Rural is the friend
            of the Coke’s, but he does nothing but laugh, and get them
            into scrapes, and go into hysterics. A double elopement takes
            place, for no earthly purpose, and Lord Charles Roebuck—
            Charley, as they call him—cheats his father, by getting his
            friend returned for Closeborough, through his valet, Bob,
            who imposes himself in his assumed character upon the
            Earl, who not seeing through the very gross deception, makes
            a confession to him, for which there is not the slightest need,
            that he has a natural son, named Robert; and then the valet passes off Lord Charles
            in the disguise of a groom, upon his
            father, for this natural son, whom he had not seen for fifteen
            years. In the end the Valet himself proves to be the earl’s
            son. There is an E. I. Colonel, the father of Kate Rockett, who
            salutes everybody in military style, and is so grossly ignorant,
            that he has never heard of the Battle of Hastings. Lady Alice
            does a thousand things that no woman, not even an abandoned
            one, could be guilty of ; and the Earl of Pompion, Secretary
            of State for the Home department, is hardly a degree better
            than an idiot, while his son Lord Charles, is more vulgar
            than any tallow chandler’s son possibly could be, who had
            enjoyed the privilege of waiting upon his father’s customers.
            The whole piece is such a conglomeration of absurdities, that
            criticism would be degraded by dissecting it. It is put upon
            the stage with a good many modern refinements, which must
            give the vulgar very strange notions of high life. In the
            Earl of Pompion’s drawing room the furniture is all burnished gold. It would take more bullion than the bank of England could furnish to make such a magnificent set out. The
            floor is covered with a real carpet, and no mistake, and the
            chandelier is real tin. In the last scene, which is laid in a
            tropical country, with a view of St. Paul’s in the distance,
            Lady Alice and Miss Rockett came in after their elopement in their opera dresses, accompanied by the Countess
            of Pompion in a winter hat, a muff and boa. Although the
            drawing room is covered with a real carpet, the lawn in front
            of the tropical summer-house is composed of boards.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Old Heads and Young Hearts is no doubt intended for a
            representation of high life, and considered as such might be
            popular with two classes in London ; those who have an itching to become acquainted with the manner in which Lords
            spend their time, and those who love to see the habits of the
            higher orders ridiculed. But there are no such classes here,
            and we can only account for the popularity of this piece, by
            attributing it to the degraded standard of dramatic taste existing in the community.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We saw this performance at the Park Theatre, where it
            was doubtless as well done as it could have been at either
            of our Theatres. Mr. Crisp, who personated Littleton
            Coke, is a rather slight, gentlemanly-looking person, who
            can hardly be classed with good actors, but he was good
            enough for his part. Mr. Barry, who always looks and
            speaks like a gentleman with some grave affair on his hands,
            represented the brother—a kind of Joseph Surface, without
            his hypocrisy—in a commendable manner ; and Mr. Chippendale did his part, Jesse Rural, with his usual neatness
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>and finish,—perhaps he overdid it a little, and laughed a little
            too much. But the acting was all well enough ; Garrick
            himself could have made nothing out of such a farrago of
            nonsense. The play has a moral, of course, which is identical with the majority of stage morals, viz.: That the most
            worthless conduct will always be rewarded by a great fortune and a beautiful wife. There are two marriages at the
            end, for no other reason than that the last act has been
            reached. The parties might as well have been married in
            the first act, and have saved all the subsequent trouble.
         </p>
         <p>The Fine Arts.
            THE ART UNION PICTURES.
            
         </p>
         <p>We hear that fault is found, by some of our artists, with
            our notices of the Art-Union pictures. We are not surprised
            at this. They were not written to please them, but to inform the public, according to our ability, of the merits and
            defects which we think some of them possess. Every artist
            has a merit of his own ; and the best service that can be rendered him, is to undeceive him when he thinks that he can
            do what nature never intended him for. It is melancholy
            to see what a waste of genius is often made by artists, in
            attempting things for which they have no qualifications.
            Perhaps the most purely original and characteristic all of the
            painters that America has produced, is Mount. He is a man
            of genius, and altogether unapproachable in his peculiar field
            of labor; but he has an uneasy hankering to obtain popularity in a line of art for which he is clearly unqualified to excel in. His small pictures of American common life, are
            among the finest things that we have ever produced in Art;
            but his large portraits are painful exhibitions of misdirected
            talents. At least, so his productions have impressed us; and
            if we speak of his works at all, we must speak what we
            think about them. No good can ever come of flattery or illnatured prejudice. We have a kindly feeling towards the
            whole race of artists in our country, and if by a stroke of our
            pen we could convert them all into Raphaels and Titians, it
            should be done. Infinite harm has been done to Art by the
            indiscriminate and unmeaning praise which has been bestowed upon all who labor at the easel, among us. It is better to praise than to blame, and a great deal easier: but
            when we bestow the same commendations on an artist of
            slender abilities that we do upon a great genius, harm is
            done to both. We have assumed the task of serving the
            public—a very onerous one, for which we do not feel ourselves peculiarly fitted by any means; but seeing a vacant
            department of editorial labor which no one seems disposed
            to fill, we have undertaken to occupy it until some one better qualified shall offer.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There is a growing interest for Art manifested among us,
            which, for the sake of both artists and public, should not be
            allowed to decrease; and the press being the only channel
            through which a knowledge of what is done in Art can be
            communicated to the public, we have determined to devote
            a portion of our Journal to that cause. In doing so, we think
            that we have a right to look for aid from those who, after
            all, are most interested in the matter, namely—the Artists.
            But we shall never seek to gain their aid by personal flatteries, or by advocating the cause of any party or clique. We
            have a few personal friends among them, whose good will
            we should be exceeding sorry to lose; but if it can only be
            retained by a sacrifice of truth, we prefer to lose it. Perhaps
            our terms of dispraise may not always be expressed as gingerly as they should; but if a culprit is to be hung, it cannot
            be a material matter to him whether he be suspended by a
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page37"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>silken or a hempen cord. It has always seemed to us, that
            the most direct way of conveying a thought is the best. It
            shall be our aim never to mix up personalities with our criticisms, and generally, when we can say nothing encouraging
            of a work we shall prefer to be silent. The young need encouragement, and praise will be likely to do them more
            good than censure; but the artist of established reputation
            can not only afford to be told of his defects, but he requires
            to be, lest he get confirmed in ill habits.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We think that the artists in this city suffer much wrong
            from having a President of their Academy who has aban-doned his profession. Mr. Morse
            has probably been doing
            more to confer renown upon himself, and benefit upon his
            country, by his scientific labors the past five years, than he
            ever did before; but when he seeks for reputation in any
            other field of employment than that of art, he should resign
            his post. His knowledge of art eminently qualified him for
            the chair of the President of the National Academy; but if
            there had been any doubt that nature never meant him for a
            painter, there should have been none when he relinquished
            his brush. No true artist ever abandoned his profession.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have given so much space to a definition of “our position,” that we have but little left for further remarks on
            the remaining pictures of the Art-Union.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There were several landscapes by Mr. Gignoux; two of
            them were in water colors, and one of the two, the Cathedral of Fribourg was a very admirable painting; the other
            was an indifferent picture, which we think must have been
            purchased by mistake. We have never seen so great a difference between the works of any artist, as we have noticed
            in the pictures by Mr. Gignoux. Some of them are exceedingly fine—his sketches from nature, for instance—while
            others are exceedingly bad, careless, and ill-considered. Mr.
            Gignoux has nothing to fear from dispraise, for he has merit
            enough to fortify his reputation against a good many volleys
            of censure. If an artist will trifle with his reputation by putting off hasty and ill-finished productions, he must be prepared for the consequences. The public have a right to
            think, when they see a picture, that it is the best the painter
            can do; and he will have no right to complain if he should
            sometimes be valued at less than his real worth. No artist
            can better afford to indulge in occasional carelessness than
            Mr. Durand; yet we have never seen a picture from his
            easel which had not the marks of being well considered, and
            finished up to the reach of his ability.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The pen-and-ink drawings by Mr. Hoppin, were the finest
            outlines that we have ever seen from any of our artists. It
            is not a style of art adapted to the expression of coarse subjects; and we think that the greatest defect of these drawings is the absence of purity and elevation of sentiment, unavoidable from the subjects illustrated. They evince talents
            of a very high order, which only require a different direction
            to produce very brilliant effects. The most successful attempts in outline, such as Flaxman’s, Retsch’s, and the late
            ones of Selous, have been of the highest class of ideal subjects, as Homer, Dante, Goethe, and Bunyan. Scott and
            Cooper, from whose works Mr. Hoppin has taken nearly
            all the subjects which we have seen of his illustrating, contain but few passages suitable to the severity of outline
            drawing. One, however, from the Merry Wives of Windsor, though mostly composed of the deformities of nature,
            Falstaff, Slender, Bardolph, &amp;c. is finely idealised, and makes
            a very close approach, if it does not quite reach, the illustrations of Faust. Mr. Hoppin’s forte is in painting animals.
            Among dogs, horses and oxen, he is perfectly at home. If
            he would go into partnership with some one of our best
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>landscape painters, Cropsey for instance, they might between
            them produce the best pictures that we have yet seen in our
            Exhibitions.
         </p>
         <p>AMERICAN PROSE WRITERS.
            NO. 2.
            N. P. WILLIS.
            
         </p>
         <p>NEW VIEWS—IMAGINATION—FANCY—FANTASY—HUMOR—WIT—SARCASM— THE PROSE STYLE
            OF MR. WILLIS.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In his poetry, and in the matter of his prose, the author of
            “Melanie” and of the “Inklings of Adventure” has, beyond
            doubt, innumerable merits:—still, they are merits which he
            shares with other writers—which he possesses in common
            with Proctor, with Heber, and with Halleck—in common
            with Neele, with Hunt, with Lamb, and with Irving; his
            prose style, however, is not only a genus per se, but it is his
            own property “in fee simple impartite,” and no man living
            has ever yet set foot upon it except himself.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Now, if any style has been long distinct—has been long
            markedly and universally peculiar—we must, of course, seek
            the source of the peculiarity not, as some persons are prone
            to suppose, in any physical habitude or mannerism—not in
            any quipping and quibbling of phrase—not in any twisting of
            antique conventionalities of expression—not, (to be brief,) in
            any mere sleight-of-pen trickeries which, at all times, may be
            more dexterously performed by an observant imitator than
            by the original quack—but in some mental idiosyncrasy, which,
            unimitated itself because inimitable, preserves the style which
            is its medium and its exponent from all danger of imitation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the style of Mr. Willis we easily detect this idiosyncrasy. We have no trouble in tracing it home—and when we
            reach it and look it fairly in the face, we recognize it on
            the instant.—It is Fancy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>To be sure, there is qnite a tribe of Fancies—although one
            half of them never suspected themselves to be such until so
            told by the metaphysicians—but the one of which we speak
            has never yet been accredited among men, and we beg pardon
            of Mr. Willis for the liberty we take in employing the topic
            of his style, as the best possible vehicle and opportunity for
            the introduction of this, our protege, to the consideration of
            the literary world.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Fancy,” says the author of “Aids to Reflection” (who
            aided Reflection to much better purpose in his “Genevieve”)
            —“Fancy combines—Imagination creates.” This was intended, and has been received, as a distinction; but it is a distinction without a difference—without even a difference of degree.
            The Fancy as nearly creates as the imagination, and neither
            at all. Novel conceptions are merely unusual combinations.
            The mind of man can imagine nothing which does not exist:
            —if it could, it would create not only ideally, but substantially—as do the thoughts of God. It may be said—“We imagine a griffin, yet a griffin does not exist.” Not the griffin
            certainly, but its component parts. It is no more than a collation of known limbs—features—qualities. Thus with all
            which claims to be new—which appears to be a creation of
            the intellect:—it is re-soluble into the old. The wildest
            effort of the mind cannot stand the test of the analysis.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We might make a distinction of degree between the fancy
            and the imagination, in calling the latter the former loftily
            employed. But experience would prove this distinction to be
            unsatisfactory. What we feel to be fancy, will be found still
            fanciful, whatever be the theme which engages it. No subject exalts it into imagination. When Moore is termed a
            fanciful poet, the epithet is precisely applied; he is. He is
            fanciful in “Lalla Rookh,” and had he written the “Inferno,”
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page38"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>there he would have been fanciful still: for not only is he essentially fanciful, but he has no ability to be anything more,
            unless at rare intervals—by snatches—and with effort. What
            we say of him at this point, moreover, is equally true of all
            little frisky men, personally considered.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The fact seems to be that Imagination, Fancy, Fantasy,
            and Humor, have in common the elements, Combination, and
            Novelty. The Imagination is the artist of the four. From
            novel arrangements of old forms which present thamselves to
            it, it selects only such as are harmonious:--the result, of course,
            is beauty itself—using the term in its most extended sense,
            and as inclusive of the sublime. The pure Imagination
            chooses, from either beauty or deformity, only the most combinable things hitherto uncombined;—the compound, as a
            general rule, partaking (in character) of sublimity or beauty,
            in the ratio of the respective sublimity or beauty of the things
            combined—which are themselves still to be considered as atomic—that is to say, as previous combinations. But, as often
            analogously happens in physical chemistry, so not unfrequently does it occur in this chemistry of the intellect, that the admixture of two elements will result in a something that shall
            have nothing of the quality of one of them—or even noth-ing of the qualities of either. The range of Imagination is
            therefore, unlimited. Its materials extend throughout the
            Universe. Even out of deformities it fabricates that Beauty
            which is at once its sole object and its inevitable test. But,
            in general, the richness or force of the matters combined—the
            facility of discovering combinable novelties worth combining
            —and the absolute “chemical combination” and proportion
            of the completed mass—are the particulars to be regarded in
            our estimate of Imagination. It is this thorough harmony of
            an imaginative work which so often causes it to be under-valued by the undiscriminating, through the character of obviousness which is superinduced. We are apt to find ourselves
            asking “why is it that these combinations have never been
            imagined before?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Now, when this question does not occur—when the harmony of the combination is comparatively neglected, and
            when in addition to the element of novelty, there is introduced the sub-element of unexpectedness—when, for example,
            matters are brought into combination which not only have
            never been combined but whose combination strikes us as a
            difficulty happily overcome—the result then appertains to the
            Fancy—and is, to the majority of mankind more grateful than
            the purely harmonious one—although, absolutely, it is less
            beautiful (or grand) for the reason that it is less harmonious.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Carrying its errors into excess—for, however enticing, they
            are errors still, or Nature lies.—Fancy is at length found impinging upon the province of Fantasy. The votaries of this
            latter delight not only in novelty and unexpectedness of
            combination, but in the avoidance of proportion. The result
            is therefore abnormal, and to a healthy mind affords less of
            pleasure through its novelty, than of pain through its incoherence. When, proceeding a step farther, however, Fantasy
            seeks not merely disproportionate but incongruous or antagonistical elements, the effect is rendered more pleasurable from
            its greater positiveness;—there is a merry effort of Truth to
            shake from her that which is no property of hers;—and we
            laugh outright in recognizing Humor.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The four faculties in question appear to me all of their
            class;—but when either Fancy or Humor is expressed to gain
            an end—is pointed at a purpose—whenever either becomes
            objective in place of subjective—then it becomes, also, pure
            Wit or Sarcasm, just as the purpose is well-intentioned or
            malevolent.
         </p>
         <p>Having thus comfortably defined our position, we shall be
            
         </p>
         <p>the more readily understood when we repeat that the marked
            idiosyncrasy of the prose style of Mr. Willis—that the charm
            which has wrought for it so vast and so well-merited a popularity—is traceable, in the last result, to the brilliant Fancy
            with which it perpetually scintillates or glows—a fancy possessed, not as in the case of Moore, to the exclusion of qualities more noble—but possessed, certainly, to an extent altogether unparallelled, and of a kind both relatively and intrinsically the most valuable, because at once the most radiant
            and the most rare.
         </p>
         <p>HISTORICAL ESSAYS.
            SURRENDER OF NEW YORK TO THE DUTCH,
            CURIOUS FACTS RECENTLY COME TO LIGHT REGARDING THIS EVENT,
            FROM THE RESEARCHES OF MR. BRODHEAD.
            
         </p>
         <p>The War of 1672, against Holland, commenced by Charles
            the Second, which all the historians attribute to the private
            relations between that monarch and Louis the Fourteenth,
            strengthened by the circumstance that his mother was a
            French Princess, and his sister, the Dutchess of Orleans, was
            not without its consequences to the colony of New York.—
            It is very evident, from the documents deposited in the British State Paper office, that the importance of this colony
            was well understood, both by the Dutch and English. Its
            commodious harbor, its commanding position, both with
            respect to Canada and New England,—its fine navigable
            river, the Hudson, the richness of the back country, as well
            as of the islands which guarded it from the sea, were always leading topics in the communications which were
            sent home to either country, by the official personages who
            at different times represented the Dutch and the English
            interests.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It seems that the Hollanders did not fail, on the breaking
            out of the war with England, to despatch a fleet to the
            American coast, under the command of two well-known
            officers, Jacob Binkes and Cornelius Evertsen de Jonge, as-sisted by three captains of the Dutch army, Anthony Coloe,
            Nicholas Boes, and Abraham Frederick Van Zye. This
            force was the result of the union of two small fleets off
            Martinique, one of which, previously under the command
            of Evertsen, had sailed for Virginia, and there captured and
            sunk a number of English and French vessels, men-of-war
            and merchantmen, after some hard-fought battles. Coming
            north to New York, they sailed up the bay, anchored at
            Staten Island, and with the first fair wind, stood for the
            city,—formed a line-of-battle off the present Battery, and
            took the fort. The manner of its surrender is the point we
            propose to discuss, and if we shall be allowed to do so, it is
            because the enlightened liberality of the State of New York
            has obtained from abroad, the interesting documents which
            throw new light upon the subject; and because its faithful
            and able agent, J. R. Brodhead, Esq., has dragged from the
            obscurity of nearly two hundred years, papers and documents which had hitherto escaped the researches and the
            knowledge of our most esteemed historians. Smith, in his
            history of New York, when speaking of the surrender, says:
            “A few Dutch ships arrived the year after, (1673) on the
            30th of July, under Staten Island, at the distance of a few
            miles from the City of New York. John Manning, a captain of an independent Company, had at that time the command of the fort, and by a message sent down to the squadron, treacherously made his peace with the enemy. On that
            very day the Dutch ships came up, moored under the fort,
            landed their men and entered the garrison, without giving
            or receiving a shot.
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page39"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>Dunlap, in his history of New York, follows the statement
            of Smith. Mr. Bancroft, in his later work, also states that
            the city was given up “without a blow." Holmes, in his
            valuable American Annals, adopts the same opinion. “On
            the arrival,” says he, “of the invading squadron, the commander of the Fort sent a messenger and made his peace
            with the enemy. Not a shot was given or returned."
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But the case is still further made up, by the formal record,
            in Smith’s History of New York, of the proceedings of a
            Court Martial, at which charges were exhibited against the
            commander of the Fort, upon his return from England, where
            he went on a visit. To these charges he pleaded guilty,
            and his sword was broken over his head, either before his own
            house, at Coenties Slip, or at the City Hall; each place
            being mentioned as the locality of his degradation. We will
            briefly notice the charges, when we have given such a narrative of the surrender as appears fully ascertained, by the
            documents of the New York agency. If these alone were to
            be the ground-work of a new history, the name of Manning
            would assume a very different rank, in our annals. The
            surrender would be attributable to some of those common
            occurrences which make up the accidents of war; or to the
            natural consequences of a previous peace; of skill and boldness on the one side, and of an accidental want of preparation on the other,—where bravery cannot furnish the want
            of the munitions of war, or supply the defects of decayed
            and useless defences.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The facts in favor of this view of the subject appear to
            be these: After the successes of Evertsen, on the coast of
            Virginia, and his meeting with his friend Binkes, off the
            Mauritius, with four men-of-war, the commanders sailed for
            New York. We can well imagine their desire to recapture
            this valuable colony, founded by their countrymen, and still
            dear to the government of the mother country. It appears,
            that among their captures was a country sloop, commanded
            by one Samuel Davis,—and on his being applied to for information as to the state of the defences at New York, he told
            them, doubtless with the idea of preventing the expedition,
            that the English Governor, Lovelace, could raise five thousand men, easily, in three hours, for the protection of the
            city,—and that there were one hundred and fifty-five pieces
            of ordnance in the fort, which could be effectively used
            against an enemy. This story, according to some of the
            accounts, would have deterred them from the enterprise, if
            another prisoner, of the name of Hopkins, and who is styled
            a professor in one of the papers, had not flatly contradicted
            the master of the sloop. He informed the Dutch Commodores that there were but sixty or eighty men in the fort,—
            that it would take several days to raise even three or four
            hundred men for its defence, and that the cannons were so
            badly mounted that a shot or two would shake them out of
            their carriages. On hearing this, to use the words of our
            authority, “the cry was for New York." The squadron
            stood for New York, accordingly, and soon arrived at Sandy
            Hook. It then moved up to Staten Island and cast anchor,
            waiting for a fair wind to get up to town. They did not
            hesitate to make up their supplies of fresh meat, from the
            cattle and sheep of the Governor, as we learn from a letter
            which he despatched to Governor Winthrop, at Boston, and
            in which he expressed a hope that he would be able to do
            something decisive towards regaining the city. According
            to his account, the squadron consisted, first, of ten sail,
            which were afterwards increased to sixteen. Another letter,
            written by a Mr. Palmos, of New London, estimates the
            force at twenty ships and one galliot. The most interesting
            testimony to which we have had access, however, is that of
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>one Isaac Arundell, of Southhold. His “relation” of the
            events was taken down at Boston, within a few days after the capture. He was in the
            fort at the time, and was an
            eye-witness of what he relates.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>On the 28th of July, O. S., said the narrator, the Dutch fleet, consisting of twelve
            sail of men-of-war and twelve prizes, came in at Sandy Hook, and that day came up to Staten
            Island, where, having a contrary wind, they tarried until the
            30th. Many of the Long Island Dutch people went on board
            the vessels, and we cannot doubt they were pleased enough
            to see the flag of their country once more upon the bay. They gave information as
            to the state of the fort, and no
            doubt informed the Commodore that they had not long previously refused to contribute any more for its repairs when
            solicited for that purpose by the Governor. They informed their countrymen of its actual condition, and of the absence of the Governor and the principal citizens. On the 30th, by the aid of a fair
            wind the fleet sailed up to the city
            and anchored before the fort, the order of battle being in the form of “a half moon.”
            At this juncture Captain Manning
            went on board in person, and demanded the reason of their visit. The reply was that
            they intended to take the place,
            that it was their own, and they would have their own.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Manning then asked for time to make ready his preparations for a fight, but he was allowed only half an hour.
            When this brief space was past, the Dutch Commodore at
            that time in command, (for it appears after the most approved models of antiquity, they relieved each other every eight
            days, and hoisted their broad pennants alternately,) fired his
            broadside and the rest after him. Hereupon, continues Arundell, the fort fired upon them again, and shot the “General’s
            ship through and through.” Although by his account the
            fort held out four hours, against this superior force, but little damage was done
            the garrison. One man only was killed,
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>and that happened in consequence of his mounting the walls sword in hand, and there
            flourishing it in defiance of the Dutch. His head was taken off by a cannon ball.
            The fort did not surrender until all the ammunition was expended, a circumstance which
            is highly favorable to the presumption
            of Captain Manning’s integrity. When the last cannon car tridge was gone, and not till then, was the flag struck.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Under cover of the smoke six hundred troops were landed
            near what was then called the Governor’s Orchard. Another person who was present stated that but four hundred men
            had muskets, the rest were armed with pistols, swords, and
            half pikes, and in our opinion were, most probably, seamen.
            These troops were in Broadway approaching the fort at the
            time the flag was struck, which so far leads to the supposition
            that it was intended to carry it by storm. A corporal in the
            fort who is authority for this last statement, says the gate
            was opened and the garrison marched forth with their arms,
            which they laid down in token of their surrender. They
            were then ordered into the fort and confined in the church
            which stood within the walls. Captain Manning was permitted to wear his sword, a permission only usual when it
            has been gallantly used.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Another circumstance connected with this event, appears
            to weigh strongly against the supposition that Captain Manning was a traitor to his country. His house was plundered
            of its contents, as well as that of the Governor and Captain Deleval, a noted loyalist
            in high favor with the government.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is said by one who was present, that Captain Manning and
            a Dr. Taylor opened the gate themselves, and that even then
            the soldiers wished to resist, but were ordered not to do so.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>During this attack, the neighboring Long Islanders could
            afford no assistance, for they had not two rounds of ammunition among them all.
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page40"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>Thus ended the assault, and such was its consequence. It
            appears that the conquerors were overjoyed with their success,
            and dispatched a messenger to Holland with the news. A
            proclamation was issued, establishing a new order of things.
            Anthony Colve was commissioned as Governor by the commodores, the people took the oath, and the late Governor
            Lovelace himself visited the Dutch squadron under assurance
            of safety, and came ashore to the fort in the commander’s
            pinnace, with the Dutch flag flying.
         </p>
         <p>A small expedition was sent up to Albany, and that place
            also surrendered, unconditionally.
            
         </p>
         <p>Many other singular and interesting facts are preserved in
            relation to this interesting event, to which the future historian
            of New York will now have access for the first time.
            Many long received errors will be corrected, and we shall be
            able to know with certainty what is authentic and reliable
            in our colonial annals.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>By the treaty of Westminster the following year, New
            York was restored to the English, and Eustatia and Surinam
            remained with the Dutch.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Commodore Binks fell in battle in 1677, at the capture of
            Tobago by the Count D’Estrades. Evertsen returned to
            Europe after a series of triumphs in the New World, and reposes at Middleburgh under a tomb which perpetuates his
            services.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As late as 1818, an oration was delivered in that town
            in honor of his memory, and funds were raised to restore the
            memorial of his valor, which time had not altogether spared.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If then we trusted to these documents alone, we should
            assert that the fort did not surrender until after a cannonade
            of four hours, that it returned the fire with effect, and the
            want of ammunition was the reason of its holding out no
            longer.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We now return to the subsequent career of Captain Manning. It is quite certain that he not only went to England,
            and was unmolested there, but was in favor with the Duke
            of York. It was on his return to this city that he was arrested and tried on the charge, to which we have alluded.
         </p>
         <p>These are to be found in Smith’s History, and are sub-
            stantially as follows:
            1.	That on the approach of the enemy, he did not put the
            fort in a state of defence.
            
         </p>
         <p>On this, we remark, that the evidence in the papers
            brought from England by our agent, shows that the Governor
            himself had failed to raise money for that purpose. How
            Captain Manning could do it without means, a d also in the
            absence of the Governor, is more than we can explain.
         </p>
         <p>2.	That he went on board to treat with the enemy treacher-
            ously.
            
         </p>
         <p>The eye witnesses declare that be went on board to ask
            the meaning of their visit, and to get time to prepare for action.
         </p>
         <p>3.	That he suffered the fleet to move without firing a gun.
            This may or may not have been unavoidable, considering
            the state of his battery, the weight of his metal, and the
            range of his guns.
            4.	That he permitted the enemy to land without the least
            opposition.
            
         </p>
         <p>The witnesses, some of them his own men, declare, that
            he fought till his last cartridge was expended, after hulling
            the commodore’s ship repeatedly.
         </p>
         <p>5.	That he struck his flag before the enemy were in sight of
            the garrison.
            This appears very doubtful, from the evidence we have
            seen. It is very certain that against the column of six hun-
            dred, approaching through Broadway, he could, with his
            handful of men, have made no effectual resistance.
            6.	That he surrendered the garrison without articles of ca-
            pitulation.
            
         </p>
         <p>So did the garrison at Albany subsequently surrender
            without articles. And if he did so surrender, he was the
            principal sufferer, for his house was pillaged. We cannot
            reconcile this fact with treachery and selfishness.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The character of the Dutch commodores, argues against
            the received opinion. They were gallant and honorable men,
            and had they made a private arrangement with Manning,
            we cannot account for the necessity of a cannonade of four
            hours upon the fort, nor find any excuse for the plunder of
            the principal houses of the town, which is never permitted
            except after a desperate resistance, and as some reward for
            the valor of the assailants.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Among the records at the Secretary of State’s office at
            Albany, which our agent has brought from Holland, are
            copies of the original papers of Binkes and Evertsen in relation to this affair. We hope an early translation of them
            will enable us to obtain further light on this subject.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>One thing we admit, that the idea of treachery was prevalent among many distinguished persons at the time, and in
            the instructions given by the Duke of York to Sir Edmund
            Andros, his governor, there was a special command not to
            molest any of the Dutch inhabitants under a pretence of their
            having dealt treacherously with their countrymen at the surrender, and not to proceed against any of the English, who
            had made themselves liable, any further than to forfeit their
            estates.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>That the States General contemplated a permanent occupancy of the colony is evident from another fact brought to
            light by the agency—that they passed a secret resolution on
            the 15th of December, 1673, after the receipt of the gratifying
            news of the surrender, appointing Joris Andringa, who was
            secretary of the fleet, Governor and Commander of the province.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The whole affair presents a singular aspect. If Captain
            Manning had made a defence, upon the testimony which we
            have quoted, and which was taken at different places without collusion or inducement to misrepresentation, he would
            probably have been acquitted. We have no facts on the
            other side whatever, beyond the report of Manning’s having
            confessed himself guilty. There may have been reasons of
            a private character on the one hand, and state reasons on the
            other, to have made it important for some explanation of the
            surrender to the Dutch. There might have been some danger of a loss of the grant to the Duke, if he had not sufficiently defended his territory against the enemy.
         </p>
         <p>At all events we have said enough to place the whole
            matter in a new light, and there for the present we leave it.
            S. D. W. B.
            
         </p>
         <p>“Calling Spirits from the vasty Deep.”—The editor of
            one of our weekly papers informs the public that he has “invoked the aid of some of the first artists in Europe” to decorate his paper; probably Tony Johannot, and Gavarni. Nothing can be more easy than to invoke the aid of such men as
            these; it must remind everybody of the modest boast of Owen
            Glendower:
         </p>
         <p>“I can call spirits from the the vasty deep.”
            "But will they come ?" said Hotspur.
            
         </p>
         <p>If these artists should happen to answer the invocation,
            we shall probably invoke them ourselves; and include the
            names of Ary Scheffer, Selous, Maclise, and a few others.
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page41"></div>
            Architecture.
            THE INTERIOR OF TRINITY CHURCH.
            To the Editor of the Broadway Journal.
            
         </p>
         <p>Sir,—In a paragraph in your introductory article, you say
            that “you will devote a good part of your columns to the
            interests of American Art:" and having read in your prospectus that “you hope that a free channel being opened, through
            which true-hearted men may let loose their thoughts,” &amp;c.
            &amp;c., I am encouraged to draw upon your liberality in offering for insertion in your unique and promising Journal, a few
            “loose thoughts” by way of criticism upon the architecture
            of Trinity Church—the greatest work, I believe, now going
            on in this country.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>My design is to take up the different departments of this
            structure seriatim; and as it would occupy too much space
            to discuss them all in one article, I will content myself for
            the present by reviewing the interior of the building, viz.
            the Plaster Work of the Arches, Mouldings, &amp;c., there
            being here most room for criticism—and the blunders most
            palpable. Although differences of opinion may and do exist, in reference to the design and proportions of a style of
            Architecture, there can be no difference of opinion where the
            fundamental rules and first principles of Architectural Geometry and Perspective have been transgressed.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>At the present it is not my intention to censure either the
            Architect who planned, or the operative who executed, this
            work. My only desire being to call the attention of the
            public, in a manner as free from technicalities as I can, to the
            fact, that the work is really blundered; and that in its present state it ought not to be allowed to go down to future ages
            as a memorial of the perfection of Art in America in the middle of the Nineteenth Century.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But to our subject. Let the spectator upon entering the
            church, take a view of the intermediate ribs springing from
            the intersections in the main aisle, and then cast his eye upon
            the horizontal moulding, running across the church—and see
            if there be any symmetry or proportion betwixt these mouldings. Attend particularly to the intersections; for although
            they have been pared and patched to make them fit, still
            the incongruity is very striking to one accustomed to works
            of this description; aud sufficiently so to a common observer.
            But I shall be better understood after I explain the cause of
            the mistake,
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The intersections of the mouldings to which I refer, it will
            be observed, occur betwixt a straight line and curved lines of
            mouldings; and the rule in such a case is to rake the curved
            line; or in other words, to diminish the column of the curved
            mouldings, by geometrical calculation, to the necessary dimensions, calculating upon the angle of intersection, so that
            the square of the straight mouldings shall coincide, or intersect,
            with the oblique end of the curved moulding. And the practice is to construct the curved mouldings upon a smaller scale,
            in proportion to the radius of the curve. For this end it is the
            duty of the Architect, in drawing his plans and specifications,
            to give a scale of the exact dimensions of the model, or “Profile,” as it is technically called, by which the different mouldings are to be constructed; which, as any man having the
            least knowledge of Perspective or Geometry, will at once perceive, must be varied in size in a proportion diminishing as
            the curve increases, or as it departs from a right angle. It is
            surely easily seen that a moulding or a curved line, rising
            archwise, can no more intersect with the square side of a
            straight moulding of the same size, than that the perpendicular of a triangle can be of the same length with the hypothenuse—and thus to the eye of an observer, the curved mould-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>ings in general, and the intermediate ribs in particular,
            appear to be lying on their sides; leaving in perspective
            a most unnatural proportion to the straight mouldings.
            The truth of the matter is, and I challenge contradiction and
            discussion, for I am in a situation to prove what I now state, that the mouldings,
            whether straight or curved, were all
            formed by the same size of a model or profile; indicating an
            ignorance of Geometry and Perspective, leaving Architecture
            altogether out of view, truly astonishing in the present age,
            and in the very centre of the seat of the Arts and Sciences in
            the Western world, and in, as some think, the brightest star
            in our bright constellation—the Orion of New York—which,
            Mr. Editor, you have very happily adopted for the title of your Journal.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It may be insisted on by those ignorant of the laws of Perspective, that in this way the horizontal line will appear to the
            eye, as it really is in fact, larger than the curved line. No
            such thing: the very fact of the smaller moulding being curved, makes it appear larger to the eye of the observer than
            it would be if projected in a straight line, whilst the exactness of the intersection of the mouldings makes the whole
            construction harmonise with the spectator's ideas of perspective, whether to the eye of a painter or a sculptor. And this
            shows how beautifully the laws of perspective, belonging to
            the Fine Arts, harmonise with the truths of geometrical
            science.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The truth is, and there is no use in withholding it, that the
            architect appears to be ignorant of geometry. And it is a fact,
            that in order to get those incongruous mouldings to intersect
            as nearly as possible, the curved mouldings had all to be pared
            or scooped off, beginning several feet from the intersections,
            in order to bring them to the necessary diminution of column. Whereas, the whole imperfect work ought to have
            been pulled down immediately upon the error being discovered, and reconstructed upon correct scientific data. As it
            stands, it is a monstrosity and an eyesore.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But I believe that I have exceeded all reasonable bounds in
            this article. I have other strictures in reserve, in reference
            to other portions of the building, which I feel would not have
            been required had free scope been given to the talents of na-tive architects.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In your remarks under the title of “Monuments to Mr.
            Clay,” in the second number of your Journal, you state that
            “Gothic churches are out of character in the nineteenth century.” They may be so,
            but still I must respectfully
            differ with you in opinion, for I have never seen any other
            style or order of architecture so apt to enwrap the mind with
            solemn and devotional thought; still I acknowledge that
            where the laws of geometry and perspective are outraged, it
            has a very contrary effect.
         </p>
         <p>Yours, respectfully,	OPERATIVE.
            
         </p>
         <p>[We give place to the above communication, depending entirely upon
            the internal evidence of its correctness. We have never seen the interior of Trinity Church, but have taken it for granted that it could not
            be more perfect than the outside, which has errors enough. Stucco in
            any shape in the interior of such a structure is sufficiently out of character, but the architect must not be blamed in this respect, unless it
            were so finished by his recommendation. Any structure of the socalled Gothic order, must of necessity be an incongruous work, unless
            it be an exact copy, and then it must be unfit. Trinity Church is a
            very showy building, and it seems to satisfy the sentiment of the promenaders in Broadway very well; and it is also a very good object
            for the Wall street Brokers to contemplate, as they hurry to and
            from "the board,” reminding them, by its tall spire, to look up, occasionally. But considered as a work of architectural expression, as a
            house of worship, and as consuming money which should be devoted to religious purposes,
            it reflects but little credit upon those who have had the responsibility of its erection.—Ed.]
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page42"></div>
            0riginal Poetry.
            THE WREATH.
            (moM THE GERMAN OF UHLER.)
            BY MARIA LOWELL.
            She gathered many little flowers,
            The child, in sunny meadows fair;
            A lady slept from forest bowers,
            Of beauty wondrous rare.
            Before the child she stands so still,
            And binds a garland in her hair;
            "It blooms not now, but bloom it will;
            Oh, wear it ever there!”
            And when the child hath grown in years,
            And walks the holy moon beneath,
            And weepeth sweet and tender tears,—
            Then buds the little wreath.
            And when her dear and true bridegroom
            Doth fold her closely to her heart,
            Ah! then the flower's perfected bloom
            From every bud did start.
            And when a lovely child she bore,
            Rocked on her breast with mother’s care,
            The green and blossomed garland wore
            A golden fruitage rare.
            And when her love was sunken where
            The grave doth hold its night of grief,
            Then showed upon her careless hair
            The faded autumn leaf.
            Soon she lies white within the tomb,
            And soon her rightful wreath she gains;
            Such golden fruit and starry bloom
            We see not on our plains.
            BEATRICE.
            Thou gentle one, that in thy sweet youth ever
            Hast kept the glad heart nature gave to thee
            Untouched by any stain, and wholly free
            From passions fire, whose poisoned flame will sever
            Beauty and joy, which thus disparted, never
            Again on earth may re-united be.
            Art not some spiritual visitant to me,
            All gentleness and grace, without endeavor,
            Moving like Heaven’s serenest star at night!
            Thy features glowing with the radiant gleam
            Of happy thoughts, and innocent delight!
            Such will I think, for thou dost ever seem,
            Unto my better and enraptured sight,
            The incarnation of an angel’s dream !	
            J. A. 
            THE FALSE RINGLET.
            BY HARRY FRANCO.
            
         </p>
         <p>There arrived at the Quarantine ground, a few years ago,
            in one of the London packets, a young Englishman, named
            Cuthbert Daunton, who had been sent here to settle a disputed account, by a mercantile firm of which his brother
            was a partner. It was early in May, the ship had been a
            long while on her passage, and the young Englishman
            thought he had lighted in Paradise when the ship sailed up
            the Narrows, and the beautiful shores of Long Island and
            New Jersey, and the green hills of Staten Island, with their
            white cottages, were revealed to his sight. The day was
            bright and warm, the atmosphere so transparent that distant
            objects only appeared distant from their diminished size, and
            the waters of the bay sparkled in the sun. The distant city
            seemed to him an island of palaces rising out of the sea, and
            so impatient was he to behold its wonders, that he could not
            wait for the ship to be towed up by a steamer, but hired
            some boatmen to pull him up to the city in a cutter. He
            landed at the Battery, and although the objects which had
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>appeared to him like palaces at a distance proved to be
            nothing better than brick stores and dwelling houses, he
            saw enough of novelty and beauty to prevent a feeling of
            disappointment. He walked across the Battery, and entered
            the sunny side of Broadway at the Bowling Green. It was
            noon, and that noble avenue was crowded with life. Fine
            equipages and beautiful women passed and repassed him,
            until he was quite bewildered. It was true that he had
            been used all his life to the bustle and crowds of London;
            but here was something different. There was more show,
            glare, sunshine and freedom. And then the contrast to life
            on ship-board was so great, that the scene would have seemed to him brilliant, even though it had been less so than
            what he had been accustomed to at home. At first he only
            saw a great crowd of fine ladies, of beautiful children, and
            prancing horses; then he began to distinguish individuals,
            and at last he could select a single object, and survey its
            outline without confusion.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>He had not wandered far when he encountered a young
            lady who completely absorbed his attention, and drew his
            thoughts from himself, such was her exceeding loveliness of
            person. Her manner was graceful beyond that of any woman he had ever seen; her dress simple but elegant, her
            feet bewitching, and her complexion exceedingly fair. As he
            walked behind her, his eyes were fascinated by a long ringlet of chesnut-colored hair, which the motion of her head
            kept dancing up and down her white neck, as though it
            were striving to kiss the beautiful shoulder over which it
            was suspended. So completely was he captivated by this
            lock of glossy hair, that every time it moved it seemed to
            make a dent in his heart. He followed this young lady a
            long distance and at last saw her enter a large brick house,
            the number of which he immediately noted in his pocket
            book.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>When he returned to the ship, his fellow passengers asked
            him where he had been and what he had seen. He replied
            that he had been in Paradise and had seen an Angel. They
            laughed at him, but he resented their merriment. He was
            very much in love, and felt very solemn, as young lovers
            often do. The thought that he might never again behold
            the fair being who had bewitched him, made him feel sad
            and ill humored. Before going to a hotel, he called upon
            a friend of his brother, to whom he brought letters, and this
            gentleman, hearing that he had not engaged lodgings, recommended him to a private boarding house in Broadway.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>His delight was unbounded when he discovered that it
            was the same house into which he had seen his unknown
            beauty enter. Perhaps she was one of its inmates. Fortunately for him there was but one room vacant, which he
            immediately secured. When the hoarders assembled at supper, he looked anxiously round the table, but he saw no one
            who resembled the owner of the Chesnut Curl. He was
            afraid that she had only been an accidental visitor, and that
            he would never see her again. But the next day at dinner
            she made her appearance at table directly opposite to where
            he sat. He was so agitated at the sight of her, that he
            could not eat; and his embarrassment was greatly increased
            by his imagining that the boarders perceived his nervousness, and guessed the cause. He only looked at the young
            lady once, so fearful was he of attracting attention, and then
            he saw that same shining ringlet, resting, as if conscious of
            its happiness, on that fair neck, which he would have given
            his life, almost, to have encircled with his arm. In the
            evening the boarders were assembled in the drawing room,
            and among them appeared the beauty. She was more fascinating now than ever. Her dress seemed more becoming, and
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page43"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>she was more free in her manners. Somebody requested her
            to sing, and as she accompanied herself on the piano, Daunton’s passion became a fever. Her voice had a melting tenderness that made his heart swell as though it would burst.
            After her song was done she laughed and chatted pleasantly
            with the gentlemen about her, and her silent admirer felt as
            though he could have strangled them, for presuming to talk
            with her so freely. So selfish is love. Without ever having spoken to her or ascertained whether or not she cared a
            button about him, he had the audacity to look upon her as
            his own peculiar property. He heard her called Miss Giiston, and he asked one of the boarders with whom he had
            become acquainted, who she was. He was told that she was
            the niece of a Canton merchant in South street. The next
            evening he had the happiness to be introduced to her; and
            he sat by her side and talked with her until he was satisfied that she was not only the most beautiful, but the most
            intellectual woman in the world. And yet she hardly did
            anything but smile at what he said to her. But there was
            such a world of meaning in her monosyllables!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Daunton was a warm hearted youth, as may be well imagined, and notwithstanding that he was exceedingly prudent and wary in business affairs, when his feelings were
            touched, he was blind and impetuous. Scarcely a week
            had passed since he landed at the Battery, and he was the
            accepted lover of Miss Gilston. In another week they
            were married. It was a run-away match. When he asked
            the young lady about her parents, she Iet fall the lids of her
            beautiful eyes and wept. Was she an orphan? Her sobs
            prevented a reply; he saw that it was a painful subject to
            her, and interpreted her silence into an affirmative reply.
            He pressed her to his heart, and while he sympathized with
            her grief, he felt a secret pleasure in believing that she had
            no one to share with him in her affections. He had seen
            her uncle once or twice on ’Change, but had not been introduced to him. He knew him from the resemblance which
            she bore to him. He was a hearty looking florid complexioned old gentleman, but there was something in his manner
            which caused Daunton to fear him. He was apprehensive
            that national prejudices, or some other feeling, might lead
            the old gentleman to oppose the match, if he made a formal
            proposal for the hand of his niece, so he very prudently determined to get married first, and ask permission afterwards.
            The young lady herself acceded to his wishes with a readiness which made her doubly dear to him.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Nothing in the world can be easier than for two young persons who are favorably disposed towards each other, to run
            away from a boarding house and get married. A clergyman
            or a magistrate is always at hand, willing to perform the ceremony for a very trifling consideration. In truth, the very
            ease with which such an affair can be conducted, deprives it
            of one half its charms, and renders run-away matches much
            less frequent than they would be if they were more difficult.
            But Daunton had scarcely a spark of romance in his nature,
            that being a feeling which requires a lively imagination
            rather than strong passions. He abounded in the latter, but
            he had very little of the former. An imaginative person can
            be content with a very small substance, if it does but cast a
            large shadow, while strong passions require something that
            can be grasped and felt, rather than thought of.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Daunton had left London with an expectation of being
            admitted into his brother’s firm on his return, and as he
            possessed a moderate fortune which had been left to him by
            an uncle a few years before, he felt himself at full liberty to
            enter into a matrimonial engagement, without asking counsel of his friends. He had enjoyed but few opportunities of
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>mingling in the society of ladies at home, but he considered himself a very competent
            judge of their character. His brother had married a woman some five years older than
            himself, a prudent excellent person, with a small fortune, but dull and homely; and
            Daunton enjoyed the thought
            highly, of introducing to his family such a perfect miracle of loveliness as his affianced
            bride. The night before his marriage he wrote to his mother, and told her if he was as sure
            of meeting an angel at the portal of death as he was at the
            flower-wreathed portal of wedlock, he would not care how short a time he tarried in
            this world.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A fellow boarder with whom he had formed an intimacy,
            was his confidant, while a young lady, a boarder also in the
            same fashionable establishment, was the confidant of Miss
            Gilston. These two confidants, like the seconds in a duel,
            arranged the business part of the affair for the principals.
         </p>
         <p>This was the programme.
            The marriage to take place in the morning at a fashionable
            church in a fashionable square.
            The two confidants to be bridesmaid and groomsman.
            After the ceremony, the newly married couple to take pos-
            session of a suite of apartments in a fashionable hotel.
            
         </p>
         <p>The next morning go to West Point and spend a couple of
            days, to give time for the uncle’s wrath to evaporate, for he
            was to be informed of the marriage as soon as they left the
            city.
         </p>
         <p>Afterwards, to return, receive the congratulations of their
            friends, and be happy.
            
         </p>
         <p>Daunton’s business would not allow him to be absent a
            longer time, and he was too much of a merchant ever to
            allow his passions to interfere with his commercial arrangements. Furthermore he was impatient to get through with
            his business engagements, that he might return home and
            exhibit his beautiful bride to his friends. The morning of
            his marriage, as he was hurrying through Wall street to dispatch a letter before the ceremony took place, he met the
            bluff old captain of the packet in which he had crossed the
            ocean.
         </p>
         <p>“Hallo, Daunton,” cried the old sailor, “you are reeling
            off your log-line at a rapid rate this hot morning.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“Ah, Captain,” replied Daunton, “I am the happiest fellow in the world. I wouldn’t change places with George
            the Fourth, (it was during that king’s reign that these events
            took place,) there is not a merchant in Threadneedle street
            rich enough to buy an hour of my time. Good bye.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Keep an eye to leeward my fine fellow,” said the Captain,
            but the happy youth was out of hearing before the words
            were uttered.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Beautiful as Miss Gilston had appeared to Daunton when
            he first saw her, when she met him in her bridal dress, he
            thought that she had never looked beautiful before. And
            when the little party returned from church to the hotel, he
            insisted on sending for a miniature painter to take her portrait, lest she should never appear so lovely again. His
            bride was flattered by the request, and without thinking of
            the many sittings requisite for a portrait, the boarding house
            friend obligingly went in search of a painter.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“My love,” said the happy husband, “the first time that
            I saw you, you wore a long ringlet down your neck; I shall
            never forget it, and I wish that you had worn it to-day.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“0 my!” said she; “Martel dressed my hair this morn-ing, but if it will please you, my love, I will put on that
            lock of hair.” And going to her dressing bureau she took
            out a little paste-board box from which she drew the identical chesnut curl which had made so many indentations upon
            the soft heart of her lover as it had bobbed up and down her
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page44"></div>
            neck, and began to fasten it with a hair-pin of the same co-
            lour behind her ear.
            
         </p>
         <p>“0 heavens!” exclaimed the astonished bridegroom, “put
            it away, put it away. I beg you will never let me see it
            again.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It was the same sunny, riant curl; it had the same
            gloss; the same tone; the same crisp cork-screwish-look, as
            though it were made on purpose to worm itself into a tender heart. What was the matter, and where was the difference? We must leave this question to be answered by
            the philosophers. The fact was, that when Daunton discovered that the bewitching lock of hair, instead of growing
            behind his wife’s ear, had been fixed there by a pin, there
            was such a sudden revolution of his feelings, that instead of
            giving him excessive delight, as it had always done before,
            the sight of it gave him a dizziness in his head.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If Daunton had been a romantic man, the sentiment of
            the thing would have satisfied him as well in one case as in
            the other. But he was a matter-of-fact person.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>When his friend returned with the artist, the bridegroom
            had altered his mind, and thought that another time would
            be better. His wife resented this as an insult, and burst into tears. A little scene followed, the two friends withdrew,
            the curtain fell; and the next morning the lovers started on
            their two days’ jaunt. On their return, they found the
            bride’s uncle waiting for them in one of the private parlors
            of the hotel. Daunton felt quite relieved when be perceived
            that the old gentleman was in a pleasant humor. He rather
            chid them for their imprudent haste, but comforted them by
            reminding them that they had got plenty of time to repent
            in. Drawing Daunton into a corner of the room, he said:
            “It would have been better for you to have consulted with
            me in the matter first, because I could have made some arrangements which would have been of benefit to you hereafter. From what I have learned about you since this affair
            came to my knowledge, I can assure you that I am very proud of your alliance. I should
            have been happy to have
            had the privilege of giving Bell away—her name was Isabella—and as her mother and
            I have not been on good terms for a
            year or two back, it would have been a proper occasion for a
            reconciliation.”
         </p>
         <p>“Bell’s mother!” ejaculated the youth, aghast.
            Yes!
            
         </p>
         <p>The explanation was soon made. Bell was his natural
            daughter, but had passed for his niece for the express purpose
            of doing what she had so successfully accomplished—getting
            a husband.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Daunton stood for a moment, stunned, sick, delirious. But
            he soon broke out into a torrent of reproaches upon his guilty
            wife, who sat trembling upon a sofa. His sense of honor was
            exacting to fastidiousness. It wounded him to the soul to reflect that his wife, the being whom he had so blindly loved,
            had been guilty of falsehood. But she was his wife, and still
            beautiful, though she appeared so to him no longer. As for
            her father, he looked upon him with the most abhorrent feelings, and would never speak to him again.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Daunton was not a man to disguise his feelings, and thenceforth his tender affections to his wife were changed to cold civilities. She had been educated at a fashionable boarding
            school, and all her brilliant accomplishments proved to be a
            superficial knowledge of music and a smattering of French
            and Italian. Her sole pleasure was in dress; and nothing but
            the most extravagant compliments to her beauty, could keep
            her in good humor. She never got them from her husband,
            of course, and she sought them elsewhere.
         </p>
         <p>Daunton was thoroughly wretched. His business was
            nearly closed; his wife’s extravagance had involved him in
            
         </p>
         <p>debt; he was anxious to return to London, and he abhorred
            the thought of taking her with him, and he could not leave
            her behind. One evening he had been detained longer than
            usual at his business, and when he went to his apartment he
            found it in great confusion and his wife gone. He waited all
            night for her return, but she did not come. Grossly as she
            had deceived him in regard to her parentage, he had never
            for a moment suspected her fidelity; and the thought of her
            proving untrue, gave him a feeling of agony which he had
            never experienced before. In the morning a note was brought
            to him, informing him that the writer had taken his lady under his protection, and advising him not to trouble himself
            to look after her, as he had taken proper steps to prevent her
            retreat from being discovered.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Daunton suffered a terrible pang for a few moments, but it
            was soon over, and he was himself again. Once more he felt
            light hearted and happy. He had lived a century in six
            months. His business was closed, and he was ready to return to his friends, with a fund of experience which he little
            dreamed of ever possessing when he left home. The same
            packet in which he had crossed the Atlantic, was on the point
            of sailing again. He jumped on board of her to secure a
            berth, and met the old captain on the quarter deck.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Hah! Daunton!” exclaimed the Falstaff-looking sailor,
            “are you as happy now as when I met you that hot morning
            in Wall street?”
         </p>
         <p>“ Oh, a vast deal more so!” replied the wifeless husband;
            “then I thought I was happy—now I know that I am.”
            CITY CHIT-CHAT.
            
         </p>
         <p>The daily conversation of a great city is a matter of nearly
            as much consequence as its daily food; and the source
            whence it is derived is hardly less difficult to discover.
            There must always be a sweet morsel for the public tongue;
            and happy is the man or woman who escapes being rolled
            under it. Last year at this time there was but one question
            asked by any body; “ can there be a church without a Bishop?” Now this question is dropped, and we hear nothing
            on every side but “the Bishop.” Naughty people say to
            each other, “you are as bad as a Bishop.” Any stranger
            dropping among us now would think that he had lighted upon a community of polemics. The office of a Bishop is the
            most dangerous dignity that can be conferred upon a mortal.
            There are more notoriously bad bishops on record than of
            any other class of officials whether in church or state. The
            great bugbear of our infancy was Bishop Bruno, whom Southey has immortalized; and ever since we had a feeling for
            art we have had a grudge against the Bishops of Cologne,
            who wasted the money in unprofitable wars which should
            have been expended in finishing their Cathedral.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“A man of the world,” who had an ambition to share
            with the Bishop in his large portion of public attention, has
            given him a fraternal embrace, and is now fairly in for a share
            of public sentiment. It is amusing to look back upon any
            dead subject of public conversation, and analyse its claims to
            public attention. Who, now, cares two straws about William Morgan, Sam Patch, or Mary Rogers? And yet each
            of these individuals in turn formed the exclusive topic of
            public conversation. In a few days the Bishop will be let
            fall; and we shall hear of him no more, until some novelist
            half a century hence shall make him the hero of a novel!
            What humbugs we are and what humbugs we pursue.
            They say that Liszt, and Thalbergh and Taglioni, are coming over here. If they do, nothing else will be talked of for
            a time. The whale must have a tub to divert itself with, and
            perhaps a more innocent one could not be thrown to it than
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page45"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>a pianist or a dancer. Boz was the greatest “go,” as he
            would himself say, that we have ever had among us; and
            perhaps the uncertainty of popular favor was more forcibly
            illustrated in his case than in any other. As the city must
            have its topic of conversation, so must the nation; and it is
            marvellous how utterly worthless any subject will appear
            the moment it is dropped. Texas is the national topic of
            conversation, now; and truly it is a subject of such vast dimensions that we can hardly believe that it ever will seem
            less. But it must obey the laws of nature like all other matters, and next year we shall marvel that we were so excited
            about so trifling an affair. Our memory does not carry us
            back to the time of the Missouri question, but we remember
            very distinctly that an editor of a paper used, on the anniversary of the vote on that question, to publish the names in large
            black letters of all the northern men who voted in favor of
            it; and that he vowed to signalize the event by publishing
            the black list, as he called it, as often as the day returned.
            But the editor still publishes his paper, though it is a good
            many years since he has published his black list. Doubtless
            he thinks it was a very silly thing ever to have done so.
            Outward events are mere accidents; it is the inward feeling
            which is alone of any consequence. Whether Texas be annexed or not is a matter of less importance to us, than the
            desire to have it.
         </p>
         <p>THE MAGAZINES.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Democratic Review for January, contains, as we
            have already noticed, an admirable paper on the social inequalities of our condition, under the head of “What is the
            Reason?” which the editor felt himself called upon to assure
            his readers, in a note, contained some things which did not
            exactly correspond with his own views. In that case, he
            should either have stricken them out or made a more particular allusion to them, that his readers might know what his
            own views on an important topic are. There are, besides,
            a long paper on the Sheik of Alexandria and his slaves,
            translated by Mr. Spring, the author of Giafar Al Barmeki,
            from the German of Hauff; and a short paper on periodical
            reading, by Mrs. Clavers, which is the least readable of all
            her writings that we have seen. It appears to have been
            written for the express purpose of introducing the pun contained in the following paragraph:
         </p>
         <p>“If we have misunderstood this matter—if we have been conjuring
            up bugbears and spectres, let it be shown by argument and examples. If this be fairly
            proved, we shall be quite willing to see the ghosts of our imagination laid, like
            other unreal mockeries—in the Read-Sea.”
            
         </p>
         <p>The other papers, consisting of the Ghost of New-York by
            Cornelius Matthews, New England Philosophy, by H. T.
            Tuckerman. Family Flattery, by the Author of a Marriage
            of Convenience, and a Biography of Henry A. Muhlenburg,
            we have not found time to read.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Columbian Magazine for February, Vol. III. No. 2.
            We have only time to glance at the illustrations of Mr. Post’s
            magazine; two of them are from pictures by Chapman, and
            are much more effective as engravings than as paintings. The first is a view of the
            birth-place of Washington, engraved
            by Rawdon, Wright, Hatch, and Smilie; and the other the
            Desertion of Sergeant Champ, by R. Hinshelwood. They are
            both exceedingly fine engravings, and would show well by
            the side of many which are imported from abroad as chef d’
            oeuvres in English illustrated works.
         </p>
         <p>The American Review, a whig Journal of politics, Litera-
            ture and Science, No 1, January 1845.
            We think that the proprietor of this New Monthly Maga-
            
         </p>
         <p>zine made a very capital mistake in giving it a partisan
            name. It must have the tendency to array against it in the
            outset of its career the very persons whom its object should
            have been to conciliate, namely, its political opponents. It
            might have been as thoroughly and decidediy whig in its
            principles as it pleased to be without making any formal announcement of the fact. It may by this means gain a
            small degree of support from the party whose organ it professes to be, but then it can make no converts from the opposite party because they will never touch it. The papers are
            all fairly written, and we have no doubt that the known talents of the Editor will secure for it a profitable circulation.
            But we think that the political part of it requires a little more
            nerve to make it of efficient service to the party. The two
            portraits with which it is ornamented are the very finest
            specimens of that kind of Art that we have ever seen in any
            American work. That of Mr. Clay is the only good portrait
            of him that we have ever seen.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Hunt’s Merchant’s Magazine, No. 67, for January.—
            The age of this Magazine tells the whole story of its excellence. Nothing short of real merit could have kept it in existence more than a year; for it is chiefly patronized by those
            who are best able to judge of its value, and who are habitually used to laying out their money with a view to getting its
            full worth. The contents of the present number consist of six
            original articles—a monthly commercial chronicle, Mercantile
            Law department, and a number of valuable statistical tables.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Golden Rule, a weekly gazette, devoted to odd fellowship, literature and general intelligence. Vol. 1, No. 1, new
            series—New York, Saturday, January 4, 1845. Published
            every Saturday morning, by Houel and Macoy, 128 Fulton
            st.. Sun Buildings. A very neat paper, nearly the size of our
            own.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam’s News Letter for January.—This
            admirable Literary Gazette, in miniature, is one of the most
            useful of our monthly periodicals; and what is better, the
            cheapest paper ever published. It can be had for the asking.
            Some periodidals would be dear at the same rate. The
            News Letter is of great service to all classes who have any
            thing to do with books, whether as readers, writers, or teachers; besides containing a good many interesting scraps for
            people in general. If a price were put upon it, we have no
            doubt that its circulation would be greatly increased. The
            publishers should remember the case of the man who stood
            all day on old London Bridge, trying to sell a guinea for a
            sixpence, without finding a purchaser. Dr. Johnson said, a
            good while ago, in reference to giving away books, that people were very apt to consider things as good for nothing
            which cost nothing.
         </p>
         <p>NEW PUBLICATIONS.
            The Conspiracy against the late Bishop of New York, by James C.
            Richmond. Price 12 1-2 cents. Burgess &amp; Stringer.
            
         </p>
         <p>Vestiges of the Natural History of Creation, attributed to the author of the Architecture of the Heavens. 1 vol. 12mo. Price 85 cents.
            Wiley &amp; Putnam.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A Letter to a Friend, in Reply to a recent Pamphlet from the Missionaries of the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, at Constantinople. By the Right Rev. Horatio Southgate. Appleton &amp; Co. Price 12 1-2 cents.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>St. Ignatius and his Companions. By the Rev. Charles Constantine
            Pise, D. D. author of “History of the Church,” “Father Rowland,” See
            New York: published by Edward Dunigan, 151 Fulton street. 1845.
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page46"></div>
            THE CONCERT ROOM.
            PHILHARMONIC SOCIETY-
            
         </p>
         <p>The second Concert of the third season of this Society took place
            on Saturday evening last at the Apollo Saloon. The arrangements for
            seating the visitors were so excellent, that though the audience were
            quite as numerous as at the first concert, when numbers had to stand
            all the evening, scarcely a dozen persons were without seats on this
            occasion. It is truly a pleasing reflection, when we think of the success
            of this admirable Society, for we are compelled to believe that the
            cause of true music is gaining a large number of advocates among the
            best classes of society, and the public at large. The “profession”
            have always been accused of giving breath to an unlimited quantity
            of cant respecting classical music; they have been charged with envy,
            malice, and prejudice, because they have set up as their standard of
            excellence, the great German writers, Haydn, Mozart, Beethoven, Weber, Mendelssohn,
            and others, in opposition to the more popular and pleasing, though less sterling Italian
            composers, Bellini, Donizet-ti, Marliani, and others. That the profession have been
            misjudged, we
            fearlessly assert, and we will also say, that the public have shown but
            little wisdom in setting up their opinion against the opinion of those
            who, from education, study, and practice, must be the most capable of judging of the
            merits of the various styles. But though the public pretend to despise the opinion of the profession, yet, in the case of this
            Society, they condescendingly consented to be led by it in the first instance, and have gladly followed it ever since.
         </p>
         <p>The programme was as follows:
            PART I.
            Symphony No. 3.	                  Haydn.
            1.	Adagio cantabile e vivace Assai.
            2.	Andante.
            3.	Minuetto and Trio, Allegro Molto.
            4. Finale, Allegro di Molto.
            Grand Scena from Der Freischutz; Mrs. Ed
            ward Loder.	                                      C. M. Weber
            Concertino, Clarionet—1st. time; Mr. W. T. 
            Greenevelt.	                                       C. M. Weber
            PART II.
            Overture to Jessonda—1st. time.	                    L. Spohr.
            Aria Del per questo istante, from the Opera of 
            La Clemenza di Tito; Mrs. E. Loder.                   Mozart.
            Quartette in Canone, from the Opera of Fidelio;
            Mrs. E. Loder, Miss De Luce,	                   Beethoven.
            Messrs. Munson and Massett.
            Descriptive Overture—Le Vampyr (1st. time.) H. Marschner.
            Conductor,	Mr. U. C. Hill.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Symphony is the second work by Haydn, ever performed by
            this Society. We have, from the first, urged the committee to place
            some of his delicious compositions before the public, being perfectly
            aware that their exquisitely simple beauty would win upon the hearts
            of the people by an irresistible fascination. But year after year passed
            by, and our suggestions were unattended to, but at last he is brought
            forward, and though under every disadvantage, the people having become accustomed to the wonderful works of Beethoven, Spohr, and
            Mendelssohn, yet how fresh and lovely his creations seem; to us
            they have ever a flavor of Spring; they are associated in our minds
            with the perfume of violets, the bursting forth of buds, the blossoming
            of odorous May; they seem to us as the voice of Nature, chanting
            forth songs of praise and gladness; their sentiment is Love and Hope,
            and their feeling, youth! fresh, vernal, unsophisticated youth!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Of the four movements of symphony No. 3, the andante is certainly
            the favorite; the subject is simple and familiar to every one, under the
            name of Haydn’s Surprise. It is a short theme of some sixteen bars,
            carried on through all the movement, but so exquisitely varied that
            the ear is positively surfeited with its sweetness. This movement was
            loudly applauded and seemed to give much satisfaction. The great fault in the other
            movements is that they are too short. Before the mind can take note of their construction
            or appreciate their beauties, lo! they have ceased. With the last movement this was
            particularly
            the case.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>An apology was made for Mrs. E. Loder, as she was laboring under the effects of a severe cold. From Christmas day up to the 3d inst.
            she entirely lost her voice, and only one day before the concert was
            she able to sing the songs of her compass. Mrs. E. Loder has gained
            a very enviable reputation in this city; among Musicians and true
            connoiseurs of the art, she is looked upon as the only classical singer
            in the country. Her pure and unsophisticated style, correct intona-tion, smooth and
            flowing execution, perfect shake and pure taste, the
            results of a first rate education, render her admirably suited to main-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>tain the position to which she has been raised by public opinion. Her
            execution of the difficult scena from Der Freyschutz called forth repeated bursts of applause. The band accompanied this scena and indeed all the solos, in a very slovenly and unartist-like manner. It was
            evident to every one that they had either not rehearsed them or they
            were determined not to play them well. In either case it is a slur upon themselves—a blot upon their reputation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Weber’s concertino for the clarinet, was performed in a most masterly manner by Mr. Groenevelt. His tone is sweet yet rich and full;
            his execution is delicate and finished in the highest degree; his style
            is chaste, pure and impassioned, and his expression is that of a man
            who feels the power of music in his heart.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Spohr’s overture is a miracle of beauty, even when contrasted with
            his other great compositions. He is a model in every way; in
            thought, construction and instrumentation. We will not attempt to
            describe it, for we have already exceeded our prescribed limits; we
            will only say that it was encored by a few determined spirits, and
            rapturously and unanimously applauded on its repetition.
         </p>
         <p>Mozart’s Del per questa istante was exquisitely sung by Mrs. E. Lo-
            der and warmly applauded. It was very badly accompanied.
            
         </p>
         <p>Beethoven’s Quartette was an injudicious selection, it being out of its
            situation, by no means an effective composition. It was very badly
            sung. Miss De Luce, though possessing naturally, a very fine voice,
            was too much under the influence of fear to do herself justice; Mr.
            Munson is in no way calculated to sing the style of music, and the
            compass and quality of voice required to do it justice is not possessed
            by Mr. Massett.
         </p>
         <p>Marschner’s Overture, Der Vampyr, is a grand, spirited and effective
            composition, and was played in admirable style.
            
         </p>
         <p>To Mr. U. C. Hill is due the credit of this admirable Concert. He
            is in truth most wonderfully improved in his method of conducting.
            The performance of Jessonda was equal to any previous performance.
            Mr. Hill seemed to be imbued with the spirit of the composer, and by
            judiciously subduing some portion of the orchestra to allow the
            points in the other instruments to appear, he produced to perfection the
            Author’s idea. We sincerely congratulate him on his success.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Messrs. J. A. Kyle, Wiese, Groenevelt, Reiff and Trosji, also demand our warm commendation for their admirable performance
            throughout the concert.
         </p>
         <p>Varieties.
            
         </p>
         <p>Fashion.—We have noticed recently in Broadway, several gentlemen wearing a kind of short cloak, rather profusely
            decorated with gimp and frogs; and with most preposterously long sleeves, slashed up to the bend of the elbow. It
            is a very singular dress, and seems to have been copied almost exactly from the fashion which prevailed in England
            during the reign of Henry VII. The dandies in those days
            shaved their beards close, but wore their hair very long;—
            their caps were enormously large, and ornamented with
            feathers of various colors, the stem of each one being profusely decorated with pearls and jewels. Our dandies have
            rejected all these showy ornaments, and are beginning to let
            their beards grow, which is an indication of greater refinement.
            But the long hanging sleeves have a very suspicious squint-ing at some greater enormity to be introduced by-and-bye.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal.—Last Saturday, January 4, brought into
            the world of publishment—as Mr. Willis would say—the first number
            of a new weekly entitled the Broadway Journal; and we have rarely
            known a better first appearance. The articles are somewhat too long,
            but they are vigorously written and the choice of subjects is good.
            Criticism appears to be the staple, and it is sharp enough, without being captious or ill-natured. A striking feature of the number is the
            best wood engraving we ever saw in any paper, daily or weekly. It
            represents a lady in the fashion of the day; the texture and folds of
            the dress are presented with a truth and delicacy which we thought
            unattainable upon wood. It reminds one much of that famous copper-plate engraving known as “the white satin dress.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We copy the above from the Commercial Advertiser, not
            for the sake of what it says of our Journal, though we value
            highly the good opinion of so respectable an authority, but
            for the sake of the commendation bestowed on the engraving
            in our first number. We were determined, if possible, to
         </p>
         <p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page47"></div>
            
         </p>
         <p>give an instance of art in this important department, equal
            to what we see in French and German works, and by chance
            we stumbled upon an American artist, recently returned from
            Paris, who produced the cut alluded to above. The design
            was one of Gavarni’s. W ith hardly a degree of exaggeration,
            it offered the keenest satire upon the wicked absurdities of
            fashion that could have been given. For lack of good ink and
            a suitable press, the impression in our paper gives but a very
            imperfect idea of the beauty of the cut. It is a singular fact,
            but good ink for wood engravings cannot be procured in this
            country. We shall exert ourselves to give good cuts hereafter, and trust to make our Journal in this particular greatly
            superior to anything ever seen here of home production.
            The public do not seem to appreciate excellence in works of
            this class, but they will come round as good examples are
            presented to them.
         </p>
         <p>DISHONORABLE AFFAIRS.
            
         </p>
         <p>We give the account of two bloodless duels, which have taken place
            at the South during the present week. In the daily papers, we find
            them recorded under the head of affairs of honor; but it strikes us, that such affairs
            would become less frequent, if the press would alter
            this kind of heading for the one that we have given above. A bloodless
            duel is much more to be deplored than a bloody one, for it holds out a
            hope to cowards that they may engage in such affairs with impunity.
            Between natives at the North, a duel is of rare occurrence; why they
            should be more frequent at the South, we never could well understand.
            Perhaps it is owing to their domestic institutions. The most tragic
            termination of a duel that we have heard of in some time, occurred in
            this neighborhood not long since. A foreign gentleman conceiving
            himself to have been insulted by his friend, sent him a challenge,
            which was accepted, and when the parties assembled in Hoboken, the
            challenger fainted dead away. All concerned except the timid gentleman were in great fume, and a scene occurred something like that between Acres and Sir Lucius O’Trigger. But the Sir Lucius in this case,
            insisted that his friend should either fight, or submit to be spat upon.
            Another challenge was then sent, the parties were promptly on the
            ground, the challenger stepped forward, the pistol was put in his hand;
            when away he went again in a swoon. It might have been only a feint But the poor gentleman was given up as a hopeless case, and the duel
            was indefinitely postponed.
         </p>
         <p>Washington, Jan. 14, 1845-
            
         </p>
         <p>The duel between Mr. Clingham and Mr. Yancey, came off yesterday afternoon, about three miles from Bladensburg. The weapons
            were pistols—-distance ten paces. Lieut. Huger, a son of Senator Huger of South Carolina, it was said was Mr. Yancey’s second, and a
            Mr. Charles L. Jones, a son of Gen. Walter Jones of this city, is reported to have been Mr. Clingham’s second. I have heard the names
            of a number of gentlemen who were present as their "friends,” but I
            need not make their names public, several Policemen arrived on the
            ground just as they were about to fire.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Had it not been for this, which hurried the operation, it might have ended more fatally.
            The word was "Ready—Fire, one, two, three.” Both fired in haste on account of the
            arrival of the Police—blazing
            away at the word "Fire” in place of waiting for "one,” “ two,” and "three.” Mr. Yancey
            fired by raising his pistol, Mr. Clingham by dropping his. Mr. C.’s ball struck the
            "vacant air” and Mr. Y.’s hit the
            ground.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The seconds then interferred. Mr. C. said he meant nothing personal to any Member of the House; and Mr. Y. withdrew his remarks
            or they fell to the ground like his ball, and struck nobody. So the
            gentlemen, who were not so before they fired, were so afterward, and
            the matter was amicably settled. Thus ends this foolish piece of business.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A hostile meeting was had between Mr. Thomas Butler King and
            Mr. Chas. Spaulding, on Monday, the 6th instant, at Amelia Island. Werpons, pistols—distance,
            ten paces.—Two shots were passed without effect, when, at the intervention of friends,
            the affair was adjusted, and the parties exchanged friendly salutations.
         </p>
         <p>The difficulty originated from some circumstances connected with the recent canvass
            of the two gentlemen while candidates for Congress
            be fore the people of this District.	[Sav. Republican.
            
         </p>
         <p>NOTICES TO READERS AND CORRESPONDENTS.—Our
            next number will contain a very superior engraving from an original
            design by one of the most promising artists in the country, of a highly
            humorous, and at the same time, truthful character; illustrative of some
            of our literary magnates.
         </p>
         <p>G. W. E. will find a communication addressed to him at our publisher’s
            office.
            The verses by G. H. will not do for our columns.
            DISEASES OF THE TEETH.
            Washington, D.C., May, 1844.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
            and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
            The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
            professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
            Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
            cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
            the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
            durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
         </p>
         <p>Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo. 
            Joshua Herrick, Me.	
            James Irvin, Pa.	
            Hon. John B. Dawson, La.
            John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
            J. Thompson, Miss.
            Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York
            LEWIS KATEN, SIGN AND ORNAMENTAL PAINTER,
            NO. 45 WILLIAM STREET,
            (basement of the leather manufacturers’ bank.)
            Block Letter Signs, Transparencies, Banners, &amp;c., Executed in the
            neatest manner.
            SPLENDID BOOKS
            SUITABLE FOR PRESENTS.
            JUST received by the subscribers, a large assortment
            
         </p>
         <p>of Splendidly Illustrated and Standard Books, all of which are
            offered for sale at reduced prices. In their collection may be found
            many costly works never before offered for sale in the United States.
            Among them are the following:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>DANIELS’ ILLUSTRATIONS OF ORIENTAL SCENERY—
            coloured in the most beautiful manner, in imitation of the original
            drawings. 6 vols. elephant folio, elegantly bound; original cost,
            $1200; reduced to $300.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>SELBY’S BIRDS OF GREAT BRITAIN— (in the style of Audubon’s Birds of America). 2 vols. elephant folio; original cost,
            $600 ; reduced to $180.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>CHAMBERLAYNE’S DRAWINGS OF THE OLD MASTERS
            —being facsimiles of the most celebrated of the Roman, Florentine, and Venetian Schools. Folio; original cost, $105; reduced
            to $28,00.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>CORONATION OF GEORGE THE FOURTH—illustrated with
            splendidly coloured Drawings, in which the portraits are taken
            from life. Folio; original cost, $262; reduced to $75,00.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>PLOOS VAN AMSTEL'S IMITATION OF DRAWINGS OF
            THE PRINCIPAL DUTCH AND FLEMISH MASTERS—
            consisting of 100 engravings. 3 vols. folio; original cost, $315;
            reduced to $90,00.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>MEYRICK'S PAINTED ILLUSTRATIONS OF ANCIENT
            ARMS AND ARMOR—the plates illuminated with Gold and Silver. 3 vols. folio; original cost, $105; reduced to $65,00.
         </p>
         <p>A Catalogue embracing 25,000 volumes of valuable Books, in every
            department of knowledge, may be had gratis, on application.
            BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, 7 Astor House.
            GRAHAME’S UNITED STATES.
            THE HISTORY OF THE UNITED STATES OF
            
         </p>
         <p>NORTH AMERICA, from the plantation of the British Colonies
            till their revolt and Declaration of Independence. By James Grahame, Esq. In four volumes.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The work will be put to press as soon as two hundred and fifty
            copies are subscribed for. It will be printed in an elegant style, equal
            to the last London edition, in four volumes octavo, and delivered to
            subscribers at two dollars a volume, in extra cloth binding.
         </p>
         <p>Subscribers names received and the books delivered by
            WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, New York.
            The Exploring Expedition.
            LEA &amp; BLANCHARD are preparing for publication,
            
         </p>
         <p>and will shortly issue, the Narrative of the United States
            Exploring Expedition, during the years 1838, 1839,1840, 1841, and
            1842, by CHARLES WILKES, U.S.N., Commander of the Expedition, etc., etc., in five magnificent large imperial octavo volumes,
            with an Atlas of Large and Extended Maps. Price Twenty-five
            Dollars to Subscribers, done up in beautiful Extra Cloth Binding.
         </p>
         <p>JOHN DOUGLAS,
            BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            
         </p>
         <p>NO. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every de-scription of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
            with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, on terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
         </p>
         <p>January 16, 1845.
            
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page48"></div>,
            GENEALOGY OF GEORGE WASHINGTON.
            THIS day is published by Wm. A, COLMAN, No. 203
            
         </p>
         <p>Broadway, the Genealogy of George Washington, the celebrated Patriot. It is beautifully engraved, splendidly printed in gold
            and colors, and illuminated with the armorial bearings of the Washington Family and its alliances for a period of many centuries past;
            exhibiting at one view a complete family history. A space is left sufficiently large for any person who may desire to have his arms emblazoned on this elegant work, before he has it framed. Price $1,50.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Arms and Crests of individuals of all nations, found and emblazoned, equal in execution and correctness to the Herald’s College
            of London, at reasonable charges.
         </p>
         <p>PROPOSALS FOR PUBLISHING BY SUBSCRIPTION,
            TRANSACTIONS
            OF THE
            Ethonological Society of New York.
            VOLUME I.
            
         </p>
         <p>THIS volume will consist of articles by members of the Ethnological Society, relating
            to various topics of interest to the
            Antiquary and Philologist. It will consist of from four to five hundred
            pages 8vo., printed on good paper and in the best manner.
         </p>
         <p>A number of engravings illustrative of the several papers, will ac-
            company the volume.
            CONTENTS OF THE VOLUME.
            Art. I. Notes on the Semi-civilized Nations of Mexico, Yucatan, and
            Central America. By Albert Gallatin.
            Sec. 1st. Languages.—Vocabularies, grammar, derived and com-
            pounded words.
            2d. Numeration.—Vigintesimal.
            3d. Calendars and Astronomy.—Mexico, Yucatan, Chiapas.
            —Extent of Astronomical knowledge.
            
         </p>
         <p>4th. History and Chronology.—Paintings designating years;
            only four known.—Tradition; early writers discussed.—
            Uncertainty of dates and events.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>5th. Conjectures on origin of semi-civilization in America.—America inhabited at a very early date.—Astronomy.—Agriculture.—Extinct race.</p>
         <p>No. 1. Appendix.—Grammatical notices.—Mexican, Tarasca,
            Ottomi, Maya, Guatemala, Huestaca.
            No. 2.	"Notes on Lord Kingsborough’s collection.
            
         </p>
         <p>—All paintings, but one, Mexican.—All but four relate to
            Mythology and Judicial Astrology.—Codices Borgianus
            and Vaticanus.
         </p>
         <p>Art. II. An Essay on the Grave-Creek Mound in the Ohio Valley.—
            By Henry R. Schoolcraft, embracing:
            1st. A description of the Tumulus, its dimensions and mode of
            structure.
            2d. An accurate drawing and description of the Inscription found
            in one of the vaults.
            
         </p>
         <p>3d. Other antiquarian articles disclosed by the opening of that
            mound, or found in other parts of the Grave-Creek Valley
            and its neighborhood.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>4th. Conjectures upon the character of the Alphabet, and the
            probable era of the Inscription, &amp;c. The whole illustrated
            with carefully executed plates.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Art. III. A Dissertation on some curious evidences of an Era of Ancient Semi-civilization in the West, noticed in the progress
            of settlements in the Mississippi Valley and the Lakes. By
            Henry R. Schoolcraft.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Description of some extensive Horticultural Beds and Furrows,
            found in the prairies and forests of the Lake Region, about
            the latitude of the sources of the Ilinois and St. Joseph’s,
            with an engraving.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Art. IV. An account of Ancient Remains in Tennessee. By Gerard
            Troost, M. Prof, of Chemistry, Geology, &amp;c. in the
            University of Tennessee.
         </p>
         <p>1.	The Mummies found in the Saltpetre Caves, with conjectures
            as to their antiquity.
            2.	The ancient Burial Places.
            3.	Traces of Phallic Worship among a people once occupying that
            section of country.
            
         </p>
         <p>Art. V. On the recent discoveries of Himyaritic Inscriptions, and the
            attempts made to decipher them. By Wm. W. Turner.
            Kingdom of the Himyarites.—Discovery of Inscriptions.
            Himyaritic Alphabet.—Alphabets found in Manuscripts.—
            Alphabets from the Inscriptions.—Ethiopic Alphabets.
            Himyaritic Language—Ehkili Language.-—General results.
            Art. VI. A visit to the Lybio-Phoenician Monument at Dugga, near
            the site of ancient Carthage. By Frederic Catherwood.
            With an account of the inscription; and a view and ground
            plan of this ancient and interesting monument.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Art. VII. An Account of the Serreculies, or Serranalies, with hints re-specting several other tribes or families of people composing
            the Fullah nation, and those inhabiting the neighboring
            Counties of Western Nigritia. By Theodore Dwight, Jr.
         </p>
         <p>1.	The statements of authors respecting the Serreculies.
            2.	The Geography, History, Learning, Arts, &amp;c., of the Serrecu-
            lies.
            3.	Their Language.
            4.	Remarks on Neighboring Nations and Tribes.
            Subscriptions received by BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, Booksellers
            and Importers, 7 Astor House, New.York.
            PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY
            AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
            
         </p>
         <p>Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
            the Medal, four first Premiums, and two “Highest Honors,” at the
            Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
            the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
            at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
            the score of economy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American Instruments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polishing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received
            promptly attended to.
         </p>
         <p>Mrs. Sigourney’s Pictorial Reader.
            
         </p>
         <p>THE PICTORIAL READER, for the Use of Schools, consisting of Original Articles for the Instruction of Young Children.
            By Mrs. L. H. Sigourney. Being an Introduction to the Boy’s Reading Book and Girl’s Reading Book, by the same author, illustrated
            by nearly One Hundred aed Fifty Engravings. A very interesting and
            instructive Book for Children, whether in school or out. Published by
            TURNER &amp; HAYDEN, No. 10 John Street,
         </p>
         <p>And for sale by all the Booksellers.
            The First Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for
            the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            GOLDSMITH'S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
            NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
            tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
            in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms—Five Dollars.
            
         </p>
         <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
            course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
            Stationary. Payable at the commencement.
         </p>
         <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen,
            and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            For sale “Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
            Price Five Dollars.
            
         </p>
         <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27. 1844.
            Goldsmith’s Gems of Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is,
            much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
            Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
            volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
            of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
         </p>
         <p>From the New York Express.
            
         </p>
         <p>Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship.—We have seen the original, as
            executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
            wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
            to be "more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
         </p>
         <p>CHARLES PERABEAU, Professor of Music,
            No. 9 Whitehall Street, New York.
            Prospectus of the Broadway Journal.
            To be Published every Saturday.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have cither elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
            to make it worthy of patronage.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers in the country; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may “let loose their
            thoughts,” will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate.
            It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octave form of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum—Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.
            A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.
            All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor
            of the Broadway Journal, and all letters on business to
            JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.
            John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      
      <div>
         
         
         <span class="person"></span>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>