<div>
   <div class="issueId">18451213</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         
         <br></br>VOL. 2.    EDGAR A. POE, EDITOR AND PROPRIETOR.     NO. 23.
         
         <br></br>NEW-YORK, SATURDAY, DECEMBER 13, 1845.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
       
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p1">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Office of the Broaday Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">349</div>
         <p>The Office of the Broadway Journal is removed to
            304 Broadway, corner of Duane.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Coquette's Song</div>
         <div class="biblPage">349</div>
         
         <div class="head">Coquette’s Song.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            
            <br></br>Ah yes—gentle sir—I will own
            
            <br></br>I ne’er saw perfection till now;
            
            <br></br>That I never—no never—have known
            
            <br></br>A smile such as yours—I’ll allow.
            
            <br></br>And your eyes—Oh, they speak to the soul
            
            <br></br>With their glances as bright as the day!
            
            <br></br>But I mean to keep my heart whole—
            
            <br></br>So away with your love-vows—away.
            
            <br></br>Away—Away—
            
            <br></br>Away with your love-vows—away!
            
            <br></br>Ah! ne’er such a voice, I’ll confess,
            
            <br></br>In its low, murmuring tones have I heard, 
            
            <br></br>So deep with emotion’s excess—
            
            <br></br>Yet soft as the tones of a bird. 
            
            <br></br>Oh! the thrilling and sweet melody
            
            <br></br>Might melt any heart to your sway— 
            
            <br></br>But dearly I love to be free—
            
            <br></br>So away with your love-vows—away—
            
            <br></br>Away—away—
            
            <br></br>Away with your love-vows—away!
            
            <br></br>No, no—I assure you ’tis vain
            
            <br></br>To sigh, and to plead, and to woo.;
            
            <br></br>But I’ll own, if I could wear a chain,
            
            <br></br>I would have it—yes—woven by you.
            
            <br></br>Some future time—may be—but now
            
            <br></br>I’ll be free as a bird on the spray!
            
            <br></br>I wont—wont be fettered—I vow;
            
            <br></br>So away with your love-talk—away—
            
            <br></br>Away—away.
            
            <br></br>Away with your love.talk—away!
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Elizabeth F. Ellet</span>.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p3">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Oblong Box</div>
         <div class="biblPage">349</div>
         <div class="head">The Oblong Box.</div>
         
         <p>Some years ago, I engaged passage from Charleston, S. C., to
            the city of New York, in the fine packet-ship “Independence,”
            Captain Hardy. We were to sail on the fifteenth of the month
            (June,) weather permitting; and, on the fourteenth, I went on
            board to arrange some matters in my state-room.
         </p>
         
         <p>I found that we were to have a great many passengers, including a more than usual number of ladies. On the list were
            several of my acquaintances; and, among other names, I was rejoiced to Bee that of Mr. Cornelius Wyatt, a young artist, for
            whom I entertained feelings of warm friendship. He had been
            with me a fellow student at C――― University, where we were
            very much together. He had the ordinary temperament of genius,
            and was a compound of misanthropy, sensibility, and enthusiasm.
            To these qualities he united the warmest and truest heart which
            ever beat in a human bosom.
         </p>
         
         <p>I observed that his name was carded upon three state-rooms;
            and, upon again referring to the list of passengers, I found that
            he had engaged passage for himself, wife, and two sisters—his
            own. The state-rooms were sufficiently roomy, and each had
            two berths, one above the other. These berths, to be sure, were
            so exceedingly narrow as to be insufficient for more than one
            person; still, I could not comprehend why there were three staterooms for these four persons. I was, just at that epoch, in one
            of those moody frames of mind which make a man abnormally
            inquisitive about trifles; and I confess, with shame, that I busied
            myself in a variety of ill-bred and preposterous conjectures about
            this matter of the supernumerary state-room. It was no business
            of mine, to be sure; but with none the less pertinacity did I occupy myself in attempts to resolve the enigma. At last I reached
            a conclusion which wrought in me great wonder why I had not
            arrived at it before, “It is a servant, of course,” I said; “what
            a fool I am, not sooner to have thought of so obvious a solution!”
            And then I again repaired to the list—but here I saw distinctly
            that no servant was to come with the party; although, in fact,
            it had been the original design to bring one—for the words “and
            servant” had been first written and then overscored. “Oh, extra
            baggage to be sure,” I now said to myself—“something he wishes
            not to be put in the hold—something to be kept under his own
            eye—ah, I have it—a painting or so—and this is what he has
            been bargaining about with Nicolino, the Italian Jew.” This
            idea satisfied me, and I dismissed my curiosity for the nonce.
         </p>
         
         <p>Wyatt’s two sisters I knew very well, and most amiable and
            clever girls they were. His wife he had newly married, and I
            had never yet seen her. He had often talked about her in my
            presence, however, and in his usual style of enthusiasm. He
            described her as of surpassing beauty, wit, and accomplishment.
            I was, therefore, quite anxious to make her acquaintance.
         </p>
         
         <p>On the day is which I visited the ship, (the fourteenth,) Wyatt
            and party were also to visit it—so the captain informed me—and
            I waited on board an hour longer than I had designed, in hope of
            being presented to the bride; but then an apology came. “Mrs.
            W. was a little indisposed, and would decline coming on board
            until to-morrow, at the hour of sailing.”
         </p>
         
         <p>The morrow having arrived, I was going from my hotel to the
            wharf, when Captain Hardy met me and said that, “owing to
            circumstances,” (a stupid but convenient phrase,) “he rather
            thought the ‘Independence’ would not sail for a day or two, and
            that when all was ready, he would send up and let me know.”
            This I thought strange, for there was a stiff southerly breeze;
            but as “the circumstances” were not forthcoming, although I
            pumped for them with much perseverance, I had nothing to do
            but to return home and digest my impatience at leisure.
         </p>
         
         <p>I did not receive the expected message from the captain for
            nearly a week. It came at length, however, and I immediately
            wont on board. The ship was crowded with passengers, and
            everything was in the bustle attendant upon making sail. Wyatt’s
            party arrived in about ten minutes after myself. There were the
            two sisters, the bride, and the artist—the latter in one of his customary fits of moody misanthropy. I was too well used to these,
            however, to pay them any especial attention. He did not even
            
            
            introduce me to his wife;—this courtesy devolving, perforce, upon
            his sister Marian—a very sweet and intelligent girl, who, in a
            few hurried words, made us acquainted.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mrs. Wyatt had been closely veiled; and when she raised her
            veil, in acknowledging my bow, I confess that I was very profoundly astonished. I should have been much more so, however,
            had not long experience advised me not to trust, with too inplicit
            a reliance, the enthusiastic descriptions of my friend, the artist,
            when indulging in comments upon the loveliness of woman.
            When beauty was the theme, I well knew with what facility he
            soared into the regions of the purely ideal.
         </p>
         
         <p>The truth is, I could not help regarding Mrs. Wyatt as a decidedly plain-looking woman. If not positively ugly, she was
            not, I think, very far from it. She was dressed, however, in exquisite taste—and then I had no doubt that she had captivated
            my friend’s heart by the more enduring graces of the intellect and
            soul. She said very few words and passed at once into her stateroom with Mr. W.
         </p>
         
         <p>My old inquisitiveness now returned. There was no servant
            —that was a settled point. I looked, therefore, for the extra
            baggage. After some delay, a cart arrived at the wharf, with an
            oblong pine box, which was everything that seeemed to be expected. Immediately upon its arrival we made sail, and in a
            short time were safely over the bar and standing out to sea.
         </p>
         
         <p>The box in question was, as I say, oblong. It was about six
            feet in length by two and a half in breadth;—I observed it attentively, and like to be precise. Now this shape was peculiar;
            and no sooner had I seen it, than I took credit to myself for the
            accuracy of my guessing. I had reached the conclusion, it will
            be remembered, that the extra baggage of my friend, the artist,
            would prove to be pictures, or at least a picture; for I knew he
            had been for several weeks in conference with Nicolino:—and
            now here was a box which, from its shape, could possibly contain nothing in the world but a copy of Leonardo’s “Last Supper and a copy of this very “Last Supper,” done by Rubini
            the younger, at Florence, I had known, for some time, to be in
            the possession of Nicolino. This point, therefore, I considered
            as sufficiently settled. I chuckled excessively when I thought of
            my acumen. It was the first time I had ever known Wyatt to
            keep from me any of his artistical secrets; but here he evidently
            intended to steal a march upon me, and smuggle a fine picture to
            New York, under my very nose; expecting me to know nothing
            of the matter. I resolved to quiz him well, now and hereafter.
         </p>
         
         <p>One thing, however, annoyed me not a little. The box did not
            go into the extra state-room. It was deposited in Wyatt's own;
            and there, too, it remained, occupying very nearly the whole of
            the floor—no doubt to the exceeding discomfort of the artist and
            his wife;—this the more especially as the tar or paint with
            which it was lettered in sprawling capitals, emitted a strong, disagreeable, and, to my fancy, a peculiarly disgusting odor. On
            the lid were painted the words—“Mrs. Adelaide Curtis, Albany, New York. Charge of Cornelius Wyatt, Esq. This side
            up. To be handled with care."
         </p>
         
         <p>Now, I was aware that Mrs. Adelaide Curtis, of Albany, was
            the artist’s wife’s mother;—but then I looked upon the whole address as a mystification, intended especially for myself. I made
            up my mind, of course, that the box and contents would never
            get farther north than the studio of my misanthropic friend, in
            Chambers Street, New York.
         </p>
         
         <p>For the first three or four days we had fine weather, although
            the wind was dead ahead; having chopped round to the northward, immediately upon our losing sight of the coast. The passengers were, consequently, in high spirits, and disposed to be
            social. I must except, however, Wyatt and his sisters, who be
            haved stiffly, and, I could not help thinking, uncourteously to the
            rest of the party. Wyatt's conduct I did not so much regard. He
            was gloomy, even beyond his usual habit—in fact he was morose
            —but in him I was prepared for eccentricity. For the sisters,
            however, I could make no excuse. They secluded themselves in
            their state-rooms during the greater part of the passage, and absolutely refused, although I repeatedly urged them, to hold commuication with any person on board.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mrs. Wyatt herself, was far more agreeable. That is to say,
            she was chatty; and to be chatty is no slight recommendation
            at sea. She became excessively intimate with most of- the ladies;
            and, to my profound astonishment, evinced no equivocal disposition to coquet with the men. She amused us all very much. I
            say “amused’’—and scarcely know how to explain myself. The
            truth is, I soon found that Mrs. W. was far oftener laughed at
            than with. The gentlemen said little about her; but the ladies,
            in a little while, pronounced her “a good-hearted thing, rather
            indifferent-looking, totally uneducated, and decidedly vulgar.”
            The great wonder was, how Wyatt had been entrapped into such
            a match. Wealth was the general solution—but this I knew to
            be no solution at all; for Wyatt had told me that she neither
            brought him a dollar nor had any expectations from any source
            whatever. “He had married,” he said, “for love, and for love
            only; and his bride was far more than worthy of his love.’
            When I thought of these expressions, on the part of my friend,
            I confess that I felt indescribably puzzled. Could it be possible
            that he was taking leave of his senses? What else could I think?
            He, so refined, so intellectual, so fastidious, with so exquisite a
            perception of the faulty, and so keen an appreciation of the beautiful! To be sure, the lady seemed especially fond of him—particularly so in his absence—when she made herself ridiculous by
            frequent quotations of what had been said by her “beloved husband, Mr. Wyatt.” The word “husband” seemed forever—to
            use one of her own delicate expressions—forever “on the tip
            of her tongue.” In the mean time, it was observed by all on
            board, that he avoided her in the most pointed manner, and, for
            the most part, shut himself up alone in his state-room, where, in
            fact, he might have been said to live altogether, leaving his wife
            at full liberty to amuse herself as she thought best, in the public
            society of the main cabin.
         </p>
         
         <p>My conclusion, from what I saw and heard, was, that the artist, by some unaccountable freak of fate, or perhaps in some fit
            of enthusiastic and fanciful passion, had been induced to unite
            himself with a person altogether beneath him, and that the natural result, entire and speedy disgust, had ensued. I pitied him
            from the bottom of my heart—but could not, for that reason,
            quite forgive his incommunicativeness in the matter of the “Last
            Supper.” For this I resolved to have my revenge.
         </p>
         
         <p>One day he came upon deck, and, taking bis arm as had been
            my wont, I sauntered with him backwards and forwards. His
            gloom, however, (which I considered quite natural under the circumstances,) seemed entirely unabated. He said little, and tha
            moodily, and with evident effort. I ventured a jest or two, and
            he made a sickening attempt at a smile. Poor fellow!—as I
            thought of his wife, I wondered that he could have heart to
            put on even the semblance of mirth. At last I ventured a home
            thrust. I determined to commence a series of covert insinuations,
            or inuendoes, about the oblong box—just to let him perceive,
            gradually, that I was not altogether the butt, or victim, of his
            little bit of pleasant mystification. My first observation was by
            way of opening a masked battery. I said something about the
            “peculiar shape of that box;" and, as I spoke the words, I
            smiled knowingly, winked, and touched him gently with my forefinger in the ribs.
         </p>
         
         
         
         <p>The manner in which Wyatt received this harmless pleasantry, 
            convinced me, at once, that he was mad. At first he stared at
            me as if he found it impossible to comprehend the witticism of
            my remark; but as its point seemed slowly to make its way into
            his brain, his eyes, in the same proportion, seemed protruding
            from their sockets. Then he grew very red—then hideously
            pale—then, as if highly amused with what I had insinuated, he
            began a loud and boisterous laugh, which, to my astonishment,
            he kept up, with gradually increasing vigor, for ten minutes or
            more. In conclusion, he fell flat and heavily upon the deck.
            When I ran to uplift him, to all appearance he was dead.
         </p>
         
         <p>I called assistance, and, with much difficulty, we brought him
            to himself. Upon reviving he spoke incoherently for some time.
            At length we bled him and put him to bed. The next morning
            he was quite recovered, so far as regarded his mere bodily health.
            Of his mind I say nothing, of course. I avoided him during the
            rest of the passage, by advice of the captain, who seemed to coincide with me altogether in my views of his insanity, but cautioned me to say nothing on this head to any person on board.
         </p>
         
         <p>Several circumstances occurred immediately after this fit of
            Wyatt’s, which contributed to heighten the curiosity with which
            I was already possessed. Among other things, this: I had been
            nervous—drank too much strong green tea, and slept ill at night
            —in fact, for two nights I could not be properly said to sleep at
            all. Now, my state-room opened into the main cabin, or diningroom, as did those of all the single men on board. Wyatt’s three
            rooms were in the after-cabin, which was separated from the
            main one by a slight sliding door, never locked even at night.
            As we were almost constantly on a wind, and the breeze was
            not a little stiff, the ship heeled to leeward very considerably;
            and whenever her starboard side was to leeward, the sliding
            door between the cabins slid open, and so remained, nobody taking the trouble to get up and shut it. But my berth was in such
            a position, that when my own state-room door was open, as well
            as the sliding door in question, (and my own door was always
            open on account of the heat,) I could see into the after-cabin quite
            distinctly, and just at that portion of it, too, where were situated
            the state-rooms of Mr. Wyatt. Well, during two nights (not
            consecutive) while I lay awake, I clearly saw Mrs. W., about
            eleven o’clock upon each night, steal cautiously from the stateroom of Mr. W. and enter the extra room, where she remained
            until daybreak, when she was called by her husband and went
            back. That they were virtually separated was clear. They had
            separate apartments—no doubt in contemplation of a more permanent divorce; and here, after all, I thought, was the mystery
            of the extra state-room.
         </p>
         
         <p>There was another circumstance, too, which interested me
            much. During the two wakeful nights in question, and immediately after the disappearance of Mrs. Wyatt into the extra stateroom, I was attracted by certain singular, cautious, subdued
            noises in that of her husband. After listening to them for some
            time, with thoughtful attention, I at length succeeded perfectly
            in translating their import. They were sounds occasioned by the
            artist in prying open the oblong box, by means of a chisel and
            mallet—the latter being apparently muffled, or deadened, by some
            soft woollen or cotton substance in which its head was enveloped.
         </p>
         
         <p>In this manner I fancied I could distinguish the precise moment
            when he fairly disengaged the lid—also, that I could determine
            when he removed it altogether, and when he deposited it upon
            the lower berth in his room; this latter point I knew, for example, by certain slight taps which the lid made in striking against
            the wooden edges of the berth, as he endeavored to lay it down
            very gently—there being no room for it on the floor. After this
            there was a dead stillness, and I heard nothing more, upon either
         </p>
         
         <p>occasion, until nearly daybreak; unless, perhaps, I may mention
            a low sobbing, or murmuring sound, so very much suppressed as
            to be nearly inaudible—if, indeed, the whole of this latter noise
            were not rather produced by my own imagination. I say it
            seemed to resemble sobbing or sighing—but, of course, it could
            not have been either. I rather think it was a ringing in my own
            ears. Mr. Wyatt, no doubt, according to custom, was merely
            giving the rein to one of his hobbies—indulging in one of his fits
            of artistic enthusiasm. He had opened his oblong box, in order
            to feast his eyes on the pictorial treasure within. There was nothing in this, however, to make him sob. I repeat therefore, that
            it must have been simply a freak of my own fancy, distempered
            by good Captain Hardy’s green tea. Just before dawn, on each
            of the two nights of which I speak, I distinctly heard Mr. Wyatt
            replace the lid upon the oblong box, and force the nails into their
            old places, by means of the muffled mallet. Having done this
            he issued from his stale-room, fully dressed, and proceeded to call
            Mrs. W. from hers.
         </p>
         
         <p>We had been at sea seven days, and were now off Cape Hatteras,
            when there came on a tremendously heavy blow from the southwest. We were, in a measure, prepared for it, however, as the
            weather had been holding out threats for some time. Everything
            was made snug, alow and aloft; and as the wind steadily freshened, we lay to, at length, under spanker and foretopsail, both
            double-reefed.
         </p>
         
         <p>In this trim, we rode safely enough for forty-eight hours—the
            ship proving herself an excellent sea boat, in many respects, and
            shipping no water of any consequence. At the end of this period,
            however, the gale had freshened into a hurricane, and our aftersail split into ribbons, bringing us so much in the trough of the
            water that we shipped several prodigious seas, one immediately
            after the other. By this accident we lost three men overboard,
            with the caboose, and nearly the whole of the larboard bulwarks.
            Scarcely had we recovered our senses, before the foretopsail went
            into shreds, when we got up a storm stay-sail, and with this did
            pretty well for some hours, the ship heading the seas much more
            steadily than before.
         </p>
         
         <p>The gale still held on, however, and we saw no signs of its
            abating. The rigging was found to be ill-fitted, and greatly
            strained; and on the third day of the blow, about five in the
            afternoon, our mizzen-mast, in a heavy lurch to windward, went
            by the board. For an hour or more, we tried in vain to get rid
            of it, on account of the prodigious rolling of the ship; and,
            before we had succeeded, the carpenter came aft and announced
            four feet water in the hold. To add to our dilemma, we found
            the pumps choked and nearly useless.
         </p>
         
         <p>All was now confusion and despair—but an effort was made
            to lighten the ship by throwing overboard as much of her cargo
             as could be reached, and by cutting away the two masts that
            remained. This we at last accomplished—but we were still
            unable to do anything at the pumps; and, in the mean time, the
            leak gained on us very fast.
         </p>
         
         <p>At sundown, the gale had sensibly diminished in violence, and,
            as the sea went down with it, we still entertained faint hopes of
            saving ourselves in the boats. At eight, P. M., the clouds broke
            away to windward, and we had the advantage of a full moon
            —a piece of good fortune which served wonderfully to cheer our
             drooping spirits.
         </p>
         
         <p>After incredible labor we succeeded, at length, in getting the
             long-boat over the side without material accident, and into this
            we crowded the whole of the crew and roost of the passengers. 
            This party made off immediately, and, after undergoing much suffering, finally arrived, in safety, at Ocracoke Inlet, on the third
            day after the wreck.
         </p>
         
         
         <p>Fourteen passengers, with the Captain, remained on board,
            resolving to trust their fortunes to the jolly-boat at the stern.
            We lowered it without difficulty, although it was only by a miracle that we prevented it from swamping as it touched the water.
            It contained, when afloat, the captain and his wife, Mr. Wyatt
            and party, a Mexican officer, wife, four children, and myself,
            with a negro valet.
         </p>
         
         <p>We had no room, of course, for anything except a few positively necessary instruments, some provision, and the clothes
            upon our backs. No one had thought of even attempting to
            save anything more. What must have been the astonishment
            of all then, when, having proceeded a few fathoms from the ship,
            Mr. Wyatt stood up in the stern-sheets, and coolly demanded of
            Captain Hardy that the boat should be put back for the purpose
            of taking in his oblong box!
         </p>
         
         <p>“Sit down, Mr. Wyatt,” replied the Captain, somewhat sternly;
            “you will capsize us if you do not sit quite still. Our gunwale
            is almost in the water now.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“The box!” vociferated Mr. Wyatt, still standing—“the box,
            I say! Captain Hardy, you cannot, you will not refuse me. Its
            weight will be but a trifle—it is nothing—mere nothing. By the
            mother who bore you—for the love of Heaven—by your hope of
            salvation, I implore you to put back for the box!”
         </p>
         
         <p>The Captain, for a moment, seemed touched by the earnest
            appeal of the artist, but he regained his stern composure, and
            merely said—
         </p>
         
         <p>“Mr. Wyatt, you are mad. I cannot listen to you. Sit down,
            I say, or you will swamp the boat. Stay—hold him—seize him!
            —he is about to spring overboard! There—I knew it—he is over!
            
         </p>
         
         <p>As the Captain said this, Mr. Wyatt, in fact, sprang from the
            boat, and, as we were yet in the lee of the wreck, succeeded, by
            almost superhuman exertion, in getting hold of a rope which
            hung from the fore-chains. In another moment he was on board,
            and rushing frantically down into the cabin.
         </p>
         
         <p>In the meantime, we had been swept astern of the ship, and
            being quite out of her lee, were at the mercy of the tremendous
            sea which was still running. We made a determined effort to
            put back, but our little boat was like a feather in the breath of
            the tempest. We saw at a glance that the doom of the unfortunate artist was sealed.
         </p>
         
         <p>As our distance from the wreck rapidly increased, the madman
            (for as such only could we regard him) was seen to emerge from
            the companion-way, up which, by dint of a strength that appeared gigantic, he dragged, bodily, the oblong box. While we
            gazed in the extremity of astonishment, he passed, rapidly, several turns of a three-inch rope, first around the box and then
            around his body. In another instant both body and box were in
            the sea—disappearing suddenly, at once and forever.
         </p>
         
         <p>We lingered awhile sadly upon our oars, with our eyes riveted
            upon the spot. At length we pulled away. The silence remained
            unbroken for an hour. Finally, I hazarded a remark.
         </p>
         
         <p>"Did you observe, Captain, how suddenly they sank? Was
            not that an exceedingly singular thing? I confess that I entertained some feeble hope of his final deliverance, when I saw him
            lash himself to the box, and commit himself to the sea.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“They sank, as a matter of course,” replied the Captain, “and
            that like a shot. They will soon rise again, however—but not till
            the salt melts.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“The salt!” I ejaculated.</p>
         
         <p>“Hush!” said the Captain, pointing to the wife and sisters of
            the deceased. “We must talk of these things at some more
            appropriate time.”
         </p>
         <div class="ab">----</div>
         
         <p>We suffered much, and made a narrow escape; but fortune
            befriended us, as well as our mates in the long boat. We landed,
            in fine, more dead than alive, after four days of intense distress,
            upon the beach opposite Roanoke Island. We remained here a
            week, were not ill-treated by the wreckers, and at length obtained
            a passage to New York.
         </p>
         
         <p>About a month after the loss of the “Independence,” I happened to meet Captain Hardy in Broadway. Our conversation
            turned, naturally, upon the disaster, and especially upon the sad
            fate of poor Wyatt. I thus learned the following particulars.
         </p>
         
         <p>The artist had engaged passage for himself, wife, two sisters
            and a servant. His wife was, indeed, as she had been represented, a most lovely, and most accomplished woman. On the
            morning of the fourteenth of June, (the day in which I first visited
            the ship,) the lady suddenly sickened and died. The young husband was frantic with grief—but circumstances imperatively forbade the deferring his voyage to New York. It was necessary to
            take to her mother the corpse of his adored wife, and, on the
            other hand, the universal prejudice which would prevent his doing
            so openly, was well known. Nine-tenths of the passengers
            would have abandoned the ship rather than take passage with
            a dead body.
         </p>
         
         <p>In this dilemma, Captain Hardy arranged that the corpse, being
            first partially embalmed, and packed, with a large quantity of
            salt, in a box of suitable dimensions, should be conveyed on
            board as merchandize. Nothing was to be said of the lady’s
            decease; and, as it was well understood that Mr. Wyatt had
            engaged passage for his wife, it became necessary that some
            person should personate her during the voyage. This the
            deceased’s lady’s-maid was easily prevailed on to do. The extra
            state-room, originally engaged for this girl, during her mistress’
            life, was now merely retained. In this state-room the pseudo
            wife slept, of course, every night In the day-time she performed,
            to the best of her ability, the part of her mistress—whose person,
            it had been carefully ascertained, was unknown to any of the
            passengers on board.
         </p>
         
         <p>My own mistakes arose, naturally enough, through too careless, too inquisitive, and too impulsive a temperament. But of
            late, it is a rare thing that I sleep soundly at night. There is a
            countenance which haunts me, turn as I will. There is an hysterical laugh which will forever ring within my ears.
         </p>
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">Edgar A. Poe</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="biblTitle">A Shipwreck</div>
         <div class="biblPage">352</div>
         <div class="head">A Shipwreck.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>I launched a bark on Fate’s deep tide—
            
            <br></br>A frail and fluttering toy,
            
            <br></br>But freighted with a thousand dreams
            
            <br></br>Of beauty and of joy.
            
            <br></br>Ah me! it found no friend in them—
            
            <br></br>The wave—the sky—the gale—
            
            <br></br>Though Love enraptured took the helm—
            
            <br></br>And Hope unfurled the sail!
            
            <br></br>And you, who should its pilot be—
            
            <br></br>To whom in fear it flies—
            
            <br></br>Forsake it, on a treacherous sea,
            
            <br></br>To seek a prouder prize.
            
            <br></br>Alas for Love! bewildered child!
            
            <br></br>He weeps the helm beside,
            
            <br></br>And Hope has furled her fairy sail,
            
            <br></br>Nor longer tempts the tide.
            
            <br></br>Despair and Pride in silence fling
            
            <br></br>Its rich freight to the wave,
            
            <br></br>And now an aimless wreck it floats,
            
            <br></br>That none would stoop to save.
         </div> 
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">F. S. Osgood.</span>
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="biblTitle">Critical Notices</div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.
            
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p5">
            <div class="biblTitle">Poems by Frances Osgood</div>
            <div class="biblPage">353</div>
            <div class="ab">Poems. By Frances S. Osgood. New- York: Clark &amp; Austin.</div>
            
            <p>A neat volume of 252 pages duodecimo, including many but
               by no means all, or even the best, of the author’s late compositions, with several of those which made up the “Wreath of Wild
               Flowers from New-England.
            </p>
            
            <p>The book opens with these few words of Preface:</p>
            
            <p>The Author’s chief fear, in collecting and publishing the following Poems, is that they may not be thought worthy the notice
               of that just and true criticism, whose praise and blame are alike
               valuable, and would by her be equally welcomed and appreciated.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have no poetess among us who has been so universally
               popular as Mrs. Osgood—and yet, with the exception of “The
               Wreath of Wild Flowers," (an English publication,) this is the
               first collection of her Poems. Our only regret is that she has not
               presented us, in one view, all that she has written in verse. In
               omitting so much, she is in danger of losing the credit to which
               she is so fairly entitled on the score of versatility—of variety in
               expression and invention. There is scarcely a form of poetical
               composition in which she has not made experiment, and there is
               not one in which she has not very creditably succeeded.
            </p>
            
            <p>Of course, then, it is a task of no little difficulty to give any
               generalization of her powers. We may say, in the beginning,
               however, that in no one poetical requisite is she deficient. Her
               negative merits are of the highest respectability. We look in
               vain, throughout her writings, for an offence against taste, or
               decorum—for a low thought—a platitude of expression—a violation of grammar—or for any of those lapses in the mere technicality of composition, of which, in America, we meet so abundant
               examples. A happy refinement—an exquisite instinct of the
               pure—the delicate—the graceful—gives a charm inexpressible to
               everything which flows from her pen.
            </p>
            
            <p>In respect to the positive merits—to the loftier excellences of
               the Muse—we are constrained to speak with somewhat more
               reserve. Deficient—that is to say markedly deficient at no
               point—Mrs. Osgood has, nevertheless, neither the bold and rich
               imagination of Maria Brooks—nor the rhythmical ear and glowing fervor of Mrs. Welby—but to no other American poetesses is
               she, even in these particulars, inferior. A peculiar trait of her
               mind is its versatility and originality of poetic invention—whether in the conception of a theme or in the manner and tone of its
               handling. A portion, or rather a consequence of this trait, is a
               certain piquancy, point, and epigrammatic terseness of phraseology—in which she is approached only by Miss Gould. But it is
               in that indescribable something which, for want of a more definite
               term, we are accustomed to call grace—that Will-o’-the-Wisp,
               which in its supreme development may be said to involve nearly
               all that is pure and ethereal in poetry—it is in this charm of
               charms—so magical because at once so shadowy and so irresistible that Mrs. Osgood pre-eminently excels. It is in this that
               she has no equal among her countrywomen, it is this rod of the
               enchanter which throws open to her the road to all hearts.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the collection now before us there occur very many of those
               half sentimental half allegorical or rather emblematical compositions, of which the authoress seems to be especially fond—for the
               reason, perhaps, that she constructs them with little facility, and
               that, for their mere ingenuity, they are admired by the mass of
               mankind. We regret to see these pieces in the volume;—they
               are, in general, very graceful pleasantries—but no more—and
               quite unworthy her who could pen so truly consistent and beautiful a prosopopeia as
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">THE SPIRIT OF POETRY.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Leave me not yet! Leave me not cold and lonely,
               
               <br></br>Thou dear Ideal of my pining heart!
               
               <br></br>Thou art the friend—the beautiful—the only,
               
               <br></br>Whom I would keep, tho’ all the world depart!
               
               <br></br>Thou, that dost veil the frailest flower with glory,
               
               <br></br>Spirit of light and loveliness and truth!
               
               <br></br>Thou that didst tell me a sweet fairy story
               
               <br></br>Of the dim future, in my wistful youth!
               
               <br></br>Thou, who canst weave a halo round the spirit,
               
               <br></br>Through which nought mean or evil dare intrude,
               
               <br></br>Resume not yet the gift, which I inherit
               
               <br></br>From Heaven and thee, that dearest, holiest good!
               
               <br></br>Leave me not now! Leave me not cold and lonely,
               
               <br></br>Thou starry prophet of my pining heart!
               
               <br></br>Thou art the friend—the tenderest—the only,
               
               <br></br>With whom, of all, ’twould be despair to part.
               
               <br></br>Thou that cam’st to me in my dreaming childhood,
               
               <br></br>Shaping the changeful clouds to pageants rare,
               
               <br></br>Peopling the smiling vale, and shaded wildwood,
               
               <br></br>With airy beings, faint yet strangely fair;
               
               <br></br>Telling me all the sea-born breeze was saying,
               
               <br></br>While it went whispering through the willing leaves.
               
               <br></br>Bidding me listen to the light rain playing
               
               <br></br>Its pleasant tune, about the household eaves;
               
               <br></br>Tuning the low, sweet ripple of the river,
               
               <br></br>Till its melodious murmur seem’d a song,
               
               <br></br>A tender and sad chaunt, repeated ever,
               
               <br></br>A sweet, impassion’d plaint of love and wrong!
               
               <br></br>Leave me not yet! Leave me not cold and lonely,
               
               <br></br>Thou star of promise o’er my clouded path!
               
               <br></br>Leave not the life that borrows from thee only
               
               <br></br>All of delight and beauty that it hath!
               
               <br></br>Thou, that when others knew not how to love me.
               
               <br></br>Nor cared to fathom half my yearning soul,
               
               <br></br>Didst wreathe thy flowers of light, around, above me,
               
               <br></br>To woo and win me from my grief’s control.
               
               <br></br>By all my dreams, the passionate, and holy,
               
               <br></br>When thou hast sung love’s lullaby to me—
               
               <br></br>By all the childlike worship, fond and lowly,
               
               <br></br>Which I have lavish’d upon thine and thee—
               
               <br></br>By all the lays my simple lute was learning,
               
               <br></br>To echo from thy voice, stay with me still!
               
               <br></br>Once flown—alas! for thee there’s no returning!
               
               <br></br>The charm will die o’er valley, wood, and hill.
               
               <br></br>Tell me not Time, whose wing my brow has shaded,
               
               <br></br>Has wither’d spring’s sweet bloom within my heart.
               
               <br></br>Ah, no! the rose of Love is yet unfaded,
               
               <br></br>Though Hope and Joy, its sister flowers, depart.
               
               <br></br>Well do I know that I have wrong’d thine altar,
               
               <br></br>With the light offerings of an idler’s mind,
               
               <br></br>And thus, with shame, my pleading prayer I falter,
               
               <br></br>Leave me not, spirit! deaf, and dumb, and blind!
               
               <br></br>Deaf to the mystic harmony of nature,
               
               <br></br>Blind to the beauty of her stars and flowers!
               
               <br></br>Leave me not, heavenly yet human teacher,
               
               <br></br>Lonely and lost in this cold world of ours!
               
               <br></br>Heaven knows I need thy music and thy beauty
               
               <br></br>Still to beguile me on my weary way,
               
               <br></br>To lighten to my soul the cares of duty,
               
               <br></br>And bless with radiant beams: the darken’d day;
               
               <br></br>To charm my wild heart in the worldly revel,
               
               <br></br>Lest I, too, join the aimless, false, and vain;
               
               <br></br>Let me not lower to the soulless level
               
               <br></br>Of those whom now I pity and disdain!
               
               
               <br></br>Leave me not yet!—leave me not cold and pining,
               
               <br></br>Thou bird of paradise, whose plumes of light,
               
               <br></br>Where’er they rested, left a'glory shining;
               
               <br></br>Fly not to heaven, or let me share thy flight!
               
            </div>
            
            <p>Of its kind—a kind not of the highest—there have been written
               few finer poems than this. It is replete with feeling, with elevated sentiment—and its versification is correct—sonorous, harmonious and well-sustained.
            </p>
            
            <p>One of the best of Mrs. Osgood’s shorter poems is entitled</p>
            
            <div class="bibl">SHE LOVES HIM YET.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>She loves him yet! 
               
               <br></br>I know by the blush that rises 
               
               <br></br>Beneath the curls 
               
               <br></br>That shadow her soul-lit cheek; 
               
               <br></br>She loves him yet! 
               
               <br></br>Thro’ all Love’s sweet disguises 
               
               <br></br>In timid girls, 
               
               <br></br>A blush will be sure to speak. 
               
               <br></br>But deeper signs 
               
               <br></br>Than the radiant blush of beauty, 
               
               <br></br>The maiden finds, 
               
               <br></br>Whenever his name is heard.— 
               
               <br></br>Her young heart thrills, 
               
               <br></br>Forgetting herself—her duty— 
               
               <br></br>Her dark eye fills, 
               
               <br></br>And her pulse with hope is stirr’d. 
               
               <br></br>She loves him yet! 
               
               <br></br>The flower the false one gave her 
               
               <br></br>When last he came, 
               
               <br></br>Is still with her wild tears wet. 
               
               <br></br>She'll ne’er forget, 
               
               <br></br>However his faith may waver. 
               
               <br></br>Thro’ grief and shame, 
               
               <br></br>Believe it—she loves him yet! 
               
               <br></br>His favorite songs 
               
               <br></br>She will sing—she heeds no other; 
               
               <br></br>With all her wrongs 
               
               <br></br>Her life on his love is set. 
               
               <br></br>Oh, doubt no more! 
               
               <br></br>She never can wed another: 
               
               <br></br>Till life be o’er, 
               
               <br></br>She loves—she will love him yet! 
               
            </div>
            
            <p>There is in this a rich simplicity which cannot be too highly
               admired, and the metre is original and otherwise of peculiar
               excellence.
            </p>
            
            <p>We cannot forbear quoting the noble poem entitled</p>
            
            <div class="bibl">ASPIRATIONS.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>I waste no more in idle dreams my life, my soul away:
               
               <br></br>I wake to know my better self,—I wake to watch and pray.
               
               <br></br>Thought, feeling, time, on idols vain, I’ve lavished all too long;
               
               <br></br>Henceforth to holier purposes I pledge myself, my song!
               
               
               <br></br>Oh! still within the inner veil, upon the spirit’s shrine,
               
               <br></br>Still unprofaned by evil, bums the one pure spark divine
               
               <br></br>Which God has kindled in us all, and be it mine to tend
               
               <br></br>Henceforth, with vestal thought and care, the light that lamp maylend.
               
               
               <br></br>I shut mine eyes in grief and shame upon the dreary past—
               
               <br></br>My heart, my soul pour’d recklessly on dreams that could not last.
               
               <br></br>My bark has drifted down the stream, at will of wind or wave,
               
               <br></br>An idle, light, and fragile thing, that few had cared to save.
               
               
               
               <br></br>Henceforth the tiller Truth shall hold, and steer as Conscience tells,
               
               <br></br>And I will brave the storms of Fate tho’ wild the ocean swells.
               
               <br></br>I know my soul is strong and high, if once I give it sway;
               
               <br></br>I feel a glorious power within, tho’ light I seem and gay.
               
               
               <br></br>Oh, laggard soul! unclose thine eyes. No more in luxury soft
               
               <br></br>Of joy ideal waste thyself! awake, and soar aloft!
               
               <br></br>Unfurl this hour those falcon wings which thou dost fold too long;
               
               <br></br>Raise to the skies thy lightning gaze, and sing thy loftiest song.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>Here, as in nearly all the compositions of Mrs. Osgood, the
               rhythm is singularly good, without art,—sonorous, well-balanced
               and well-modulated. The “'aspirations”—or more properly,
               perhaps, the bitter and unavailing regrets—have in them a touching—a despairing sadness which makes us shudder as we read.
            </p>
            
            <p>Neither of the poems just quoted, however, conveys much of
               the ordinary manner of the poetess. This is far better exemplified in
            </p>
            
            <div class="bibl">LENORE.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Oh! fragile and fair, as the delicate chalices,
               
               <br></br>Wrought with so rare and so subtle a skill;
               
               <br></br>Bright relics, that tell of the pomp of those palaces,
               
               <br></br>Venice—the sea-goddess—glories in still.
               
               
               <br></br>Whose exquisite texture, transparent and tender,
               
               <br></br>A pure blush alone from the ruby wine takes;
               
               <br></br>Yet ah! if some false hand, profaning its splendor,
               
               <br></br>Dares but to taint it with poison,—it breaks!
               
               <br></br>So when Love pour’d thro’ thy pure heart his lightning,
               
               <br></br>On thy pale cheek the soft rose-hues awoke,—
               
               <br></br>So when wild Passion, that timid heart frightening,
               
               <br></br>Poison’d the treasure—it trembled and broke!
               
            </div>
            
            <p>Here we have a full representation of the author’s customary
               turn of thought—of her grace of expression—of her facility in
               illustration—of her exactitude—and of her epigrammatism. The
               versification (except in the first quatrain) is not as good as usual.
               The first two lines of the third are even rough. The rhythm is
               anapoestic—but the anapoestic all false and inadmissible—e g.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">So when Love | poured through thy | pure heart' his | lightning,
               On thy pale | cheek the soft | rose hues a | woke.
               
            </div>
            
            <p>Here the necessarily long syllables love, through, heart,pale,soft
               and hues, should be short, and the rhythm halts because they are
               not so. There is, also, either a syllable too much or a syllable
               too little at “lightning”—but these are trivialities of which it is,
               perhaps, hypercritical to speak.
            </p>
            
            <p>We conclude this imperfect notice by the citation of what we
               consider as, upon the whole, the finest poem in the collection.
            </p>
            
            <div class="bibl">A SONG.</div>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Yes! “lower to the level” 
               
               <br></br>Of those who laud thee now! 
               
               <br></br>Go! join the joyous revel, 
               
               <br></br>And pledge the heartless vow! 
               
               <br></br>Go! dim the soul-born beauty 
               
               <br></br>That lights that lofty brow! 
               
               <br></br>Fill, fill the bowl! let burning wine 
               
               <br></br>Drown, in thy soul, Love’s dream divine! 
               
               <br></br>Yet when the laugh is lightest, 
               
               <br></br>When wildest goes the jest, 
               
               <br></br>When gleams the goblet brightest, 
               
               <br></br>And proudest heaves thy breast, 
               
               <br></br>And thou art madly pledging 
               
               <br></br>Each gay and jovial guest,— 
               
               <br></br>A ghost shall glide amid the flowers— 
               
               <br></br>The shade of Love’s departed hours! 
                
               
               
               <br></br>And thou shalt drink in sadness 
               
               <br></br>From all the splendor there, 
               
               <br></br>And curse the revel’s gladness, 
               
               <br></br>And hate the banquet’s glare, 
               
               <br></br>And pine 'mid Passion's madness, 
               
               <br></br>For true Love’s purer air, 
               
               <br></br>And feel thou’dst give their wildest glee 
               
               <br></br>For one unsullied smile from me! 
               
               <br></br>Yet deem not this my prayer, love, 
               
               <br></br>Ah, no! if I could keep 
               
               <br></br>Thy alter’d heart from care, love, 
               
               <br></br>And charm its griefs to sleep, 
               
               <br></br>Mine only should despair love, 
               
               <br></br>I—I alone would weep! 
               
               <br></br>I—I alone would mourn the flowers 
               
               <br></br>That fade in Love’s deserted bowers!
            </div> 
            
            <p>There is here a terse, concentrated and sustained energy which
               impresses us with a high opinion of the power of the poetess, and
               which warrants us in saying that she could do better—very far
               better than she has hitherto done. The poem would be improved,
               however, (as would all poems) by the substitution throughout of
               “you” for “thee” and so forth—the modern and colloquial for
               the ancient and so called poetical pronoun.
            </p>
            
            <p>The limits of our paper warn us to bring these comments to a
               close. We shall resume this subject—to us a truly delightful
               one—at some future opportunity, in the more ample pages of
               Godey’s Magazine.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p6">
            <div class="biblTitle">The History of Silk, Cotton, Linen, Wool, and Other Fibrous Substances</div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>The History of Silk, Cotton, Linen, Wool, and other Fibrous Substances; including Observations on Spinning, Dyeing and
               Weaving. Also, an Account of the Pastoral Life of the An
               cients, their Social State and Attainments in the Domestic Arts.
               With Appendices on Pliny’s Natural History; on the Origin
               and Manufacture of Linen and Cotton Paper; on Felting,
               Netting, etc. Deduced from Copious and Authentic Sources.
               Illustrated by Steel Engravings. New-York: Harper &amp;
               Brothers.
            </p>
            <p>This is a large and valuable octavo of 464 pages. We have
               given the title in full as the most succinct mode of conveying the
               nature and purpose of the work—one which no scholar can
               afford to do without, and which needs no recommendation from us
               to those engaged in manufacturing pursuits.
            </p>
            
            <p>This able work supplies, in fact, a desideratum whose need has
               been long felt. No methodical treatise on Fibrous Substances
               has hitherto existed—and even the topic itself has very remarkably eluded the investigation of the learned. The Textrinum
               Antiquorum of Yates is almost the sole work devoted to the
               ancient history of the theme, and the nature of that treatise places
               it altogether out of popular reach.
            </p>
            <p>We quote a paragraph from the Preface:
               
            </p>
            <p>That a topic of such interest deserved elucidation will not be
               denied when it is remembered that, apart from the question of the
               direct influence these important arts have ever exerted upon the
               civilization and social condition of communities, in various ages of
               the world, there are other and scarcely inferior considerations to the
               student, involved in their bearing upon the true understanding of
               history, sacred and profane. To supply, therefore, an important
               desideratum in classical archaeology, by thus seeking the better to
               illustrate the true social state of the ancients, thereby affording a
               commentary on their commerce and progress in domestic arts, is one
               of the leading objects contemplated by the present work. In addition to this, our better acquaintance with the actual condition of
               these arts in early times, will tend, in many instances, to confirm
               the historic accuracy and elucidate the idiom of many portions of
               Holy Writ.
            </p>
            
            <p>Among the engravings which illustrate the work, is one of
               the Chinese Loom, a reduced fac-simile copied from a picture recently obtained from the Celestial Empire and now in the possession of the N. Y. Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions. There
               is, also, a representation of an Egyptian Weaving Factory—a
               reduced fac-simile from Champollion.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p7">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Artist, The Merchant, and The Statesman</div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>The Artist, The Merchant, and The Statesman. By C. E. Lester.
               Vol. 2. New York: Paine &amp; Burgess.
               
            </p>
            <p>This, the concluding volume of Mr. Lester’s entertaining book,
               has less unity of purpose, but greater variety of incident and
               anecdote, than the first. It is pervaded by a spirit of nationality
               which cannot be too highly commended—although the author
               errs in supposing that the objects for which he contends have
               not been urged upon the attention of the country in various
               quarters, with great zeal and uniformity, and for a long period of
               time. It is true, however, that the fruits of this exertion are only
               now making themselves apparent.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Lester has a heart for good and great things, as he proves
               by the warmth with which he addresses himself to the consideration of such men as Michael Angelo, Galileo, and Benjamin
               West. The paper on the Quaker painter is the most characteristic in the volume. That on British Berkeley, an early friend of
               America and a true prophet of her greatness, is equally marked
               and excellent.
            </p>
            
            <p>This second volume is embellished by a well-executed steel
               engraving, the head of Americus Vespuccius. There are also
               wood-cuts of Galileo and Tycho Brahe.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="biblTitle">Aids to English Composition</div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>Aids to English Composition, Prepared for Students of All
               Grades; embracing Specimens and Examples of School and
               College Exercises, and most of the Higher Departments of English Composition, both in Prose and Verse. By Richard
               Green- Parker, A, M. A New Edition, with Additions and
               Improvements. New- York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>As this work has acquired, with justice, a very extensive reputation, we feel it necessary merely to give its title and call attention to the issue of a new and carefully revised edition.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p9">
            <div class="biblTitle">Stable Talk and Table Talk</div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>Stable Talk and Table Talk, or Spectacles for Young Spoilsmen.
               By Harry Hieover. Philadelphia: Lea &amp; Blanchard. For
               Sale in New-York by Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>Who is Harry Hieover? At all events he is a judge of horses
               and has written a good book. Many of the Chapters are equal
               to the best of Harry Lorrequer's. A reprint from the English.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Treatise on Corns, Bunions, the Diseases of Nails, and the General Management of
               the Feet
            </div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>A Treatise on Corns, Bunions, the Diseases of Nads, and the
               General Management of the Feet. By Lewis Durlacher,
               Surgeon Chiropedist (by Special Appointment) to the Queen.
            </p>
            <p>A treatise which cannot fail to do a great deal of good by giving
               
            </p>
            <p>a clear explanation of the peculiar and most troublesome diseases
                of which it treats—thus enabling the public (it is the public who
               have corns) to apply their own remedies without the intervention
               of “corn doctors” and professors of Chiropedy.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Ambuscade</div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>The Ambuscade. An Historical Poem. By Thomas R. Whitney.
               New- York: J. S. Redfield.
               
            </p>
            <p>We have not as yet read this volume so thoroughly as to
               hazard an opinion of its merits. A glance, however, assures us
               that the author has a commendable contempt for things in
               general—very especially for reason and for rhyme.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Foster Brother</div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>The Foster Brother. A Tale of the War of Chiozza. Edited by
               Leigh Hunt. New-York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
               An admirable book—No. 66 of “The Library of Select Novels.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Wandering Jew</div>
            <div class="biblPage">355</div>
            <p>The Wandering Jew—superbly Illustrated. New-York: Harper
               &amp; Brothers.
               No. 5 is issued. The wood designs in this edition are certainly among the most magnificent we ever beheld.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <div class="biblTitle">Sermons Preached in the Chapel of Rugby School</div>
            <div class="biblPage">356</div>
            <p>Sermons preached in the Chapel of Rugby School, with an Address
               before Confirmation. -By Thomas Arnold, D. D.,Head Master
               of Rugby School, and author of "The History of Rome,” etc.
               First American edition. New York: D Appleton &amp; Co.
            </p>
            
            <p>A neat duodecimo of 284 pages. Independently of the interest
               attached to the mere name of Dr. Arnold, these Sermons have a
               rich intrinsic value. The Appletons have conferred a favor on
               the public in the issue of this series of books—the compositions,
               we mean, of Dr. Arnold.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <div class="biblTitle">Francis and Co's Cabinet Library</div>
            <div class="biblPage">356</div>
            <p>Francis &amp; Co’s Cabinet Library of Choice Prose and Poetry. Nos.
               3 and 4. The Dream and other Poems. By the Hon. Mrs.
               Norton—and The Child of the Islands, by the Hon. Mrs.
               Norton.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mrs Norton is emphatically the poet of passion—even more so
               than Byron. No single poem ever so powerfully affected us as
               “The Dying Hour,” included in No. 3 of this series. The effect,
               however, is in no respect a properly poetical one, and the same
               sentiments in prose would have produced an intenser passionate
               effect. We will endeavor to make ourselves more distinctly
               understood on this topic hereafter. Of course we admit the high
               powers of Mrs. Norton as a poetess—even in the most legitimate
               acceptation of the term.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Life of Mozart</div>
            <div class="biblPage">356</div>
            <p>The Life of Mozart, including his Correspondence. By Edward
               Holmes, Author of “A ramble among the Musicians of Germany.” New York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is No. 4 of Harper’s valuable and beautiful “New Miscellany,” and is a book of exceeding interest even to non-musical
               readers. To musicians it must have a much higher charm. The
               preface says:
            </p>
            
            <p>The only biographical notice of Mozart in English is a translation
               from the French of Bombet (M. Beyle), itself a translation from the
               German of Schlictegroll—a sketch too short and scanty to satisfy
               the interest of the subject, although quite enough to pique public
               curiosity. With the exception of occasional fragments in magazines and reviews, little more is known in England of the life of
               the musician, its struggles, varied incidents, and influence upon art,
               or of the brilliant reputations that clustered round him. The object
               of the following pages is to supply this deficiency.
            </p>
            
            <p>We cannot conclude without once again expressing our
               admiration of the taste and sound judgment evinced in the whole
               getting up of “The New Miscellany.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Treasury of History</div>
            <div class="biblPage">356</div>
            <p>The Treasury of History, No. 11. New York: Daniel Adee.
               We receive this pamphlet with a printed slip of paper con-
               taining the following words:
               
            </p>
            <p>The Treasury of History.—We are pleased to receive the 
               11th number of this valuable compendium. It will be seen that
               as the work draws to a close it increases in interest, instead of
               diminishing, and will make a perfectly unique book of reference.
               It must be prized alike by the youthful student, or more mature
               scholar, and should be found in every family. This number, being
               the last but one, contains a profusion of facts worthy to be retained
               for reference. For instance, the conclusion of the History of China;
               the History of Japan, and the East India Islands; Palestine; Egypt,
               with Syria; the Barbary States; British America, Canada, and
               Mexico; South America, Peru, Chili, Brazil, and the Republic of
               La Plata; Columbia, Bolivia, &amp;c. The West India Islands, Cuba,
               Hayti, Porto Rico, &amp;c. Also the commencement of the History of
               the United States.
            </p>
            
            <p>Published and for sale, at 25 cents per No., by Daniel Adee, 107
               Fulton street, N. Y.
               
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a circular, and, we presume, is sent round (with the
               book) to editors generally. In the present instance we have no
               hesitation in adopting the opinion as our own—that is to say,
               we agree with it—but the practice of sending round such circulars is atrocious.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Annuals and late Magazines in our next.</p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p18">
         <div class="biblTitle">Epigram: From the Spanish</div>
         <div class="biblPage">356</div>
         <div class="head">Epigram.
            FROM THE SPANISH.
         </div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>To seek his wife, with little profit,
            
            <br></br>The Thracian Orpheus went to Tophet;
            
            <br></br>A realm of such a sad condition,
            
            <br></br>He could not seek on sadder mission:
            
            <br></br>Disposed to punish guest so human,
            
            <br></br>Grim Pluto gives him up the woman;
            
            <br></br>Yet, when the Bard’s songs overcome him,
            
            <br></br>Grows softened, and back takes her from him.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">W. Gilmore Simms</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p19">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Drama</div>
         <div class="biblPage">356</div>
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>Under this head we have exceedingly little to observe. Mrs.
            Mowatt has turned the heads of the Richmondians, who, with a
            j proper taste, appreciate her sweet tones, her excellent elocution,
            j and her peculiar grace and beauty. She is now in Charleston.
         </p>
         
         <p>Miss Charlotte Barnes will appear at the Park probably
            about the middle of this month.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Murdoch is everywhere successful.</p>
         
         <p>We were at the Park on Monday last, to see Mrs. Kean in
            ‘‘Ion.” The play itself is one admirably adapted to the powers of
            the actress—assimilated in every respect to her genius—for
            genius she undoubtedly possesses—not the less great because
            subdued in tone.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Ion” is no drama—if we think of what a drama should be.
            It never profoundly moves us. It stimulates rather the fancy
            than the passions. It is poetical, classical, “correct,” (in the
            French sense,) but no play—comparatively of course—it is better
            than ninety-nine plays out of a hundred.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mrs. Kean evinces her genius chiefly in her exquisite intonation and gesture. No one, without genius, and that of a lofty order,
            could so thrill us by a mere tone. Her step is indeed the poetry
            of motion, and her limbs might put to the blush (if limbs or if
            marble could blush) those of the Venus of Cleomenes. Her figure,
            in other respects, is not particularly good—and the scarf of Ion
            gives an unpleasant roundness to the shoulders.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Kean’s acting impressed us more favorably than we had
            been led to anticipate. There were one or two points at which
            his reading (not his readings) produced an evident thrill of emotion throughout the audience. The dresses of Adrastus are
            excessively unbecoming.
         </p>
         
         <p>We shall see “Ion” again and speak of it less at random.
            
         </p>
         <p>At Palmo’s, on Thursday last, a company of fashionable
            amateurs made an attempt at “Hamlet.” We shall give an
            account of the performance in our next.
         </p>
         
         <p>The German Opera promises well.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Olympic, the Bowery, the Chatham, and the Richmond
            Hill theatres have all, we learn, been well attended of late, but
            we have been prevented, by an unusual press of business, from
            visiting either. It is our purpose to speak somewhat at large,
            hereafter, of theatrical matters.
         </p>
         
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p20">
         <div class="biblTitle">Sleep On</div>
         <div class="biblPage">357</div>
         <div class="head">Sleep On.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>Sleep on—for the starlight above thee is gleaming,
            
            <br></br>While love’s eye keeps watch o’er the couch of thy rest:
            
            <br></br>Sleep on—thy repose will be calmed by its beaming—
            
            <br></br>’Twill picture in thine, love, the dreams it loves best.
            
            <br></br>Sleep on—for the night-flowers around us are shaking
            
            <br></br>Their sweet incense cup to the zephyrs they love;
            
            <br></br>And the lone nightingale with music is waking
            
            <br></br>The echo of flower-crowned mountain and grove.
            
            <br></br>Sleep on—for the bright water-spirit is murm’ring
            
            <br></br>Her soft lullaby to the starry-gemm’d night,
            
            <br></br>That now on her pure, silent bosom is slumb’ring,
            
            <br></br>Gilding each dream-wave with crescents of light.
            
            <br></br>Sleep on—for the moonlight, though sweet, is as fleeting
            
            <br></br>As the soft, gentle rays that affection may shed—
            
            <br></br>Sleep on—e’er the Day-God again gives his greeting,
            
            <br></br>And night on her dark wing hath tremblingly fled.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">H. S. Delgrove</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p21">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Fine Arts</div>
         <div class="biblPage">357</div>
         <div class="head">The Fine Arts</div>
         
         <p>Miss Northall, on Wednesday evening, the 3d, had not
            as large an audience as we expected; owing, perhaps, to the inclemency of the weather. It was, however, one of the best concerts of the season. Miss Northall sang beautifully; better than
            on any other occasion. Mrs. Loder sustained her well-earned
            reputation, and Signor De Begnis sang as if he grew younger
            every day. Messrs. Kyle, Timm, and Marks did their parts
            well; the latter even better than we expected, and on the whole,
            we never were more pleased. We hope Miss Northall will soon
            favor us with a repetition of this concert.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have received the following pieces:
            Night and Morning, Valse characteristique.
            Diane, Rondeau de Chasse.
            Souvenir de Belville, Valse.
            L'Hortense, Galope brillante.
            L'Amitié, Variations Brillantes.
            Bellone, Polonaise à la Militaire.
            United States' Grand Waltz.
            La Liberté, Variations brillantes.
            All of them composed by Charles Grobe.
            
         </p>
         <p>There is a freshness and originality in the compositions of this
            gentleman, which is not often found in pieces of the same description. We like his idea of expressing night and morning by
            minor and major, though we think the motives of the two waltzes
            should have been a little more different. The United Slates’ Grand
            Waltz is really a gem, and L'Amitié, a set of variations on a theme
            of La fille du Régiment, is as pleasing as it is easy and brilliant.
         </p>
         
         <p>Another Pianist has lately arrived from France, and intends
            giving a series of concerts in this city.
            
         </p>
         <p>A Complimentary Concert has been tendered to Mr. Paterson,
            the Editor of the Anglo-American, in which all the principal
            talent of this city will appear.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Christian Huber’s Concert.—A very select audience
            greeted this eminent artist on his appearance, and cheers and bravos were the reward of his masterly execution of the most difficult
            compositions on the Violoncello. But it seems that Mr. Huber
            has not been fortunate in the selection of his pieces, and that his
            assistants have been less so in the selection of theirs. The former gave us too little of the cantabile and portamente, while the
            
            latter gave us altogether too much of it. We must except Mr.
            Gibert, for he sang the Serenade from Don Pasquale and the Romance “Le Bon Curé,” with admirable grace.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Templeton had a crowded house at his farewell concert.</p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p22">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Deathless Smile</div>
         <div class="biblPage">357</div>
         <div class="head">The Deathless Smile.</div>
         
         <div class="lg">
            <br></br>I saw one in her maidenhood,
            
            <br></br>From whom the life had fled;
            
            <br></br>And yet so lovely was her face,
            
            <br></br>It seemed she was not dead!
            
            <br></br>Her eyelids as in sleep were closed—
            
            <br></br>Her brow was white as snow;
            
            <br></br>A smile still lingered on her lips,
            
            <br></br>As if ’twere loth to go.
            
            <br></br>And it may be a smile so sweet—
            
            <br></br>So quiet and serene—
            
            <br></br>Was never on the healthy brow
            
            <br></br>Of living maiden seen.
            
            <br></br>Perchance the wondrous bliss which burst
            
            <br></br>Upon her raptured mind,
            
            <br></br>When first she woke in glory’s courts—
            
            <br></br>Now left its trace behind.
            
            <br></br>Her end was peace. I thought that they
            
            <br></br>Who loved her should not grieve,
            
            <br></br>For these last words they heard her say—
            
            <br></br>“My spirit, Lord! receive.”
            
            <br></br>And when they laid her in the earth,
            
            <br></br>Her cheek still held the bloom;
            
            <br></br>That smile, so sweet, the gentle maid
            
            <br></br>Bore with her to the tomb!
            
            <br></br>Would it be strange if brighter tints
            
            <br></br>Upon the blossoms crept,
            
            <br></br>Which grew above the sacred spot
            
            <br></br>Where that meek maiden slept.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">O. H. Mildeberger</span>.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="biblTitle">Editorial Miscellany</div>
         <div class="head">Editorial Miscellany.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Broadway Journal</div>
            <div class="biblPage">357</div>
            <p>The Broadway Journal may be obtained in the City of New
               York of the following agents:—Taylor, Astor House; Crosby,
               Exchange, William street; Graham, Tribune Buildings; Lockwood, Broadway and Grand; and Burgess &amp; Stringer, Ann and
               Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Harbinger</div>
            <div class="biblPage">357</div>
            <p>“The Harbinger—Edited by The Brook-Farm Phalanx”—
               is, beyond doubt, the most reputable organ of the Crazyites.
               We sincerely respect it—odd as this assertion may appear. It
               is conducted by an assemblage of well-read persons who mean
               no harm—and who, perhaps, can do less. Their objects are
               honorable, and so forth—all that anybody can understand of
               them—and we really believe that Mr. Albert Brisbane and one
               or two other ladies and gentlemen understand all about them that
               is necessary to be understood. But what we, individually, have
               done to “The Harbinger,” or what we have done to “The
               Brook-Farm Phalanx,” that “The Brook-Farm Phalanx” should
               stop the ordinary operations at Brook-Farm for the purpose
               of abusing us, is a point we are unable to comprehend. If we
               have done anything to affront “The Brook-Farm Phalanx” we
               will make an apology forthwith—provided “The Brook-Farm
               Phalanx” (which we have a great curiosity to see) will just step
               into our office, which is 304 Broadway.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the mean time, by way of doing penance for any unintentional offence that we may have given The Phalanx, we will just
               
               copy, verbatim, a very severe lesson it has been lately reading |
               to ourselves.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p25">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Raven and Other Poems</div>
            <div class="biblPage">357</div>
            <p>The Raven and other Poems. By Edgar A. Poe. New York 
               and London: Wiley and Putnam, 161 Broadway; 6 Waterloo
               Place, pp. 91.
               
            </p>
            <p>Mr. Poe has earned some fame by various tales and poems, which 
               of late has become notoriety through a certain blackguard warfare 
               which he has been waging against the poets and newspaper critics
               of New England, and which it would be most charitable to impute
               to insanity. Judging from the tone of his late articles in the Broadway Journal, he seems to think that the whole literary South and
               West are doing anxious battle in his person against the old timehonored tyrant of the North. But what have North or South to do
               with affairs only apropos to Poe? He shows himself a poet in
               this, at least, in the magnifying mirror of his own importance. To
               him facts lose their barren literality—to him a primrose is more
               than a primrose; and Edgar Poe, acting the constabulary part of a
               spy in detecting plagiarisms in favorite authors, insulting a Boston
               audience, inditing coarse editorials against respectable editresses,
               and getting singed himself the meanwhile, is "nothing less than the
               hero of a grand mystic conflict of the elements.
            </p>
            
            <p>The present volume is not entirely pure of this controversy, else
               we should ignore the late scandalous courses of the man, and speak
               only of the “Poems.” The motive of the publication is too apparent; it contains the famous Boston poem, together with other
               juvenilities, which, he says, “private reasons—some of which have
               reference to the sin of plagiarism, and others to the date of Tennyson’s first poems”—have induced him to republish. Does he mean
               to intimate that he is suspected of copying Tennyson? In vain have
               we searched the poems for a shadow of resemblance. Does he think
               to convict Tennyson of copying him? Another of those self-exaggerations which prove, we suppose, his poetic imagination.
            </p>
            
            <p>In a sober attempt to get at the meaning and worth of these poems
               as poetry, we have been not a little puzzled. We must confess they
               have a great deal of power, a great deal of beauty, (of thought frequently, and always of rhythm and diction,) originality, and dramatic effect. But they have more of effect than of expression; to
               adopt a distinction from musical criticism; and if they attract you
               to a certain length, it is only to repulse you the more coldly at last.
               There is a wild unearthliness, and unheavenliness, in the tone of all
               his pictures, a strange unreality in all his thoughts; they seem to
               stand shivering, begging admission to our hearts in vain, because
               they look not as if they came from the heart. The ill-boding
               “Raven,” which you meet at the threshold of his edifice, is a fit
               warning of the hospitality you will find inside. And yet the
               “Raven” has great beauty, and has won the author some renown; we
               were fascinated till we read it through; then we hated to look at it, or
               think of it again: why was that? There is something in it of the
               true grief of a lover, an imagination of a broken-heartedness enough
               to prove a lover in earnest, a power of strange, sad melody, which
               there is no resisting. So there is in all his poems. Mr. Poe has made
               a critical study of the matter of versification, and succeeded in the art
               rather at the expense of nature. Indeed the impression of a very
               studied effect is always uppermost after reading him. And you have
               to study him to understand him. This you would count no loss, if,
               when you had followed the man through his studies, you could find
               anything in them beyond the man and his most motiveless moods,
               which lead you nowhere; if you could find anything better at bottom
               than the pride of originality. What is the fancy which is merely
               fancy, the beauty which springs from no feeling, which neither illustrates nor promotes the great rules and purposes of life, which
               glimmers strangely only because it is aside from the path of human
               destiny? Edgar Poe does not write for Humanity; he has more of
               the art than the soul of poetry. He affects to despise the world
               while he writes for it. He certainly has struck out a remarkable
               course: the style and imagery of his earliest poems mark a very
               singular culture, a judgment most severe for a young writer, and a
               familiarity with the less hacknied portions of classic lore and no-
               
               menclature. He seems to have had an idea of working out his forms
               from pure white marble. But the poet’s humility is wanting; a
               morbid egotism repels you. He can affect you with wonder, but
               rarely with the thrill of any passion, except perhaps of pride, which
               might be dignity, and which therefore always is interesting. We
               fear this writer even courts the state described by Tennyson:
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>A glorious devil, large in heart and brain,
               
               <br></br>That did love beauty only, (beauty seen
               
               <br></br>In all varieties of mould and mind,)
               
               <br></br>And knowledge for its beauty; or if good,
               
               <br></br>Good only for its beauty, seeing not
               
               <br></br>That Beauty, Good, and Knowledge, are three sisters
               
               <br></br>That doat upon each other, friends to man,
               
               <br></br>Living together under the same roof,
               
               <br></br>And never can be sundered without tears;
               
               <br></br>And he that shuts Love out, in turn shall be
               
               <br></br>Shut out by Love, and on her threshold lie
               
               <br></br>Howling in utter darkness.
            </div>
            
            
            <p>There is something in all this which we really respect—an evident wish to be sincere, pervading the whole tone of the sermon
               —an anxious determination to speak the truth—at least as far as
               convenient. The Brook Farm Phalanx talks to us, in short,
               “like a Dutch uncle,” and we shall reply to it, very succinctly,
               in the same spirit.
            </p>
            <p>“Very charitable to impute to insanity.” Insanity is a word
               that the Brook Farm Phalanx should never be brought to mention under any circumstances whatsoever. “No more of that,
               Hal, an ye love me.”
            </p>
            <p>“The time-honored tyrant of the North.” Very properly
               rugavvos—not Batiasus. King Log at best. The sceptre is departed.
            </p>
            <p>“Insulting a Boston audience”—very true—meant to do it—
               and did.
               
            </p>
            <p>“Getting singed in return.” The singeing refers, we presume,
               to the doubling,in five weeks,the circulation of the “Broadway
               Journal.”
            </p>
            <p>“Motive of the publication too apparent.” “The Raven, etc.,”
               was in the publishers’ hands a month or six weeks before we received the invitation from the Lyceum—and we read the last
               proofs on the evening before that on which we “insulted the
               Boston audience.” On these points The Brook Farm Phalanx are
               referred to Messrs. Wiley and Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Discover no shade of resemblance to Tennyson.” Certainly
               not—we never could discover any ourselves. Our foot-note
               (quoted by the Phalanx) has reference to an article written by Mr.
               Charles Dickens in the London Foreign Quarterly Review. Mr.
               Dickens in paying us some valued, though injudicious compliments, concluded by observing, that “we had all Tennyson’s
               spirituality, and might be considered as the best of his imitators”
               —words to that effect. Our design has been merely to demonstrate (should a similar accusation again be made) that the poems
               in question were published before Tennyson had written at all.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Has acquired some renown by the Raven.” We cannot approve of the “same”—especially in the mouths of those worshippers of Truth, The Brook Farm Phalanx.</p>
            
            <p>The Brook Farm Phalanx knows very well—and so do we—
               that no American poem gained for its author even one half so
               much “renown” in the same period of time. The renown is
               quite as small a thing as the poem—and we have therefore no
               scruple in alluding to it—although we do so only because it
               shocks us to hear a set of respectable Crazyites talking in so disingenuous a manner. Reform it altogether, or give up preaching
               about Truth.
            </p>
            
            <p>As for the rest, we believe it is all leather and prunella—the
               opinion of “The Snook Farm Phalanx.” We do trust that, in
               future, “The Snook Farm Phalanx” will never have any opinion
               of us at all.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p26">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Most Eminent Living Writer of Portugal</div>
            <div class="biblPage">359</div>
            <p>The most eminent living writer of Portugal, indeed the only
               one of any considerable eminence, is Senhor Almeida Garrett, a
               leading deputy of the ultra-liberal opposition in Lisbon, who has
               very high powers both as an orator and a poet; though his poetical works appear rather deficient in strength of original thought.
               His prose is both brilliant and powerful. His poems are of considerable extent, and not the least of their charms is that he is a
               good scholar and eminent for antiquarian research. He is of the
               blank-verse school, which in Portugal is a great misfortune.
               We extract the following as a favorable specimen, and the more
               willingly because it unfolds the beauties of a word, “Saudade,”
               upon the exclusive possession of which the Portuguese particularly pride themselves. There is certainly no one word in any other
               European language which conveys the same idea. It expresses
               the sweet yet painful sensation created by the contemplation of a
               beloved object from which we are separated:—
            </p>
            
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>Oh tender yearning! bitterness of joy
               
               <br></br>For the unhappy, thorn of absence with
               
               <br></br>Delicious puncture piercing through the heart,
               
               <br></br>Awakening pain that lacerates the soul.
               
               <br></br>Yet hath it pleasure;―tender yearning grief!
               
               <br></br>Mysterious power that canst awaken hearts,
               
               <br></br>And make them ooze forth, drop by drop distilled,
               
               <br></br>Not life-blood, but of soft and dewy tears
               
               <br></br>A solacing abundance;—yearning grief;
               
               <br></br>Beloved name, that sounds so honey-sweet
               
               <br></br>In lips of Lucitania; sound unknown
               
               <br></br>To the proud mouths of these Sycambrians
               
               <br></br>Of foreign lands;—oh, tender yearning grief!
               
               <br></br>Thou magic Power that dost transport the soul
               
               <br></br>Of absence unto solitary friend,
               
               <br></br>Of wandering lover to his mistress lorn,
               
               <br></br>And even the sad and wretched exile, most
               
               <br></br>Unhappy of Earth’s children, bear'st in dreams
               
               <br></br>Back to his country’s bosom, dreams so sweet
               
               <br></br>That cruel’tis the dreamer to awake.
               
               <br></br>If, on thy humid altar, tear-bedewed,
               
               <br></br>I laid my heart, which fast was throbbing still
               
               <br></br>When from my bleeding breast I plucked it forth
               
               <br></br>At Tagus’ mouth beloved;—come in thy car,
               
               <br></br>By gently murmuring doves gray-pinioned drawn,
               
               <br></br>And seek my heart which, Goddess, sighs for thee!
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mr. Hudson</div>
            <div class="biblPage">359</div>
            <p>Mr. Hudson, on Tuesday evening last, read to an audience of
               some two hundred persons, at the Society Library, his Lecture on
               Lear (or a portion of it) recently delivered at Boston, and much
               complimented in one or two of the Boston papers. We listened
               to the lecturer with profound attention, and (for the first time)
               heard him throughout. He did not favorably impress us. His
               good points are a happy talent for fanciful, that is to say for unexpected (too often far-fetched) illustration, and a certain cloudy
               acuteness in respect to motives of human action. His bad points
               are legion—want of concentration—want of consecutiveness—
               want of definite purpose—want of common school education—
               utter incapacity to comprehend a drama out of its range of mere
               character—an absurd passion for the lower species, that is to say,
               for the too obvious species of antithesis—a more absurd rage for
               metaphor and direct simile, without the least ability to keep them
               within bounds, or to render them consistent, either per se, or with
               the matter into which they are introduced—to crown all, a pitiable
               affectation of humility altogether unbecoming a man, an elocution
               that would disgrace a pig, and an odd species of gesticulation
               of which a baboon would have excellent reason to be ashamed.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p28">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Tribune Says</div>
            <div class="biblPage">359</div>
            <p>The Tribune says;―"The article in the American Review of
               this month, entitled  'The Facts of M. Valdemar's Case, by Edgar
               A. Poe,’ is of course a romance—who could have supposed it
               otherwise? Those who have read Mr. Poe’s visit to the Maelstrom, South Pole, &amp;c., have not been puzzled by it, yet we learn
               that several good matter-of-fact citizens have been, sorely. It is
               a pretty good specimen of Poe’s style of giving an air of reality
               to fictions, and we utterly condemn the choice of a subject, but
               whoever thought it a veracious recital must have the bump of
               Faith large, very large indeed.”
            </p>
            
            <p>For our parts we find it difficult to understand how any dispassionate transcendentalist can doubt the facts as we state them;
               they are by no means so incredible as the marvels which are
               hourly narrated, and believed, on the topic of Mesmerism. Why
               cannot a man’s death be postponed indefinitely by Mesmerism?
               Why cannot a man talk after he is dead? Why?—why?—that
               is the question; and as soon as the Tribune has answered it to
               our satisfaction we will talk to it farther.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p29">
            <div class="biblTitle">Hon. Wm. C. Preston</div>
            <div class="biblPage">359</div>
            <p>Hon. Wm. C. Preston has been elected President of the South
               Carolina College at Columbia. It is understood that he will accept
               and commence the duties of the Presidency early in the ensuing
               year. In the meantime, Rev. Dr. Hooper will discharge them.
               Rev. Dr. Henry has been offered the Greek Professorship, and we
               sincerely hope that he may accept it. The accession of Mr.
               Preston is of course, per se, and without reference to the secession
               of Dr. Henry, a subject of congratulation to the College—hut
               upon the whole, some injustice, we think, has been done to the
               late President. We shall speak more fully in our next.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p30">
            <div class="biblTitle">The Mirror Says</div>
            <div class="biblPage">359</div>
            <p>The Mirror says:
               The editor of the Philadelphia North American has “scared up”
               a feminine genius—a poetical wonder—hear him: “The greatest
               poet of her sex who ever lived, is Maria Brooks. She is as much
               above Mrs. Hemans, Miss Landon, Mrs. Norton, et id omne genus,
               as they are above the sickliest sentimentalists of the chambermaids’
               gazettes!!
            </p>
            
            <p>There is, perhaps, some exaggeration in the North American’s
               estimate of Mrs. Brooks, but far more in the Mirror’s attempt at
               depreciation. Mrs. Maria Brooks, author of “Zophiel, or The
               Bride of Seven,” is fairly entitled to be culled the greatest of
               American poetesses. Her imagination and audacity of thought
               and expression, are not far behind Miss Barrett. Her chief faults
               are bombast and extravagance.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p31">
            <div class="biblTitle">Connoisseurs and Amateurs of Tea</div>
            <div class="biblPage">359</div>
            <p>Connoisseurs and amateurs of Tea would do well to look over
               the Catalogue of Teas on sale at the warehouse of the Pekin Tea
               Company, No. 75 Fulton street. See advertisement in this
               week’s Journal. Hitherto it has been impossible to procure
               really good green tea at less than a dollar per pound. The Pekin
               Company afford an exquisite article at 75 cents—other teas at
               proportionate rates. We can conscientiously recommend them.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p32">
            <div class="biblTitle">A Late "Tribune"</div>
            <div class="biblPage">359</div>
            <p>A late "Tribune” has a very just review of Longfellow. We
               quote a few passages:—
               
            </p>
            <p>The portrait which adorns this volume is not merely flattered or
               idealized, but there is an attempt at adorning it, by expression
               thrown into the eyes, with just that which the original does not
               possess, whether in face or mind. We have often seen faces whose
               usually coarse and heavy lineaments were harmonized at times into
               beauty by the light that rises from the soul into the eyes. The intention Nature had with regard to the face and its wearer, usually
               eclipsed beneath bad habits or a bad education, is then disclosed and
               we see what hopes Death has in stove for that soul. But here the
               
               enthusiasm thrown into the eyes only makes the rest of the face
               look more weak, and the idea suggested is the anomalous one of a
               Dandy Pindar.
            </p>
            
            <p>Such is not the case with Mr. Longfellow himself. He is never
               a Pindar, though he is sometimes a Dandy even in the clear and ornamented streets and trim gardens of his verse But he is still more
               a man of cultivated taste, delicate though not deep feeling, and some,
               though not much, poetic force.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Longfellow has been accused of plagiarism. We have been
               surprised that any one should have been anxious to fasten special
               charges of this kind upon him, when we had supposed it so obvious
               that the greater part of his mental stores were derived from the
               works of others. He has no style of his own growing out of his own
               experiences and observations of nature. Nature with him, whether
               human or external, is always seen through the windows of literature.
               There are in his poems sweet and tender passages descriptive of his
               personal feelings, but very few showing him as an observer, at first
               hand, of the passions within, or the landscape without.
            </p>
            
            <p>This want of the free breath of nature, this perpetual borrowing of
               imagery, this excessive, because superficial, culture which he has
               derived from an acquaintance with the elegant literature of many
               nations and men, out of proportion to the experience of life within
               himself, prevent Mr. Longfellow’s verses from ever being a true refreshment to ourselves. He says in one of his most graceful verses:
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg">
               <br></br>From the cool cistern of the midnight air
               
               <br></br>My spirit drank repose;
               
               <br></br>The fountain of perpetual peace flows there,
               
               <br></br>From those deep cisterns flows.
            </div>
            
            <p>Now this is just what we cannot get from Mr. Longfellow. No
               solitude of the mind reveals to us the deep cisterns.
            </p>
            
            <p>Yet there is a middle class, composed of men of little original
               poetic power, but of much poetic taste and sensibility, whom we
               
               would not wish to have silenced. They do no harm but much
               good, (if only their minds are not confounded with those of a higher
               class,) by educating in others the faculties dominant in themselves In this class we place the writer at present before us.
            </p>
            
            <p>We must confess a coolness toward Mr. Longfellow, in consequence of the exaggerated praises that have been bestowed upon himWhen we see a person of moderate powers receive honors which
               should be reserved for the highest, we feel somewhat like assailing
               him and taking from him the crown which should be reserved for
               grander brows.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p33">
            <div class="biblTitle">Errata</div>
            <div class="biblPage">360</div>
            
            <p>Errata.—Several, of a vexatious character, occurred in our
               last week’s Journal—especially in the fine poem “Epicedium,”
               by Mr. Rowley; among other blunders, a whole line was omitted. We have taken measures to prevent anything of this kind
               for the future.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p34">
            <div class="biblTitle">Mr. Thomas H. Lane</div>
            <div class="biblPage">360</div>
            <p>Mr. Thomas H. Lane is the only person (besides ourself)
               authorized to give receipts or transact business for “The
               Broadway Journal.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p35">
            <div class="biblTitle">To Correspondents</div>
            <div class="biblPage">360</div>
            <p>To Correspondents.—Many thanks to the author of “The
               New Generation”—also to P. P. C.; we will write him fully in
               a few days. Our friends F. W. T. and P. B. shall also soon hear
               from us—if indeed they have not already quite given us up.
            </p>
            
            <p>We are forced to decline “Remembrance” “Autumn,” and the
               Lines to Estelle—the Sonnet may appear.
            </p>
            
            <p>The proposition of I. R. O. is respectfully declined.</p>
            
            <p>The numbers desired by our friend A. M. I. can he obtained.
               We thank him sincerely for his late favor.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="biblTitle">Advertisements</div>
         <div class="biblPage">360</div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">JUST PUBLISHED
               In advance of the London edition,)
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">LIFE OF THE GREAT CONDE,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">BY LORD MAHON.</div>
            
            <p>TWO NUMBERS—beautifully printed, in clear type, $1 00. “A
               highly interesting and skillful narrative.”—Qtiar. Review.
            </p>
            
            <p>The above work forms Nos. 34 and 35 of the Library of Choice
               Reading. Published and for sale by
               WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 101 Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">General Furnishing Hardware, Cutlery, Tools, &amp;c.</div>
            
            <div class="head">OSBORN &amp; LITTLE,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Importers anil General Dealers in English, German, and
               
               <br></br>American
               
               <br></br>HARDWARE, CUTLERY, &amp;,C.,
               
               <br></br>No. 33 FULTON STREET,
               
               <br></br>between pearl and water streets,
               
               <br></br>[Where the business has been carried on for eighty years past.]
               
               <br></br>NEW YORK.
               
               <br></br>Charlses Osborn. 	
               
               <br></br>CHARLES S. LITTLE. 
            </div>
            
            <p>Hardware, Cutlery, Nails, Locks, Latches, Butts, Screws, Anvils,
               Vices, Saws, Files, Shovels and Spades, Hollow Ware, Corn and
               Coffee Mills, Rivets, Pumps, Curriers’ Hones, Crucibles, Black
               Lead, Pots, &amp;c. tec. Also, Genuine Haarlaem Oil. American
               Coopers and Carpenters’ Edge Tools, of Albertson’s, Conger’s
               Barton’s Horton’s, Gifford’s, and other makers. Also, Cooper’s
               Truss Hoops.	nov8—3m
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JOHN ANDERSON &amp;, Co.,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">IMPORTERS AND DEALERS IN
               
               <br></br>CHOICE SEGARS, and Manufacturers of Premium Tobacco
               
               <br></br>and Snuffs—2 Wall, and 13 and 15 Duane streets, New York.
               
               <br></br>nov8—3m
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">UNITED STATES HOTEL.</div>
            
            <p>THE PROPRIETOR OF THIS HOTEL, desires to return his
               thanks to his friends, and the traveling portion of the community generally, for the favors which they have bestowed upon him
               since he opened his establishment, and to assure them that he will
               spare no exertions to render his House worthy of the patronage of
               which he has already received so liberal a share.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">H. JOHNSON.
               
               <br></br>Nov. 8th, 1845.	6m
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JAMES PIRSSON,</div>
            
            <p>PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER, 88, 90, and 92 Walker
               Street, near Elm. A large stock of the finest instruments
               always on hand. Terms moderate. For Sale—a splendid Harp,
               nearly new—to be sold at a great bargain for cash.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PENMANSHIP.</div>
            
            <p>RE-OPENING OF GOLDSMITH’S WRITING ACADEMY,
               XL 289 Broadway—La Farge Buildings, Corner of Reade street.
               Terms reduced to Three Dollars, and no extra charge.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the citizens of New
               York and Brooklyn, that his rooms are now open, during the day
               and evening, for Pupils and Visitors. Mr. G’s. specimens of
               PENMANSHIP
               have received the First Premium Five Years, from the American
               Institute, and he guarantees to all, in TEN EASY AND INTERESTING EXERCISES, a free and elegant style of writing, that
               the pupils cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale, at the Academy, GOLDSMITH’S GEMS OF PENMANSHIP.</p>
            
            <p>Ladies’ Class meets daily at 11 o’clock. Gentlemen’s day and
               evening. See circular.	s18
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">WEDDING, VISITING, AND PROFESSIONAL CARDS</div>
            
            <p>Engraved and Printed at VALENTINE’S, 1 Beekman-st.
               Lovejoy’s Hotel.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JOHN BURFORD,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PORTRAIT AND LANDSCAPE PAINTER.
               
               <br></br>27 Dey Street.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">NEW BOOKS,
               TO BE PUBLISHED BY
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">MESSRS. WILEY &amp; PUTNAM,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">IN DECEMBER.
               
               <br></br>I.
            </div>
            
            <p>Carlyle’s new Work. The Letters and Speeches of Oliver Cromwell, with Elucidations, by Thomas Carlyle, in 2 vols. 8 vo., with
               Portrait, engraved by F. Hall from an original by Cooper, in the
               possession of Archdeacon Berners. Also, 2 vols. 16mo., in the
               “Library of Choice Readings.”
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">II.</div>
            
            <p>Stories from the Italian Poets, being a summary in Prose of the
               Poems of Dante, Pulci, Bolardo, Ariosto, and Tasso, with comments
               throughout, occasional passages versified, and Critical Notices of
               the Lives and Genius of the Authors. By Leigh Hunt, l6mo.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">III.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Book of Christmas. By T. K. Hervey.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">IV.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Views and Reviews in American History, Literature, and Art.
               
               <br></br>By W. Gilmore Simms.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">V.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Alps and the Rhine. By J. T. Headley.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">VI.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Mrs. Southey's Poems. The Birth-day, and other Poems—Sol-
               
               <br></br>itary Hours. By Caroline Southey, 2 vols. 16mo.—(Shortly.)
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">VII.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Author of “Undine." Theiodolf the Icelander. By La
               
               <br></br>Motte Fouqué, l6mo.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">VIII.</div>
            
            <p>Tales from the German of Zschokke, second series. Illumination; or, the Sleep Walker—The Broken Cup—Jonathan Frock
               — The Involuntary Journey—Leaves from the Journal of a Poor
               Curate in Wiltshire. By Parke Godwin.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IX.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Vicar of Wakefield.—An edition on superior paper, with
               
               <br></br>choice Illustrations by Mulready.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">JUST PUBLISHED.</div>
            
            <p>The Life of the Great Condi. By Lord Mahon, forming Nos.
               XXXIV. and XXXV. of “The Library of Choice Reading.”
               dec 4	WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PAINE &amp; BURGESS, 62 JOHN STREET.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">HAVE lately published—
               
               <br></br>1.	The Artist, Merchant and Statesman, 2 vols. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>2.	Trippings in Authorland, by Fanny Forrester, 12mo.
               
               <br></br>3.	Songs and Ballads, by Geo. P. Morris, 32mo. gilt.
               
               <br></br>4.	Prariedom; Rambles and Scrambles in Texas, or New Estre-
               
               <br></br>madura, with a Map, by a Southron, 1 vol. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>5.	Autobiography of Alfieri, 1 voL 12mo.
               
               <br></br>6.	Citizen of a Republic, by Ceba, 1 vol. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>7.	Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli, 2 vols. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>8.	Challenge of Barletta, by D’Azeglio, 1 vol. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>9.	Musical Spelling Book, by E. Ives, 1 vol. 8vo.
               
               <br></br>10.	Beethoven Collection of Sacred Music.
               
               <br></br>11.	Rambles by Land and Water, or Notes of Travel in Cuba and
               
               <br></br>Mexico, elegantly illustrated, by B. M. Norman, 1 vol. 12mo.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">NEARLY READY,
               
               <br></br>1. Montezuma, The Last of the Aztecs; an Historical Ro-
               
               <br></br>mance on the Conquest of Mexico, by Edward Maturin, 2 vols.
               
               <br></br>12mo.
               
               <br></br>2. Morris &amp; Willis’ Library of the Rose and Poetry of Europe
               
               <br></br>and America, 1 vol. 8vo. An elegant and valuable Gift Book.
               
               <br></br>3. Old Continental, or the Price of Liberty; by the author
               
               <br></br>of “Dutchman’s Fireside,” 2 vols. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>4. Man in the Republic, by C. Mathews, 32mo. gilt.
               
               <br></br>5. Musical ABC, for children, lGmo.
               
               <br></br>6. Greece of the Greeks, by G. A. Perdicaris, late U. S. Consul
               
               <br></br>at Athens, 2 vols. 12mo. illustrated.
               
               <br></br>7.	Musical Reader, 4to.
               
               <br></br>8.	The Prince, by Machiavelli, 1 vol. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>9.	The Musical Wreath, 4to.
               
               <br></br>10.	Over the Ocean! or Glimpses of Many Lands, by a Lady.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>THOMAS H. CHALMERS, (formerly Conductor to Dubois
               and Stodart,) No. 383 Broadway, will keep a complete assortment of the latest approved Grand Action Piano Fortes of the most
               superior quality; such as he is prepared to guarantee for their excellence of Tone, Touch, and External Finish, and to endure in any
               climate. A liberal discount from the standard prices. Fiano Fortes
               Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on hire.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">GURNEY’S
               PREMIUM DAGUERRIAN GALLERY,
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">189 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.</div>
            
            <p>PICTURES taken at this Establishment are not excelled in this
               country—so say his numerous patrons. The public are invited
               to call and judge for themselves.	oct2
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">G. B. CLARKE,</div>
            
            <p>MERCHANT TAILOR, (from Brundage, Broadway,) No. 132
               William Street, 3 doors from Fulton, N. Y.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Dress Coat, from $12 00 to $20 00      Making and Trimming.
               Pants,	“	2	50 to 	8 00	                 Dress Coat,	from $6 00 to $9	 00
               Vests,	“	1	50 to	 4 50	                   Pants,	“1 50 to 2 	00
               Vests,	“1 50 to 2	 00
            </div>
            
            <p>N. B. Seasonable SACK COATS, VESTS, See., always on hand,
               from $1 50 upwards.	nov8—3m
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">THE SECOND VOLUME OF
               THE ARISTIDEAN:
            </div>
            
            <p>A JOURNAL OF REVIEWS, POLITICS, AND LIGHT LITERATURE—By Thomas Dunn English, and numerous collaborators—commences on the 20th of January, 1846.</p>
            
            <p>The Aristidean is published monthly, each number containing
               80 pages, octavo, printed on handsome white paper, with bold, clear
               type, at Five Dollars per annum, payable in advance.
            </p>
            
            <p>The aim of the editor has been to establish a Journal of Art and
               Letters, whose papers should be distinguished for force, vigor, sarcasm and pith, rather than an unutterable and bathetic profundity;
               one, which should not fear to expose literary quackery, and give to
               writers a proper precedence; one that had the moral courage to
               praise an enemy’s good works, and censure a friend’s bad ones; one
               that would maintain a rigorous independence on literary, political
               and religious matters; one that would attack all abuses without
               scruple; one that was insensible to fear, and deaf to favor; and one
               that depended for success on the merit of its papers, and not on the
               names announced as contributors. If the editor may judge from the
               high panegyric of the press, and the more substantial evidence of an
               increasing subscription list, he has succeeded in his intention.
            </p>
            
            <p>Those desiring to sustain an independent and fearless magazine
               will be kind enough to remit their subscriptions by mail, rather
               than through an agent.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">THOMAS DUNN ENGLISH,
               
               <br></br>decl3—tf	304 Broadway, city of New York.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES,</div>
            
            <p>CHEAP FOR CASH.—The Subscribers have on hand a
               handsome assortment of 6, 6 1/2, and 7 octave mahogany and rosewood Pianos, which they will warrant, and sell low for cash or approved paper.	GLENN, ROGERS, &amp; Co.,
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Manufacturers, 152 Fulton street, east of Broadway</div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>V.F. HARRiSON, 23 CANAL STREET, N. Y.—Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
               Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of G and 7 octaves. They are made
               from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful
               workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the business.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B.—Wanted a second hand Parlor Organ.</p>
            
            <p>Piano Fortes hired by the month.</p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">AEOLIAN ATTACHMENT.</div>
            
            <p>Herrmann s. saroni, professor of music, 116
               Leonard street, New York, teaches the Piano Forte, with or
               without Coleman’s celebrated Attachment.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
            
            <p>H. WORCESTER, No. 139 THIRD AVENUE, CORNER
               of 14th street, respectfully informs his friends and the public,
               that he has a good assortment of Piano Fortes, in rosewood and mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octavos. Persons wishing to purchase
               will find it to their advantage to call and examine before purchasing
               elsewhere.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">J. BALLARD,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR, SINGING AND FLUTE.
               
               <br></br>No. 15 Spring street.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JOHN H. GENIN,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">FASHIONABLE HAT AND CAP ESTABLISHMENT,
               
               <br></br>214 Broadway.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">HARPER &amp; BROTHERS’ RECENT PUBLI-
               CATIONS.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">In one splendidly printed volume, with above 1000 engravings.
               
               <br></br>Sheep Extra.—Price $3 75.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">I.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">ENCYCLOPAEDIA OF DOMESTIC ECONOMY.</div>
            
            <p>“The wide range of topics comprised in this valuable publication,
               commends it to the attention of an unusually extended class of readers.-—to the family circle primarily, the architect, the horticulturist, the cabinet-maker, and others to whom the work addresses
               itself. It is undoubtedly by far the best work of reference ever presented for the use of families. Every housekeeper would find the
               work a real treasure.”—Globe.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">II.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">PROFESSOR WHEWELL’S ELEMENTS OF MORALITY.
               
               <br></br>Two volumes 12mo. extra gilt, $1.—Forming the commencement of
               
               <br></br>HARPERS NEW MISCELLANY.
            </div>
            
            <p>“A work of extraordinary merit. It is a thorough discussion of the
               fundamental principles of morals, by one of the profoundest thinkers
               of the age; and whether his conclusions are adopted or not, no
               reader can fail to perceive in any page, the traces of discrimination,
               thought, and a high moral aim. Its classic purity and precision of
               style is also a strong recommendation of the work.”—Observer.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">III.
               
               <br></br>MORRELL’S AMERICAN SHEPHERD;
            </div>
            
            <p>Being a complete history of the sheep, with their breeds, management, diseases, &amp;c. Illustrated by numerous engravings, 1 vol.
               12mo., cloth binding, §1—paper covers 75 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The above named volume, which is issued under the immediate
               sanction of the New-York State Agricultural Society, is a work of
               great practical importance, and contains a prodigious amount of
               instructive matter, suited to the farmer, the cattle fattener, the
               agriculturist and the wool-grower. Every one interested in these
               departments of commerce, would find the work invaluable.”—Evening Gazette.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IV.
               
               <br></br>ILLUSTRATED WANDERING JEW.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">In numbers; price 25 cents each. Profusely embellished.</div>
            
            <p>“We think these illustrations evince more vigor, brilliancy, and
               effect, than almost anything of the kind we have yet seen. As the
               Harpers publish this revised and elegant edition at such very trifling
               charge, we doubt not a prodigious demand will await it from the
               public; and it richly merits the largest popularity.”—Ev. Post.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">v.
               
               <br></br>GEN. GREEN’S
               
               <br></br>TEXAN EXPEDITION AGAINST MIER,
            </div>
            
            <p>Including the subsequent imprisonment of the author; his sufferings and final escape from the Castle of I’erote: with reflections
               upon the present political and probable future relations of Texas,
               Mexico and the United States, &amp;c. Illustrated by thirteen line engravings. One volume, Svo. $2.
            </p>
            
            <p>“This stirring narrative of the perilous and heroic exploits of a
               small band of patriotic Texans, who won not only laurels by their
               prowess, but liberty, is so rife with thrilling interest that it will
               win the attention of the public with the fascination of a romance.”—
               Com. Adv.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VI.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">CURIOUS AND UNIQUE WORK.
               
               <br></br>Now ready in one beautiful octavo volume, with many Engravings
               
               <br></br>on steel. Price, $2.
               
               <br></br>NARRATIVE OF A MISSION TO BOKHARA,
               
               <br></br>In the year 1843-45, to ascertain the fate of Col. Stoddart and
               
               <br></br>Capt. Conolly.
               
               <br></br>By the Rev. Joseph Wolff, LL.D.
            </div>
            
            <p>“This work has created a prodigious excitement throughout
               England; it is unique in its character, as a literary production. It
               seems to partake of the features of an autobiography; the narrative
               being full of personal detail, description of the perilous adventure
               and imminent hazard of the author, in his expedition through the
               East. No man living, perhaps, has traveled so extensively as this
               celebrated individual, and few could have contributed a more intensely interesting narrative of his experience.
            </p>
            
            <p>“It will thus be seen that this extraordinary and eccentric man
               is admirably qualified to present a transcript of Asiatic Characteristics,—supplying much that is novel and exceedingly curious about
               tribes and nations of which we know so little. To say that the
               work is an acceptable addition to the library of travel, is affirming
               far too little of so striking a production: it is a book that ought to
               be read and deliberately enjoyed by every intelligent person, for its
               quaintness, freshness, and superabounding interest. The work is
               elegantly printed as a library book, and adorned by some dozen curious fac-similes of oriental drawings.”—Courier and Enquirer.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">IMPORTANT WORKS,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">RECENTLY published by
               
               <br></br>J. &amp; H. G. LANGLEY, 8 ASTOR HOUSE.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">I.
               
               <br></br>VON RAUMER’S new work.
            </div>
            
            <p>America and the American People: being the result of the author’s recent travels through the United States. Translated from
               the German of Frederick Von Uaumer, by Professor Wm. W. Turner. 1 vol. 8vo. 330 pp. Price $2.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">lI.
               
               <br></br>ELIZA COOK’S POETICAL WORKS.
            </div>
            
            <p>New Edition, containing all her recent productions. Edited by
               Rufus Griswold. 1 vol. 12 mo., illustrated with a portrait and
               twelve exquisite English engravings. Copies in Morocco, super,
               $3 50—Cloth Gilt, $2 50.
            </p>
            
            <p>“This is a beautiful volume, splendidly bound, and still more
               elegantly illustrated, and combining some of the choicest poems in
               the language. The “Old Arm Chair” is one of the most popular
               poems, and has touched the hearts of thousands who never knew
               even the name of the author. She writes for the heart, and her
               beautiful songs always reach it. The book forms one of the most
               elegant holiday presents yet offered.”—Cour. &amp; Enq.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">III.
               
               <br></br>MISS BARRETT’S POEMS.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Drama of Exile, and other Poems, by Elizabeth B. Barrett,
               2vols. 12mo., elegantly printed.—$2 00.
            </div>
            
            <p>“Miss Barrett is worth a dozen of Tennyson, and six of Motherwell—equal, perhaps, in original genius, to Keats and Shelley—
               There are beauties enough in one of her poems to have made a fame
               in Waller’s time.”—Willis' Evening Mirror.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">IV.
               
               <br></br>GREGG’S SANTA FE AND THE PRAIRIES.
            </div>
            
            <p>Commerce of the Prairies, or the Journal of a Santa Fe Trader.
               The personal observation of a trader, made on eight several expeditions across the Great Western Prairies, and during an almost
               uninterrupted residence of nine years in Northern Mexico.—Illustrated with numerous engravings. New Edition, revised by the
               Author. By Josiah Gregg. 2vols. 12mo.	$2 00.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">v.
               
               <br></br>M. DE TOCQUEVILLE’S GREAT WORK.
            </div>
            
            <p>Democracy in America, by Alexis De Tocqueville. Third edition, in 2 vols. 8vm Corrected and Enlarged, with an original Index. Translated by Henry Reeve, Esq., with introductory Prefaces,
               by the honorable John C. Spencer. Price £4 00 in muslin or sheep.
            </p>
            <p>“This work is one of the most profound and philosophical ever
               writen upon the character and institutions of our country.—Boston
               Traveler.
            </p>
            
            <p>“As a study of political science, this book stands unrivaled in
               our times; equally remarkable for lueidity of style, acuteness and
               delicacy of reasoning, and for the moral and intellectual vigor with
               which it has been conceived and completed.”—London Times.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VI.
               
               <br></br>DE TOCQUEVILLE ABRIDGED.
            </div>
            
            <p>Designed for District School Libraries, Colleges, &amp;c. In accordance with the recommendation of several superintendents of District Schools, the Publishers beg to announce that they have just
               issued a condensed edition of the above standard work, adapted expressly for the use of District Schools, Colleges, &amp;c., to form 1 vol.
               12mo. Price $1 00.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VII.
               
               <br></br>THE LIFE OF GENERAL FRANCIS MARION.
            </div>
            
            <p>By W. Gilmore Simms, author of “Guy Rivers.” &amp;c. Ac.
               Seventh edition, revised by the author, with numerous engravings,
               1 vol. 12mo.—$1.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Few characters have stood out more boldly on our Revolutionary
               Annals, or have supplied more interesting and exciting materials
               for the historian than that of Gen. Marion; and it is not saying too
               much to claim for the work before us no less the merit of accredited
               historical truth, than the most stirring and absorbing attributes of
               high-wrought fiction.”—Democratic Review.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">VIII.
               
               <br></br>THE POETICAL WORKS OF PRAED.
            </div>
            
            <p>Lillian, and other Poems, Fanciful and Facetious. By William
               Mackworth Praed. First collected edition. Edited by R. W.
               Griswold, 1 vol. 12mo., muslin,. $1 25.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Praed was the Poet of Society, a fellow of infinite humor,’ and
               in scholarship and art, surpassed by none of the English poets of
               the age. Though many of his pieces have been almost universally
               read in this country, they have never yet been printed collectively,
               either here or in England.”—Democratic Review.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">DENTISTRY.</div>
            
            <p>DOCT. H. E. SCHOONMAKER, Dental Surgeon, Office, 446
               Houston st., two doors from Broadway—opposite St. Thomas’
               Church.
            </p>
            
            <p>Doct. S.’s experience and skill in his profession give him confidence in asserting that his operations are unsurpassed by any Dentist in this city. Dr. S.’s manner of inserting artificial teeth varies
               in many essential points from the usual mode; and his success in
               pleasing all, he is happy to say, has brought him many difficult
               cases, which had been unsuccessfully treated by Dentists of established professional reputation, and whose prices for the same operation were double his own. The object in inserting artificial teeth
               is to supply the deficiency occasioned by the loss of natural teeth,
               both in regard to utility, comfort in wearing, and natural appearance. In all these points, Dr. S.’s manner is pre-eminent. His
               mechanical tact and ingenuity have enabled him to surmount many
               obstacles, which have long, with the profession generally, impeded
               the path to success in every operation. He makes use of the best
               materials in all his operations—and in cases where the gum has
               fallen away by absorption, (which is always the case, more or less,
               when teeth have been extracted,) which causes a contraction of the
               lips and cheeks, the disfigurement of which cannot be fully obviated
               without adopting the artificial gums, which will supply the deficiency, and give to the mouth its usual redundancy—besides, their
               beauty and natural appearance render detection impossible.
            </p>
            
            <p>Dr. S. would be happy to refer those who require it, to many of
               the best families in this City, in which he has practised.
            </p>
            
            <p>Ladies who desire it, can have their teeth examined at their resi-
               dences, by sending their address as above.	nov8—9t
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PAINE &amp; BURGESS, 62 JOHN STREET,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">WILL PUBLISH, IN A FEW DAYS,</div>
            
            <p>THE ARTIST, MERCHANT, AND STATESMAN, Part I.—
               This work is made up of the choicest and most original material
               on Fine Arts, Commerce, and Political Economy, by C. Edwards
               Lester.
            </p>
            
            <p>PRARIEDOM; Rambles and Scrambles in Texas, or New Estremadura, by a Southron, 1 vol. 12mo. with a map. “It is light and
               vivacious—filled with incident—easy and flowing in style, and brilliant in imagery.”—Evening Mirror.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">THEY ARE PREPARING FOR PUBLICATION,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Songs and Ballads by Gen. G. P. Morris, 32mo. gilt.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Rambles by Land and Water, or Notes of Travel in Cuba and Mex-
               
               <br></br>ico; including a canoe voyage up the river Panuco, and Researches
               
               <br></br>among the Antiquities of Taumelipas, by B. M. Norman, 1 vol. 12mo.
               
               <br></br>illustrated.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Greece of the Greeks, by G. A. Perdicaris, U. S. Consul at
               
               <br></br>Athens, 2 vols. 12mo. illustrated.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Trippings in Authorland, by Fanny Forrester.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Montezuma, the Last of the Aztecs; an Historical Romance of
               
               <br></br>the Conquest of Mexico, by Edward Maturin, 2 vols. 12mo.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">“This is an original American work.”</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Prince, by Machiavelli, 1 vol. 12mo.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Man in the Republic, by C. Mathews, 1 vol. 32mo. gilt.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Old Continental, or the Price of Liberty; an historical ro-
               
               <br></br>mance, by the author of the “Dutchman’s Fireside,” 2 vols. 12mo.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">NOW READY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Medici Series of Italian Prose.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Autobiography of Alfieri, 1 vol. 12mo. Price 50 cents.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Secret Thoughts and Actions of Genius, blended with the
               
               <br></br>wildest adventures and strongest caprices.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Citizen of a Republic; what are his rights and duties, by
               
               <br></br>Ansaldo Ceba, 1 vol. 12mo. Price 50 cents. “A book of condens-
               
               <br></br>ed and rare thoughts, like diamonds finely polished and richly set.”
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Challenge of Barletta, a Romance of the times of the Medici,
               
               <br></br>1 vol. 12mo.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">"A gem gathered from the jeweled mine of Italian romance.”</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli, 2 vols. 12mo.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">“The charmed records of the classic city of the Amo, by the mas-
               
               <br></br>ter spirit of his age.”	nov 8
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">WILEY &amp; PUTNAM</div>
            
            <p>PROPOSE to supply, if there is sufficient patronage, the original
               London editions of the following Periodicals at the prices annexed, to be mailed in London.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Periodicals will be put in strong wrappers with printed address, and can be sent to any part of the United States; so that they
               may be received as soon as the letters per Boston Steamers.
            </p>
            
            <p>All persons wishing to subscribe will please address Wiley &amp;
               Putnam, before the first of December next.
            </p>
            
            <p>Subscriptions must be paid in all cases in advance.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">Edinburgh Review,	$3	50	  Quarterly Review,	$3	50
               Foreign Quarterly Review,	3	50	North British Review,	3	 50
               Westminster Review,	3	50	      For. and Colonial Review,	3 	50
               Forbes’ Medical Review,	4	00	  Blackwood’s Magazine,	5	 00
               Frazer’s Magazine,	5	00	        Presbyterian Review,	3 	50
               dec 13—3t
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">CHEAP MUSIC.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">HOMANS &amp; ELLIS have published the first No. of
               
               <br></br>THE MUSICAL WORLD.
            </div>
            
            <p>A Semi-monthly Magazine, containing sixteen pages of beautifully printed Music, and a Journal of Musical Biography, Criticism, and News.</p>
            
            <p>Edited by Henry C. Watson.—Contents of No. 1.</p>
            
            <div class="ab">I'll he There,—words by Fitzball—music by Herbert Rodwell.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Let no thought of care oppress thee,—words by Charles Jeffreys,
               
               <br></br>music by Bellini.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Far away in my own bright land,—	“	“Bellini.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">O cast that shadow from thy brow,—a beautiful ballad.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The sunny hours of childhood,—words by J. L. Carpenter—
               
               <br></br>music by J. Hanowav, 11. A.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">The melodies of man y lands,—words by Charles Jeffreys—music
               
               <br></br>by C. W. Glover.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Price 25 Cents.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">The second number of the Musical World will be published on
               
               <br></br>the 15th inst.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">In Press—Grand Galop, by Leopold de Meyer, with a portrait
               
               <br></br>and critical biography, will be ready early next week.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">KNOX’S HATS.</div>
            
            <p>THE FALL STYLE OF GENTLEMEN’S HATS are now
               ready for the season, 1845, which for lightness and superiority
               of color cannot be surpassed—which is a very important part of the
               hat, retaining the color till it is worn out. Any article sold in this
               establishment is never misrepresented but sold for what it is. Also
               the Fall style of Boy’s and Children’s Caps, of various patterns.
               Gentlemen can have their hats made to order in any shape or style
               they wish. A full assortment of Ladies’ Muffs, of all kinds.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">C. KNOX, No. 110 Fulton st.
               
               <br></br>nov 8—3m	between William and Nassau sts.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">NEW WORKS,
               TO BE PUBLISHED BY
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">MESSRS. WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 151 BROADWAY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">IN THE MONTH OF NOVEMBER.
               
               <br></br>I.
               
               <br></br>Western Clearings, by Mrs. C. M. Kirkland, author of “A
               
               <br></br>New Home,” &amp;c., 1 vol. 16mo. 50 cents.
               
               <br></br>II.
               
               <br></br>The Raven and other Poems, by Edgar A. Poe, 1 vol. 16mo.
               
               <br></br>31 cents.
               
               <br></br>III.
               
               <br></br>Viewsand Reviews in American History, Literature, and Science,
               
               <br></br>by W. Gilmore Simms. 1 vol. 16mo.
               
               <br></br>IV.
               
               <br></br>Life of the Great Condi, by Lord Mahon, 2 vols. 16mo. 37 1/2
               
               <br></br>cents each.
               
               <br></br>v.
               
               <br></br>Charles Lamb's Specimens of English Dramatic Poets, 2 vols.
               
               <br></br>16mo. 50 cents each.
               
               <br></br>VI.
               
               <br></br>The Rhine, by Victor Hugo.
               
               <br></br>VII.
               
               <br></br>Father Riga’s Residence in China, 1 vol. 16mo.	37 1/2 cts.
               
               <br></br>VIII.
               
               <br></br>The Fall of the Jesuits, 1 vol. 16mo. 37  1/2 cts.
               
               <br></br>IX.
               
               <br></br>Lectures on the English Poets, by Wm. Hazlitt. 1 vol. 16mo.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">TO MEDICAL MEN</div>
            
            <p>This day published, the London lancet for November, a Journal of British, Foreign, Medical and Chemical Science, Criticism and News—edited by Thomas Wakely, M. P.
               Surgeon, and Henry Bennett, M. D.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is the fifth number of the second volume, containing, besides
               its usual quantity of valuable matter, the 2d Lecture of a series of
               Lectures on Organic Chemistry, by Justus Liebig.
            </p>
            
            <p>Also, four additional Lectures on the Mechanism and Management of Natural and Difficult Labors, by Edward W. Murphy, A. M.
               M. D.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Terms—$5 per annum, in advance; single numbers 50 cents—
               
               <br></br>mailed to any part of the United States, by
               
               <br></br>BURGESS, STRINGER &amp; CO.
               
               <br></br>222 Broadway, corner of Ann st.
               
               <br></br>P. S.—The postage to any distance on the Lancet is 6 1/4 cts.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">CATALOGUE OF TEAS,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">ON SALE AT THE TEA WAREHOUSE OF THE
               
               <br></br>PEKIN TEA COMPANY,
               
               <br></br>Importers of fine Green and Black Teas, No. 75 Fulton street,
               
               <br></br>New York.
            </div>
            
            <p>[The teas mentioned in this Catalogue arc done up in quarter,
               half-pound, and pound packages—the first, or inside wrapper is
               lead, the second wrapper is water-proof paper, and the third, or
               outside wrapper, is of Chinese rice paper. The company sell none
               but good teas, done up in this superior manner, all of them grown
               in the most luxurious districts in China. Country dealers can
               select as small a quantity of each kind as they like, and have them
               packed in one chest. These teas also come in five pound Chinese
               packages, called quattoons, a very convenient, fanciful and portable
               shape.]
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Green Teas.	Black Teas.
               
               <br></br>Young Hyson, sweet cargo, 50             Pouchong, good, full flavor, 38
               
               <br></br>do	do	do	do finer, 62 1/2	            do	fine,	50
               
               <br></br>do	do	finer	cargo,	75	                do	veiy superior,	75
               
               <br></br>do	do	extra	fine,	87 1/2
               
               <br></br>do	do	Silver Leaf,	1,00              Souchong, good,	38
               
               <br></br>Silver Leaf — Seldom sold,	              do	extra fine,	50
               
               <br></br>even by large dealers, be-
               
               <br></br>cause of the very small pro-   Oolong, strong, flavor fine,      50
               
               <br></br>fits made on its sale. This	             Oolong—This tea is a great
               
               <br></br>is a very superior tea.	                        favorite, and gives universal
               
               <br></br>do do Golden Chop, Planta-                     satisfaction.
               
               <br></br>tion or Garden growth, 1,50	                      do	very fine,	 621/2
               
               <br></br>Golden Chop — This is the	                        do	in one pound	and
               
               <br></br>finest Green Tea cultivated	                      half pound cattys,
               
               <br></br>in China. It is of the first	                    extra fine,	75
               
               <br></br>pickings, and excels all other
               
               <br></br>Green Teas for its delicacy                 Ne Plus Ultra,	1,50
               
               <br></br>of flavor, strength, and aro-                 Ne Plus Ultra—This tea is
               
               <br></br>ma. Heretofore this tea has	                   as fragrant and sweet as a
               
               <br></br>never reached this country,	                   nosegay. It yields a perfume
               
               <br></br>except in small lots, as pre-	                 that is truly delightful. It is
               
               <br></br>sents to importers.	                            of garden growth, and supe-
               
               <br></br>Hyson,* very fine,	75	                       rior to anything of the kind
               
               <br></br>do Plantation growth,   1,00	               ever sold in this country.
               
               <br></br>Gunpowder, good,
               
               <br></br>do	superior, [Read	                       English Breakfast Tea, very
               
               <br></br>“monstrous fraud”	                                           fine, 50
               
               <br></br>below,]	1,00                                       do	do do in
               
               <br></br>do	small leaf, planta-	                           one pound and half pound
               
               <br></br>tion growth,	1,25	                               cattys.	62 1/2
               
               <br></br>Imperial, good,	—
               
               <br></br>do Brisk and fragrant,                     Howqua’s Mixture, a strong
               
               <br></br>[Read “monstrous	                             and rich black tea, Pekoe
               
               <br></br>fraud” below,]	1,00	                           flavor,	75
               
               <br></br>do curious leaf, very                      Congo, good,	37 1/2
               
               <br></br>superior,	1,25	                                do	very fine,	50
               
               <br></br>Hyson Skin, good, fine flavor,  38            Pekoe	Flowers, good,	87 1/2
               
               <br></br>do	do extra fine,	62 1/2	                     do do garden	growth, 1,50
            </div>
            
            <p>* Caution.—Large quantities of Hyson Skin are retailed in this
               market as being a Hyson Tea. It is well worth while to compare
               the Hyson Tea usually sold at 75 cents with the genuine article
               that the company offer at the same price. The difference is so perceptible, on trial, as to render any further comment unnecessary.
            </p>
            
            <p>Monstrous Fraud—Gunpowder and Imperial Teas cannot be
               retailed by small dealers, in this country, at 75 cents per pound,
               because they frequently cost that money in China, and no Importer
               in this city can sell good Gunpowder or Imperial Tea at a less price
               than 75 cents per pound by the hundred packages. T. F. Davies,
               Esq., in his interesting work on China, details the manner in
               which he saw the lowest grades of Black Teas manufactured and
               colored with Prussian Blue, so as to closely imitate Gunpowder and
               Imperial Teas, and adds, the Prussian Blue being a combination of
               Prussic Acid with Iron, is of course a dangerous poison. Let purchasers therefore beware of adulterated teas, and deal with those
               venders whose characters and resources raise them above suspicion.
               Beware of the Gunpowder and Imperial Teas retailed at 75 cents
               per pound, and compare them with the genuine article sold by the
               Pekin Tea Company. No one, it is presumed, wishes to drink
               poison. The company have published a book,giving full details on
               this subject, which may be had at their warehouse, 75 Fulton street,
               free of charge.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Recommendations.</div>
            
            <p>We drink Green Tea, and for many years have been paying one
               dollar per pound for it. But thanks to the Pekin Tea Company, we
               now get a better tea from them at 75 cents per pound. We drink one
               pound per week, by which we are now saving thirteen dollars per year,
               and enjoying better tea in the bargain. Commend us to the Pekin Tea
               Company, say we.—[Mirror.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street, are performing a great
               and good work, and will, in a few years, beyond all doubt, drive all the
               poor teas which have deluged this country, and defrauded consumers
               of the article, out of the market. They import none but pure and fragrant teas, and retail them by the single pound at wholesale prices.
               Families are always sure of obtaining good teas at this great tea ware     house, in quantities to suit their convenience, and at the same price
               that the merchant pays who buys to sell again.—[Daily True Sun.
            </p>
            
            <p>You may be sure of obtaining at all times, pure and highly flavored
               teas, by the single pound, at wholesale prices, of the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street. They have probably the largest stock, and
               greatest variety of green and black teas, of any one establishment in
                   the United States. They are doing a large business, and a great benefit
                   to consumers of tea.—[Atlas.
            </p>
            
            <p>Heretofore it has been very difficult, indeed impossible, to always
                   obtain good green and black teas; but now you have only to visit the
               ware-rooms of the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street,’to obtain as
               delicious and fragrant teas as you could wish for.—Daily Sun.
            </p>
            
            <p>If any of our readers desire to have good tea, they can obtain it of
               the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street.—[Mercury.
               
            </p>
            <p>A Word to Tea Drinkers.—The Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton
               street, have imported into this market some five hundred thousand dollars worth of the finest grade of green and black teas, grown in the
               Celestial Empire, done up in all the various fancy packages that Chinese ingenuity can invent. It is a privilege to buy teas at this great
               establishment, and a luxury and comfort to drink them. They sell
               good teas only, and retail them at wholesale prices. Country merchants
               who wish to always sell good teas can always obtain them at this place,
               on reasonable terms.—[Emporium.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Pekin Ten Company.—We very cheerfully call the attention
               of all lovers of pure and fragrant Teas, both in town and country, to the
               great tea warehouse of this company. Our long acquaintance with the
               proprietors enables us to bespeak for them the entire confidence of the
               public. We know that their teas, both in quality and price, are all that
               is stated of them. Many a lover of the fragrant herb has been compelled to eschew the drinking of tea in consequence of its injurious
               effects, until at length he has become hopeless of finding, among any of
               the imported varieties of tea in our market, a kind which had not such
               an effect. In this, however, such persons will be agreeably disappointed.
               The Pekin Tea Company nave commenced the importation of choice
               varieties of Garden Teas, of most delicious flavor—cultivated and
               picked with great care, which have heretofore never been introduced
               into this country, except as presents to importers. Among these they
               have an Oolong, mild as zephyr, and fragrant as a rose, which we especially recommend to all nervous persons. Its effect upon many of
               those who have tried it, is to make them confirmed tea-drinkers. Ladies
               who have tried it say they never before drank such tea. But all tastes
               can here be suited, with the great advantage over other stores of getting
               a pure article at wholesale price, however small the quantity. The
               company’s warehouse is at 75 Fulton street.—[New World.
            </p>
            
            <p>Tea.—The Pekin Tea Company, No. 75 Fulton street, unquestionably
               sell the best teas imported into this market. That they sell them
               cheaper than any other establishment, is a fact proven in a thousand
               instances since they have opened their store.
            </p>
            
            <p>We would advise our friends to call at this place, and if they don’t
               wish to buy, at least to obtain a little pamphlet, kept on their counter,
               entitled “Hints to Tea-Driukers,” and therefrom learn a little useful
               information on the subject. The pamphlet is given gratis.—[AngloAmerican.
            </p>
            
            <p>The finest specimens of green and black teas ever sold in this
               country, are imported by the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street.
               Those who want good teas at reasonable prices, can always get them
               there.—[Tribune.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have tried the teas imported by the Pekin Tea Company. 75
               Fulton street, and, if we live, will try them often. They are selling
               the most delicious teas we ever drank, and retail them at wholesale
               prices.—[Evening Post.	oct. 8.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p36">
         <div class="biblTitle">The Broadway Journal</div>
         <div class="biblPage">364</div>
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL:</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Edgar A. Poe,::::::	Editor and Proprietor.
            
            <br></br>IS PUBLISHED EVERY SATURDAY:
            
            <br></br>OFFICE 304 BROADWAY, CORNER OF DUANE.
            
            <br></br>Terms $3,00 per annum—single numbers six and a quarter cents.
         </div>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal is, in its general character, a literary
            paper, occupying itself with original, and more especially with
            critical articles, in every department of Literature, properly so
            called—with a preference, nevertheless, for the Belles Lettres
            and the Fine Arts. There is no better medium in the country for
            literary or artistical advertisements.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">AGENTS
            
            <br></br>Bedding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass        Thos H Pease, New Haven, Ct
            
            <br></br>R G H Huntington, Hartford, Ct   J C Morgan, New Orleans
            
            <br></br>M Baullemet, Mobile, Ala              W W Kingsley, New London, Ct
            
            <br></br>Robinson &amp; Jones, Cincinnati, O   G N Beesley, Utica, N Y
            
            <br></br>D M Dewey, Rochester, NY            B Strang, Peekskill, N Y
            
            <br></br>J Robertson, Syracuse, N Y            Haliburton &amp; Dudley, Boston, Mass
            
            <br></br>W E Russell, Schenectady, NY       S Thompson, Worcester, Mass
            
            <br></br>Levi Willard, Troy, N Y                  Peter Cooke, Hartford, Ct
            
            <br></br>G Jones, Albany, NY                       H Esten, Providence, R I
            
            <br></br>S F Hoyt, Newburgh, N Y               Safford &amp; Park, Norwich, Ct
            
            <br></br>Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore. Md     John Tomlin, P M Jackson, Tenn
            
            <br></br>Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia     S Hart, Sen., Charleston, S C.
         </div>
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back"></div>
</div>