<div>
   <div class="front">
          <div>
         <div class="head">THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
            <div class="ab"> 
            <br/>VOL. 2. NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JULY 26, 1845.	NO. 3.</div>
            <div class="ab">Three Dollars per Annum.	Single Copies, 6 1-4 Cents.	</div> 
         <div class="ab">EDITED BY	EDGAR A. POE AND HENRY C. WATSON.	</div>
         <div class="ab">Published at 136 Nassau St.
          By JOHN BISCO.</div>
      </div>
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      <br/>
      <div class="columnbreak"/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">The Literary Life of Thingum Bob, Esq.
<br/>LATE EDITOR OF THE “ GOOSETHERUMFOODLE.”
<br/>BY HIMSELF.</div>
         <p>
            <br/>I am now growing in years, and—since I understand that
<br/>Shakespeare and Mr. Emmons are deceased—it is not im-
<br/>possible that I may even die. It has occurred to me, there-
<br/>fore, that I may as well retire from the field of Letters and
<br/>repose upon my laurels. But I am ambitious of signalizing
<br/>my abdication of the literary sceptre by some important be-
<br/>quest to posterity; and, perhaps, I cannot do a better
<br/>thing than just pen for it an account of my earlier career.
<br/>My name, indeed, has been so long and so constantly before
<br/>the public eye, that I am not only willing to admit the nat-
<br/>uralness of the interest which it has every where excited, but
<br/>ready to satisfy the extreme curiosity which it has inspired.
<br/>In fact it is no more than the duty of him who achieves great-
<br/>ness, to leave behind him, in his ascent, such landmarks as
<br/>may guide others to be great. I propose, therefore, in the
<br/>present paper, (which I had some idea of calling “ Memo-
<br/>randa to serve for the Literary History of America,”) to give
<br/>a detail of those important, yet feeble and tottering first steps,
<br/>by which, at length, I attained the high road to the pinnacle
<br/>of human renown.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Of one’s very remote ancestors it is superfluous to say
<br/>much. My father, Thomas Bob, Esq., stood for many
<br/>years at the summit of his profession, which was that of a
<br/>merchant-barber, in the city of Smug. His warehouse was
<br/>the resort of all the principal people of the place, and espe-
<br/>cially of the editorial corps—a body which inspires all about
<br/>it with profound veneration and awe. For my own part, I
<br/>regarded them as Gods, and drank in with avidity the rich wit
<br/>and wisdom which continuously flowed from their august
<br/>mouths during the process of what is styled “ lather.” My
<br/>first moment of positive inspiration must be dated from that
<br/>ever-memorable epoch, when the brilliant conductor of the
<br/>‘‘Gad-Fly,’’ in the intervals of the important process just
<br/>mentioned, recited aloud, before a conclave of our apprentices,
<br/>an inimitable poem in honor of the “ Only Genuine Oil-of-
<br/>Bob,” (so called from its talented inventor, my father,) and
<br/>for which effusion the editor of the “ Fly" was remunerated
<br/>with a regal liberality, by the firm of Thomas Bob and com-
<br/>pany, merchant barbers.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>The genius of the stanzas to the “ Oil-of-Bob" first breath-
<br/>ed into me, I say, the divine afflatus. I resolved at once to
<br/>become a great man and to commence by becoming a great
<br/>poet. That very evening I fell upon my knees at the feet
<br/>of my father.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Father,” I said, “ pardon me!—but I have a soul above
<br/>lather. It is my firm intention to cut the shop. I would
<br/>be an editor—I would be a poet—I would pen stanzas to
<br/>the ‘ Oil-of-Bob.’ Pardon me and aid me to be great!”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ My dear Thingum,” replied my father, (I had been
<br/>christened Thingum after a wealthy relative so surnamed,)
<br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <br/>“ My dear Thingum,” he said, raising me from my knees by
<br/>the ears—“ Thingum, my boy, you’re a trump, and take af-
<br/>ter your father in having a soul. You have an immense
<br/>head, too, and it must hold a great many brains. This
<br/>I have long seen, and therefore had thoughts of making you
<br/>a lawyer. The business, however, has grown ungenteel,
<br/>and that of a politician don’t pay. Upon the whole you
<br/>judge wisely;—the trade of editor is best:—and if you can
<br/>be a poet at the same time,—as most of the editors are, by
<br/>the by,—why you will kill two birds with one stone. To
<br/>encourage you in the beginning of things, I will allow you a
<br/>garret; pen, ink and paper ; a rhyming dictionary ; and a
<br/>copy of the ‘ Gad-Fly.’ I suppose you would scarcely de-
<br/>mand any more.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“I would be an ungrateful villain if I did,” I replied with
<br/>enthusiasm. “ Your generosity is boundless. I will repay
<br/>it by making you the father of a genius.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Thus ended my conference with the best of men, and im-
<br/>mediately upon its termination, I betook myself with zeal to
<br/>my poetical labors ; as upon these, chiefly, I founded my
<br/>hopes of ultimate elevation to the editorial chair.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>In my first attempts at composition I found the stanzas to
<br/>“ The Oil-of-Bob” rather a draw-back than otherwise.
<br/>Their splendor more dazzled than enlightened me. The
<br/>contemplation of their excellence tended, naturally, to discour-
<br/>age me by comparison with my own abortions; so that for
<br/>a long time I labored in vain. At length there came into
<br/>my head one of those exquisitely original ideas which now
<br/>and then will permeate the brain of a man of genius. It
<br/>was this:—or, rather, thus was it carried into execution.
<br/>From the rubbish of an old book-stall, in a very remote cor-
<br/>ner of the town, I got together several antique and altogeth-
<br/>er unknown or forgotten volumes. The bookseller sold them
<br/>to me for a song. From one of these, which purported to be
<br/>a translation of one Dante's “Inferno,” I copied with re-
<br/>markable neatness a long passage about a man named Ugo-
<br/>lino, who had a parcel of brats. From another which con-
<br/>tained a good many old plays by some person whose name
<br/>I forget, I extracted in the same manner, and with the same
<br/>care, a great number of lines about “ angels" and “ ministers
<br/>saying grace,” and “goblins damned,” and more besides of
<br/>that sort. From a third, which was the composition of some
<br/>blind man or other, either a Greek or a Choctaw—I cannot
<br/>be at the pains of remembering every trifle exactly—I took
<br/>about fifty verses beginning with “ Achilles’ wrath,” and
<br/>“ grease,” and something else. From a fourth, which I re-
<br/>collect was also the work of a blind man, I selected a page
<br/>or two all about “ hail” and “holy light;” and although a
<br/>blind man has no business to write about light, still the verses
<br/>were sufficiently good in their way.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Having made fair copies of these poems I signed everyone
<br/>of them " Oppodeldoc,” (a fine sonorous name,) and, doing
<br/>each up nicely in a separate envelope, I despatched one to
<br/>each of the four principal Magazines, with a request for
<br/>speedy insertion and prompt pay. The result of this well
<br/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/> 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page34"/>
            <br/>conceived plan, however, (the success of which would have
<br/>saved me much trouble in after life,) served to convince me
<br/>that some editors are not to be bamboozled, and gave the
<br/>coup-de-grace (as they say in France,) to my nascent hopes,
<br/>(as they say in the city of the transcendentals.)</p>
         <br/>
         <p>The fact is, that each and every one of the Magazines in
<br/>question, gave Mr. “Oppodeldoc’ a complete using-up, in
<br/>the “ Monthly Notices to Correspondents.” The “ Hum-
<br/>Drum” gave him a dressing after this fashion:</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ ‘Oppodeldoc,’ (whoever he is,) has sent us a long tirade con-
<br/>cerning a bedlamite whom he styles ‘ Ugolino,” who had a great 
<br/>many children that should have been all whipped and sent to bed 
<br/>without their suppers. The whole affair is exceedingly tame—not
<br/>to say flat. ‘Oppodeldoc,’ (whoever he is,) is entirely devoid of
<br/>imagination—and imagination, in our humble opinion, is not only
<br/>the soul of Poesy, but also its very heart. Oppodeldoc,’ (whoever
<br/>he is,) has the audacity to demand of us, for his twattle, a ‘ speedy
<br/>insertion and prompt pay.’ We neither insert nor purchase any
<br/>stuff of the sort. There can be no doubt, however, that he would
<br/>meet with a ready sale for all the balderdash he can scribble, at the
<br/>office of either the ‘ Rowdy-Dow,’ the ‘ Lollipop,’ or the ‘ Goose-
<br/>therumfoodle.’ ”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>All this, it must be acknowledged, was very severe upon
<br/>“ Oppodeldoc”—but the unkindest cut was putting the word
<br/>Poesy in small caps. In those five preeminent letters what
<br/>a world of bitterness is there not involved !
<br/>But “ Oppodeldoc” was punished with equal severity in
<br/>the “ Rowdy-dow,” which spoke thus:</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“We have received a most singular and insolent communication
<br/>from a person, (whoever he is,) signing himself ‘ Oppodeldoc’—
<br/>thus desecrating the greatness of the illustrious Roman Emperor so
<br/>named. Accompanying the letter of ‘ Oppodeldoc,’ (whoever he
<br/>is,) we find sundry lines of most disgusting and unmeaning rant
<br/>about ‘ angels and ministers of grace’—rant such as no madman
<br/>short of a Nat Lee, or an ‘ Oppodeldoc,’ could possibly perpetrate.
<br/>And for this trash of trash, we are modestly requested to ‘ pay
<br/>promptly.’ No sir—no ! We pay for nothing of that sort. Apply
<br/>to the ‘ Hum-Drum,’ the ‘ Lollipop,’ or the ‘ Goosetherumfoodle.’
<br/>These periodicals will undoubtedly accept any literary offal you
<br/>may send them—and as undoubtedly promise to pay for it.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>This was bitter indeed upon poor “ Oppodeldoc but, in
<br/>this instance, the weight of the satire falls upon the “ Hum-
<br/>drum,” the “ Lollipop,” and the “ Goosetherumfoodle,” who
<br/>are pungently styled “ periodicals" — in Italics, too — a
<br/>thing that must have cut them to the heart.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Scarcely less savage was the “Lollipop,” which thus
<br/>discoursed:</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Some individual, who rejoices in the appellation ‘ Oppodeldoc,’
<br/>(to what low uses are the names of the illustrious dead too often
<br/>applied!) has enclosed us some fifty or sixty verses, commencing
<br/>after this fashion:</p>
         <br/>
         <div class="lg">
            <br/>Achilles’ wrath, to Greece the direful spring
<br/>Of woes unnumbered, &amp;c., &amp;c., &amp;c., &amp;c.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>‘ Oppodeldoc,’ (whoever he is,) is respectfully informed that
<br/>there is not a printer’s devil in our office who is not in the daily ha-
<br/>bit of composing better lines. Those of ‘ Oppodeldoc’ will not scan.
<br/>' Oppodeldoc' should learn to count. But why he shouldehave con-
<br/>ceived the idea that we, (of all others, we!) would disgrace our
<br/>pages with his ineffable nonsense, is utterly beyond comprehension
<br/>Why, the absurd twattle is scarcely good enough for the ‘ Hum-
<br/>Drum,’ the ‘ Rowdy-Dow,’ the ‘ Goosetherumfoodle’—things that
<br/>are in the practice of publishing ‘ Mother Goose’s Melodies’ as ori-
<br/>nal lyrics. And ‘Oppodeldoc, (whoever he is,) has even the assu-
<br/>rance to demand pay for this drivel. Does 'Oppodeldoc,' (who-
<br/>ever he is,) know—is he aware that we could not be paid to insert
<br/>it?”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>As I perused this I felt myself growing gradually smaller
  <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <br/>and smaller, and when I came to the point at which the edi-
<br/>tor sneered at the poem as “ verses," there was little more
<br/>than an ounce of me left. As for “ Oppodeldoc” I began to
<br/>experience compassion for the poor fellow. But the “ Goose-
<br/>therumfoodle” showed, if possible, less mercy than the “ Lol-
<br/>lipop.” It was the “ Goosetherumfoodle” that said :</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ A wretched poetaster, who signs himself ‘ Oppodeldoc,’ is silly
<br/>enough to fancy that we will print and pay for a medley of incohe-
<br/>rent and ungrammatical bombast which he has transmitted to us,
<br/>and which commences with the following most intelligible line:</p>
         <div class="lg">
            <br/>“ Hail, Holy Light! Offspring of Heaven, first born.”</div>
         <br/>
         <p>“ We say, ‘ most intelligible.’ ‘Oppodeldoc,’ (whoever he is,)
<br/>will be kind enough to tell us, perhaps, how ‘hail' can be ‘ holy
<br/>light.’ We always regarded it as frozen rain. Will he inform us,
<br/>also, how frozen rain can be, at one and the same time, both ‘ holy
<br/>light,’ (whatever that is,) and an ‘ offspring?'—which latter term, (if
<br/>we understand any thing about English,) is only employed, with
<br/>propriety, in reference to small babies of about six weeks old. But
<br/>it is preposterous to descant upon such absurdity—although ‘ Oppo-
<br/>deldoc,’ (whoever he is,) has the unaparalleled effrontery to sup-
<br/>pose that we will not only ‘ insert’ his ignorant ravings, but (abso-
<br/>lutely) pay for them !</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Now this is fine—it is rich!—and we have half a mind to
<br/>punish 'his young scribbler for his egotism, by really publishing his
<br/>ffusion, verbatim et literatim, as he has written it. We could in-
<br/>flict no punishment so severe, and we would inflict it, but for the
<br/>boredom which we should cause our readers in so doing.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Let ‘ Oppodeldoc,’ (whoever he is.) send any future composition
<br/>of like character to the ' Hum-Drum,’ the ‘Lollipop,’ or the ‘ Row-
<br/>dy-Dow.’ They will ‘insert' it. They ‘insert’ every month just
<br/>such stuff. Send it to them. WE are not to be insulted with im-
<br/>punity.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>This made an end of me ; and as for the “ Hum-Drum,’&gt;
<br/>the “Rowdy-Dow,” and the “Lollipop,” I never could com-
<br/>prehend how they survived it. The putting them in the
<br/>smallest possible minion, (that was the rub—thereby insinu-
<br/>ating their lowness—their baseness,) while WE stood look-
<br/>ing down upon them in gigantic capitals!—oh it was too bit-
<br/>ter !—it was wormwood—it was gall. Had I been either of
<br/>these periodicals I would have spared no pains to have the
<br/>“ Goosetherumfoodle” prosecuted. It might have been done
<br/>under the Act for the “Prevention of Cruelty to Animals.”
<br/>As for “ Oppodeldoc,” (whoever he was,) I had by this time
<br/>lost all patience with the fellow, and sympathized with him
<br/>no longer. He was a fool, beyond doubt, (whoever he was,)
<br/>and got not a kick more than he deserved.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>The result of my experiment with the old books, convinc-
<br/>ed me, in the first place, that “honesty is the best policy,”
<br/>and, in the second, that if I could not write better than Mr.
<br/>Dante, and the two blind men, and the rest of the old set, it
<br/>would, at least, be a difficult matter to write worse. I took
<br/>heart, therefore, and determined to prosecute the “ entirely
<br/>original," (as they say on the covers of the magazines,) at
<br/>whatever cost of study and pains. I again placed before my
<br/>eyes, as a model, the brilliant stanzas on “ The Oil-of-Bob,”
<br/>by the editor of the “ Gad-Fly,” and resolved to construct an
<br/>Ode on the same sublime theme, in rivalry of what had al-
<br/>ready been done.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>With my first verse I had no material difficulty. It ran
<br/>thus:</p>
         <div class="lg">
            <br/>To pen an Ode upon the “ Oil-of-Bob.”</div>
         <br/>
         <p>Having carefully looked out, however, all the legitimate
<br/>rhymes to “ Bob,” I found it impossible to proceed. In this
<br/>dilemma I had recourse to paternal aid ; and, after some hours
<br/>of mature thought, my father and myself thus constructed
<br/>the poem:</p>
         <br/>
         <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/> 
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page35"/>
         <div class="lg">
            <br/>To pen an Ode upon the "Oil-of-Bob”
  <br/>Is all sorts of a job.
<br/>(Signed,)	Snob.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>To be sure this composition was of no very great length—
<br/>but I “ have yet to learn” as they say in the Edinburgh Re
<br/>view, that the mere extent of a literacy work has any thing
<br/>to do with its merit. As for the Quarterly cant about
<br/>“ sustained effort,” it is impossible to see the sense of it.
<br/>Upon the whole, therefore, I was satisfied with the success
<br/>of my maiden attempt, and now the only question regarded
<br/>the disposal I should make of it. My father suggested that I
<br/>should send it to the “ Gad-Fly”—but there were two rea-
<br/>sons which operated to prevent me from so doing. I dreaded
<br/>the jealousy of the editor—and I had ascertained that he did
<br/>not pay for original contributions. I therefore, after due
<br/>deliberation, consigned the article to the more dignified
<br/>pages of the “ Lollipop,” and awaited the event in anxiety,
<br/>but with resignation.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>In the very next published number I had the proud satis-
<br/>faction of seeing my poem printed at length, as the leading
<br/>article, with the following significant words, prefixed in ita-
<br/>lics and between brackets :</p>
         <br/>
         <p>[" We cali the attention of our readers to the subjoined admirable
<br/>stanzas on “ The Oil-of-Bob." We need say nothing of their subli-
<br/>mity, or of their pathos:—it is impossible to peruse them without
<br/>tears. Those who have been nauseated with a sad dose on the same
<br/>august topic from the goose-quill of the editor of the “ Gad-Fly,"
<br/>will do well to compare the two compositions.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>P. S. We are consumed with anxiety to probe the mystery which
<br/>envelops the evident pseudonym “ Snob." May we not hope for a
<br/>personal interview ?"]</p>
         <br/>
         <p>All this was scarcely more than justice, but it was, I con-
<br/>fess, rather more than I had expected :—I acknowledge this,
<br/>be it observed, to the everlasting disgrace of my country and
<br/>of mankind. I lost no time, however, in calling upon the
<br/>editor of the “ Lollipop,” and had the good fortune to find
<br/>this gentleman at home. He saluted me with an air of pro-
<br/>found respect, slightly blended with a fatherly and patroniz-
<br/>ing admiration, wrought in him, no doubt, by my appearance
<br/>of extreme youth and inexperience. Begging me to be seat-
<br/>ed, he entered at once upon the subject of my poem ;—but
<br/>modesty will ever forbid me to repeat the thousand compli-
<br/>ments which he lavished upon me. The eulogies of Mr.
<br/>Crab, (such was the editor’s name,) were, however, by no
<br/>means fulsomely indiscriminate. He analyzed my composi-
<br/>tion with much freedom and great ability—not hesitating to
<br/>point out a few trivial defects—a circumstance which ele-
<br/>vated him highly in my esteem. The “ Gad-Fly” was, of
<br/>course, brought upon the tapis, and I hope never to be sub-
<br/>jected to a criticism so searching, or to rebukes so withering,
<br/>as were bestowed by Mr. Crab upon that unhappy effusion.
<br/>I had been accustomed to regard the editor of the “ Gad-Fly”
<br/>as something superhuman; but Mr. Crab soon disabused me
<br/>of that idea. He set the literary as well as the personal cha-
<br/>racter of the Fly (so Mr. C. satirically designated the rival
<br/>editor,) in its true light. He, the Fly, was very little better
<br/>than he should be. He had written infamous things. He
<br/>was a penny-a-liner, and a buffoon. He was a villain.
<br/>He had composed a tragedy which set the whole country in
<br/>a guffaw, and a farce which deluged the universe in tears.
<br/>Besides all this, he had the impudence to pen what he meant
<br/>for a lampoon upon himself, (Mr. Crab,) and the temerity to
<br/>style him “ an ass.” Should I at any time wish to express
<br/>my opinion of Mr. Fry, the pages of the “Lollipop,” Mr.
<br/>Crab assured me, were at my unlimited disposal. In the
<br/>meantime, as it was very certain that I would be attacked in
<br/>the Fly for my attempt at composing a rival poem o
  <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <br/>Oil-of-Bob,” he (Mr. Crab,) would take it upon himself to
<br/>attend, pointedly, to my private and personal interests. If I
<br/>were not made a man of at once, it should not be the fault
<br/>of himself, (Mr. Crab.)</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Mr. Crab having now paused in his discourse, (the latter
<br/>	portion of which I found it impossible to comprehend,) I ven-
<br/>tured to suggest something about the remuneration which
<br/>I had been taught to expect for my poem, by an announce-
<br/>ment on the cover of the “ Lollipop,” declaring that it, (the
<br/>j“ Lollipop,”) “ insisted upon being permitted to pay exorbi-
<br/>tant prices for all accepted contributions;—frequently expend-
<br/>ing more money for a single brief poem than the whole an-
<br/>nual cost of the ‘ Hum-Drum,’ the ‘ Rowdy-Dow,’ and the
<br/>' Goosetherumfoodle’ combined.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>As I mentioned the word “ remuneration,” Mr. Crab first
<br/>opened his eyes, and then his mouth, to quite a remarkable
<br/>extent: causing his personal appearance to resemble that of
<br/>a highly-agitated elderly duck in the act of quacking;—and
<br/>in this condition he remained, (ever and anon pressing his
<br/> hands tightly to his forehead, as if in a state of desperate be-
<br/>wilderment) until I had nearly made an end of what I had
<br/>to say.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Upon my conclusion, he sank back into his seat, as if
<br/>much overcome, letting his arms fall lifelessly by his side,
<br/>but keeping his mouth still rigorously open, after the fashion
<br/>of the duck. While I remained in speechless astonishment
<br/>at behaviour so alarming, he suddenly leaped to his feet and
<br/>made a rush at the bell-rope ; but just as he reached this, he
<br/>appeared to have altered his intention, whatever it was, for
<br/>he dived under a table and immediately re-appeared with a
<br/>cudgel. This he was in the act of uplifting, (for what pur-
<br/>pose I am at a loss to imagine,) when, all at once, there came
<br/>a benign smile over his features, and he sank placidly back
<br/> in his chair.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Mr. Bob,” he said, (for I had sent up my card before as-
<br/>cending myself,) “ Mr. Bob, you are a young man, I presume
<br/> —very ?”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I assented; adding that I had not yet concluded my third
<br/>lustrum.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“Ah!” he replied, “very good! I see how it is—say no
<br/>more ! Touching this matter of compensation, what you ob-
<br/> serve is very just: in fact it is excessively so. But—ah—ah
<br/> —the first contribution—the first, I say—it is never the Ma-
<br/> gazine custom to pay for—you comprehend, eh ? The truth
<br/>is, we are usually the recipients in such case.” [Mr. Crab
<br/>smiled blandly as he emphasized the word “ recipients.”]
<br/>“ For the most part, we are paid for the insertion of a maiden
<br/>attempt—especially in verse. In the second place, Mr. Bob,
<br/>the Magazine rule is never to disburse what we term in
<br/>France the argent comptant :—I have no doubt you under-
<br/>stand. In a quarter or two after publication of the article—
<br/>or in a year or two—we make no objection to giving our note
<br/>at nine months :—provided always that we can so arrange
<br/>our affairs as to be quite certain of a ‘ burst up’ in six. I
<br/>really do hope, Mr. Bob, that you will look upon this expla-
<br/>nation as satisfactory.” Here Mr. Crab concluded, and the
<br/>tears stood in his eyes.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Grieved to the soul at having been, however innocently,
<br/>the cause of pain to so eminent and so sensitive a man, I
<br/>hastened to apologize, and to reassure him, by expressing my
<br/>perfect coincidence with his views, as well as my entire ap-
<br/>preciation of the delicacy of his position. Having done all
<br/>this in a neat speech, I took leave.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>One fine morning, very shortly afterwards, “ I awoke and
<br/>found myself famous.” The extent of my renown will e
<br/>best estimated by reference to the editorial opinions of the
<br/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/> 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page36"/>
            <br/>day. These opinions, it will be seen, were embodied in cri-
<br/>tical notices of the number of the “ Lollipop-’ containing my
<br/>poem, and are perfectly satisfactory, conclusive and clear
<br/>with the exception, perhaps, of the hieroglyphical marks
<br/>“ Sep. 15—1 t."	appended to each of the critiques.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>The “Owl,” a journal of profound sagacity, and well
<br/>known for the deliberate gravity of its literary decisions—the
<br/>“ Owl,"’ I say, spoke as follows:</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ ‘ The Lollipop !’ The October number of this delicious Maga-
<br/>zine surpasses its predecessors, and sets competition at defiance.
<br/>In the beauty of its typography and paper—in the number and ex-
<br/>cellence of its steel plates—as well as in the literary merit of its con-
<br/>tributions—the 'Lollipop’ compares with its slow-paced rivals as
<br/>Hyperion with a Satyr. The ‘ Hum-Drum.’ the ' Row.ly-Dow,’ and
<br/>the ’ Goosetherumfoodle,’ excel, it is true, in braggadocio, but, in
<br/>all other points, give us the ‘ Lollipop !' How this celebrated jour
<br/>nal can sustain its evidently tremendous expenses, is more than we
<br/>can understand. To be sure, it has a circulation of 100,000, and
<br/>its subscription-list has increased one fourth during the last month:
<br/>but, on the other hand, the sums it disburses constantly for contri-
<br/>butions are inconceivable. It is reported that Mr. Slyass received
<br/>no less than thirty-seven and a half cents for his inimitable paper on
<br/>‘ Pigs.’ With Mr. Crab, as editor, and with such names upon the
<br/>list of contributors as Snob and Slyass, there can be no such word as
<br/>‘ fail’ for the ‘ Lollipop.’ Go and subscribe. Sep. 15—1t."</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I must say that I was gratified with this high-toned notice
<br/>from a paper so respectable as the “ Owl.” The placing my
<br/>name—that is to say my nom de guerre—in priority of station
<br/>to that of the great Slyass, was a compliment as happy as I
<br/>felt it to be deserved.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>My attention was next arrested by these paragraphs in
<br/>the “ Toad”—a print highly distinguished for its upright-
<br/>ness, and independence—for its entire freedom from sycophan-
<br/>cy and subservience to the givers of dinners.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ The ‘ Lollipop’ for October is out in advance of all its contem-
<br/>poraries, and infinitely surpasses them, of course, in the splendor of
<br/>its embellishments, as well as in the richness of its literary contents,
<br/>The ‘ Hum-Drum,’ the ‘ Rowdy-Dow,’ and the ‘ Goosetherum-
<br/>foodle’ excel, we admit, in braggadocio, but, in all other points,
<br/>give us the ‘Lollipop" How this celebrated Magazine can sustain
<br/>its evidently tremendous expenses, is more than we can understand.
<br/>To be sure, it has a circulation of 200,000, and its subscription list
<br/>has increased one third during the last fortnight, but on the other
<br/>hand, the sums it disburses, monthly, for contributions, are fearfully
<br/>great. We learn that Mr. Mumblelhumb received no less than fifty
<br/>cents for his late ‘ Monody in a Mud-Puddle.’</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Among the original contributors to the present number we no-
<br/>tice, (besides the eminent editor, Mr. Crab.) such men as Snob,
<br/>Slyass, and Mumblethumb. Apart from the editorial matter, the
<br/>most valuable paper, nevertheless, is, we think, a poetical gem by
<br/>‘ Snob,’ on the ‘ Oil-of-Bob’—but our readers must not suppose,
<br/>from the title of this incomparable bijou, that it bears any similitude
<br/>to some balderdash on the same subject by a certain contemptible
<br/>individual whose name is unmentionable to ears polite. The pre-
<br/>sent poem ‘ On the Oil-of-Bob,’ has excited universal anxiety and
<br/>curiosity in respect to the owner of the evident pseudonym, ‘ Snob'
<br/>—a curiosity which, happily, we have it in our power to satisfy.
<br/>' Snob’ is the nom-de-plume of Mr. Thingum Bob, of this city,—a
<br/>relative of the great Mr. Thingum, (after whom he is named,) and
<br/>otherwise connected with the most illustrious families of the State.
<br/>His father, Thomas Bob, Esq., is an opulent merchant in Smug.
<br/>Sep. 15—1 t.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>This generous approbation touched me to the heart —the
<br/>more especially as it emanated from a source so avowedly—
<br/>so proverbially pure as the “ Toad.” The word “ balder-
<br/>dash,” as applied to the “ Oil-of-Bob” of the Fly, I considered
<br/>singularly pungent and appropriate. The words “ gem” and
<br/>"bijou," however, used in reference to my composition,
  <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <br/> struck me as being, in some degree, feeble. They seemed
<br/> to me to be deficient in force. They were not sufficiently
<br/>prononces, (as we have it in France.)</p>
         <br/> 
         <p>I had hardly finished reading the “ Toad,” when a friend
<br/>placed in my hands a copy of the “ Mole,” a daily, enjoying
<br/>high reputation for the keenness of its perception about mat-
<br/>ters in general, and for the open, honest, above-ground style
<br/>of its editorials. The “ Mole” spoke of the “ Lollipop” as
<br/>follows :</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ We have just received the ‘ Lollipop’ for October, and must say
<br/>that never before have we perused any single number of any perio-
<br/>dical which afforded us a felicity so supreme. We speak advisedly.
<br/>The ‘Hum-Drum,’ the ‘ Rowdy-Dow’ and the ‘ Goosetherumfoodle’
<br/>must look well to their laurels. These prints, no doubt, surpass
<br/>every thing in loudness of pretension, but, in all other points, give
<br/>us the ‘ Lollipop !’ How this celebrated Magazine can sustain its
<br/>evidently tremendous expenses, is more than we can comprehend.
<br/>To be sure, it hits a circulation of 300,000 ; and its subscription-list
<br/>has increased one half within the last week, but then the sum it dis-
<br/>burses, monthly, for contributions, is astoundingly enormous. We
<br/>have it upon good authority, that Mr. Fatquack received no less
<br/>than sixty-two cents and a half for his late Domestic Nouvelette, the
<br/> ‘ Dish-Clout.’</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ The contributors to the number before us are Mr. Crab, (the
<br/> eminent editor,) Snob, Mumblelhumb, Fatquack and others; but,
<br/>after the inimitable compositions of the editor himself, we prefer a
<br/> diamond-like effusion from the pen of a rising poet who writes
<br/>over the signature ‘ Snob’—a nom de guerre which we predict will
<br/>one day extinguish the radiance of ‘ Boz.’ ‘ Snob,’ we learn, is a
<br/> Mr. Thingum Bob, sole heir of a wealthy merchant of this city,
<br/> Thomas Bob. Esq., and a near relative of the distinguished Mr.
<br/> Thingum. The title of Mr. B.’s admirable poem is the ' Oil-of-Bob’
<br/>—a somewhat unfortunate name, by-the-bye, as some contemptible
<br/>vagabond connected with the penny press has already disgusted the
<br/> town with a great deal of drivel upon the same topic. There will
<br/>be no danger, however, of confounding the compositions. Sep. 15
<br/>—1 t."</p>
         <br/>
         <p>The generous approbation of so clear-sighted a journal as
<br/>the “ Mole" penetrated my soul with delight. The only ob-
<br/>jection which occurred to me was, that the terms “con-
<br/>temptible vagabond-’ might have been better written “odious
<br/>and contemptible, wretch, villain and vagabond.” This would
<br/> have sounded more gracefully, I think. “Diamond-like,”
<br/>also, was scarcely, it will be admitted, of sufficient intensity
<br/> to express what the “Mole" evidently thought of the brilliancy
<br/> of the “ Oil-of-Bob.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>On the same afternoon in which I saw these notices in the
<br/>“Owl,” the “Toad,” and the “Mole,” I happened to meet
<br/>with a copy of the “ Daddy-Long-Legs,” a periodical prover-
<br/>bial for the extreme extent of its understanding. And it was
<br/>the -‘Daddy-Long Legs" which spoke thus:</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ The ‘ Lollipop’!! This gorgeous Magazine is already before
<br/>the public for October. The question of pre-eminence is forever
<br/> put to rest, and hereafter it will be excessively preposterous in the
<br/>‘ Hum-Drum,’ the ‘ Rowdy-Dow,’ or the ‘ Goosetherumfoodle,’ to
<br/> make any farther spasmodic attempts at competition. These jour-
<br/>nals may excel the ‘ Lollipop’ in outcry, but, in all other points, give
<br/>us the ‘ Lollipop!’ How this celebrated Magazine can sustain its
<br/> evidently tremendous expenses, is past comprehension. To be sure
<br/> it has a circulation of precisely half a million, and its subscription-list
<br/> has increased seventy-five per cent, within the last couple of days ;
<br/> but then the sums it disburses, monthly, for contributions, are
<br/>scarcely credible ; we are cognizant of the fact, that Mademoiselle
<br/>Cribalittle received no lets than eighty-seven cents and a half for
<br/> her late valuable Revolutionary Tale, entitled ‘ The York-Town
<br/>Katy-Did, and the Bunker-Hill Katy-Did’nt.’</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ The most able papers in the present number, are, of course,
<br/> those furnished by the editor, (the eminent Mr. CRAB.) but there
<br/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/> 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page37"/>
            <br/>are numerous magnificent contributions from such names as Snob;
<br/>Mademoiselle Cribalittle ; Slyass; Mrs. Fibalittle; Mumblethumb;
<br/>Mrs. Squibalittle; and. last, though not least, Fatquack. The world
<br/>may well be challenged to produce so rich a galaxy of genius.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ The poem over the signature ‘ Snob’ is, we find, attracting uni-
<br/>versal commendation, and, we are constrained to say, deserves, if
<br/>possible, even more applause than it has received. The ‘ Oil-of-
<br/>Bob' is the title of this masterpiece of eloquence and art. One or
<br/>two of our readers may have a very faint, although sufficiently dis-
<br/>gusting recollection of a poem (?) similarly entitled, the perpetra_
<br/>tion of a miserable penny-a-liner, mendicant, and cut-throat, connect-
<br/>ed in the capacity of scullion, we believe, with one of the indecent
<br/>prints about the purlieus of the city ; we beg them, for God’s sake,
<br/>not to confound the compositions. The author of the ‘ Oil-of.Bob,
<br/>is, we hear, Thingum Bob, Fsq.. a gentleman of high genius, and
<br/>a scholar. ‘ Snob’ is merely a nom-de-guerre. Sept. 15—1 t.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I could scarcely restrain my indignation while I perused
<br/>the concluding portions of this diatribe. It was clear to me
<br/>that the yea-nay manner—not to say the gentleness—the
<br/>positive forbearance with which the “Daddy-Long-Legs”
<br/>spoke of that pig, the editor of the “Gad-Fly”—it was evi-
<br/>dent to me, I say, that this gentleness of speech could pro-
<br/>ceed from nothing else than a partiality for the Fly—whom
<br/>it was clearly the intention of the “ Daddy-Long-Legs” to
<br/>elevate into reputation at my expense. Any one, indeed,
<br/>might perceive, with half an eye, that, had the real design of
<br/>the “Daddy” been what it wished to appear, it, (the “Dad-
<br/>dy,”) might have expressed itself in terms more direct, more
<br/>pungent, and altogether more to the purpose. The words
<br/>“ penny-a-liner,” “mendicant,” “scullion,” and “cut-throat,”
<br/>were epithets so intentionally inexpressive and equivocal, as
<br/>to be worse than nothing when applied to the author of the
<br/>very worst stanzas ever penned by one of the human race.
<br/>We all know what is meant by “ damning with faint praise,"
<br/>and, on the other hand, who could fail seeing through the
<br/>covert purpose of the “ Daddy”—that of glorifying with
<br/>feeble abuse ?</p>
         <br/>
         <p>What the “ Daddy” chose to say of the Fly, however, was
<br/>no business of mine. What it said of myself was. After the
<br/>noble manner in which the “Owl,” the “Toad,” the
<br/>“ Mole,” had expressed themselves in respect to my ability,
<br/>it was rather too much to be cooly spoken of by a thing like
<br/>the “ Daddy-Long-Legs,” as merely “a gentleman of high
<br/>genius and a scholar.” Gentleman indeed ! I made up my
<br/>mind, at once, either to get a written apology from the
<br/>“ Daddy-Long-Legs,” or to call it out.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Full of this purpose, I looked about me to find a friend
<br/>whom I could entrust with a message to his Daddyship, and,
<br/>as the editor of the “ Lollipop” had given me marked tokens
<br/>of regard, I at length concluded to seek assistance upon the
<br/>present occasion.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I have never yet been able to account, in a manner satis-
<br/>factory to my own understanding, for the very peculiar coun-
<br/>tenance and demeanor with which Mr. Crab listened to me,
<br/>as I unfolded to him my design. He again went through
<br/>the scene of the bell-rope and cudgel, and did not omit the
<br/>duck. At one period I thought he really intended to quack.
<br/>His fit, nevertheless, finally subsided as before, and he began
<br/>to act and speak in a rational way. He declined bearing the
<br/>cartel, however, and in fact, dissuaded me from sending it at
<br/>all; but was candid enough to admit that the “ Daddy- 
<br/>Long-Legs” had been disgracefully in the wrong—more es-
<br/>pecially in what related to the epithets “gentleman and
<br/>scholar."</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Towards the end of this interview with Mr. Crab, who
<br/>really appeared to take a paternal interest in my welfare,
<br/>he suggested to me that I might turn an honest penny and,
  <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <br/>at the same time, advance my reputation, by occasionally
<br/>playing Thomas Hawk for the “Lollipop.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I begged Mr. Crab to inform me who was Mr. Thomas
<br/>Hawk, and how it was expected that I should play him.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Here Mr. Crab again “ made great eyes,” (as we say in
<br/>Germany,) but at length, recovering himself from a profound
<br/>attack of astonishment, he assured me that he employed the
<br/>words “ Thomas Hawk” to avoid the colloquialism, Tommy,
<br/>which was low—but that the true idea was Tommy Hawk
<br/> —or tomahawk—and that by “ playing tomahawk” he re-
<br/> ferred to scalping, brow-beating and otherwise using-up the
<br/>herd of poor-devil authors.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I assured my patron that, if this was all, I was perfectly
<br/> resigned to the task of playing Thomas Hawk. Hereupon
<br/>Mr. Crab desired me to use-up the editor of the “ Gad-Fly”
<br/>forthwith, in the fiercest style within the scope of my ability,
<br/>and as a specimen of my powers. This I did, upon the spot,
<br/>in a review of the original “Oil-of-Bob,” occupying thirty-
<br/>six pages of the “Lollipop.” I found playing Thomas
<br/>Hawk, indeed, a far less onerous occupation than poetizing;
<br/>for I went upon system altogether, and thus it was easy to
<br/>do the thing thoroughly and well. My practice was this.
<br/>I bought auction copies (cheap) of “ Lord Brougham’s
<br/>Speeches," “ Cobbett’s Complete Works,” the “ New Slang-
<br/>Syllabus,” the “ Whole Art of Snubbing,” “ Prentice’s Bill-
<br/>ingsgate,” (folio edition,) and “ Lewis G. Clarke on Tongue.”
<br/>These works I cut up thoroughly with a curry-comb, and
<br/>then, throwing the shreds into a sieve, sifted out carefully
<br/>all that might be thought decent, (a mere trifle); reserving
<br/>the hard phrases, which I threw into a large tin pepper-cas-
<br/>tor with longitudinal holes, so that an entire sentence could
<br/>get through without material injury. The mixture was then
<br/>ready for use. When called upon to play Thomas Hawk, I
<br/>anointed a sheet of fools-cap with the while of a gander's
<br/>egg; then, shredding the thing to be reviewed as I had pre-
<br/>viously shredded the books,—only with more care, so as to
<br/>get every word separate—I threw the latter shreds in with
<br/>the former, screwed on the lid of the castor, gave it a shake,
<br/>and so dusted out the mixture upon the egg’d foolscap;
<br/>where it stuck. The effect was beautiful to behold. It was
<br/>captivating. Indeed the reviews I brought to pass by this
<br/>simple expedient have never been approached, and were the
<br/>wonder of the world. At first, through bashfulness—the re-
<br/>sult of inexperience—I was a little put out by a certain in-
<br/>consistency—a certain air of the bizarre, (as we say in
<br/>France,) worn by the composition as a whole. All the
<br/>phrases did not fit, (as we say in the Anglo-Saxon.) Many
<br/>were quite awry. Some, even, were up-side-down ; and
<br/>there were none of them which were not, in some measure,
<br/>injured, in regard to effect, by this latter species of accident,
<br/>when it occurred :—with the exception of Mr. Lewis Clarke’s
<br/>paragraphs, which were so vigorous, and altogether stout,
<br/>that they seemed not particularly disconcerted by any ex-
<br/>treme of position, but looked equally happy and satisfactory,
<br/>whether on their heads, or on their heels.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>What became of the editor of the “Gad-Fly,” after the
<br/>publication of my criticism on his “ Oil-of-Bob," it is some-
<br/>what difficult to determine. The most reasonable conclu-
<br/>sion is, that he wept himself to death. At all events he dis-
<br/>appeared instantaneously from the face of the earth, and no
<br/>man has seen even the ghost of him since.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>This matter having been properly accomplished, and
<br/>the Furies appeased, I grew at once into high favor with
<br/>Mr. Crab. He took me into his confidence, gave me a per-
<br/>manent situation as Thomas Hawk of the “ Lollipop,” and
<br/>as, for the present, he could afford me no salary, allowed me
<br/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/> 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page38"/>
            <br/>to profit, at discretion, by his advice.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ My Dear Thingum,” said he to me one day after dinner,
<br/>“I respect your abilities and love you as a son. You shall
<br/>be my heir. When I die I will bequeath you the ‘ Lollipop.’
<br/>In the meantime I will make a man of you—I will— provid-
<br/>ed always that you follow my counsel. The first thing to
<br/>do is to get rid of the old bore.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Boar ?” said I inquiringly—“pig, eh?—aper ? (as we
<br/>say in Latin)—who ?—where ?</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ Your father,” said he.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“Precisely,” I replied,—“pig.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ You have your fortune to make, Thingum,” resumed
<br/>Mr. Crab. “ and that governor of yours is a millstone about
<br/>your neck. We must cut him at once.” [Here I took out
<br/>my knife.] “ We must cut him,” continued Mr. Crab, “ de-
<br/>cidedly and forever. He won’t do—he won't. Upon sec-
<br/>cond thoughts, you had better kick him, or cane him, or
<br/>something of that kind.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>What do you say,” I suggested modestly, “to my kicking
<br/>him in the first instance, caning him afterwards, and wind-
<br/>ing up by tweaking his nose?”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Mr. Crab looked at me musingly for some moments, and
<br/>then answered:</p>
         <br/>
         <p>“ I think, Mr. Bob, that what you propose would answer
<br/>sufficiently well—indeed remarkably well—that is to say, as
<br/>far as it went—but barbers are exceedingly hard to cut, and
<br/>I think, upon the whole, that, having performed upon Thom-
<br/>as Bob the operations you suggest, it would be advisable to
<br/>blacken, with your fists, both his eyes, very carefully and
<br/>thoroughly, to prevent his ever seeing you again in fashion-
<br/>able promenades. After doing this, I really do not perceive
<br/>that you can do any more. However—it might be just as
<br/>well to roll him once or twice in the gutter, and then put
<br/>him in charge of the police. Any time the next morning
<br/>you can call at the watch-house and swear an assault.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I was much affected by the kindness of feeling towards
<br/>me personally, which was evinced in this excellent advice
<br/>of Mr. Crab, and I did not fail to profit by it forthwith.
<br/>The result was, that I got rid of the old bore, and began to
<br/>feel a little independent and gentleman-like. The want of
<br/>money, however, was, for a few weeks, a source of some
<br/>discomfort; but at length, by carefully putting to use my
<br/>two eyes, and observing how matters went just in front of
<br/>my nose, I perceived how the thing was to be brought about.
<br/>I say “ thing”—be it observed—for they tell me the Latin
<br/>for it is rem. By the way, talking of Latin, can any one tell
<br/>me the meaning of quocunque—or what is the meaning of
<br/>modo ?</p>
         <br/>
         <p>My plan was exceedingly simple. I bought, for a song, a
<br/>sixteenth of the “ Snapping-Turtle:”—that was all. The
<br/>thing was done, and I put money in my purse. There were
<br/>some trivial arrangements afterwards, to be sure; but these
<br/>formed no portion of the plan. They were a consequence—a
<br/>result. For example, I bought pen, ink and paper, and put
<br/>them into furious activity. Having thus completed a Maga-
<br/>zine article, I gave it, for appellation, “Fol-Lol, by the Author
<br/>of 'The Oil-of-Bob,’” and enveloped it to the “Goosether-
<br/>umfoodle.” That journal, however, having pronounced it
<br/>“twattle” in the “Monthly Notices to Correspondents,” I
<br/>reheaded the paper “ ‘ Hey-Diddle-Diddle’ by Thingum Bob,
<br/>Esq., Author of the Ode on ' The Oil-of-Bob,’ and Editor of
<br/>the ‘ Snapping-Turtle.’ ” With this amendment, I reenclos-
<br/>ed it to the “ Goosetherumfoodle,” and, while I awaited a
<br/>reply, published daily, in the “ Turtle," six columns of what
<br/>may be termed philosophical and analytical investigation of
<br/>the literary merits of the “ Goosetherumfoodle,” as well as 
  <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <br/>of the personal character of the editor of the “ Goosetherum-
<br/>foodle.” At the end of a week the “ Goosetherunifoodle”
<br/>discovered that it had, by some odd mistake, “ confounded a
<br/>stupid article, headed ‘ Hey-Diddle-Diddle’ and composed by
<br/>some unknown ignoramus, with a gem of resplendent lustre
<br/>similarly entitled, the work of Thingum Bob, Esq., the cele-
<br/>brated author of ‘ The Oil-of-Bob.’ ” The “ Goosetherumfoo-
<br/>dle” deeply “ regretted this very natural accident,” and pro-
<br/>mised, moreover, an insertion of the genuine ‘ Hey-Diddle-
<br/>Diddle’ in the very next number of the Magazine.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>The fact is I thought—I really thought—I thought at the
<br/>time—I thought then—and have no reason for thinking oth-
<br/>erwise now—that the “ Goosetherumfoodle” did make a mis-
<br/>take. With the best intentions in the world, I never knew
<br/>any thing that made as many singular mistakes as the
<br/>“ Goosetherumfoodle.” From that day I took a liking to the
<br/> “ Goosetherumfoodle,” and the result was I soon saw into
<br/> the very depths of its literary merits, and did not fail to ex-
<br/>patiate upon them, in the “ Turtle,” whenever a fitting op-
<br/> portunity occurred. And it is to be regarded as a very pecu-
<br/> liar coincidence—as one of those positively remarkable coin-
<br/> cidences which set a man to serious thinking—that just
<br/> such a total revolution of opinion—just such entire boulever-
<br/>sement, (as we say in French,)—just such thorough topsitur-
<br/> viness, (if I may be permitted to employ a rather forcible
<br/> term of the Choctaws,) as happened, pro and con, between
<br/> myself on the one part, and the “Goosetherunifoodle” on
<br/>the other, did actually again happen, in a brief period after-
<br/> wards, and with precisely similar circumstances, in the case
<br/>of myself and the “Rowdy-Dow,” and in the case of myself
<br/>and the “ Hum-Drum.”</p>
         <br/>
         <p>Thus it was that, by a master-stroke of genius, I at length
<br/> consummated my triumphs by “ putting money in my purse”
<br/>and thus may be said really and fairly to have commenced
<br/> that brilliant and eventful career which rendered me illus-
<br/>trious, and which now enables me to say, with Chateau-
<br/>briand, “I have made history”—“I'ai fait l’histoire."</p>
         <br/>
         <p>I have indeed “ made history.” From the bright epoch
<br/>which I now record, my actions—my works—are the pro-
<br/>perty of mankind. They are familiar to the world. It is,
<br/>then, needless for me to detail how, soaring rapidly, I fell
<br/> heir to the “ Lollipop”—how I merged this journal in the
<br/> “ Hum-Drum”—how again I made purchase of the “ Row-
<br/>dy-Dow,” thus combining the three periodicals—how, lastly,
<br/>I effected a bargain for the sole remaining rival, and united
<br/>all the literature of the country in one magnificent Magazine,
<br/>known every where as the</p>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">“ Rowdy-Dow, Lollipop, Hum-Drum,
<br/>and
<br/>GOOSETHERUMFOODLE.”</div>
         <br/>
         <p>Yes; I have made history. My fame is universal. It ex-
<br/>tends to the uttermost ends of the earth. You cannot take
<br/> up a common newspaper in which you shall not see some al-
<br/>lusion to the immortal Thingum Bob. It is Mr. Thingum Bob
<br/> said so, and Mr. Thingum Bob wrote this, and Mr. Thingum
<br/>Bob did that. But I am meek and expire with an humble
<br/> heart. After all, what is it?—this indescribable something
<br/> which men will persist in terming “ genius ?” I agree with
<br/>Buffon—with Hogarth—it is but diligence after all.</p>
         <br/> 
         <p>Look at me !—how I labored—how I toiled—how I wrote !
<br/> Ye Gods, did I not write ? I knew not the word “ ease.”
<br/>By day I adhered to my desk, and at night, a pale student, I
<br/>consumed the midnight oil. You should have seen me—
<br/>you should. I leaned to the right. I leaned to the left. I
<br/>sat forward. I sat backward. I sat upon end. I sat tete
<br/>baissee, (as they have it in the Kickapoo,) bowing my head
<br/>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/> 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page39"/>
            <br/>close to the alabaster page. And, through all, I—wrote.
<br/>Through joy and through sorrow, I—wrote. Through hung-
<br/>er and through thirst, I—wrote. Through good report and 
<br/>through ill report, I—wrote. Through sunshine and through 
<br/>moonshine, I—wrote. What I wrote it is unnecessary to 
<br/>say. The style !—that was the thing. I caught it from 
<br/>Fatquack—whizz!—fizz !—and I am giving you a specimen
<br/>of it now.</p>	
         <div class="byline">
            <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">Critical Notices.</div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">A Chaunt of Life and other Poems, with Sketches &amp; Essays.
<br/>By Rev. Ralph Hoyt. In Six Parts. Part II. New York: 
<br/>Le Roy and Hoyt.</div>
            <br/>
            <p>The Publishers’ Advertisement to this beautiful volume in-
<br/>forms us that “ the first part was very kindly received by the 
<br/>reading public and the press, but a considerable number of
<br/>elegantly bound copies being destroyed by fire, the author
<br/>became embarrassed and unable to proceed”—until aided or
<br/>urged to do so, we presume, by the present publishers. It
<br/>would have been, indeed, a great pity to abandon an enter-
<br/>prise so flatteringly commenced. We shall look with inter-
<br/>est for the completion of the series.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>Part II. contains the second Canto of a very fine poem,
<br/>“ The Chaunt of Life.” From the first stanza we quote the
<br/>three remarkably beautiful lines :</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Slow droop the eyelids of the drowsy day;
<br/>All weary life and every heart oppressed,
<br/>In soothing slumber now may sink to rest.</div>
            <br/>
            <p>The fourth and fifth stanzas are very noble:—</p>
            <br/>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Give me to love my fellow, and in love,
<br/>If with none other grace to chaunt my strain,
<br/>Sweet key-note of soft; cadences above,
<br/>Sole star of solace in life's night of pain.
<br/>Chief gem of Eden, fractured in that fall
<br/>That ruined two fond hearts, and tarnished all!
<br/>Redeemer! be thy kindly spirit mine;
<br/>That pearl of Paradise to me restore,
<br/>Pure, fervent, fearless, lasting, love divine,
<br/>Profound as ocean, broad as sea and shore.
<br/>While Man I sing, free, subject, and supreme,
<br/>O!	for a soul, as ample as the theme !
<br/>Sad prelude I have sung, by Sorrow led
<br/>Along the mournful shades that own her sway,
<br/>Where, Ay a stream that weeping eyes have shed,
<br/>Low chaunted I my melancholy luy,
<br/>In pensive concord with the sootheless wail
<br/>Of sighing wanderers in that lonely vale.
<br/>Ah, chide not those whose wo seems hard to bear,
<br/>The heart must hover where its treasures sleep;
<br/>I saw the great, the wise, the gifted there.
<br/>With humbler multitudes compelled to weep;
<br/>No penury, no wealth commands relief!
<br/>No Serf, no Sovereign in the realms of grief!</div>
            <br/>
            <p>We Italicise two passages, however, for their defects, and
<br/>not for their merits. We can conceive that a gem may be
<br/>“fractured in a fall” and even (imperfectly) that in so falling
<br/>it may “ruin two fond hearts”, but how it can “ tarnish all”
<br/>or anything, in so falling, does not appear. The stream of
<br/>tears is in shockingly bad taste. But the stately and pensive
<br/>thought and well-sustained modulation of the stanzas amply
<br/>redeem these demerits.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>Mr. Hoyt is occasionally halting in his metre, although
<br/>rarely or ever in his rhythm. In stanza VIII. a foot is miss-
<br/>ng in the fifth line :</p>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Rise ! with heroic strength be strong.</div>
            <br/>
            <p>In stanza XII. there is a superfluous foot in the second line:
</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Ecbatana and Babylon and Tyre remote—</div>
            <br/>
            <p>although the stanza as a whole is particularly sonorous and
<br/>Miltonic.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>The poem entitled “Old” has so many rare and peculiar
<br/>excellences, that we shall venture to copy it in full. It will
<br/>forcibly remind our readers of Mr. Durand’s exquisite picture
<br/>“ An Old Man’s Recollections”—although between poem and
<br/>painting there is nothing more than a perfectly admissible
<br/>similarity. The quaintness is, in our opinion, to be defended
<br/>as a legitimate effect, conferring high pleasure upon a nume-
<br/>rous and cultivated class of minds. In his continuous and
<br/>absolutely uniform repetition of the first line in the last of
<br/>each stanza, he has by much exceeded the legitimate limits
<br/>of the quaint, and impinged upon the simply ludicrous. The
<br/>poem, nevertheless, abounds in lofty merit, and has, in espe-
<br/>cial, some exquisite passages of pathos and of imagination.
<br/>We Italicise some of these.</p>
            <br/>OLD.
<div class="lg">
               <br/>By the way-side, on a mossy stone
<br/>Sat a hoary pilgrim sadly musing;
<br/>Oft I marked him sitting there alone,
<br/>All the landscape like a page perusing ;
<br/>Poor, unknown,
<br/>By the way-side, on a mossy stone.
<br/>Buckled knee and shoe, and broad-rimmed hat,
<br/>Coat as ancient as the form ’twas folding,
<br/>Silver buttons, queue, and crimped cravat,
<br/>Oaken staff, his feeble hand upholding,
<br/>There he sat !
<br/>Buckled knee and shoe, and broad-rimmed hat.
<br/>Seemed it pitiful he should sit there.
<br/>No one sympathizing, no one heeding,
<br/>None to love him for his thin grey hair,
<br/>And the furrows all so mutely pleading,
<br/>Age, and care;
<br/>Seemed it pitiful he should sit there.
<br/>It was summer, and we went to school.
<br/>Dapper country lads and little maidens,
<br/>Taught the motto of the “ Dunce’s Stool,’i
<br/>Its grave import still my fancy ladens,
<br/>“ Here’s a FOOL!’’
<br/>It was summer, and we went to school.
<br/>When the stranger seemed to mark our play,
<br/>(Some of us were joyous, some sad-hearted,
<br/>I remember well,—too well,—that day !)
<br/>Oftentimes the tears unbidden started,—
<br/>Would not stay !
<br/>When the stranger seemed to mark our play.
<br/>One sweet spirit broke the silent spell—
<br/>Ah!to me her name was always heaven
<br/>She besought him all his grief to tell,—
<br/>(I was then thirteen, and she eleven,)
<br/>Isabel!
<br/>One sweet spirit broke the silent spell.
<br/>Angel, said he sadly, I am old ;
<br/>Earthly hope no longer hath a morrow,
<br/>Yet why I sit here thou shall soon be told,
<br/>Then his eye betrayed a pearl of sorrow,—
<br/>Down it rolled !
<br/>Angel, said he sadly, I am old !
<br/>I have tottered here to look once more
<br/>On the pleasant scene where I delighted
<br/>In the careless, happy days of yore,
<br/>Ere the garden of my heart was blighted—
<br/>To the core!
<br/>I have tottered here to look once more !
<br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/> 
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page40"/>
               <br/>All the picture now to me how dear!
<br/>E'en this gray old rock where I am seated,
<br/>Is a jewel worth a journey here;
<br/>Ah, that such a scene must be completed
<br/>With a tear!
<br/>All the picture now to me how dear!
<br/>Old stone School-House !—it is still the same !
<br/>There’s the very step so oft I mounted;
<br/>There’s the window creaking in its frame,
<br/>And the notches that I cut and counted
<br/>For the game;
<br/>Old stone School-House !—it is still the same !
<br/>In the cottage, yonder, I was born :
<br/>Long my happy home—that humble dwelling ;
<br/>There the fields of clover, wheat, and corn,
<br/>There the spring, with limpid nectar swelling ;
<br/>Ah, Forlorn!—
<br/>In the cottage, yonder, I was born.
<br/>Those two gate-way sycamores you see,
<br/>Then were planted, just so far asunder
<br/>That long well-pole from the path to free,
<br/>And the wagon to pass safely under
<br/>Ninety-three
<br/>Those two gate-way sycamores you see ?
<br/>There’s the orchard where we used to climb
<br/>When my mates and I were boys together,
<br/>Thinking nothing of the flight of lime,
<br/>Fearing nought but work and rainy weather;
<br/>Past its prime!
<br/>There’s the orchard where we used to climb !
<br/>There, the rude, three-cornered chestnut rails,
<br/>Round the pasture where the flocks were grazing,
<br/>Where so sly, I used to watch for quails
<br/>In the crops of buckwheat we were raising,—
<br/>Traps and trails,—
<br/>There, the rude, three-cornered chesnut rails.
<br/>There’s the mill that ground our yellow grain ;
<br/>Pond, and river still serenely flowing ;
<br/>Cot, there nestling in the shaded lane,
<br/>Where the lily of my heart was blowing,—
<br/>Mary Jane !
<br/>There’s the mill that ground our yellow grain !
<br/>There’s the gate on which I used to swing,
<br/>Brook and bridge, and barn, and old red stable;
<br/>But alas ! the morn shall no more bring
<br/>That dear group around my father’s table ;
<br/>Taken wing !
<br/>There’s the gate on which I used to swing !
<br/>I am fleeing !—all I loved are fled;
<br/>Yon green meadow was our place for playing;
<br/>That old tree can tell of sweet things said,
<br/>When around it Jane and I were straying;—
<br/>She is dead !
<br/>I am fleeing!—all I loved are fled !
<br/>Yon white spire—a pencil on the sky.
<br/>Tracing silently life’s changeful story,
<br/>So familiar to my dim old eye,
<br/>Points me to seven that are now in glory
<br/>There on high
<br/>Yon white spire, a pencil on the sky !
<br/>Oft the aisle of that old church we trod,
<br/>Guided thither by an angel mother;
<br/>Now she sleeps beneath its sacred sod,—
<br/>Sire and sisters, and my little brother—
<br/>Gone to God !
<br/>Oft the aisle of that old church we trod !
<br/>There I heard of Wisdom’s pleasant ways,
<br/>Bless the holy lesson !—but, ah, never
<br/>Shall I hear again those songs of praise,
<br/>Those sweet voices,—silent now forever !
<br/>Peaceful days!
<br/>There I heard of Wisdom’s pleasant ways.
  <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>There my Mary blest me with her hand,
<br/>When our soul drank in the nuptial blessing,
<br/>Ere she hastened to the spirit-land;
<br/>Yonder turf her gentle bosom pressing :
<br/>Broken band!
<br/>There my Mary blest me with her hand.
<br/>I have come to see that grave once more,
<br/>And the sacred place where we delighted,
<br/>Where we worshipped in the days of yore,
<br/>Ere the garden of my heart was blighted
<br/>To the core !
<br/>I have come to see that grave once more.
<br/>Angel, said he, sadly, I am old !
<br/>Earthly hope no longer hath a morrow;
<br/>Now why I sit here thou hast been told;
<br/>In his eye another pearl of sorrow,—
<br/>Down it rolled !
<br/>Angel, said he, sadly, I am old !
<br/>By the wayside, on a mossy stone,
<br/>Sat the hoary pilgrim, sadly musing;
<br/>Still I marked him sitting there alone,
<br/>All the landscape, like a page perusing;
<br/>Poor, unknown,
<br/>By the way-side, on a mossy stone !</div>
            <br/>
            <p>The stanza commencing “ Buckled knee and shoe,” &amp;c.
<br/> puts us somewhat too forcibly in mind of Oliver Wendell
<br/>Holmes’ “Old Man.” The exclamation “Ninety-Three!”
<br/>introduced, as it is, independently of the observations which
<br/> surround it, must be regarded as one of the happiest instan-
<br/>ces either of refined art or of natural pathos.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>“The stanza beginning “Yon white spire” cannot be too
<br/> warmly commended.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>“ New” is a pendant to “ Old,” but its artificiality of con-
<br/>struction is even more displeasingly apparent. We quote
<br/>one or two sweet passages :</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Ah, June can only charm her eyes
<br/>With flowers of paradisial dyes
<br/>And azure skies.</div>
            <div class="ab">
               <br/>This, however, should read, “ Ah, only June,” &amp;c.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>The glowing tranquil summertime;
<br/>The summertime;
<br/>Too listless in a maiden’s prime ;
<br/>Dull melancholy pantomime !
<br/>Oh for a gay autumnal clime !
<br/>Too listless in a maiden’s prime
<br/>The summertime.
<br/>Love nestles in that gentle breast—
<br/>That gentle breast.
<br/>Ah Love will never let it rest—
<br/>The cruel sly ungrateful guest
<br/>(A viper in a linnet’s nest)
<br/>Ah Love will never let it rest—
<br/>That gentle breast.'</div>
            <p>
               <br/>“Boemus” is the concluding poem of the volume, and is
<br/>marked by the same peculiarities of metre—peculiarities,
<br/>however, which, in a composition such as this, must be con-
<br/>sidered out of place. We conclude our review with the quo-
<br/>tation of a very spirited stanza—a stanza which would do no
<br/>discredit to Campbell, and is much in his vein :</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>O’er all the silent sky
<br/>A dark and scowling frown;
<br/>But darker scowled each eye
<br/>When all resolved to die!
<br/>When (night of dread renown!)
<br/>Three thousand stars went down!</div>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Mysteries of Berlin. To be Completed in Ten Parts.
<br/>Part VII.</div>
            <br/>
            <p>This is a very weak and absurd imitation, or rather exagger-
<br/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/> 
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page41"/>
               <br/>ation of all the most reprehensible features of “The Myste-
<br/>ries of Paris.”</p>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Roman Pontiff, or a Sketch of the Lives of the Su-
<br/>preme Heads of the Roman Catholic Church. New York.
<br/>H. G. Daggers &amp; Co.</div>   
            <br/>
            <p>A pamplet of great interest. Its title so fully explains its
<br/>design that we need say little about it. The work is well
  <br/>translated from the French.</p>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">Two Letters on Slavery in the United Stales, addressed to
<br/>Thomas Clarkson, Esq. By J. H. Hammond. Columbia,
<br/>S. C. Allen McCarter &amp; Co.</div>
            <br/>
            <p>A nervously written pamphlet, the design of which is to
<br/>show that slavery is an inevitable condition of human so-
<br/>ciety.</p>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">ISRAFEL.<span class="anchor" id="a001">
                  <a href="#n001"/>
               </span> 
            </div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>In Heaven a spirit doth dwell
<br/>“ Whose heart-strings are a lute;"
<br/>None sing so wildly well
<br/>As the angel Israfel,
<br/>And the giddy stars (so legends tell)
<br/>Ceasing their hymns, attend the spell
<br/>Of his voice, all mute.
<br/>Tottering above,
<br/>In her highest noon,
<br/>The enamoured moon
<br/>Blushes with love,
<br/>While, to listen, the red levin
<br/>(With the rapid Pleiads, even,
<br/>Which were seven,)
<br/>Pauses in Heaven.
<br/>And they say (the starry choir
<br/>And the other listening things)
<br/>That Israfeli’s fire
<br/>Is owing to that lyre
<br/>By which he sits and sings—
<br/>The trembling living wire
<br/>Of those unusual strings.
<br/>But the skies that angel trod,
<br/>Where deep thoughts are a duty,
<br/>And Love’s a grown up God,
<br/>And the Houri glances are
<br/>Imbued with all the beauty
<br/>Which we worship in a star.
<br/>Thou art not, therefore, wrong,
<br/>Israfeli, who despisest
<br/>An unimpassioned song,
<br/>To thee the laurels belong,
<br/>Best bard, because the wisest!
<br/>Merrily live, and long!
<br/>The ecstasies above
<br/>With thy burning measures suit—
<br/>Thy grief, thy joy, thy hate, thy love,
<br/>With the fervor of thy lute—
<br/>Well may the stars be mute !
<br/>Yes, Heaven is thine ; but this
<br/>Is a world of sweets and sours;
<br/>Our flowers are merely—flowers,
<br/>And the shadow of thy perfect bliss
<br/>Is the sunshine of ours.
<br/>If I could dwell
<br/>Where Israfel
  <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>Hath dwelt, and he where I,
<br/>He might not sing so wildly well
<br/>A mortal melody,
<br/>While a bolder note than this might swell
<br/>From my lyre within the sky.</div>
            <br/>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">EDGAR A. POE</span>.</div>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">Musical Department.</div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <div class="head">French Opera—Park Theatre.—</div>
               <p>The intense heat of the
<br/>weather has been sadly injurious to the success of the vari-
<br/>ous theatres, keeping away hundreds who would otherwise
<br/>have visited such places of amusement.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>La Juive has been represented once, but we were unable
<br/>to attend. It was, however, we understand, very successful,
<br/>having been produced on a scale of the greatest magnificence.
<br/>Should it be again performed, we will describe it fully.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>La Fille du Regiment was produced last week. If Doni-
<br/>zetti had never written any thing but La Fille du Regiment
<br/>and L’ E'isir d'Amore, his name would surely be preserved
<br/>for posterity. There are many beauties of high character in
<br/>all his serious operas, but he is never so thoroughly at home
<br/>as in the works of lighter character. Throughout both the
<br/>operas mentioned there is a continued flow of delicious me-
<br/>lody, varied and original in its character; the concerted pie-
<br/>ces also exhibit an unusual degree of excellence, and the in-
<br/>strumentation is of a higher order of merit, being more richly
<br/>and variously harmonized. La Fille du Regiment is truly
<br/>French. Donizetti has most happily imitated the peculiarity
<br/>of the school. It lacks however the quaintness of Auber,
<br/>and sometimes the Italian school intrudes, as in the lovely
<br/>romance, “ Il faut partir,” sung by Marie ; but as a whole it
<br/>is an admirable conception, worked out with masterly skill.</p>
               <br/>
               <div class="ab">The cast was as follows :
<br/>Marie (La Fille du Regiment) . . . M’lle Calve.
<br/>Marchioness de Berkenfeldt .... M’me Mathieu.
<br/>Ten o, a Tyrolinn peasant........M. Buscher.
<br/>Sulpice, a sergeant..............M. Bernard.
<br/>Hortensius, a steward............M. Mathieu.</div>
               <br/>
               <p>M'lle Calve personated La Fille most admirably. Her
<br/>manner was that of a pelted child of rude but chivalric men
<br/>—a happy mixture of playful boldness and shrinking maiden
<br/>modesty. In all that M'lle Calve does, she is a true woman
<br/>—whether as the playful coquette, teasing but tender, wil-
<br/>ful to commit a fault, but eager and earnest to sue for for-
<br/>giveness; or as the young girl, whose nature, full of the
<br/>stronger and deeper emotions, gratitude and affection for her
<br/>protectors, and love for one who loves her fondly in return ;
<br/>whether as the wild and light-hearted vivandiere, or as the
<br/>titled lady—Mile Calve is the true woman in all, faithful to
<br/>life in every phase of the character.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>Of her singing we can truly say, that in the character of
<br/>Marie she exhibits more excellence than in any other cha-
<br/>racter she has appeared in. Her execution of “ Il faut par-
<br/>tir” was a beautiful exhibition of deep, tender, and regretful
<br/>feeling. " Chacun le sait” was admirable for its point and
<br/>finish, and the enthusiasm with which she gave “ Salut a la
<br/>France,” could only be equalled by the reception it met with
<br/>from the audience. She dressed the part with her usual
<br/>taste,—which is perfection. We hope to see her repeat this
<br/>character.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>Madame Mathieu as the Marchioness Berkenfield, elicited
<br/>general approbation. Her acting and singing in the trio,
<br/>“ Le jour naissait,’’was not to be surpassed; while in the
<br/>graver portions of the character she was equally good. Her
<br/>second dress was in truth a most admirable costume.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>M. Coeuriot, who was to have played Tonio, continuing
  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/> 
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page42"/>
                  <br/>seriously indisposed, M. Buscher, at two days’ notice, had to
<br/>undertake the part. He acquitted himself very creditably, 
<br/>His voice is not quite equal to the music, although it is cer-
<br/>tain that he would have appeared to much greater advan-
<br/>tage had he been more familiar with the music.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>M. Bernard, as the old Sergeant, is deserving of our warm- 
<br/>est commendation. Not for one moment did he forget the 
<br/>character of the Old Soldier. It was a true picture from the 
<br/>beginning to the end. The sternness of the old warrior, the
<br/>tender affection for La Fille, and the quiet quizzing of the
<br/>peculiarities of the antiquated Marchioness, each received at
<br/>his hands full justice. His singing was correctly and artisti-
<br/>cally rendered.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The acting of M. Mathieu as the Steward, was an exqui-
<br/>site piece of quiet humour.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The chorusses were well executed, although scarcely equal
<br/>to some former performances.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The Band displayed its usual excellence. In the finale to
<br/>the second act, however, where the short fugue passage oc-
<br/>curs, there was much obscurity among the stringed instru-
<br/>ments, but M. Prevost ably retrieved the error. We must
<br/>particularly compliment M. Ribas for his exquisite perform-
<br/>ance upon the “ Chor Anglaise” in Marie’s song, “ Il faut
<br/>partir”; also the first violoncellist for his obligato accompa-
<br/>niment in the second act.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <br/>
               <div class="head">Opening of the Organ for Trinity Church, New Ha-
<br/>ven.—</div>
               <p>We were present at Mr. Erben’s Factory, Centre-
<br/>street, on the occasion of the exhibition of an organ built for
<br/>the above church.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The following is a statement of the construction, &amp;c., &amp;c.
<br/>The organ is contained in a splendid gothic case of black
<br/>walnut. It has two complete sets of keys and two octaves of
<br/>pedals.</p>
               <br/>
               <div class="ab">GREAT ORGAN.	13	Principal.
<br/>1 Open Diapason (metal pipes  	14 Hautboy,
<br/>throughout.)	15	Trumpet.
<br/>2	Stop Diapason.	16	Cornet.
<br/>3	Principal.		--
<br/> 4 Twelfth.	CHOIR BASS.
<br/> 5 Fifteenth.	17 Stop Diapason.
<br/>6	Cornet.	  18 	Principal.
<br/>7	Sesqualtra.		--
<br/>8	Trumpet.	19	Double Diapasons from CCC— 16
<br/>9 Flute.	j	foot—Two Octaves.
<br/>SWELL ORGAN.		COUPLING STOPS.
<br/>10 Open Diapason.	20 Gt. Organ and Swell.
<br/>11 Stop Diapason.	21 Gt. Organ and Pedals.
<br/>12 Dulciano.	22 Pedals and Choir Organ.</div>
               <br/>
               <p>It will be seen by this statement that the organ, although
<br/>it is by no means a large instrument, possesses considerable 
<br/>power; indeed, for its size, it possesses extraordinary power. 
<br/>A coupling movement for the Great Organ and Swell, which 
<br/>goes as low as C below Fiddle G, gives great power to the
<br/>instrument and enriches the Great Organ exceedingly, when
<br/>used either full or in part. The pedals down to 16 foot C, are
<br/>very good, speaking almost immediately, and being equal
<br/>throughout.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The Reed Stops are admirable ; we must particularize the
<br/>exceeding beauty and delicacy of the Hautboy in the Swell,
<br/>and of the rough, full, and truly characteristic quality of the
<br/>trumpet in the same department, showing great improve-
<br/>ment in a few years in these particular stops. The Flute is
<br/>in the Great Organ, and is very mellow, soft and delicate. It
<br/>can be used as a solo stop with more convenience and better
<br/>effect than if it were in the Swell. Organ builders should
<br/>bear this in mind, and never put the Flute Stop in any other
<br/>than the Great Organ or Choir.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>To the Diapasons generally we must award unqualified
<br/>praise; they are exceedingly heavy and rich. The Pedals
<br/>may be coupled either with the Great Organ or Swell, or both.
  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>
                  <br/>The omission of Composition Pedals is, however, much to be
<br/>regretted, as they so greatly facilitate the labor of the organ-
<br/>ist, in the rapid change of stops necessary to produce striking
<br/>effects.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>Shortly after we went in, Mr. W. A. King, Organist of St.
<br/>Peter’s Church, sat down to the organ. Mr. King is acknow-
<br/>ledged to be the most eminently capable man of all men in
<br/>the country, to show off an organ, of whatever size, to the
<br/>greatest advantage. As an extemporaneous player, we have
<br/>not met his equal on this continent; his fancy is brilliant,
<br/>—his thoughts of beauty succeed each other in rapid succes-
<br/>sion ; he handles his subject with much clearness; these
<br/>qualifications, combined with his perfect knowledge of the
<br/>various and beautiful combinations, and his complete mastery
<br/>over the King of Instruments, have gained for him his high
<br/>and well-earned reputation. His performance on this occa-
<br/>sion was extemporaneous; in it he introduced several beauti-
<br/>ful airs from Robert Le Diable. So masterly was his perfor-
<br/>mance—so various and so orchestral was his treatment of his
<br/>themes, that he kept a very miscellaneous audience rapt and
<br/>silent for something more than half an hour—the hightest tri-
<br/>bute that could be paid to his genius.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>Altogether, we were much delighted with the exhibition,
<br/>and we consider that the congregation of Trinity Church, N.
<br/>H., cannot fail to be truly gratified with their purchase.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
               <br/>
               <div class="head">Musical Review. — </div>
               <div class="ab">Oh! Say Not; Sing a Careless Lay.
<br/>Composed and dedicated to the author of the words,
<br/>Miss Justine Bayard, by Herman S. Saroni. Thou
<br/>Art Welcome, Dearest Sister. The words by Jonas B.
<br/>Phillips. The music composed and dedicated to his friend,
<br/>Eugene Plunkett, by Herman S. Saroni. The Heart's
<br/>Despair. Words by Jonas B. Phillips. The music com-
<br/>posed and respectfully dedicated to Miss Frances P. Wood
<br/>by Herman S. Saroni.</div>
               <br/>
               <p>All the above pieces are published by John F. Nunn, 240
<br/>Broadway.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The first song is in E minor, common time. It is construct-
<br/>ed upon the simplest form of English ballads. The first eight
<br/>bars are in E minor ; it then changes for a brief period into C
<br/>minor, returning again to the original key. The melody is
<br/>exceedingly plaintive and expressive, and, although the
<br/>closes are somewhat hackneyed and common-place, yet the
<br/>accompaniments are so full and so judiciously used they re-
<br/>deem and dignify the character of the song. A false relation
<br/>occurs in the twelfth bar of each verse, where the right hand
<br/>accompaniment and the voice descend in seconds, making a
<br/>most inharmonious effect. A false accent is also given in
<br/>the third verse to the word ‘joyously.’ The accent falls with
<br/>a minim note upon the penultimate syllabic. This should
<br/>always be avoided in order to preserve the integrity of the
<br/>pronunciation. The poetry is pretty and full of sentiment,
<br/>and is modelled after the style which Haynes Bayley render-
<br/>ed so popular.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>It is got out in excellent style.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The second song is by far the most melodious composition
<br/>we have seen from Mr. Saroni's pen. It is truly a gushing
<br/>forth of feeling and sensibility. A right hearty “Welcome
<br/>to his Sister" was evidently the feeling nearest to his heart,
<br/>and he has expressed it with singular fidelity. We recom-
<br/>mend this song most earnestly to our musical friends. The
<br/>poetry by Mr. J. B. Phillips is smooth and agreeable, and ex-
<br/>presses a warm and amiable sensibility. The third song is
<br/>in C minor, 3-4 time. Its character is mournful to a painful
<br/>degree. The principal subject is to be found in the symphony,
<br/>and is given to the left hand. It is well carried out through
<br/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/> 
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page43"/>
                  <br/>the song, and imparts to it a sad and reflective lone, which
<br/>forcibly impresses the hearer. This song has not the stamp
<br/>of genuineness so strongly marked as the second under
<br/>notice, but it is a good song.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>All these songs are got out in admirable style by J. F.
<br/>Nunns, 240 Broadway. Our musical friends would do well
<br/>to look them through.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
          <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
            <br/>
            <p>At Niblo's, Mrs. Mowatt is still delighting large, fashion-
<br/>able, and very intellectual audiences, who testify their sym-
<br/>pathy with the woman, not less than their approbation of the
<br/>actress, by the most profound and respectful attention.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>Last week we had seen the fair debutante only in Pauline,
<br/>but we have since been charmed with her delineations of Juli-
<br/>ana, in “The Honeymoon,” and Lucy Ashton, in “ The Bride
<br/>of Lammermoor.” The former of these plays has very little
<br/>to recommend it—especially to Mrs. Mowatt. Its leading
<br/>incident is grossly absurd. A duke (Aranza,) wedding, in his
<br/>character of duke, a haughty gentlewoman (Juliana) makes
<br/>her believe, after marriage, that he is not only a peasant, but
<br/>more entirely brutal and disgusting than peasant ever yet
<br/>was. He maltreats her in almost every way—sneers at her—
<br/>insists upon her standing up in his presence and attending his
<br/>friends in the capacity of a slave—locks her up in her cham-
<br/>ber—refuses her communication with her parents—does every
<br/>thing in short but strike her—and makes his brutality only
<br/>the more odious by putting on, at one point, the airs of a man
<br/>of honor—drawing down the rapturous approbation of the
<br/>audience by certain rhodomontade to the effect that</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>“ Whoever lays his hand upon a woman,
<br/>Save in the way of kindness, is a villain
<br/>Whom’t were base flattery to call a coward.”</div>
            <br/>
            <p>—as if the severest personal chastisement he could have in-
<br/>flicted would not have been less cowardly than his other
<br/>bestial affronts to her dignity and honor. But all this would
<br/>be nothing, if we were not required to believe that, by such
<br/>conduct, the duke finally subdues the haughty temper of his
<br/>wife, and actually secures her most passionate love! These
<br/>things are so grossly unnatural as to destroy all the verisimi-
<br/>litude of the play—and the total irrelevancy of the under-plots
<br/>confirm the difficulty and strengthen the disgust. “ The
<br/>Honeymoon,” in short, is a wretched affair, which has been
<br/>unluckily saved to the stage (for its sins) by a number of spark-
<br/>ling points well adapted to tell with audiences too ill-culti-
<br/>vated to estimate merit otherwise than in detail—and especi-
<br/>ally by a quality which, so far from saving it, should have
<br/>secured its instant condemnation—we mean its palpable pla-
<br/>giarism of all the worst demerits of “The Taming of the
<br/>Shrew.”</p>
            <br/>
            <p>In Juliana—because Juliana is a role altogether out of na-
<br/>ture—we did not expect Mrs. Mowatt to do much—for not
<br/>much is there for any one to do. So far as a gracefully dash-
<br/>ing demeanour goes, she nevertheless accomplished some-
<br/>thing—and</p>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>Oh what a deal of scorn looks beautiful
<br/>In the contempt and anger of her lip !</div>
            <br/>
            <p>We were delighted, however, to find her announced as
<br/>Lucy in “ The Bride of Lammermoor,” for our remembran-
<br/>ces of this opera were connected only with the music of Bel-
<br/>lini and the glowing romance of Scott. If, in all the litera-
<br/>ture of fiction, there is a character for which Mrs. Mowatt is
<br/>peculiarly adapted, it is the Lucy Ashton of the original
<br/>“Bride of Lammermoor.” If the authoress of “Fashion”
<br/>knew her own strength, she would confine herself, nearly al- 
  <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>together, to the depicting in letters, as well as on the stage,
<br/>the more gentle sentiments and the most profound passions.
<br/>Her sympathy with the latter is evidently intense. In the ut-
<br/>terance of the truly generous—of the really noble—of the un-
<br/>affectedly passionate—we see her bosom heave—her cheek
<br/>grow pale—her limbs tremble—her chiselled lip quiver—and
<br/>Nature's own tear rush impetuously to the eye. Now it is
<br/>this freshness of the heart which will provide for her the
<br/>greenest laurels. It is this enthusiasm—this well of deep
<br/>feeling—which should be made to prove to her an exhaustless
<br/>source of fame ! As actress, it is to her a mine of wealth—
<br/>worth all the dawdling instructions in the world. Mrs.
<br/>Mowatt, as she now stands, is quite as able to give lessons in
<br/>stage routine to any actor or actress in America, as is any
<br/>actor or actress to give lessons to her. Let her throw all
<br/>support to the winds—trust proudly to her own grace of man-
<br/>ner—her own sense of art—her own rich and natural elocu-
<br/>tion—and let her be assured that these qualities, as she now
<br/>possesses them, are all sufficient, when considered simply as
<br/>the means by which the great end of natural acting is to be
<br/>consummated—as the mere instruments by which she may
<br/>effectively and unimpededly lay bare to the audience the
<br/>movements of her own passionate heart.
</p>
            <br/>
            <p>Feeling this—being well assured, from first seeing Mrs.
<br/>Mowatt as Pauline, that her forte lay in the depicting of
<br/>passion, we were anxious to see her in Juliet (a part which
<br/>will yet render her immortal) and were delighted when we
<br/>saw her announced for Lucy Ashton. But alas ! it was
<br/> Scott’s Lucy and not the Opera Lucy of which we dreamed.
<br/>The play, as we saw it on Tuesday, is miserably ineffective
<br/>—and the remembrance of that most passionate and roman-
<br/>tic of novels, will intrude itself to render the defects of the
<br/>dramatization more palpable. We even fancied that we
<br/> could perceive the depressing influence of this remembrance
<br/>in the countenance of Mrs. Mowatt. With a bosom full of
<br/>emotion, she seemed to suffer from the total insufficiency of
<br/>the words of the dramatist, to give utterance to her thought.
<br/>But what was to be done was done to admiration. The
<br/>actress lost no opportunity. The appeal to the mother was
<br/>very noble acting. The signing of the contract, and the wild
<br/>shriek at the sudden entrance of Edgar, would have done
<br/>honor to any one. The apathetic and mute despair at the
<br/>conclusion of the play, and during the interview with Ravens-
<br/>wood in the mother’s presence—the dumb uncomprehending
<br/>wretchedness—the half-conscious rendering up of the broken
<br/>gold—the laboring anxiety for the relief of words—the final
<br/>maddening confession, heart-breaking, and death in the
<br/>lover’s arms—were the teachings not of Mr. Crisp, but of
<br/>Nature herself—speaking in tones that could not be misun-
<br/>derstood. The audience grew pale, and were betrayed into
<br/>silence and tears—and if any one went away sneering that
<br/>night, it is at least quite certain that he felt ashamed of the
<br/>sneer.</p>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">The Fine Arts.</div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <div class="head">Joseph Bonaparte's Collection of Paintings.—</div>
               <p>It will
<br/>doubtless prove a source of high gratification to all who feel
<br/>interested in the Fine Arts, that the valuable paintings which
<br/>Joseph Bonapate collected together at Bordentown, will not
<br/>be transmitted to England for sale, but will be sold at Borden-
<br/>town on the 17th and 13th of September next. Such a col-
<br/>lection should not be divided. It should form the nucleus of
<br/>a great gallery.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>If the wealthy and ardent admirers of the Fine Arts in
<br/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/> 
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page44"/>
                  <br/>New York, would but take the matter in hand, how easy it
<br/>would he, by subscription, to purchase the entire collection
<br/>for New York.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>Why should not Mr. Astor give to our city this collection ?
<br/>It would be a gift to posterity, and would make his name his-
<br/>torical with the progress of the Fine Arts in this country.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>Catalogues, which will be sent to the numerous institutions
<br/>through the whole range of the country, are now in prepara-
<br/>tion.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <div class="head">The New York Herald vs. The National Academy of
<br/>Fine Arts.—</div>
               <p>While defending the National Academy against
<br/>the ill-judged remarks, false accusations, and grossly ignor-
<br/>ant misstatements which appeared in the Herald a short
<br/>time since, we wish it to be distinctly understood that we
<br/>are no partisans of the Academy or its supporters. What
<br/>we have done is simply an act of common justice to the Aca-
<br/>demy ; at the same time it is an act of duty imperative on us
<br/>to endeavor to disabuse the public mind of any false impres-
<br/>sions which the article in the Herald was calculated to con-
<br/>vey.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The following quotations from the Herald will clearly
<br/>prove the utter ignorance of the writer in question, of all that
<br/>appertains to the National Academy, its constitution, and
<br/>the intention of its establishment.
</p>
               <br/>
               <p>National Academy of Design.—This institution has now closed its
<br/>exhibition for the season, and one or two remarks in review may be
<br/>made with propriety. One of these applies to the character of the
<br/>works, and on this topic we have to say, that little improvement has
<br/>been observable in the pictures over those of former seasons. This
<br/>stationary state of the exhibition is a matter of regret, and totally at
<br/>variance with the specific end and object of the association, which are
<br/>by introducing to public notice, and awards of premiums to excellence,
<br/>to develop latent talent, encourage genius, and foster a true taste. To
<br/>accomplish this, no person who reads the discourses of Sir Joshua
<br/>Reynolds, and other standard writings on the Fine Arts, can overlook
<br/>the essential importance of high models to the education of the artist.
<br/>This admitted, the inference is obvious, that for the improvement of
<br/>students at least, a few works of a high order of excellence would be
<br/>of infinitely more service than the most extensive accumulations of
<br/>mediocre or worthless pictures, such as compose the major part of
<br/>those displayed every season by the Academy of Design.
</p>
               <br/>
               <p>To the first remark we would simply reply that the rooms
<br/>of the Academy were open as usual for the works of every
<br/>artist, but if the artists will not improve from year to year,
<br/>surely the Council of the Academy is not to be blamed. In
<br/>the next place, the object of the institution is not to award
<br/>premiums, but simply to instruct young students, and to offer
<br/>them when sufficiently advanced, and other artists, a medium
<br/>through which their works may be presented to the public.
<br/>The Academy offers no premium to the exhibitor. The
<br/>exhibition is composed of the works of artists and not of pu-
<br/>pils. When an artist ceases to be a pupil, he ceases to ac-
<br/>knowledge the competency if any tribunal to judge of his
<br/>works short of that of public opinion. To the award of that
<br/>tribunal he cheerfully submits, and the prize he contends for
<br/>is Fame.
</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The introduction of Sir Joshua Reynolds’ name would
<br/>have much weight, did the opinions quoted from him bear
<br/>any relation to the subject in question. The accumulation
<br/>of valuable pictures is the province of the directors of a
<br/>National Gallery, which gallery should be opened, as in
<br/>England, France, &amp;c. certain days in the week, for the study
<br/>of the pupils of the National Academy.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>"Another fault attributable to it is the mode of its management,
<br/>which we are sorry to say does not betray liberality, or solicitude for
<br/>the character of the body. Cliques are bad enough, and detestable
<br/>under any circumstances; but to allow their influence over an institu-
<br/>tion avowedly dedicated to one or more of the Fine Arts, smells of
<br/>sacrilege. What do the “ Council” then say to the charge against the
<br/>composition of the body—that it is made up of a coterie of painters, to
<br/>the exclusion of those who are not—that they practise a system of fa-
  <br/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/>voritism, giving prominence often to wretched daubs, because the au-
<br/>thors have influence with them, and consigning to neglect works of
<br/>merit or of promise, for reasons best known to themselves, and the
<br/>sufferers from their partiality.”</p>
               <br/>
               <p>What defence can we make to the terrible charge that
<br/>“artists,” and only artists, presume to manage an institution
<br/>devoted to instruction in the arts? We will merely inquire
<br/> if persons ignorant of music are more competent to teach
<br/> than musicians ?—if one who never read a law book is more
<br/> capable to defend a cause than a practised lawyer? When
<br/> these questions are answered in the affirmative universally,
<br/> this charge will have some weight, but until then we trust
<br/> that every professional association will be managed by pro-
<br/>fessional men.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The charge of unfairness in the conduct of the hanging
<br/>committee, scarcely needs a reply. Their task is a most dif-
<br/>ficult and a most unthankful one. That they are accused of
<br/>unfairness is not to us a matter of surprise—had they not
<br/>been so accused would indeed have been surprising, for what
<br/>artist that ever exhibited but believed his works (however
<br/>wretched) deserving of the very best place upon the walls.
<br/>This charge is too frivolous to require further comment.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>“ Once more, wo reproach the Council of the Academy of Design
<br/>With giving a sordid and gravelling character to their policy. They
<br/>do not seem to be aware that money making is not the object of the
<br/>institution, or are ignorant of the truth that the gain of pence and the
<br/>acquisition of taste and artistical skill, have no connection with—no
<br/>affinity for each other. Making money is not the end to be sought in
<br/>these exhibitions, and yet there is good ground for binning the mana-
<br/>gers for a departure from this truth. Instead of concocting narrow
<br/>plans for gain, it is the office of the managers to disburse all the funds
<br/>they are able in patronising and encouraging merit without favor or
<br/>partiality ; and one mode of doing so would be the establishment of a
<br/>Drawing School, which has been too long neglected. We want to see
<br/>this Academy of Design with an “odor of nationality about it,” and
<br/>to have that it must not be narrow, sordid, or illiberal, but comprehen-
<br/>sive in its objects, simple in its operations, and elevated in its motives
<br/> —then it will be what it professes to be, an American Academy of
<br/>Design.”</p>
               <br/>
               <p>To this last charge of “ sordid and grovelling policy” we
<br/>have only to oppose facts. Not one single cent of the money
<br/>received from the public exhibition has ever been appropria-
<br/>ted to the personal uses of the members of the Academy.
<br/>The whole of such proceeds has been expended in sustaining
<br/> the institution, as the reports will triumphantly show.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The last two sentences of the Herald’s sagacious article
<br/>cap the climax of the writer’s incredible ignorance, and
<br/>shameless assurance. Has the man been sleeping for the
<br/>last twenty years? or were his statements merely wilful and
<br/>malicious slanders, penned with the intention to prejudice
<br/> the public against the National Academy? We are com-
<br/>pelled to believe the latter suggestion, arguing from the illib-
<br/>eral tone of the article throughout. This person actually
<br/> asks the Council of the National Academy why they do not
<br/>establish a drawing academy ? Why, such a school has been
<br/>in existence for the last twenty years! It was established
<br/>by and supported always from the funds of the Academy.
<br/> It is open several months in the winter season for students—
<br/>free of expense. Some of the finest casts, from the antique,
<br/>in the world, are at the service of the students. In fact the
<br/>number of classical models in the school is very great. Be-
<br/>sides statuary the student has the advantage of drawing
<br/>from the life figure; to procure which is a heavy tax upon
<br/>the funds of the society. These advantages are freely of-
<br/>fered, gratuitously, to young persons desirous of studying the
<br/>art, and the number of pupils to this school, collected from
<br/>all parts of the country, has been sixty and upwards every
<br/>year. Does this smack of “sordid and grovelling policy"?
<br/>Is this the conduct of narrow-minded or illiberal men? If
<br/>they desired to keep the entire public patronage, why should
<br/>they voluntarily instruct so large a number of young men,
<br/>
                  <br/>
                  <div class="columnbreak"/> 
                  <div class="pagebreak" id="#page45"/>
                  <br/>some of whom might naturally be expected to deprive them
<br/>of some portion of that patronage, when they might if they
<br/>choose appropriate that money to themselves, which is now
<br/>as it were the means of existence and fume to hundreds.</p>
               <br/>
               <p>The Academy has its faults, but there is so much that is
<br/>excellent in it that we have thought it proper to put the pub-
<br/>lic in possession of the facts. In our future numbers we
<br/>shall make the public acquainted with the history of this so-
<br/>ciety and the benefits it has conferred upon the artist in this
<br/>country.</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">SONNET.——SILENCE.</div>
            <div class="lg">
               <br/>There are some qualities—some incorporate things,
<br/>That have a double life, which thus is made
<br/>A type of that twin entity which springs
<br/>From matter and light, evinced in solid and shade.
<br/>There is a two-fold Silence—sea and shore—
<br/>Body and soul. One dwells in lonely places,
<br/>Newly with grass o’ergrown ; some solemn graces,
<br/>Some human memories and tearful lure,
<br/>Render him terrorless : his name's “ No More.”
<br/>He is the corporate Silence: dread him not!
<br/>No power hath he of evil in himself;
<br/>But should some urgent fate (untimely lot!)
<br/>Bring thee to meet his shadow (nameless elf,
<br/>That haunteth the lone regions where hath trod
<br/>No foot of man,) commend thyself to God !</div>
            <br/>
            <div class="byline">
               <span class="person">P.</span>
            </div>
         </div>
          <div>
            <br/>
            <div class="head">Prison Association.</div>
            <br/>
            <div class="ab">First Report of the Female Department of the Prison Asso-
<br/>ciation of New York.</div>
            <br/>
            <p>The object of this most praiseworthy attempt is to give
<br/>the convict a fair chance for re-commencing life, on equal
<br/>terms with those amongst whom he finds him or herself, when
<br/>released from confinement. The idea is one capable of the
<br/>best results, if fairly carried out; which we feel assured it
<br/>will be, when intrusted to such hands as it appears naturally
<br/>to have fallen into. No public reform appears to us so loud-
<br/>ly to be called for, or with so much justice, as that which
<br/>would ameliorate the condition of the prisoners in or cut of
<br/>jail: and, perhaps, from the existing state of things, it is
<br/>even more incumbent upon society to help him from getting
<br/>into prison, than in the first instance even to send him there.
<br/>When we consider the stigma attached to the fact of ever
<br/>having been confined in a prison, (whether justly or unjustly) ;
<br/>that it too often casts a blight upon a man’s character and
<br/>prospects, from which he rarely recovers: and then only-
<br/>from admirable resolution, patience, and a most uncommon
<br/>force of mind and character: it is a most solemn prompting
<br/>of the conscience that commands us to treat the victim of
<br/>folly, of ignorance, or of crime, with at least the same toler-
<br/>ant spirit, the same equal justice which we ourselves would
<br/>hope for, in the same situation.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>The fact really is, that very many are obliged to ‘commit’
<br/>themselves, or perish by the bleak freezing of neglect;’ that
<br/>to obtain a shelter and food to sustain life, they must e’en
<br/>return to the hated jail.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>That a small number, like Mr. Rathbun of Buffalo, whom
<br/>we have ever admired for his enterprise and public spirit:
<br/>whom we have thought a much more eminent man than
<br/>many of his fellow speculators and tempters to doubtful
<br/>schemes of profit; whose offence considered not as a selfish
<br/>crime, but as springing from a desire to advance the public
<br/>interests, and to interweave his name (a laudable ambition)
<br/>with his favorite town, we might almost pardon as venial,
<br/>were not justice the most exacting of all virtues—that not a
  <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/>
               <br/>few like him, by dint of energy, the salient spring of self-confi-
<br/>dence, and great activity of mind, can occasionally recover
<br/>lost ground, perhaps become better and alter many thereby,
<br/>is no argument against a society like the present, whose aim
<br/>is to help the vast majority, who are not able to help them-
<br/> selves.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>The report is clearly and skilfully drawn up, in an admi,
<br/>rable spirit of humanity, and with an eye to impartial justice,
<br/>and a wise economy, at the same time. We have been re-
<br/>quested to make the following statement:</p>
            <br/>
            <p>“ The Female Department of the New York Association,
<br/>being about to establish a Home for the temporary reception
<br/>of such discharged convicts as may appear willing to reform,
<br/>earnestly solicit immediate aid from all those interested in
<br/>this attempt, in the form of money, clothing, household fur-
<br/> niture, fuel, books, or goods of any description,—in short
<br/>everything; that can be used in a large and destitute family.</p>
            <br/>
            <div class="ab">Caroline M. Kirkland, Cor. Sec'y.”</div>
         </div>
          <div>
            <br/>
            <div class="head">Mr. Willis.—</div>
            <p>Nothig for a long time has given us so
<br/>true a pleasure as to learn that this distinguished gentleman
<br/>has entirely recovered his health. He is now busily at work
<br/>—and has commenced his anxiously expected Letters for
<br/>The Mirror”—four of them having been already received.
<br/>Among all our men of literature there is not one whose laur-
<br/>els have been more nobly earned than have been those of
<br/>Mr. Willis. The country has a right to be proud of him—
<br/>and is.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>It is extraordinary, says Mr. W. in one of his late letters,
<br/>how little the English change ! Regent-street, after four or
<br/>five years, is exactly what Regent-street was. The men
<br/>have the same light cravats, coats too small, overbrushed
<br/>whiskers, and look of being excessively washed. The car-
<br/>riages and horses exactly the same. The cheap shops have
<br/>the same placard of “ Selling Off” in their broad windows.
<br/>The blind beggars tell the same story, and are led by the
<br/>same dogs: but what is stranger than all this sameness is,
<br/>that the ladies look the same ! The fashions have perhaps
<br/>changed—in the milliner’s shops! But the Englishing that
<br/>is done to French bonnets after they are bought, or the En
<br/>glish way in which they are worn, overpowers the novelty,
<br/>and gives the fair occupants of the splendid carriages of Lon-
<br/>don the very same look they had ten years ago.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>Still, there are some slight differences observable in the
<br/>street, and among others, I observe that the economical pri-
<br/>vate carriage called a “ Brougham,” is very common. These
<br/>are low cabs, holding two or four persons, with a driver, and
<br/>perhaps a footman in livery on the outside seat, and one
<br/>horse seems to do the work as well as two. This fashion
<br/>would be well introduced into New York—that is so say, if
<br/>our city is ever to be well enough paved to make a drive any
<br/>thing but a dire necessity. The paving of London is really
<br/>most admirable. Vast city as it is, the streets are as smooth
<br/>as a floor all over it, and to ride is indeed a luxury. The
<br/>breack-neck, hat-jamming and dislocating jolts of Broadway
<br/>must seem to English judgment an inexcusable stain on our
<br/>public spirit. And, Apropos of paving—the wooden pave-
<br/>ment seems to be entirely out of favor. Regent street is laid
<br/>in wooden blocks, and in wet weather (and it rains here some
<br/>part of every day,) it is so slippery that an omnibus which
<br/>has been stopped in going up the street is with difficulty start-
<br/>ed again. The horses almost always come to their knees,
<br/>thongh the ascent is very slight, and the falls of cart and car-
<br/>riage-horses are occurring continually. Nothing seems to
<br/>"do" like the McAdam pavement, and wherever you find it
<br/>in London, you find it in as perfect order as the floor of
<br/>
               <br/>
               <div class="columnbreak"/> 
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page46"/>
               <br/>bowling-alley. I see that all heavy vehicles, (by the way)
<br/>are compelled to have very broad wheels, and they rather
<br/>improve the road than spoil it. A law to the same effect
<br/>should be passed in New York, if it ever has a pavement
<br/>worth preserving.</p>
         </div>
          <br/>
         <div>
            <p>We are requested to call the attention of our readers to the
<br/>advertisement of Messrs. J. B. Carey, &amp;c., Manufacturers of
<br/>Ornamental Show Cards, 34 Beekman st.</p>
            <br/>
            <p>These cards are adapted to all kinds of business. We
<br/>have seen some beautiful specimens at their rooms, display-
<br/>ing much taste in the getting up, and were assured that they
<br/>have already found their way into most of the large cities in
<br/>the United States. Those about to purchase we would ad-
<br/>vise to call as above and examine the styles.</p>
         </div>
         <div>
            <br/>
            <div class="head">Items—Literary or Scientific.</div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>Miss Cushman is daily growing in favor with the Cockneys. To
<br/>exhibit her lately in light comedy, the “ School for Scandal" has
<br/>been produced.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>While Hackett was playing at the Haymarket recently in Mon-
<br/>sieur Mallet, a cross of the Chevalier of the Legion of Honor fell
<br/>from his breast, when Prince Albert, who was in the house at the
<br/>time, accompanying the Queen, sent his private Secretary, Mr. An-
<br/>son, with an elegant breastpin, which he had been wearing at the
<br/>time, as a present to the American actor.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>The Rev. Mr. Barham, author of the well known Ingoldsby Le-
<br/>gends, died last week at his residence, Amen corner, St. Paul’s,
<br/>London.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>The French Operatic Company from Brussels, at Covent Gar-
<br/>den Theatre, has been very successful.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>The idlers of Paris are flocking in numbers to gaze upon the
<br/>open circus, called the Hippodrome, and modelled after the Roman
<br/>Coliseum, which is fast advancing to its conclusion in the neighbor-
<br/>hood of the Etoile. Stakes driven into its vast arena already mark
<br/>out the path of the antique chariots which are to revive the Olympic
<br/>contests. A hundred horses have been purchased for the service
<br/>of the establishment.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>An English ship, the Victory, which has just arrived from the
<br/>Mediterranean, states that on the 18th ult., in lat. 36 40 86, and
<br/>Ion. 13 44 36, immense balls of fire were seen to issue from the
<br/>sea.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>Mr. William John O’Connell recently obtained a verdict, in the
<br/>Court of Common Pleas, London, and £50 damages, against the
<br/>proprietors of the Morning Post, for a libel.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>“ Eugene Sue,” says Tate’s Magazine, “ runs a fair chance of be-
<br/>ing better known, and certainly better appreciated throughout the
<br/>British Dominions, than Sir Walter Scott.” “ The Mysteries” are
<br/>the confessions of Vidocq, and something worse, turned into a ro-
<br/>mance, strong, filthy, and full-flavored. Mankind is there repre-
<br/>sented, not in his glory, but in utterly incredible debasement. It is
<br/>so interesting to trace and gloat upon our intimate connection with
<br/>the brutes! Faugh? can we endure such infamy, and yet pretend
<br/>that our hearts are clean ?</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>There is every reason to believe that the Irish Collegiate Bill
<br/>will prove a failure in the working. The Irish Members, headed
<br/>by O’Connell, who have come over to Parliment in connexion with
<br/>the measure, have not succeeded in persuading the Government to
<br/>accede to the requirements of the Irish Catholic Bishops.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>The new comet was first seen in the south of Europe, by the offi-
<br/>cers of the middle-watch of her Majesty’s steamer Volcano, on its
<br/>voyage from Malta and Marseilles.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div class="columnbreak"/>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>The Napoleon Museum in London has been lately sold. Most
<br/>of the articles connected with the personal and historical associations
<br/>of the extraordinary man they commemorated have been sold for
<br/>almost nothing.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>The project to throw a high tube composed of sheet iron, across
<br/>the Menai Straits, for the transmit of a railway, has been abandon-
<br/>ed ; owing, doubtless, to the probable disastrous effect of a gale of
<br/>wind pressing upon such an extent of surface as so large a tube
<br/>would necessarily present. It is in contemplation, to erect in its
<br/>stead two bridges of solid construction, both of them uniting on the
<br/>Britannia Rock, and to throw out two piers from each side of the
<br/>Straits.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>The fund for erecting a marble monument to the memory of Rob-
<br/>ert Southey, Esq., the late poet Laureate, in Crossthwaite church,
<br/>Keswick, is progressing in such a manner as to afford the utmost
<br/>satisfaction to those exerting themselves in the undertaking.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>Mr. Charles Green, the aeronaut, made his-three hundredth as-
<br/>cent in his large balloon, from the ground of the Albert saloon, at
<br/>Hoxton.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>A steamer, to be called the ‘ Lady of the Lake,’ has been launch-
<br/>ed on the Windermere. This is said to be the first steamer on any
<br/>English or Irish lake.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>Madame Laret recently ascended in the balloon from Avignon.
<br/>The balloon dropped into the Rhone, and but for the exertions of a
<br/>young man, who jumped into the river to her rescue, she would
<br/>have been drowned.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>Mr. Everett, the American Minister, has been delivering an Ad-
<br/>dress before the British Agricultural Association at Cambridge.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>Punch complains that some one of the English Magazines has
<br/>stolen (from Hood’s) a story called “ The Red Herring” or some-
<br/>thing of that kind, and details the incidents. We read the whole
<br/>matter years ago in the original French.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>A work called “The European Diplomatists,” by Capefigne, the
<br/>second volume of which has just appeared, is mueh read and relish.
<br/>ed. Sir Robert Peel is severely dealt with by the author; but the
<br/>best portraits are of Mole, Guizot, and Broglie. It is a work to be
<br/>recommended to all English statesmen. The tragedy of ‘ Lucrece,’
<br/>which was refused at the Theatre Francais, has produced the author
<br/>60,000 francs.</p>
            </div>
            <br/>
            <div>
               <p>“ Poets, painters, feuilletonistes, and all our men and women
<br/>of rank,” says the Paris correspondent of the New-York Mirror,
<br/>“ are retiring to their ‘ Sabine fields,’ while the bar and the
<br/>bench are on the wing for Baden, Hambourg, Spa, and Vichy. M.
<br/>Cunou-Gridune is expected at the latter place, and M. Guizot has
<br/>retained his apartments for the month of July. A small revolution
<br/>has been consummated in the musical department of the bath.
<br/>Young Musard has been dethroned, and his sceptre passed to the
<br/>hands of an obscure pretender, M. Strauss, not he of Vienna, but a
<br/>very clever Strauss for all that. The literary men of distinction
<br/>have their Tusculums, like the great letter writers of Rome—with-
<br/>out adverting to the three castles of M. Scribe, or of the magnificent
<br/>property of Mr. Vanderburch—purchased with only half the “ au-
<br/>thor’s rights” of a single farce, “The Gamin du Paris"—Soulie has
<br/>a delicious villa at Bievre, and Jules Janin an architectural gem at
<br/>Passy. I may cite many other retreats, where the imagination and
<br/>the fancy may inhale, with the fresh breezes of nature and spring,
<br/>poetical inspirations. Alexander Dumas is installed in the pret-
<br/>tiest and greenest spot of the terrace of St. Germain, in a delicious
<br/>cottage, formed of two purlieus, which overlook the brightest
<br/>scenes: the eye wanders over the immense panorama of the woods
<br/>of Vesmay and Charenton—admires the sides of Marli—and follows
<br/>the “ sinuous Seine," winding its slow way through “alleys green.”</p>
            </div>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div class="columnbreak"/> 
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page47"/>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <p>To the Author of the “ Lines on the Grecian Flute.” 
<br/>We fear that we have mislaid the poem.</p>
         </div>
         <br/>
         <div>
            <div class="head">Index to our first Volume.—</div>
            <p>We did not purpose to pub-
<br/>lish an Index to our first volume, but by the numerous re-
<br/>quests for one, we have been induced to change our mind.
<br/>We shall accordingly forward a complete Index to our
<br/>subscribers in the next number of the Journal.</p>
         </div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">THE
<br/>SOUTHERN LITERARY MESSENGER.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">B. B. MINOR, Editor and Proprietor.
<br/>Published monthly, at Richmond. Va. Price Five Dollars per year.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>THE MESSENGER has been established since
<br/>	1835, has a large subscription list, and is the principal organ of 
<br/>Southern opinion.</p>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">Subscriptions received by John Bisco, at the office of the “ Broad-
<br/>way Journal,” 135 Nassau streeet.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">A. G. BAGLEY’S</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">CELEBRATED IMPROVED EVER-POINTED
<br/>GOLD PEN.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>THIS PEN RECEIVED THE HIGHEST PRE-
<br/>mium at the last Fair of the American Institute, and has been pro-
<br/>nounced by the First Teachers of Penmanship in the country, to be
<br/>infinitely superior to any Gold Pen ever before introduced to the Ame-
<br/>rican public. The lasting properties of this Pen are undoubted, owing
<br/>to the total absence of corrosibility from any of the inks in use; and the
<br/>peculiar shape of the nibs—which was first introduced by Bagley—
<br/>makes it more pleasant to use, renders it less liable to damage, more
<br/>easy to repair, and prevents the necessity of the great care that other
<br/>articles of the kind require.</p>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">MANUFACTORY, 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
<br/>Jy 26</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">J. B. CARY &amp;. CO.,</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">ARTISTS,</div>
         <p>MANUFACTURERS OF ORNAMENTAL SHOW
<br/> CARDS adapted for Utility, as well Adornment, for stores in all
<br/>kinds of business. Specimens may be seen in the leading stores of the
<br/>principal cities of the Union.</p>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">Agents for Boston: Messrs. Sowle &amp; Shaw. Mr. J. L. Lazarus is
<br/>now visiting the Eastern States, all orders received by him will meet
<br/>with prompt attention. 34 Beekman-Strcet, (late 323 Broadway.)
<br/>Observe ! Our names are printed at the foot of each card, and
<br/>we caution the public that imitators are in the field.	Jy 26</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PLEASANT SUMMER READING.
<br/>FOR TRAVELLERS AND OTHERS.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab"> 1. Eothen ; or Traces of Travel in the East..................50
<br/>“ The picked book of the season.”
<br/>2	Mary Schweidler, The Amber Witch.........................37
<br/>" A beautiful and pure fiction.”
<br/>3	Undine and Sintram. By Fouque............................50
<br/>" The rarest essence of romantic genius.”
<br/>4	Imagination and Fancy. By Leigh Hunt. . .................50
<br/>“ A delicate volume of illustrative criticism.”
<br/>5	The diary of Lady Willoughby.............................25
<br/>" Though a fiction, of profound religious interest.”
<br/>6	Hazlitt’s Table Talk, on Men, Things, &amp;c. 2 parts. ...	 75
<br/>" Most brilliant papers of a sparkling writer.”
<br/>7	Headlong Hall and Nightmare Abeby........................38
<br/>" Lively and piquant satirical sketches.”
<br/>8	The French in Algiers....................................37
<br/>“ Full of stirring incident and anecdote.”
<br/>9	Ancient Moral tales from the Gesta Rom...................38
<br/>“ The stories are very beautiful and moral.”
<br/>10	Crescent and the Cross. Dy E. Warburton, 2 parts. . .	1 00
<br/>" A truly delightful work from first to last.”
<br/>11	The Age of Elizabeth. By W. Hazlitt......................50
<br/>" Full of originality and genius.”
<br/>12	Journal of an African Cruiser............................50
<br/>" Quite a refreshing and delightful work.”
<br/>13	Tales. By Edgar A. Poe...................................50
<br/>" Characteristic tales of thrilling interest.”
<br/>14	Letters from Italy. By J. T. Headley. ,..................50
<br/>" The best book of travels ever published here.”
<br/>Published and for sale by
<br/>Jy 26	WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.—</div>
         <div class="ab">THOMAS H. CHAMBERS,
<br/>(formerly Conductor to Dubois &amp; Stodart), No. 385 Broadway,
<br/>will keep a complete assortment of the largest approved Grand Action
<br/>Piano Fortes, of the most superior quality; such as he is prepared to
<br/>guarantee for their excellence of Tone Touch, and External Finish,
<br/>and to endure in any climate. A liberal discount from the standard
<br/>prices. Piano Fortes Tuned and Repaired. Piano Fortes always on hire.</div>
      </div>
          <br/>
      <br/>
      <div class="columnbreak"/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">INTERESTING WORKS
<br/>JUST PUBLISHED BY
<br/>HARPER &amp; BROTHERS, NEW-YORK.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">THE NEW REFORMATION.
<br/>Now ready, with curious Illustrative Plate, price 25 cents, or Muslin,
<br/>37 1-2 cents.
<br/>JOHN RONGE,
<br/>THE HOLY COAT OF TREVES,
<br/>AND THE NEW GER. CATHOLIC CHURCH.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>Including authentic details of the events connected with the recent
<br/>exhibition of the pretended " Coat of our Lord ” in the Cathedral of
<br/>Treves, during the months of August and September, 1844 : compris-
<br/>ing the letters and protestations of the author against the imposition
<br/>and superstitions of the Roman Catholic priests, &amp;c.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>This publication is exceedingly opportune; it will be perused with
<br/>deep interest by the Protestant community at large.</p>
         <div class="ab">—Commercial Ad-
<br/>vertiser.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>The noble protest of Ronge has been circulated in Germany, not by
<br/>thousands, but by millions of copies ; and it has been hailed with loud
<br/>applause by all classes, because it expeesses a public sentiment, and
<br/>finds a response in all hearts.</p>
         <div class="ab">—New York Observer.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES.
<br/>In one volume, 12mo.. beautifully printed, price 75 cts.
<br/>A PILGRIMAGE TO TREVES,
<br/>THROUGH THE VALLEY OF THE MEUSE, AND THE FOREST OF
<br/>ARDENNES.
<br/>BY CHARLES EDWARD ANTHON, Esq.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>This is the production of a young American, who had the rare for-
<br/>tune to be present at the most marvellous occurrence of the I9th cen-
<br/>tury—the exhibition of the Holy Robe. In addition to a very graphic
<br/>description of this extraordinary event, which, from the excitement it
<br/>has created, seems destined to be an era in the Christian Church, this
<br/>unpretending volume is replete with antiquarian lore, relating to the
<br/>city of Charlemagne, from which the “ Pilgrimage ” commences—
<br/>the intermediate historic and poetic ground; and of the once renowned
<br/>city of Treves, with which it closes. It is the work of a scholar, and
<br/>cannot fail to enlist a profound interest. </p>
         <div class="ab">—Oswego Advertiser.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">MR. PRESCOTT’S HISTORICAL WORKS.
<br/>In 3 volumes 8vo, beautifully printed and accompanied with fine En-
<br/>gravings.
<br/>HISTORY OF
<br/>THE CONQUEST OF MEXICO.
<br/>WITH A LIFE OF THE CONQUERER, HERNANDO CORTES,
<br/>AND A VIEW OF ANCIENT MEXICAN CIVILIZATION.
<br/>BY WILLIAM H. PRESCOTT, Esq.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>Mr. Prescott appears to possess almost every qualification for his
<br/>task; he has a pure, simple, and eloquent style—a keen relish for the
<br/>picturesque—a quick and discerning judgment of character, and a calm,
<br/>generous and enlightened spirit of philanthropy, There is no exag-
<br/>geration in stating that his "Conquest of Mexico” contains most of the
<br/>valuable qualities which distinguish the most popular historical writers
<br/>in our language of the present day. It unites the chivalrous but truth-
<br/>ful enthusiasm of Col. Napier, and the vivacity of the accomplished
<br/>author of the “ Siege of Granada,” with the patient and ample research
<br/>of Mr. Tytler.</p>
         <div class="ab">—Edinburgh Review, May, 1845.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">In 3 volumes 8vo, uniform with the above, with Portraits and Maps.
<br/>HISTORY OF THE
<br/>REIGN OF FERDINAND AND ISBAELLA,
<br/>THE CATHOLIC.
<br/>BY WILLIAM II. PRESCOTT, Esq.
<br/>The Tenth Edition.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>It would be altogether supererogatory to make this celebrated work
<br/>the subject of critical analysis, since it has so long been distinguished
<br/>by the concurrent and enthusiastic applause of the whole reading com-
<br/>munity. We know of scarcely any other work so amusing, instruc-
<br/>tive, and powerfully attractive as the " History of Ferdinand and Isa-
<br/>bella it possesses every charm which elegance of diction, graceful-
<br/>ness of style, and interest of subject can impart. In a word, it is such
<br/>a production as could only have emanated from a mind richly stored
<br/>with the wealth of sound learning, genius, and the felicitous art of its
<br/>application.</p>
         <div class="ab">—N. Y. Review.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div> 
         <div class="ab">—A. H. GALE &amp; CO.s Ware-
<br/> Rooms, No. 289 Broadway — Manufactory Third Avenue, corner
<br/>of 13th Street.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>Purchasers are invited to call and examine their extensive assort-
<br/>ment of Rosewood and Mahogany Piano Fortes, with from six to
<br/>seven octaves, embracing every variety of patterns, made in their well-
<br/>known substantial manner, under their immediate and personal super-
<br/>intendence, by skillful and experienced mechanics, from the best sea-
<br/>soned materials.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>These instruments embrance many important improvements, which
<br/>will recommend themselves, and are finished in the highest state of
<br/>perfection, with the best French grand action, warranted in every re
<br/>spect by the manufacturer.</p>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <br/>
      <div class="columnbreak"/> 
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page48"/>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">A CARD.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">WM. A. KING, PROFESSOR of the PIANO-
<br/> FORTE, ORGAN. &amp;c. has removed to No. 22 Bank street,
<br/>where his terms for giving instruction can be ascertained.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER.</div>
         <div class="ab">—JAMES
<br/>PIRSSON, 88, 90, &amp; 92 Walker Street, near Elm. A
<br/>Large Stock of the finest instruments always on hand. Terms mode-
<br/>rate. FOR SALE—A Splendid Harp, nearly new. To be sold at a
<br/>great bargain for cash.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
         <div class="ab">—V. F. HARRISON, 23 Canal
<br/>Street, N.Y.
<br/>Instruments made with the most recent improvements, such as Iron
<br/>Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are made
<br/>from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most faithful
<br/>workmanship, the result of 23 years experience m the business.
<br/>N. B. Wanted, a second-hand Parlor Organ.
<br/>Piano Fortes on hire by the month.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div>
         <div class="ab">—JOHN PETHICK, (formerly
<br/> Mundy &amp; Pethick,) invites the attention of the musical public to
<br/>the elegant and varied assortment he now has at his Old Establish-
<br/>ment corner of Cottage Place and Bleecker street, which he will sell 
<br/>at prices unusually low.		
<br/>J. P. having been actively engaged in the business tor the last twen-
<br/>ty years, and, for a large portion of that time manufacturing for two
<br/>of the largest Music Stores in the city, feels warranted in saying that
<br/>his instruments will bear a favorable comparison with those of the
<br/>best makers in this country or Europe, and that they contain all the
<br/>real improvements of the day.
<br/>Second hand Pianos Bought, Sold and Exchanged, also Tuned and
<br/>Repaired.
<br/>New York, April 23d, 1845.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PIANO FORTES.</div> 
         <div class="ab">The Subscribers, while return-
<br/>ing thanks to their numerous friends and to the public, would, at
<br/>the same time call attention to their Stock of Instruments, of six and
<br/>seven octaves, just finished, in elegant Rosewood and mahogany cases.
<br/>The subscribers, from their long experience in every department of
<br/>the business, have been enabled to add several important improvements
<br/>to the action, so that their Instruments, they feel assured will prove,
<br/>upon examination, equal to any in the market.
<br/>STODART &amp; DUNHAM, 361 Broadway.
<br/>Manufactory, 13th st., between 3d and 4th Avenues.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">the boehm flute.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">NEW INVENTION.
<br/>Adopted at the Royal Academy of Music, London, the Conservato-
<br/>ire at Paris, and the Principal Musical Institutions in Europe.
<br/>MR. LARRABEE, Manufacturer of the ‘Boehm Flute,’
<br/>110 Fulton St. N. Y., anxious to introduce to the Amateurs of
<br/>this city the above Imported Invention, which has been so enthusi-
<br/>astically received and generally used by the most distinguished Eu-
<br/>ropean artists, feels happy in being able to place before them the
<br/>following testimonial to its merits, signed by two of the most distin-
<br/>guished of our resident Artists.
<br/>We hereby testify to the excellence of the Boehm Flute, as manufac-
<br/>tured by Mr. J. D. Larrabee; to the beauty of its tone, the perfec-
<br/>tion of its tune, and the simplicity of its fingering, which renders
<br/>a brilliant execution comparatively easy.
<br/>Philip Ernst, (who has already introduced it
<br/>successfully among his pupils.)
<br/>John A. Kyle, Principal Flute of the Philhar-
<br/>monic Society, and Italian Opera, Professor and Teacher of the Boehm
<br/>Flute, 41 Forsyth st. New York.
<br/>Amateurs and Professors are requested to call at the manufactory
<br/>110 Fulton st. and judge for themselves.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">VANDENHOFF’S ELOCUTION.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">SECOND EDITION.—This valuable work is being
<br/> introduced into a large number of the best Schools in the City and
<br/>Country.
<br/>It only needs to be generally known to become universally estab-
<br/>lished.
<br/>Testimonials are received from every quarter.
<br/>From Rev. R. F. Burnham, Rector of St. Paul’s Church, Hoboken.
<br/>“ Having seen with much pleasure, a second edition, by your house,
<br/>of “ A Plain System of Elocution,” I beg leave to express to you my
<br/>opinion of the high merit of that work.
<br/>Its title is in keeping with the plan pursued in the book; a rare fact
<br/>in this age of making many books. In the work may be found what
<br/>this age needs—a System of Elocution, that presents to the learner
<br/>something tangible; and that combines meaning with beauty, and
<br/>beauty with force.
<br/>I hereby express the opinion that the Principals of Seminaries of
<br/>Learning would benefit the department of Elocution, by the introduc-
<br/>tion of Mr. Vandenhoff's System.”
<br/>C. SHEPARD, Publisher,
  <br/>191 Broadway, opposite John-street.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div class="columnbreak"/>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">GREAT REDUCTION IN PRICE.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">THE FIRST PREMIUM A WARDED FIVE YE A RS BY THE AMERICAN INSTI-
<br/>TUTE FOR THE BEST SPECIMEN OF OFF-HAND PENMANSHIP.
<br/>GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,
<br/>No. 289 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
<br/>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercan-
<br/>tile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
<br/>in 10 lessons of 1 hour each.
<br/>Double entry Book-keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough course
<br/>of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and Sta-
<br/>tionery. Payable at the commencement.
<br/>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 7 P. M., daily, for gentlemen,
<br/>and from 11 to 1 o’clock, for ladies. Private instruction given.
<br/>For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
<br/>Price Five Dollars.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">PAINE AND BURGESS,</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">62 JOHN STREET, N. Y.,
<br/>ARE just sending to press a New Series of Choice
<br/>Works, selected from the Prose Literature of Italy. Translated
<br/>and Edited by Edwards Lester, U. S. Consul at Genoa, auther of the
<br/> "Glory and Shame of England,” &amp;c., &amp;c. This series will be made
<br/>up of original translations of the best works of the best Italian writers,
<br/>with original notes and sketches in illustration of the Genius, the Lives
<br/>and Times of the Authors. Five vols. are ready for the Press.
<br/>1. Ettore Fieramosca, or the Challenge of Barletta, an Historical
<br/>Romance of the Times of the Medici, by Agegbio.
<br/>2 and 3, The Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli.
<br/>4. The Autobiography of Alfieri.
<br/>These numbers will be issued in quick succession, in beautiful style,
<br/>and sold for fifty cents per volume. The object of this series is to
<br/>make known to the American people the Literature of Italy.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="ab">TO THE EDITOR OF THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
<br/>SIR —WE WILL THANK YOU TO CAUTION
<br/> the public against a set of imposters who are calling upon our cus-
<br/>tomers, asserting that they are engaged by us in the capacity of agents.
<br/>In several instances they have succeeded in obtaining orders. But
<br/>when the goods are delivered great dissatisfaction has been given by
<br/>the infamous and utterly base imitations. But still persisting that the
<br/>cards are our manufacture, they too often succeed in foisting them
<br/>upon the unsuspecting. We ourselves would strenuously caution the
<br/>said parties that, should they persist after this notice, we will try what
<br/>effect a State Prison will have upon them.
<br/>We are, Sir, Yours most obl’y.
<br/>J. B. CAREY &amp; CO ,
<br/>Ornamental Show Card Manufacturers,
<br/>34 Beckman street, (late 323 Broadway.)
<br/>An agent wanted for New York City. Also one for New York State
<br/>—whose name will be published as our authorized agent.</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">BERTINI’S METHOD FOR THE PIANO.</div>
         <br/>
         <p>THIS is the only thorough, complete and progressive work
<br/>yet published in this country. Where pupils have used this me-
<br/>thod, the most rapid advancement has been observed in all cases.
<br/>The most prominent feature of this work is that the lessons, exerci-
<br/>ses, scales and studies are given in such progressive order, that they
<br/>enlist the interest of pupils, and carry them almost imperceptibly
<br/>through those mechanical difficulties which, otherwise, are too often
<br/>made irksome in other instruction books. The time has arrived when
<br/>a superficial knowledge of the Piano is of but little account, and it is
<br/>only by the study of such methods us Bertini’s that pupils will be ena-
<br/>bled to read music with facility, and at the same time become good
<br/>musicians.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>This method commences in the most plain and simple manner ; the
<br/>rudiments of music being given and illustrated at the same time, and
<br/>each lesson is fully explained by marginal notes on the same page.</p>
         <br/>
         <p>The publishers are in possession of the highest recommendations
<br/>from professional gentlemen, who speak of the superior merits of
<br/>Bertini’s Method over all others yet published in this country, most
<br/>of them having used the foreign copies previously. It will only be
<br/>necessary to give a few of the names in the principal cities.</p>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">BOSTON	NEw-York.
<br/>Messr. G. J. Webb,	Messrs. H. C. Timm,
<br/>J. G. Maeder,	W. Alpers,
<br/>H.T. Hach,	U. C. Hill,
<br/>E. L. White,	F. H. Brcwn,
<br/>David Paine,	Philadelphia.
<br/>A Kurek,	B. C. Cross,
<br/>T. B. Moses.	Joseph Duggan.
<br/>Albany—O. J. Shaw.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">Professors and Teachers are respectfully invited to examine the
<br/>work. American edition published by E. H. WADE and W. H.
<br/>OAKES, 197 Washington street. Boston</div>
      </div>
      <br/>
      <div>
         <div class="head">AGENTS FOR THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.</div>
         <br/>
         <div class="ab">Redding &amp; Co.....................Boston, Mass.
<br/>Colon &amp; Adriance,................Philadelphia, Pa.
<br/>R. G. H. Huntington, ...... Hartford, Ct.
<br/>Georoe Jones.............. . Albany, N. Y.
<br/>Thomas H. Pease..................New-Haven, Ct.
<br/>L.	Willard,.....................Troy.
<br/>M.	Baullemet,...................Mobile, Al.
  <br/>J. C. Morgan, .	. . New Orleans.</div>
      </div>
        </div>
   <div class="back">
          <a href="#a001"/>
      <div class="note" id="n001"> And the angel Israfel, whose heart-strings are a lute, and who has the
            weetest voice of all God’s creatures.—SALE's KORAN.</div>
        </div>
</div>
