<div>
   <div class="issueId"></div>
   <div class="front">
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      
      <div>
         <p>﻿TEE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            VOL. 1.	NEW YORK, SATURDAY, JANUARY 4, 1845.	N° 1.
            
         </p>
         <p>Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by Variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</p>
         <p>Locke.
            INTRODUCTORY.
            
         </p>
         <p>There is but one way of coming into the world, says Dean
            Swift, although there are a great many ways of going out of it,
            and we wish there were but one way of coming before the public in a newspaper for the first time ; that we might be spared the possibility of a blunder in our first appearance, by following in the line of safe precedents. But since we are left
            to our own discretion, and have no kind friend to take us by
            the hand and present us to our dear friend, the Public, we
            will tell our own story as shortly as possible.
         </p>
         <p>It is not improbable that somebody may object to our
            name, and exclaim with Milton’s Stall-reader,
            Bless us, what a word on
            A title page is this!
            
         </p>
         <p>but we have chosen it for the sake of individuality,andbecause it
            is indigenous, and furthermore is indicative of the spirit which
            we intend shall characterise our paper. Broadway is confessedly the finest street in the first city of the New World. It is
            the great artery through which flows the best blood of our system. All the elegance of our continent permeates through it.
            If there is a handsome equipage set up, its first appearance is
            made in Broadway. The most elegant shops in the City line
            its sides ; the finest buildings are found there, and all fashions exhibit their first gloss upon its sidewalks. Although
            it has a character of its own, the traveller often forgets himself in walking through it, and imagines himself in London
            or Paris. Wall street pours its wealth into its broad channel, and all the dealers in intellectual works are here centered ; every exhibition of art is found here, and the largest caravanseries in the world border upon it. Its pavement has
            been trod by every distinguished man that has visited our
            continent; those who travel through it are refreshed by the
            most magnificent fountains in the world. It has a sunny
            side too, where we have opened our office of delivery. It terminates at one end in the finest square in the city, doubtless in
            the Union, and at the other in the Battery, unrivalled for its
            entire beauty, by any marine parade in the world. So travellers
            say. For ourselves, we have seen many in the old world
            and the new, but none that equal it. As Paris is France,
            and London, England; so is Broadway, New York; and
            New York is fast becoming, if she be not already, America,
            in spite of South Carolina and Boston.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have little hope of making our paper among other
            journals, what Broadway is among other streets, but we
            shall do what we can to render it in some degree worthy of
            the name that we have given it. We are fully aware that
            “ we have a reasonable quantity of giants” to encounter in our
            undertaking, and that we have to rely more upon good intentions than good weapons to overcome them, but it must be an
            unreasonably tall giant that shall overcome our perseverance
            in the end.
         </p>
         <p>In the conduct of our paper we shall follow the advice of Iso-
            crates to his pupils, and “ study the people,” but rather with a
            
         </p>
         <p>view to profit them than ourselves. We have a prodigious respect for the people, tempered with no small amount of love,
            but we think with Falstaff, “ that either well-bearing, or ignorant carriage, is caught, as men take diseases, one of another ; therefore it is well to take heed of our company;" and
            we shall chose rather to talk to the people than with them.
            We do not arrogate to ourselves the character of a reformer;
            yet we hope to reform some of the abuses which we sometimes hear spoken of as existing among us. The husbandman who never pulls up a weed in his garden can never
            hope to see them all removed from his enclosures.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We shall endeavor to make our paper entirely original,—
            and, instead of the effete vapors of English Magazines,
            which have heretofore been the chief filling of our weekly
            journals, give such homely thoughts as may be generated
            among us; and if our columns do not smack of home, it
            will be because “ our spirits have been so married in conjunction with the participation of foreign society,” that we
            cannot procure a divorce.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As we are entirely disconnected with any of the traders
            in literature, and have no personal friends among our literary producers,—saving an illustrious name or two, in Mr.
            Griswold’s Pantheon—we have no inducements to indulge
            in the luxury of puffing; but we entertain so kindly a feeling towards the whole brood of unfortunates, called American authors, that we can never find it in our hearts to utter
            an ill word of them, or to treat them otherwise than with
            honest candor.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Although our daily and weekly press often contain admirable criticisms on literature and art, with the spirit of a
            quarterly review compressed into the limits of a half column,
            yet these are rather accidental than a general rule, and the
            public, in many cases, must submit to the actual cautery of
            buying and reading a new book before they can judge of its
            quality. There are too many good things to be had for
            time and money, to waste these precious commodities on
            uncertain productions. A sixpence worth of honest criticism will often save a dollar, or an hour, from being misspent.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We shall devote a good part of our columns to the interests of American Art; especially to Painting and Architecture,—and shall give specimens of American designs, in
            both departments, as often as they can be procured of sufficient merit to entitle them to notice.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Lecture room, the Concert, and the Theatre, will all
            be dealt with ; and though we hoist the signal of no political party, we shall dabble in politics when there is any thing
            in the wind worth heeding.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As the refinement of modem times has given birth to a
            ladies’ literature, which, out of compliment to the sex is
            made as unmeaning as possible, we shall so far conform to
            the complexion of the times as to have a Ladies’ Leaf,
            wherein we shall do our best to be very lady-like and innocent. We can promise all, both ladies and gentlemen, that
            we shall raise no blushes on the cheek of modesty, because
            modest people are not easily put out of countenance; but
            the salacious and foul-minded are always changing colour.
            Our pen has two ends to it, and if we sometimes fail to
         </p>
         <p>
            make an impression with the point, we shall occasionally
            reverse it and tickle with the feather.
            
         </p>
         <p>We hope to receive the aid of true hearted and good people, in our undertaking, not only as subscribers but as contributors ; to the first we will give the worth of their money,
            and to the others the worth of their articles.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As we infringe upon no man’s quarter-section, but have
            squatted upon unoccupied ground, we hope to be allowed
            the privilege of sowing our dragon’s teeth in peace ; but
            if we are attacked, the enemy may expect an army of
            armed sentences falling upon his flank or rear, at all manner
            of unseasonable periods. But as the eye can see every thing
            but itself, so an Editor is very likely to see every body’s
            mistakes but his own, and we shall certainly quarrel with
            no good-natured friend who reminds us of our slips.
         </p>
         <p>REVIEWS.
            
         </p>
         <p>" An author may be considered as a merciful substitute to the legislature. He acts, not by punishing crimes, but by preventing them. If
            the author be, therefore, still so necessary among us, let us treat him
            with proper consideration, as a child of the public; and indeed a
            child of the public he is in all aspects; for while so well able to direct
            others, how incapable is he frequently found of guiding himself.”
         </p>
         <p>Mind among the Spindi.es. [Republished from Charles Knight’s
            weekly volumes.] Boston, Jordan, Swift, &amp; Wiley, 1845.
            
         </p>
         <p>Our first review shall be of an American author, what
            one we will determine by lot, to save us from a partial 
            feeling in the outset, when we have concluded our prefatory 
            remarks. There should be no sectional feelings in literature
            or art. No political barriers or geographical distinctions can
            prevent our sympathies from embracing the whole world of
            mind; all the malice of ill-natured spirits that has been exerted the last half century, to make a gap between British
            and American minds, has been without the slightest effect.
            The authors of Great Britain are still our bosom friends, and
            such of our own authors as find their way to London, are
            kindly entreated, in spite of the Foreign Quarterly and Mrs.
            Trollope. We said a good many severe things, even malicious, about Dickens, as soon as he left us; but we seized
            on his Christmas Carol with as hearty a good will as old
            Scrooge poked his timid clerk in the ribs the morning
            after Christmas. It is the vainest of all efforts to fight
            against genius ; no national prejudices are strong enough to
            contend with it; no laws can affect it; no earthly power
            control it. Mankind will gladly receive its productions, let
            them come whence they will. What matters it to us
            that Frederika Bremer is a Swede, inhabiting a country of
            which we hardly knew anything until we heard of it from
            her; she is our dear friend, and her name is often heard at
            our firesides, as though she were our cousin, or next door
            neighbour; and Mary Howitt’s name is affectionately spoken
            by thousands in our country, who only know her by her
            pretty little stories; and her country people, too, are as
            fond of Mary Clavers, and Lydia Maria Child, as though they
            were the daughters of English soil. Many an Englishman,
            who thinks he does his country a service in speaking ill of
            America, entertains a feeling for Washington Irving, as for
            a kinsman. And we, who think it a proof of patriotism to
            abuse the land of our fathers, are ever on the alert to catch
            every ray of light that radiates from the minds of its people.
            We appear to feel no animosities against the better part of
            men, which is their mind, but only against their poor perishable bodies, which, if let alone, would soon enough come to
            naught of themselves.
         </p>
         <p>It would ill become us, then, in the outset of our career as
            reviewers, to enter upon our duty with a narrow feeling of
            
         </p>
         <p>partiality for our own authors, to the unjust exclusion of foreigners, from our sympathies. But this liberal feeling will
            compel us to give our first attention and widest space to the
            authors of our own country, because they have the greatest
            odds to contend with, having a forestalled opinion against
            them in the minds of their own countrymen, and the best
            paid and most fertile authors in the world for competitors,
            whose works are imported scot free to our markets.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>An American author is one of those rare creatures, who
            think more seriously of the welfare of others, than of their
            own. He is prima facie a good fellow; and as a matter of
            course, an utterer of inspired thoughts ; for having no inducements to exertion, he speaks because he must. He knows no
            law but the law of his own being, like the wind and the rain,
            the dew and the lightning. He is, because he is. There are
            no artificial stimulants to bring him out. No offers from booksellers ; no demands from the public. His lightnings are produced by no machinery, but dart from the clouds of his imagination, because they will; they may not strike, nor dazzle
            always; but they flash of their own accord, without the aid
            of saltpetre or charcoal. They who sit in his light, think
            as little of his sufferings, from which they derive their enjoyments, as we do of the leviathan that was slaughtered in
            Coromandel, to afford us the luxury of spermaceti.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>How different is the lot of the British author, who seizes
            his pen as Nelson did his sword, with thoughts of Westminster Abbey or a peerage. We have not even a “ corner” for
            our poets ; they are shoved aside entirely, unless one of their
            number, like Mr. Griswold, erects a Pantheon for the whole
            that he may have a niche for himself.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Numerous as English authors are, it is a marvel, considerring the hot-bed in which they are forced, that their number
            should be so small. With such splendid rewards as are
            showered upon their poets and romancers, it is a wonder
            that the whole nation does not give itself up to literature.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Considering the rewards of authors with us, the appearance of even one, would be proof of national superiority.
            In England authors are sure of something. If not a peerage,
            a baronetage; if not that, knighthood, a pension, a consulship, employment in a public office, or a guinea a sheet at
            least. If none of these, they are sure to be lionized, and reviewed, and read, and illustrated, and at last put into Westminster Abbey. We must confess that some of these honors
            have not a very dazzling aspect seen from our point of observation, at the distance of three thousand miles, but they
            appear to have a strong influence upon British minds.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have seen the British Parliament engaged day after
            day, debating the subject of copyright, and grave statesmen
            and great orators advocating the rights of an author to the
            control of his own productions ; and we have seen our own
            national Legislature receive numerous petitions on the same
            subject, from different parts of the Union, and treat them
            with silent contempt. At the first session of the present
            Congress there were several petitions, signed by some of the
            best men in the nation, presented to both houses, praying for
            an international copyright, received in silence, referred to a
            committee, and never heard of again.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In France and in Germany, the most reliable instrument
            to carve a fortune with, or cut a road to preferment, is the
            pen; with us it is a magnet in the hands of those who use it,
            to draw upon them contempt and poverty.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The only author upon whom our Government, or the Nation, has bestowed an office, is Mr. Irving And among all
            of our foreign ambassadors, what one could be more safely
            trusted with the interests of the Republic ? And among all of
            our literary men, what one could have so dishonored his
         </p>
         <p>
            country at a foreign court, as our bullying and incompetent
            ambassador to Mexico ?
            
         </p>
         <p>The appointment of Mr. Irving was the “ lone star”of Mr
            Tyler’s administration; we would that the appointment of
            Mr. Shannon were the sole mistake. Mr. Everett is a literary man, though not an author; but he is a politician, and
            he gained his appointment by his political, which with us
            means party services. The same was the case with Bancroft, whose history would have done but little towards giving him a collectorship without his politics.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The whole nation was in a ferment a few months since,
            and every paper in the country had something to say about
            the hostility of John Bull, at the appearance in an English
            Review of an article that questioned the originality of some
            of the Abderites in Mr. Griswold’s collection. And the
            Thunderer of the great North American Review, with the
            aid of a Harvard Professor, retaliated in an article which
            gave a dreadful scorching to a score or two of British poets
            whose works had been a century or more forgotten. These
            were hopeful signs, as the philanthropists say, that public
            sentiment was coming right upon an important subject; and
            that the nation would at last manifest a sufficient interest in
            her authors to enable them to compete with Englishmen on
            equal terms, by modifying our copyright law, so that the
            present system of literary piracy should be abolished. But
            the nation was content to rail at John Bull, and let her own
            authors sink or swim, as they could.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Paulding, another of our authors who has had the
            rare fortune to receive an appointment from our Government,
            also wrote a reply to the famous Review of our poets in
            the Foreign Quarterly ; in which he not only made himself
            appear exceedingly ridiculous, but exceedingly dishonest, by
            gravely stating as facts, idle newspaper reports, which were
            pure inventions. The obnoxious article in the Foreign Quarterly was written in a bad spirit, beyond question; but
            what then, as honest Fluellen says;
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ If the enemy is an ass, and a fool, and a prating coxcomb, is it meet, think you, that we should also, look you,
            be an ass, and a fool, and a prating coxcomb ? In your conscience, now ?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It ill became our authors to manifest an angry spirit at
            the appearance of a Review unfavorable to some of them,
            from an English pen; since, in many instances, they have
            been indebted to a British review for an introduction to
            their own countrymen ; and we could name several who
            had to wait for a foreign endorsement before they could pass
            current at home.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We put our hand upon a genuine American book lying
            before us, which owes its publication in London, and its republication here, to the generous and hearty commendations
            bestowed upon it by Mr. Dickens and Harriet Martineau.
            It is a book of which the whole country should be proud ;
            for if the Northern slaves—as the South Carolina statesmen
            call our honest laborers, who live by the sweat of their own
            brows—can produce a work like this, what may we not
            expect from our educated classes who have leisure to register their thoughts and observations. Among all the vehement abusers of the Foreign Quarterly and Mr. Dickens, we
            fear that there are not many who can say of this modest
            book as he has said of it in his Notes; “ I brought away
            from Lowell four hundred good solid pages,which I have read
            from beginning to end. Of the merits of the Lowell Offering, as a literary production, I will only observe, putting
            entirely out of sight the fact of these articles having been
            written by these girls, after the arduous labors of the day,
            that it will compare advantageously with a great many
         </p>
         <p>English Annuals.”
            
         </p>
         <p>Ought not such hearty good feeling as this, expressed
            towards an American production which Americans themselves hardly knew the existence of, to have been enough
            to outweigh the ill opinions of a dozen such articles as that
            in the Foreign Quarterly Review ?	
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mind among the Spindles, is a selection of thirty-eight
            articles, mostly prose, from the Lowell Offering. It was
            published by Charles Knight, in London, among his weekly
            volumes, with an introductory letter by Harriet Martineau,
            and is now republished in Boston, with the introduction of
            the English editor, as a recommendation to the American
            reader.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>These papers must necessarily possess an interest for the
            English reader which they do not for us; part of this interest arises from wonder that the female operatives in a Cotton
            mill should be able, not only to write at all, but have leisure
            and ability to write in a manner that will compare favourably with English Annuals ; and partly from the freshness of
            the life described, so new to an English reader, but so familiar with us. But they possess sufficient novelty in this
            meridian to recommend them to notice, and to many of our
            Broadway girls they will present scenes as new as to an
            English countess. Every woman in America should possess
            a copy of this modest little book, for the honor of her
            sex.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Although the articles are the productions of different
            minds, they are all distinguished by an earnest simplicity
            and an entire absence of attempt at fine writing, which we
            could hardly have looked for in the productions of so great
            a number of young women in any condition of life.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is true that the Lowell Offering was often spoken of a
            year or two ago by people who looked upon a factory girl
            who could write, with some such feelings as they would
            have looked upon a learned pig, and that the papers were
            favorably noticed by the North American Review, and some
            other literary periodicals ; but the present publication is owing entirely to the favorable reception which the work has
            received in England.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have room but for one extract, an exceedingly
            simple but vivid description of a sugar-bee, which will
            make the visitors of Thompson and Weller’s candy saloon
            have watery mouths as they read the account of making
            our forest confectionary.
         </p>
         <p>The Sugar-making Excursion.
            
         </p>
         <p>It was on a beautiful morning in the month of March,
            (one of those mornings so exhilarating that they make even
            age and decrepitude long for a ramble,) that friend H. called
            to invite me to visit his sugar lot—as he called it—in company with the party which, in the preceding summer, visited
            Moose Mountain upon the whortleberry excursion. It was
            with the pleasure generally experienced in revisiting former
            scenes, in quest of novelty and to revive impressions and
            friendships, that our party set out for this second visit to
            Moose Mountain.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A pleasant sleigh-ride of four or five miles, brought us
            safely to the domicile of friend H., who had reached home
            an hour previously, and was prepared to pilot us to his sugar camp. “ Before we go,” said he, “ you must one and
            all step within doors, and warm your stomachs with some
            gingered cider.” We complied with his request, and after
            a little social chat with Mrs. H., who welcomed us with a
            cordiality not to be surpassed, and expressed many a kind
            wish that we might spend the day agreeably, we made for
            the sugar camp, preceded by friend H., who walked by the
            side of his sleigh, which appeared to be well loaded, and
            which he steadied with the greatest care at every uneven
            place in the path.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Arrived at the camp, we found two huge iron kettles suspended on a pole, which was supported by crotched stakes,
            driven in the ground, and each half full of boiling syrup.
            This was made by boiling down the sap, which was gath-
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>ered from troughs that were placed under spouts which
            Were driven into rock-maple trees, an incision being first
            made in the tree with an auger. Friend H. told us that it
            had taken more than two barrels of sap to make what syrup
            each kettle contained. A steady fire of oak bark was burning underneath the kettles, and the boys and girls, friend
            H.’s sons and daughters, were busily engaged in stirring the
            syrup, replenishing the fire, &amp;c.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Abigail, the eldest daughter, went to her father’s sleigh,
            and taking out a large rundlet, which might contain two or
            three gallons, poured the contents into a couple of pails.
            This we perceived was milk, and as she raised one of the
            pails to empty the contents into the kettles, her father called out, “ Ho, Abigail! hast thee strained the milk?” “Yes,
            father,” said Abigail.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Well,” said friend H., with a chuckle, “ Abigail understands what she is about, as well as her mother would;
            and I’ll warrant Hannah to make better maple-sugar than
            any other woman in New England, or in the whole United
            States—and you will agree with me in that, after that sugar
            is turned off and cooled.” Abigail turned to her work,
            emptied the milk into the kettles, and then stirred their contents well together, and put some bark on the fire.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Come, Jemima,” said Henry L., “let us try to assist
            Abigail a little, and perhaps we shall learn to make sugar
            ourselves; and who knows but what she will give us a
            ' gob’ to carry home as a specimen to show our friends ; and
            besides, it is possible that we may have to make sugar
            ourselves at some time or other ; and even if we do not, it
            will never do us any harm to know how the thing is done.”
            Abigail furnished us each with a large brass scummer, and
            instructed us to take off the scum as it arose, and put it into
            the pails ; and Henry called two others of our party to come
            and hold the pails.
         </p>
         <p>“ But tell me, Abigail,” said Henry, with a roguish leer,
            “ was that milk really intended for whitening the sugar ?”
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Yes,” said Abigail with all the simplicity of a Quakeress, “ for thee must know that the milk will all rise in a
            scum, and with it every particle of dirt or dust which may
            have found its way into the kettles.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Abigail made a second visit to her father’s sleigh, accompanied by her little brother, and brought from thence a large
            tin baker, and placed it before the fire. Her brother brought
            a peck measure two-thirds full of potatoes, which Abigail
            put into the baker, and leaving them to their fate, returned
            to the sleigh, and with her brother’s assistence carried several parcels, neatly done up in white napkins, into a little
            log hut of some fifteen feet square, with a shed roof made of
            slabs. We began to fancy that we were to have an Irish
            lunch. Henry took a sly peep into the hut when we first
            arrived, and he declared there was nothing inside, save some
            squared logs, which were placed back against the walls, and
            which he supposed were intended for seats. But he was
            mistaken in thinking that seats were every convenience
            which the building contained,—as will presently be shown.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Abigail and her brother had been absent something like
            half an hour, and friend H. had in the meantime busied himself in gathering sap, and putting it in some barrels hard by.
            The kettles were clear from scum, and their contents were
            bubbling like soap. The fire was burning cheerfully, the
            company all chatting merrily, and a peep into the baker told
            that the potatoes were cooked.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Abigail and her brother came, and taking up the baker,
            carried it inside the building, but soon returned, and placed
            it again before the fire. Then she called to her father, who
            came and invited us to go and take dinner.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We obeyed the summons; but how were we surprised,
            when we saw how neatly arranged was every thing. The
            walls of the building were ceiled around with boards, and
            side tables fastened to them, which could be raised or let
            down at pleasure, being but pieces of boards fastened with
            leather hinges and a prop underneath. The tables were
            covered with napkins, white as the driven snow, and loaded
            with cold ham, neat’s tongue, pickles, bread, apple sauce,
            preserves, dough-nuts, butter, cheese, and potatoes—without
            which a Yankee dinner is never complete. For beverage,
            there was chocolate, which was made over a fire in the building—there being a rock chimney in one comer. “ Now,
            neighbors,” said friend H., “ if you will but seat yourselves
            on these squared logs, and put up with these rude accommodations, you will do me a favor. We might have had
            our dinner at the house, but I thought that it would be a
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>novelty, and afford more amusement to have it in this little
            hut which I built to shelter us from what stormy weather we
            might have in the season of making sugar.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We arranged ourselves round the room, and right merry
            were we, for friend H.’s lively chat did not suffer us to be
            otherwise. He recapitulated to us the manner of his life
            while a bachelor ; the many bear fights which he had had ;
            told us how many bears he had killled ; how a she-bear denned in his rock dwelling the first winter after he commenced
            clearing his land—he having returned home to his father’s
            to attend school; how, when he returned in the spring, he
            killed her two cubs, and afterwards the old bear, and made
            his Hannah a present of their skins to make a muff and tippet ; also his courtship, marriage, &amp;c.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the midst of dinner, Abigail came in with some hot
            mince-pies, which had been heating in the baker before the
            fire out of doors, and which said much in praise of Mrs. H.’s
            cookery.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We had finished eating and were chatting as merrily as
            might be, when one of the little boys called from without,
            “Father, the sugar has grained.” We immediately went
            out, and found one of the boys stirring some sugar in a bowl
            to cool it. The fire was raked from beneath the kettles,
            and Abigail and her eldest brother were stirring their contents with all haste. Friend H. put a pole within the bail
            of one of the kettles, and raised it up, which enabled two of
            the company to take the other down, and having placed it in
            the snow, they assisted friend H. to take down the other;
            and while we lent a helping hand to stir and cool the sugar,
            friend H.’s children eat their dinners, cleared away the tables,
            put what fragments were left into their father’s sleigh, together with the dinner dishes, tin baker, rundlet, and the
            pails of scum, which were to be carried home for the swine.
            A firkin was also put into the sleigh: and after the sugar
            was sufficiently cool, it was put into the firkin, and covered
            up with great care.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>After this we spent a short time promenading around the
            rock-maple grove, if leafless trees can be called a grove. A
            large sap trough, which was very neatly made, struck my
            fancy, and friend H. said he would make me a present of it
            for a cradle. This afforded a subject for mirth. Friend H.
            said we must not ridicule the idea of having sap-troughs
            for cradles ; for that was touching quality, as his eldest child
            had been rocked many an hour in a sap-trough, beneath the
            shade of a tree, while his wife sat beside it knitting, and he
            was hard by, hoeing corn.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Soon we were on our way to friend H.’s house, which we
            all reached in safety ; and where we spent an agreeable evening, eating maple sugar, apples, beech-nuts, &amp;c. We also
            had tea about eight o’clock which was accompanied by every desirable luxury—after which we started for home.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As we were about taking leave, Abigail made each of us
            a present of a cake of sugar, which was cooled in a tin heart.
            —“ Heigh ho !” said Henry L., “ how lucky ! We have had
            an agreeable visit, a bountiful feast—have learned how to
            make sugar, and have all got sweethearts!”
         </p>
         <p>We went home, blessing our stars and the hospitality of
            our Quaker friends.
            
         </p>
         <p>I cannot close without telling the reader, that the sugar
            which was that day made was nearly as white as loaf-sugar, and tasted much better.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Drama of Exile, other Poems : By Elizabeth Barrett
            Barrett, Author of “ The Seraphim,” and other Poems. New York:
            Henry G. Langley
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“A well-bred man,” says Sir James Puckle, in his “Gray
            Cap for a Green Head,” “ will never give himself the liberty
            to speak ill of women.” We emphasize the “man.” Setting aside, for the present, certain rare commentators and
            compilers of the species G—, —creatures neither precisely
            men, women, nor Mary Wollstonecraft’s—setting these
            aside as unclassifiable, we may observe that the race of
            critics are masculine—men. With the exception, perhaps,
            of Mrs. Anne Royal, we can call to mind no female who
            has occupied, even temporarily, the Zoilus throne. And
            this, the Salic law, is an evil; for the inherent chivalry of
            the critical man renders it not only an unpleasant task to
            him “to speak ill of a woman,” (and a woman and her
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>book are identical,) but an almost impossible task not to laud
            her ad nauseam. In general, therefore, it is the unhappy
            lot of the authoress to be subjected, time after time, to the
            downright degradation of mere puffery. On her own side
            of the Atlantic, Miss Barrett has indeed, in one instance at
            least, escaped the infliction of this lamentable contumely
            and wrong; but if she had been really solicitous of its infliction in America, she could not have adopted a more effectual
            plan than that of saying a few words about “the great
            American people,” in an American edition of her work, published under the superintendence of an American author.*
            Of the innumerable “ native ” notices of “ The Drama of
            Exile,” which have come under our observation, we can
            call to mind not one in which there is any thing more remarkable than the critic’s dogged determination to find
            nothing barren, from Beersheba to Dan. Another in the
            " Democratic Review ” has proceeded so far, it is true,
            as to venture a very delicate insinuation to the effect that
            the poetess “ will not fail to speak her mind though it bring
            upon her a bad rhyme;" beyond this, nobody has proceeded: and as for the elaborate paper in the new Whig
            Monthly, all that any body can say or think, and all that
            Miss Barrett can feel respecting it is, that it is an eulogy
            as well written as it is an insult well intended. Now
            of all the friends of the fair author, we doubt whether one
            exists, with more profound—with more enthusiastic reverence and admiration of her genius, than the writer of these
            words. And it is for this very reason, beyond all others
            that he intends to speak of her the truth. Our chief regret
            is, nevertheless, that the limits of this “ Journal” will preclude the possibility of our speaking this truth so fully, and
            so much in detail, as we could wish. By far the most valuable criticism that we, or that any one could give, of the
            volumes now lying before us, would be the quotation of
            three fourths of their contents. But we have this advantage
            —that the work has been long published, and almost universally read—and thus, in some measure, we may proceed,
            concisely, as if the text of our context, were an understood thing.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In her preface to this, the “ American edition” of her
            late poems, Miss Barrett, speaking of the Drama of Exile,
            says:—“ I decided on publishing it, after considerable hesitation and doubt. Its subject rather fastened on me than
            was chosen ; and the form, approaching the model of the
            Greek tragedy, shaped itself under my hand rather by force
            of pleasure than of design. But when the compositional
            excitement had subsided, I felt afraid of my position. My
            own object was the new and strange experiment of the
            fallen Humanity, as it went forth from Paradise into the
            Wilderness, with a peculiar reference to Eve’s allotted grief,
            which, considering that self-sacrifice belonged to her womanhood, and the consciousness of being the organ of the Fall
            to her offence, appeared to me imperfectly apprehended
            hitherto, and more expressible by a woman than by a man. ’
            In this abstract announcement of the theme, it is difficult to
            understand the ground of the poet’s hesitation to publish ;
            for the theme in itself seems admirably adapted to the pur-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>* We are sorry to notice, in the American edition, a multitude of typographical errors, many of which affect the sense, and should therefore be
            corrected in a second impression, if called for. How far they are chargeable
            to the London copy, we are not prepared to say. “ Froze,” for instance, is
            printed “ frore.” "Foregone,” throughout, is printed “ forgone.” “ Wordless ” is printed “ worldless”—“worldly," “wordly”—“spilt,” “split,"
            etc., etc.,—while transpositions, false accents, and mis-punctuations abound.
            We indicate a few pages on which such inadvertences are to be discovered.
            Vol. 1—23, 26, 37, 45, 53, 56, 80, 166, 174, 180, 185, 251. Vol 2—109, 114,
            240, 247, 253,272.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>poses of the closet drama. The poet, nevertheless, is, very
            properly, conscious of failure—a failure which occurs not in
            the general, but in the particular conception, and which
            must be placed to the account of “ the model of the Greek
            tragedies.” The Greek tragedies had and even have high
            merits; but we act wisely in now substituting for the external and typified human sympathy of the antique Chorus, a
            direct, internal, living and moving sympathy itself; and
            although AEschylus might have done service as “a model,’
            to either Euripides or Sophocles, yet were Sophocles and
            Euripides in London to-day, they would, perhaps, while
            granting a certain formless and shadowy grandeur, indulge
            a quiet smile at the shallowness and uncouthness of that
            Art, which, in the old amphitheatres, had beguiled them
            into applause of the OEdipus at Colonos.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It would have been better for Miss Barrett if, throwing
            herself independently upon her own very extraordinary resources, and forgetting that a Greek had ever lived, she had
            involved her Eve in a series of adventures merely natural,
            or if not this, of adventures preternatural within the limits
            of at least a conceivable relation—a relation of matter to
            spirit and spirit to matter, that should have left room for
            something like palpable action and comprehensible emotion
            —that should not have utterly precluded the development
            , of that womanly character which is admitted as the principal object of the poem. As the case actually stands, it is
            only in a few snatches of verbal intercommunication with
            Adam and Lucifer, that we behold her as a woman at all.
            For the rest, she is a mystical something or nothing, enwrapped in a fog of rhapsody about Transfiguration, and the
            Seed, and the Bruising of the Heel, and other talk of a nature that no man ever pretended to understand in plain prose,
            and which, when solar-microscoped into poetry “upon the
            model of the Greek drama,” is about as convincing as the
            Egyptian Lectures of Mr. Silk Buckingham—about as much
            to any purpose under the sun as the hi presto! conjurations
            of Signor Blitz. What are we to make, for example, of
            dramatic colloquy such as this?—the words are those of a
            Chorus of Invisible Angels addressing Adam:
         </p>
         <p>Live, work on, O Earthy !
            
         </p>
         <p>By the Actual’s tension
            Speed the arrow worthy
            Of a pure ascension.
         </p>
         <p>From the low earth round you
            Reach the heights above you ;
            From the stripes that wound you
            Seek the loves that love you !
            God’s divinest burneth plain
            Through the crystal diaphane
            Of our loves that love you.
            
         </p>
         <p>Now we do not mean to assert that, by excessive “ tension” of the intellect, a reader accustomed to the cant of the
            transcendentalists (or of those who degrade an ennobling philosophy by styling themselves such) may not succeed in ferretting from the passage quoted, and indeed from each of
            the thousand similar ones throughout the book, something
            that shall bear the aspect of an absolute idea—but we do
            mean to say first, that, in nine cases out of ten, the thought
            when dug out will be found very poorly to repay the labor
            of the digging;—for it is the nature of thought in general, as
            it is the nature of some ores in particular, to be richest when
            most superficial. And we do mean to say, secondly, that,
            in nineteen cases out of twenty, the reader will suffer the
            most valuable one to remain unmined to all eternity, before
             he will be put to the trouble of digging for it one inch.
            And we do mean to assert, thirdly, that no reader is to be
            condemned for not putting himself to the trouble of digging
            even the one inch; for no writer has the right to impose any
            such necessity upon him. What is worth thinking is distinctly thought: what is distinctly thought, can and should
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>be distinctly expressed, or should not be expressed at all.
            Nevertheless, there is no more appropriate opportunity than
            the present for admitting and maintaining, at once, what has
            never before been either maintained or admitted—that there
            is a justifiable exception to the rule for which we contend.
            It is where the design is to convey the fantastic—not the obscure. To give the idea of the latter we need, as in general,
            the most precise and definitive terms, and those who employ
            other terms but confound obscurity of expression with the
            expression of obscurity. The fantastic in itself, however,—
            phantasm—may be materially furthered in its development
            by the quaint in phraseology:—a proposition which any
            moralist may examine at his leisure for himself.
         </p>
         <p>The “ Drama of Exile” opens with a very palpable bull:
            —" Scene, the outer side of the gate of Eden, shut fast with
            
         </p>
         <p>clouds”—[a scene out of sight!]—“ from the depth of which
            revolves the sword of fire, self-moved. A watch of innumerable angels rank above rank, slopes up from around it to the
            zenith; and the glare cast from their brightness and from
            the sword, extends many miles into the wilderness. Adam
            and Eve are seen in the distance, flying along the glare. The
            angel Gabriel and Lucifer are beside the gate.”—These are
            the “ stage directions” which greet us on the threshold of the
            book. We complain first of the bull: secondly, of the bluefire melo-dramatic aspect of the revolving sword; thirdly, of
            the duplicate nature of the sword, which, if steel, and sufficiently enflamed to do service in burning, would, perhaps,
            have been in no temper to cut; and on the other hand, if
            sufficiently cool to have an edge, would have accomplished
            little in the way of scorching a personage so well accustomed
            to fire and brimstone and all that, as we have very good
            reason to believe Lucifer was. We cannot help objecting,
            too, to the “innumerable angels,” as a force altogether disproportioned to the one enemy to be kept out:—either the
            self-moving sword itself, we think, or the angel Gabriel alone,
            or five or six of the “ innumerable” angels, would have sufficed to keep the devil (or is it Adam ?) outside of the gate—
            which, after all, he might not have been able to discover, on
            account of the clouds.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Far be it from us, however, to dwell irreverently on matters which have venerability in the faith or in the fancy of
            Miss Barrett. We allude to these nidiseries at all—found here
            in the very first paragraph of her poem,—simply by way of
            putting in the clearest light the mass of inconsistency and
            antagonism in which her subject has inextricably involved
            her. She has made allusion to Milton, and no doubt felt secure in her theme (as a theme merely) when she considered
            his “ Paradise Lost.” But even in Milton’s own day, when
            men had the habit of believing all things, the more nonsensical the more readily, and of worshipping, in blind acquiescence, the most preposterous of impossibilities—even then,
            there were not wanting individuals who would have read the
            great epic with more zest, could it have been explained to
            their satisfaction, how and why it was, not only that a snake
            quoted Aristotle’s ethics, and behaved otherwise pretty much
            as he pleased, but that bloody battles were continually being
            fought between bloodless “ innumerable angels,” that found
            no inconvenience in losing a wing one minute and a head the
            next, and if pounded up into puff-paste late in the afternoon,
            were as good “ innumerable angels” as new the next morning, in time to be at reveille roll-call: And now—at the
            present epoch—there are few people who do not occasionally
            think. This is emphatically the thinking age;—indeed it may
            very well be questioned whether mankind ever substantially
            thought before. The fact is, if the “Paradise Lost” were
            written to-day (assuming that it had never been written
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>when it was), not even its eminent, although over-estimated
            merits, would counterbalance, either in the public view, or in
            the opinion of any critic at once intelligent and honest, the
            multitudinous incongruities which are part and parcel of its
            plot.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p> But in the plot of the drama of Miss Barrett it is something
            even worse than incongruity which affronts: —a continuous
            mystical strain of ill-fitting and exaggerated allegory—if, indeed, allegory is not much too respectable a term for it. We
            are called upon, for example, to sympathise in the whimsical
            woes of two Spirits, who, upspringing from the bowels of the
            earth, set immediately to bewailing their miseries in jargon
            such as this:
         </p>
         <p>I am the spirit of the harmless earth;
            God spake me softly out among the stars,
            As softly as a blessing of much worth—
            And then his smile did follow unawares,
            That all things, fashioned, so, for use and duty,
            Might shine anointed with his chrism of beauty—
            Yet I wail!
            I drave on with the worlds exultingly,
            
         </p>
         <p>Obliquely down the Godlight’s gradual fallIndividual aspect and complexity
            Of gyratory orb and interval,
         </p>
         <p>Lost in the fluent motion of delight
            Toward the high ends of Being, beyond Sight—
            Yet I wail!
            
         </p>
         <p>Innumerable other spirits discourse successively after the
            same fashion, each ending every stanza of his lamentation
            with the “yet I wail!” When at length they have fairly
            made an end, Eve touches Adam upon the elbow, and hazards, also, the profound and pathetic observation—“Lo,
            Adam, they wail!”—which is nothing more than the simple
            truth—for they do—and God deliver us from any such wailing again!
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is not our purpose, however, to demonstrate what every
            reader of these volumes will have readily seen self-demonstrated—the utter indefensibility of “The Drama of Exile,”
            considered uniquely, as a work of art. We have none of us
            to be told that a medley of metaphysical recitatives sung
            out of tune, at Adam and Eve, by all manner of inconceivable abstractions, is not exactly the best material for a poem.
            Still it may very well happen that among this material there
            shall be individual passages of great beauty. But should any
            one doubt the possibility, let him be satisfied by a single extract such as follows:
         </p>
         <p>On a mountain peak
            
         </p>
         <p>Half sheathed in primal woods and glittering
            In spasms of awful sunshine, at that hour
            A lion couched,—part raised upon his paws,
         </p>
         <p>With his calm massive face turned full on thine,
            
         </p>
         <p>And his mane listening. When the ended curse
            Left silence in the world, right suddenly
            He sprang up rampant, and stood straight and stiff,
         </p>
         <p>As if the new reality of death
            Were dashed against his eyes,—and roared so fierce,
            (Such thick carnivorous passion in his throat
            Tearing a passage through the wrath and fear)—
            And roared so wild, and smote from all the hills
            Such fast keen echoes crumbling down the vales
            To distant silence,—that the forest beasts,
            
         </p>
         <p>One after one, did mutter a response
            In savage and in sorrowful complaint
            Which trailed along the gorges.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There is an Homeric force here—a vivid picturesqueness
            which all men will appreciate and admire. It is, however,
            the longest quotable passage in the drama, not disfigured
            with blemishes of importance;—although there are many—
            very many passages of a far loftier order of excellence, so
            disfigured, and which, therefore, it would not suit our immediate purpose to extract. The truth is,—and it may be as
            well mentioned at this point as elsewhere—that we are
            not to look in Miss Barrett’s works for any examples of what
            has been occasionally termed “ sustained effort;" for neither
            are there, in any of her poems, any long commendable paragraphs, nor are there any individual compositions which
            will bear the slightest examination as consistent Art-products. Her wild and magnificent genius seems to have con-
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>tented itself with points—to have exhausted itself in flashes;
            —but it is the profusion—the unparalleled number and close
            propinquity of these points and flashes which render her
            book one flame, and justify us in calling her, unhesitatingly,
            the greatest—the most glorious of her sex.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The “ Drama of Exile ” calls for little more, in the way
            of comment, than what we have generally said. Its finest
            particular feature is, perhaps, the rapture of Eve—rapture
            bursting through despair—upon discovering that she still
            possesses, in the unwavering love of Adam, an undreamed-of
            and priceless treasure. The poem ends, as it commences, 
            with a bull. The last sentence gives us to understand that
            “ there is a sound through the silence, as of the falling tears
            of an angel.” How there can be sound during silence, and
            how an audience are to distinguish, by such sound, angel
            tears from any other species of tears, it may be as well,
            perhaps, not too particularly to inquire.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Next, in length, to the Drama, is “ The Vision of Poets.” 
            We object to the didacticism of its design, which the poetess
            thus states:	“ I have attempted to express here my view
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>of the mission of the veritable poet—of the self-abnegation
            implied in it, of the uses of sorrow suffered in it, of the
            great work accomplished in it through suffering, and of the
            duty and glory of what Balzac has beautifully and truly
            called ' la patience angelique du genie.” This “ view” may
            be correct, but neither its correctness nor its falsity has anything to do with a poem. If a thesis is to be demonstrated,
            we need prose for its demonstration. In this instance, so
            far as the allegorical instruction and argumentation are lost
            sight of, in the upper current—so far as the main admitted
            intention of the work is kept out of view—so far only is the
            work a poem, and so far only is the poem worth notice, or
            worthy of its author. Apart from its poetical character,
            the composition is thoughtful, vivid, epigrammatic, and abundant in just observation—although the critical opinions introduced are not always our own. A reviewer in “ Blackwood’s Magazine,” quoting many of these critical portraits, 
            takes occasion to find fault with the grammar of this tristich:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Here AEschylus—the women swooned
            To see so awful when he frowned
            As the Gods did—he standeth crowned.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“What on earth,” says the critic, “are we to make of
            the words ' the women swooned to see so awful’?....The
            syntax will punish future commentators as much as some of
            his own corrupt choruses.” In general, we are happy to 
            agree with this reviewer, whose decisions respecting the
            book are, upon the whole, so nearly coincident with ours,
            that we hesitated, through fear of repetition, to undertake 
            a critique at all, until we considered that we might say a
            very great deal in simply supplying his omissions; but he
            frequently errs through mere hurry, and never did he err
            more singularly than at the point now in question. He evidently supposes that “ awful ” has been misused as an
            adverb and made referrible to “ women.” But not so; and
            although the construction of the passage is unjustifiably
            involute, its grammar is intact. Disentangling the construction, we make this evident at once: " Here AEschylus (he)
            standeth crowned, (whom) the women swooned to see so
            awful, when he frowned as the Gods did.” The “he” is
            excessive, and the “ whom ” is understood. Respecting the
            lines,
         </p>
         <p>Euripides, with close and mild
            Scholastic lips, that could be wild,
            And laugh or sob out like a child
            Right in the classes,
            the critic observes:—“ ‘ Right in the classes ’ throws our in-
            tellect completely upon its beam-ends.” But, if so, the fault
            
         </p>
         <p>possibly lies in the crankness of the intellect; for the words
            themselves mean merely that Sophocles laughed or cried
            like a school-boy—like a child right (or just) in his classes—
            one who had not yet left school. The phrase is affected,
            we grant, but quite intelligible. A still more remarkable
            misapprehension occurs in regard to the triplet,
         </p>
         <p>And Goethe, with that reaching eye
            His soul reached out from, far and high,
            And fell from inner entity.
            
         </p>
         <p>The reviewer’s remarks upon this are too preposterous
            not to be quoted in full;—we doubt if any commentator of
            equal dignity ever so egregiously committed himself before.
            “ Goethe,” he says, “ is a perfect enigma, what does the
            word ‘ fell’ mean ? SELVOS we suppose—that is, ‘ not to be
            trifled with.’ But surely it sounds very strange, although
            it may be true enough, to say that his ‘ fellness’ is occasioned by inner entity.’ But perhaps the line has some
            deeper meaning which we are unable to fathom.” Perhaps
            it has : and this is the criticism—the British criticism—the
            Blackwood criticism—to which we have so long implicitly
            bowed down ! As before, Miss Barrett’s verses are needlessly involved, but their meaning requires no OEdipus. Their
            construction is thus intended:—“ And Goethe, with that
            reaching eye from which his soul reached out, far and high,
            and (in so reaching) fell from inner entity.” The plain prose
            is this:—Goethe, (the poet would say), in involving himself
            too far and too profoundly in external speculations—speculations concerning the world without him—neglected, or made
            miscalculations concerning his inner entity, or being,—concerning the world within. This idea is involved in the metaphor of a person leaning from a window so far that finally
            he falls from it—the person being the soul, the window the
            eye.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Of the twenty-eight “ Sonnets,” which immediately succeed the “ Drama of Exile,” and which receive the especial
            commendation of Blackwood, we have no very enthusiastic
            opinion. The best sonnet is objectionable from its extreme
            artificiality; and, to be effective, this species of composition,
            requires a minute management—a well-controlled dexterity
            of touch—compatible neither with Miss Barrett’s deficient
            constructiveness, nor with the fervid rush and whirl of her
            genius. Of the particular instances here given, we prefer
            “ the Prisoner,” of which the conclusion is particularly beautiful. In general, the themes are obtrusively metaphysical,
            or didactic.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ The Romaunt of the Page,” an imitation of the old English ballad, is neither very original in subject, nor very skilfully put together. We speak comparatively, of course :—It
            is not very good—for Miss Barrett:—and what we have said
            of this poem will apply equally to a very similar production,
            “ The Rhyme of the Dutchess May.” The “ Poet and the
            Bird”—“A Child Asleep”—“Crowned and Wedded”—
            “ Crowned and Buried”—“ To Flush my Dog”—“ The Fourfold Aspect”—“ A Flower in a Letter”—“ A Lay of the early Rose”—“ That Day”—“ L. E. L’s Last Questio”—“ Catarina to Camoens”—“Wine of Cyprus”—“The Dead Pan”
            —“Sleepingand Watching”—“A Portrait”—“The Mournful Mother”—and “A Valediction”—although all burning
            with divine fire, manifested only in scintillations, have nothing in them idiosyncratic. “ The House of Clouds” and
            “ The Last Bower” are superlatively lovely, and show the
            vast powers of the poet in the field best adapted to their legitimate display :—the themes, here, could not be improved.
            The former poem is purely imaginative ; the latter is unobjectionably because unobtrusively suggestive of a moral, and
            is, perhaps, upon the whole, the most admirable composition
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>in the two volumes:—or, if it is not, then “ The Lay of the
            Brown Rosarie” is. In this last the ballad-character is elevated—etherealized,—and thus made to afford scope for an
            ideality at once the richest and most vigorous in the world.
            The peculiar foibles of the author are here too, dropped bodily, as a mantle, in the tumultuous movement and excitement of the narrative.
         </p>
         <p>To be Continued.
            FASHION.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Willis in his Lecture on Fashion, talks of the absurdities of fashion, as though fashion itself were anything but
            an absurdity. He makes a note of the puzzling fact, that
            only the least enlightened part of mankind adopts a fashion
            suited to its wants and keeps it unchanged. But he makes
            no guess at the cause of this singular truth, for which we
            are sorry, since we have no time to look into the depths of
            the matter, and no good reason floats upon the surface of it
            that we can discern. Perhaps fashion is only the changing
            form of Progress towards perfection, and if we glance over
            the fashion plates of the last five centuries, we can hardly
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>arrive at any other conclusion; and yet the fashions of ladies’
            dresses at the present day are very nearly as outrageous as
            they .were fifty years ago, when George the Third was compelled to issue a command to restrain their growing redundancies, to save him the expense of enlarging his Palace;
            since, to such extreme breadth did the Court ladies carry their
            gowns, that not more than half a dozen could inhabit the
            same room with comfort. We have an example of a fashionable lady of that period before us, taken from the “ Gallery
            of Fashion,” published in 1796.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is sufficiently monstrous; and yet only 50 years ago,
            women were habited in such attire, which seems like an attempt to burlesque dress, this was the fashion at the most refined and modest court in Europe. Contrasted with the
            fashion of the present day, it is not very grotesque, nor very
            absurd. The worst part of it still remains, the pinched waist
            of the wearer and the monstrous waste of the dress. We give
            an instance of the present taste, which every body will see
            has not been exaggerated, as the fashions usually are in the
            fashion plate, of ladies’ magazines. Indeed, this has been
            taken from the life, but the lady not wanting to be recognized
            by her friends, has turned her back upon the public.
         </p>
         <p>Ben Johnson has given the most correct definition of fash-
            ion in his Discoveries that we have ever seen.
            “ Nothing is fashionable until it be deformed.”
            This leaves nothing more to be said. But if any body should
            
         </p>
         <p>doubt that fashion is, essentially, deformity; let it be thought
            on for a moment why fashion endures for so short a time, if
            not because of its hideousness. Any fashion that were beautiful would endure forever. We never grow weary of anything that is pure, or beautiful or good. But gentleness,
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>charity, high mindedness, youth and loveliness, have never 
            been in the fashion. Early rising, industry, forbearance, 
            simple diet, comfortable apparel, have never been in fashion
            among the fashionable. But the opposite of these. Duel- 
            ling always has been, and is now, the very extreme point of
            fashion. So is wine drinking; so are late hours, unhealthy 
            food, and killing dresses.
         </p>
         <p>OLE BUL’S NIAGARA.
            BY  L. MARIA CHILD.
            
         </p>
         <p>[From the tone of criticism, on Ole Bul's great performance, which has
            pervaded the press, and the reported stillness of his auditors, it would
            seem that people went to hear Niagara in India-rubbers, expecting to see
            rainbows reflected from the gas-lights about the per former’s fingers, and
            came away disappointed, because they were not thoroughly soaked in the
            spray of his instrument. It would doubtless give entire satisfaction if
            he were to play it with an accompaniment from a Croton hydrant. Let
            him take the hint at the next performance. But we have never heard of
            anybody, save Mrs. Butler, who did not feel disappointment at the first
            sight of the great Cataract; it could hardly be expected that its idea,
            presented in the tones of a violin, should be more successful in a first
            impression, than the tremendous reality, itself. But there was one
            kindred hearer, if no more, at the first representation of Niagara, as
            the following letter will show.—Ed.]
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>You ask me for my impressions of Ole Bul’s Niagara. It
            is like asking an AEolian harp to tell what the great organ of
            Freyburg does. But since you are pleased to say that you value my impressions, because they are always my own, and not
            another person’s; because they are spontaneous, disinterested,
            and genuine; I will give you the tones as they breathed
            through my soul, without anxiety to have them pass for
            more than they are worth.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I did not know what the composer intended to express. I
            would have avoided knowing, if the information had been
            offered ; for I wished to hear what the music itself would say
            to me. And thus it spoke: The serenely beautiful opening
            told of a soul going forth peacefully into the calm bright atmosphere. It passes along, listening to the half-audible,
            many-voiced murmurings of the summer woods. Gradually,
            tremulous vibrations fill the air, as of a huge cauldron seething in the distance. The echoing sounds rise and swell, and
            finally roar and thunder. In the midst of this, stands the
            soul, striving to utter its feelings.
         </p>
         <p>“ Like to a mighty heart the music seems,
            That yearns with melodies it cannot speak.”
            
         </p>
         <p>It wanders away from the cataract, and again and again
            returns within sound of its mighty echoes. Then calmly,
            reverentially, it passes away, listening to the receding chorus of Nature’s tremendous drums and trombones; musing
            solemnly as it goes, on that vast sheet of waters, rolling now
            as it has rolled, “ long, long time ago.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Grand as I thought Niagara when I first heard it, it opened upon me with increasing beauty when I heard it repeated.
            I then observed many exquisite and graceful touches, which
            were lost in the magnitude of the first impression. The
            multitudinous sounds are bewildering in their rich variety.
         </p>
         <p>“ The cataracts blow their trumpets from the steep.”
            “The whispering air
            Sends inspiration from the rocky heights,
            And dark recesses of the caverned rocks ;
            The little rills, and waters numberless,
            Blend their notes with the loud streams."
            There is the pattering of water-drops, gurglings, twitter-
            ings, and little gushes of song.
            " The leaves in myriads jump and spring,
            As if with pipes and music rare,
            Some Robin Goodfellow were there,
            And all the leaves in festive glee,
            Were dancing to the minstrelsy.”
            
         </p>
         <p>The sublime waterfall is ever present, with its echoes; but
            present in a calm contemplative soul. One of the most poetic minds I know, after listening to this music, said to me,
            “ The first time I saw Niagara, I came upon it through the
            woods, in the clear sunlight of a summer’s morning; and
            these tones are a perfect transcript of my emotions.” In
            truth, it seems to me a most wonderful production; a perfect
            disembodied poem; a most beautiful mingling of natural
            sounds with the reflex of their impressions on a refined and
            poetic mind. This serene grandeur, this pervading beauty,
            which softens all the greatness, is probably the principal
            reason why it does not captivate the ears of the public, as
            much as they had anticipated.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is a great disadvantage to any work of art to be much
            talked of before it appears. People had formed all sorts of
            expectations, and were disappointed not to hear their own
            conceptions uttered in sound. Some expected to hear all
            Niagara, with its powerful bass notes, on the violin alone;
            and apparently forgot that they owed to Ole Bul’s genius the
            grandly-expressive orchestral accompaniment. Some, it is
            said, even complained that they did not hear the cataract.
            Their ears might have been better satisfied, perhaps, if there
            had been a great hydrant running, or a huge water-wheel
            revolving, behind the scenes.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I supposed that Niagara was not received with loud applause, because the souls of the audience were, like my own,
            too much stilled by its solemn and majestic beauty. When I
            heard that many were disappointed in it, I felt as if my spirit
            would be suffocated to remain in a city, that had not souls to
            appreciate a production like that. But one never need distrust
            the human soul. It always responds to what comes from the
            soul. During the following days, people who were strangers
            to Ole Bul, were continually saying to me, “ I was indignant
            at the want of enthusiasm.” “ Really, I have never before
            been so much impressed with Ole Bul’s genius.” Then came
            tidings that foreign critics, and musical amateurs, who were
            present, thought it a composition full of majesty and beauty,
            and were surprised that it was not received with warmer
            applause. Like all refined and skilfully elaborated produc tions, it will take time to grow upon the popular ear. If I
             were to hear it a hundred times, I should discover some new
             beauty every time, though I should never be able thoroughly
             to appreciate it. The artist has thrown into it the earnest
            strength of his soul, and prepared it with great care, because
            he wished to offer a fitting tribute to this country. Perhaps
            America will not discover the magnificence of the compli ment, till applauding Europe teaches her its value.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>At the second concert, a Rondo Giocoso, of Ole Bul’s composing, greeted my ears for the first time. It is the lightest,
            airiest thing imaginable ; like the hum of bees among the
            flowers. It is the very Spirit or Joy, throwing smiles and
            roses as she dances by.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Then, too, I heard The Solitude of the Prairie for the first
            time; and never did music so move the inmost depths of my
            soul. Its spiritual expression breathes through heavenly melodies. With a voice earnest and plaintive as the nightingale,
            it spoke to me of inward conflict; of the soul going forth into
            solitude, alone and sad. The infinite stretches itself out, in
            darkness and storm. Through the fierce tempestuous struggle, it passes alone, alone, as the soul must ever go through
            all its sternest conflicts. Then comes self-renunciation, humility and peace. And thus does the exquisitely beautiful
             music of this Prairie Solitude lay the soul lovingly into its
             rest.
         </p>
         <p>Many, who have hitherto been moderate in their enthusi-
            asm about Ole Bul, recognize in these new compositions
            
            
         </p>
         <p>more genius than they supposed him to possess. Tastefully 
            intertwined Fantasias, or those graceful musical garlands, 
            Rondos, might be supposed to indicate merely a pleasing degree of talent and skill. But those individuals must be hard
            to convince, who do not recognize the presence of genuine
            inspiration, in the deep tenderness of the Mother’s Prayer,
            that sounds as if it were composed at midnight, alone with
            the moon; in the fiery, spirit-stirring eloquence of the Polacca Guerriera, composed at Naples, in view of flaming Vesuvius ; in the deep spiritual melody of the Prairie Solitude;
            and in the bold yet serene grandeur of Niagara. The individuality of Ole Bui’s compositions, their unrepeating variety,
            and certain passages which occur in them all, have frequently suggested to my mind the existence of a latent slumbering
            power, which has not room to exert its full strength in music
            composed for the violin.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I speak as a novice, but my speech has the merit of being
            unaffected. In the presence of mere skill, I know not what
            to say. It may please me somewhat; but whether it is more
            or less excellent than some other thing, I cannot tell. But
            bring me into the presence of genius, and I know it, by rapid
            intuition, as quick as I know a sunbeam. I cannot tell how
            I know it. I simply say, This is genius; as I say, This is a
            sunbeam.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is an old dispute, that between genius and criticism, and
            probably will never be settled ; for it is one of the manifold
            forms of conservatism and innovation. In all departments
            of life, genius is on the side of progress, and learning on the
            side of established order. Genius comes a Prophet from the
            future, to guide the age onward. Learning, the Lawgiver,
            strives to hold it back upon the past. But the prophet always revolutionizes the laws ; for thereunto was he sent.—
            Under his powerful hand, the limitations gradually yield and
            flow, as metals melt into new forms at the touch of fire.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is as true of music, as of everything else. Its rules
            have been constantly changing. What is established law
            now was unknown, or shocking, a hundred years ago. Every great genius that has appeared in the art, has been accused of violating the rules. The biographer of Haydn says:
            “ The charming little thoughts of the young musician, the
            warmth of his style, the liberties which he sometimes allowed himself, called forth against him all the invective of the
            musical monastery. They reproached him with errors of
            counterpoint, heretical modulations, and movements too daring. His introduction of prestissimo made all the critics of
            Vienna shudder.” An English nobleman once begged him
            to explain the reason of certain modulations and arrangements in one of his quartetts. “ I did so because it has a
            good effect,” replied the composer. “ But I can prove to
            you that it is altogether contrary to the rules,” said the nobleman. “ Very well,” replied Haydn, “arrange it in your
            own way, hear both played, and tell me which you like the
            best.” “But how can your way be the best, since it is contrary to the rules?” urged the nobleman. “ Because it is the
            most agreeable,” replied Haydn ; and the critic went away
            unconvinced.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Beethoven was constantly accused of violating the rules.—
            In one of his compositions, various things were pointed out
            to him as deviations from the laws, expressly forbidden by
            masters of the art. “ They forbid them, do they ?” said
            Beethoven. “Very well. I allow them.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Do not understand me as speaking scornfully of knowledge and critical skill. Only presumptuous, self-conceited ignorance does this. On the contrary, I labor with earnest industry, to acquire more and more knowledge of rules, in
            all the forms of art. But, in all the higher and more spir-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>itual manifestations, I recognize laws only as temporary and
            fluxional records of the progressive advancement of the soul.
            I do not deny the usefulness of criticism ; but genius forever
            remains the master, and criticism the servant.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Whether critics will consider Niagara as abounding with
            faults, when they examine into its construction, I cannot
            conjecture. It is their business to analyze genius, and the
            mischief is, they are generally prone to dissect in the shadow of their own hands. To speak playfully, it is my own
            belief that cataract-thunderings, sea-moanings, tree-breathings, wind-whistlings, and bird-warblings, are none of them
            composed according to the rules. They ought all to be sent
            to Paris or Rome, to finish their education, and go silent
            meanwhile, unless they can stop their wild everlasting variations.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I have not yet learned to become reconciled to the sudden
            crash of the orchestra, which, in almost all complicated music, comes in to snap beautiful melodies,
         </p>
         <p>“As if a lark should suddenly drop dead,
            While the blue air yet trembled with its song.”
            
         </p>
         <p>I suppose it is right, because all composers will have it so.
            Moreover, I know it is so in nature, and it is so in the experience of the soul. But, after all, those clashing instruments
            always seem like the devil in the universe, of whom it never
            becomes quite clear to me what need there is of his being
            there.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I have less affinity for fun, than for earnest impassioned
            utterance; but really there is no withstanding the admirable comic power of tone and gesture, in Signor Queerico,—
            (Sanquirico.) In this dull heavy atmosphere, which has for
            weeks hung over us like a pall, he is positively a benefactor;
            as agreeable as a glimpse of sunshine.	L. M. C.
         </p>
         <p>“IS GENIUS CONSCIOUS OF ITS POWERS?"
            
         </p>
         <p>Not the shadow of a peradventure rests upon the question.
            By cock and pye, the best oath that I am acquainted with,
            yea ! But if any darkness encompassed the matter, that essay of Hazlitt’s in which he attempts to prove the contrary,
            dispels it. “ No really great man ever thought himself so,”
            begins the essayist, and before he drops his pen, makes these
            depreciating remarks upon himself:—
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ If the reader is not already apprised of it, he will please
            to take notice that I write this at Winterslow. My style
            there is apt to be redundant and excursive. At other times
            it may be cramped, dry, abrupt; but there it flows like a
            river, and overspreads its banks. I have not to seek for
            thoughts or hunt for images: they come of themselves, I inhale them with the breeze, and the silent groves are vocal
            with a thousand recollections—
         </p>
         <p>“ And visions as poetic eyes avow,
            Hang on each leaf, and cling to every bough.”
            
         </p>
         <p>“ Here I came fifteen years ago, a willing exile; and as I
            trod the green sward by the low wood-side, repeated the old
            line,
         </p>
         <p>“ My mind to me a kingdom is.”
            
         </p>
         <p>I found it so then, before, and since; and shall I faint, now
            that 1 have poured out the spirit of that mind to the world,
            and treated many subjects with truth, with freedom and power,
            because I have been followed with one cry of abuse ever
            since for not being a government tool ? Here I sketched my
            account of that old honest Signior Orlando Friscobaldo—
            which, with its fine, racy, acrid tone, that old crab-apple,
            G*ff**d, would have relished or pretended to relish, had I
            been a governmental tool! Here, too, I have written Table
            Talks without number, and as yet without a falling off, till
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>now that they are nearly done, or I should not make this
            boast. I could swear (were they not mine) the thoughts in
            many of, them are founded as the rock, free as air, the tone
            like an Italian picture.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This rather sounds like attaching a just estimate to one’s
            own performance, and I do not remember among all the
            commendations of the Genius of the Essayist, of seeing any
            thing more commendatory than these lines by his own hand.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But Hazlitt’s false conclusion that greatness is blind to its
            own dimensions, arises from his confounding a consciousness
            of superiority with an unconsciousness of its cause. A man
            who has given ten years to the study of Greek, is perfectly
            well aware of the source of his acquirements, as well as of
            their extent. But the learned Blacksmith who gets a knowledge of Greek in ten days, is not the less aware of his gettings, because he knows not how he got the power to get. 
            The writings of all great minds are full of instances of selfconsciousness. Shakspeare and Milton, are fuller, perhaps, 
            than any others. With what an oracular certainty they both 
            promise immortality to the names mentioned in their verse! 
            To quote instances, would seem to imply a doubt of ignorance on the part of the reader that I do not entertain.
            Every body knows that Milton promised his great epic many,
            many years, before a line of it was penned; the interval between the promise and the performance was the period of
            gestation. It required the audacity of Genius to make a
            prediction that only a Genius could fulfil. Cool, unblushing 
            egotism is almost a sure indication of greatness. There can
            be no greatness without it. The vauntings of impudence
            are a very different matter.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In naming Burke, Hazlitt says; “ Because his rank in
            letters is become a settled point with us, we conclude that
            it must have been quite as self-evident to him, and that he
            must have been perfectly conscious of his vast superiority to
            the rest of the world. Alas! not so. No man is truly himself,
            but in the idea which others entertain of him.” Regarding
            his rank in letters Burke could not have been over-confident,
            because he knew that rank depends almost as much upon
            accident as merit, but his superiority to the rest of the world
            was a fact which there are abundant reasons lor believing
            he trusted in as firmly as any of his admirers do now. The
            very powers which make a man great, also make him the
            best perceiver of his own greatness. Who has ever read
            Burns without being startled at the judgments he pronounces
            upon himself? and the gentle Sir Walter swore the most
            terrible oaths at Blackwood, the publisher, for presuming to
            suggest that an improvement might be made in one of the
            Tales of my Landlord; and the kind of omnipotent contempt
            which he expressed for Jeffrey, when the critic reviewed one
            of his poems with a slight qualification of dispraise, scarcely
            perceptible to the common eye, is to me stronger evidence of
            his Genius than the poem itself.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>That “ no man is truly himself but in the idea which others
            entertain of him,” is a vile pernicious untruth, which, if believed in, would destroy all greatness. All confidence and
            boldness would be at an end, and men would go tottering
            about, afraid to speak or act, because they could not know
            in advance, what opinions would be entertained of them. No
            man ever was great, whose opinion of himself was not independent of the opinions of others. Self-confidence is the only
            foundation upon which any great work was ever erected. It
            is the fuel which gets up the steam, without which the engine
            is useless matter. To undertake a task for which I had not
            a conscious fitness, would be the reverse of modesty; and
            modesty is as natural an accompaniment to genius, as selfconfidence.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ What a pity,” said one, “ that Milton had not the pleasure of reading Paradise Lost.” What a pity, say I, that a man
            of genius, like Hazlitt, who had often been steeped in the delights of composition, should have echoed such a misleading
            pity. Can it be believed that any body has ever taken half
            the pleasure in studying Paradise Lost, that the author did
            in composing it? What recompense would the poet have,
            if he gained none in his work ? Can any poet look upon the
            reward which his labours have brought him, and declare that
            they afforded him as much pleasure as the labours themselves ? I verily believe, that great as the delight has been
            which Jack Falstaff has afforded the world, that his author
            received more pleasure in creating him, than all the rest of
            the world has received from reading him. He heard all the
            jokes of the fat knight, uttered in the rich oily voice, and saw
            the accompanying grins and shaking of the fat heavy sides,
            and mock solemnities, that we can never hear or see ; and
            moreover, he saw and heard a thousand characteristic traits
            that could not be put upon paper. The portrait of Jack appears plump and real enough to us, but compared with the
            original that was present to the poet, he is a mere shadowy
            outline. And it is for this reason that authors have such a
            disgust for their own productions. To the reader the attempted descriptions of what the author saw, call up some
            faint resemblance of the original objects, and even these resemblances, faint as they are, give a degree of pleasure ; but
            to the author himself, his lines only impart a sickening sense
            of the feebleness with which he has depicted the glories
            which inflamed his imagination. “ I sometimes try to read
            an article which I have written in some magazine or review,
            but stop short after a sentence or two, and never recur to
            the task," says Hazlitt. Yet another person can read this
            article or review two or three times with renewed pleasure.
            Mr. Dickens has furnished a confirmation of the truth of my
            argument in the preface to Martin Chuzzlewit. He says,
            “ If my readers have derived but half the pleasure and interest from its perusal, which its composition has afforded me, I
            have ample reason to be satisfied; and if they part from any
            of my visionary friends with the least tinge of that reluctance
            and regret which I feel in dismissing them, my success has
            been complete indeed.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This is the most candid confession that any author has yet
            made. So then, great as our delight has been in the society
            of Sairey Gamp, Mr. Dickens has been twice as much delighted as any of us. And yet he will never seek her society
            again, as the rest of us will, in his own pages. His Sairey
            and our Sairey are different personages.' Ours is only a
            shadow, but he has enjoyed the reality. But, reluctance is
            not the right word to express the sensation which we experienced in taking leave of Sairey Gamp and the Junior Bailey ; a much stronger term might be used without exaggeration.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Hazlitt did not himself believe in his own theory. Like
             all dealers in paradox, either intentionally or by accident he
             continually upsets his own arguments. All the instances
            that he names, especially those of the painters, directly con tradict his assertions. He could hardly have named a great
            man who seems to have possessed himself in such perfect
             confidence of genius as Michael Angelo. I doubt whether
             an instance of a great man wanting in a just appreciation of
             his own powers, can be named. The timidity of Cowper,
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p> even, was not owing to mistrust of what he had the ability
             to do ; he was bold enough to undertake the task that he
            felt himself equal to performing. Whoever has enjoyed
            the privilege of personal intercourse with men of genius
            must have noticed many accidental bursts of conscious might
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>which would have appeared in lesser men the very sublime
            of conceit. I know an artist who said very deliberately one
            day, that he could paint as well as Titian, and draw much
            better. Such an expression as this would have made Hazlitt’s hair bristle, but if he had seen the artist work, he would
            not have said of him as he did of Annibal Caracci for making
            the same boast, that “ he was wrong.” But the same artist would have inscribed “faciebat,” upon his work notwithstanding. Doctor Johnson said that he could write a
            better cookery book than any body had ever produced. I
            am inclined to believe that he could have done it, but he
            was too busy with his dictionary.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ The greatest pleasure in life is that of reading," says Hazlitt, but any book that gives pleasure in reading must have given twice as much pleasure in composing. Let no author ever
            flatter himself that what has given him pain to produce will
            ever give any body else pleasure to read. Critics would be
            spared all their cruel fun of damning a poor book, if authors
            would only test their writings before publishing, by the sensations which their production cost. If there be truth in
            this, and I appeal to all book-makers for testimony, what an
            ocean of delight must those happy dogs Cervantes and Fielding, Rabelais, and Sterne have floundered in, while composing their immortal fun.	C.
         </p>
         <p>THE FINE ARTS.
            
         </p>
         <p>There is a painting on exhibition, and for sale, at Mr. Colman’s in Broadway, of the “ Bride of Abydos,” by Thomas
            H. Smith, a young Artist of this City, which deserves the
            attention of the friends of American An. The painting is by
            no means a faultless production, bur considering the youth
            and opportunities of the painter, it is a remarkable picture
            in respect of color and drawing. It has infinitely more merit than some of the paintings which have received the praise
            of chef d'oeuvres, by artists who put N. A. at the end of their
            names ; and we trust that a young man of so little pretension,
            and so much promise, as Mr. Smith, will not be allowed to remain long without employment, which, we understand, he
            needs at present.
         </p>
         <p>THE ART UNION PICTURES.
            
         </p>
         <p>The last distribution of works of Art, by this association,
            which took place at the Society Library, the 20th of last
            month, was an important era in the history of the Fine
            Arts in this country.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The income of the association, the last year, was something more than ten thousand dollars—nearly eight thousand
            of which have been bestowed upon the artists of our country, principally of our city. But no respect appears to have
            been had for the residence of the artist, in their purchases,
            by the Committee of Management.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The purchases generally, evinced a discriminating taste,
            and an impartiality of feeling, such as might have been
            expected from the character of the gentlemen composing
            the committee of management. Some of the pictures were
            indifferent performances, but we doubt not that they were
            richly worth the prices paid for them. Indeed, it could
            hardly be expected that ninety-two good pictures could be
            purchased for five thousand dollars, which, according to the
            report, was the total cost of the whole. We have no doubt
            that they would have sold for a handsome advance, if they
            had been offered at auction.
         </p>
         <p>A great part of the pictures were by our young artists;
            
         </p>
         <p>but it is hoped that the increased income of the Art Union
            will induce our older artists to compete for the prizes of the
            association with the younger members of the profession. It
            is greatly to the credit of Mr. Durand that he has seconded
            the wishes of the committee with zeal and good feeling,
            putting his pictures at less prices than he would to a private
            purchaser.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>His large landscape, The Passing Shower, was the favorite
            of the last distribution, and we regard it as the best of all
            his pictures. It was better finished—although it had not
            half the marks of elaborate care—than his “ Lake Scene,”
            which the association distributed last year. At the first
            glance it reminds you of Gainsborough’s market waggon,
            from the position of the waggon that has just crossed the
            brook ; but there all resemblance ends. The trees in this
            picture are marked with a fine individuality of character,
            which is a sure merit in a landscape. One of the cedars, in
            particular, struck us as a fine portrait.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The bank of mist, driven on by the squall, is managed
            with an exceedingly fine effect,—and the glimpse of sunlight, darting between the opening which the road makes
            through the wood, has the same cheerful influence upon the
            feelings of the spectator, which such realities have in the
            open air, and makes us sympathize with the farmer, who is
            hastening home before the rising storm. The cattle are
            finely put upon the canvass, and show that the painter is a
            lover and close observer of rural scenery and its accompaniments.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Scenes like these are Mr. Durand’s forte ; he is at home
            here, and a genius; but in the solemn solitudes, which Cole
            loves so well, he is out of his element, and only a man of
            fine talent. There is no such thing as universality of genius.
            No man of genius ever could play upon more than one string.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Durand is a gentle spirit; he loves quiet sunny places, rippling brooks, fleecy clouds, and willows that grow
            by water courses. The name of the street which he has
            chosen for his dwelling is an indication of his nature—Amity
            Street. It is a pity that he should ever employ his pencil
            in depicting any other nature than that which seems so well
            to harmonize with his own. We have seen two of his
            landscapes recently, which have been purchased by two
            gentlemen of this city, that are in his very happiest manner ; both alike in feeling but unlike in composition. They
            have such cool shadows, such soft skies, and sparkling
            brooks, that you could hardly long for the country while
            they were hanging before you, they satisfy the sentiment so
            fully. The cattle standing in the water, cooling their hoofs,
            make you long to pull off your boots and splash in the
            clear stream.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the picture of “The Passing Shower,” he has obscured
            the distant village by a cloud of black mist, which is fast
            enshrouding the fair landscape in its heavy folds; but he loves
            not these dismal aspects of nature, and he has thrown across
            it a bow of promise, which imparts to us his own cheerfulness of feeling. It is in such traits as these that artists
            reflect themselves, and awaken sympathy in others.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Cole loves the solemn stillness of our forests and prairies,
            and he has selected the foot of the Catskill mountains for
            his studio. There was only one of his pictures in the distribution, and though small and unpretending, it possessed
            much of his character. A still lake, a clear sky without a
            cloud, the ruins of a majestic tree stretching out its scathed
            but giant branches; and hoary old rocks ; it is the very poetry of solitude, and you hold your breath lest the echo of
            your voice should frighten you. There’s nothing living in
            sight—indeed, nothing could live there, for there’s not a
         </p>
         <p>
            particle of atmosphere. It looks like the earth, before God
            breathed upon it.
            
         </p>
         <p>The landscapes of Mr. Cole have generally been complained of as wanting atmosphere. But they have no need
            of it. He loves to represent Nature as she looked before
            living beings began to bustle about upon her surface. Before
            the serpent had begun to hiss, or the wolf to howl. His
            rocks, his trees, his water, live apart in the depths of stillness. Atmosphere would only soften their severe outlines,
            and their peculiar character would be gone ; they would be
            like the rocks and trees of another artist, if seen in an
            atmosphere, and the charm which they now have would be
            lost.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Cole’s tame pictures are tame in the extreme. His
            forte is in the vast and solitary. One of his first paintings
            was the representation of a howling snow storm, on the
            Catskill mountains, with a wolf in the foreground, growling
            louder than the winter wind. It is many a year since we
            saw it, but it appalled us to that degree that we never think
            of it but with a shudder. Indeed, it is a pelting storm that
            beats against our window while we write, that has brought
            it freshly to mind.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mount AEtna seems to have greatly possessed Mr. Cole’s
            imagination. He never gave a stronger instance of his
            ruling passion than in his ascent to the crater of the hoary
            monarch. He has painted scores of pictures since, with the
            snow-capped volcano in the distance ; and it is to be regretted that he should ever have employed his pencil about such
            romantic trifles as his “ Past and Present,” and “ The Departure and Return;" and scores of other inanities in which
            he seems like a Sampson in the toils of some bewitching
            Delilah. He is the most imaginative of our painters—or
            perhaps it were better to say that his imagination is of a
            more epic cast. Nothing is easier with him than to produce
            an effect of grandeur and wildness ; nothing harder than to
            be soft and fanciful.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is to be regretted, that among all the pictures there was
            but one historical composition—De Soto discovering the
            Mississippi, by Rothermel, of Philadelphia. There was a
            small sketch, by the same artist, in oil, made for the Art
            Union, which gave us a high opinion of his abilities. It
            was the embodiment of a well known revolutionary anecdote, “ The Man who fought on his own hook;" but the
            subject is too meagre for a large picture.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The two great favorites with the public, after Durand’s
            landscape, judging from the sensation among the audience
            when the numbers were drawn, were “ The Compositor,”
            by Charles E. Weir, and “Long Jake,” by Lieut. Deas.
            They are both admirable pictures. “ The Compositor” had
            gained hosts of admirers, when in the exhibition last summer, but “ Long Jake ” had never been seen, excepting a
            day or two in Mr. Colman’s—but at the rooms of the Art
            Union. We have no hesitation in pronouncing Mr. Weir a
            better painter than his brother; and we think that “ The
            Compositor ” will fully justify our opinion. Doubtless there
            are many who will differ from us, and perhaps it were better not to institute comparisons between them.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Long Jake ” comes to us from the outer verge of our
            civilization; he is a Sante Fe trader, and with his rifle in
            hand, his blazing red shirt, his slouched hat, long beard and
            coal black steed, looks as wild and romantic as any of the
            characters in Froissart’s pages, or Salvator Rosa’s pictures.
            But “ Long Jake ” was not always a Santa Fe trader—there
            are traits of former gentleness and refinement in his countenance, and he sits upon his horse as though he were fully
            conscious of his picturesque appearance. The purple hills
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>and the brown furze harmonize finely in the picture, and
            give it a very romantic aspect. Altogether, “Long Jake”
            is not a picture to be forgotten. His red shirt and his
            honest face will live in many a mind's eye, during the next
            generation. We hope that Lieut. Deas will send us some
            companions to keep him company from the far West.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The “ View in Orange County,” by Cropsy, is well known
            to the picture-loving public ; it gained many admirers in the
            exhibition of the National Academy, and while hanging in
            the gallery of the Art Union. It is unquestionably an exceedingly fine picture,—a representation of quiet, every day
            nature, without a particle of romance or imagination. The
            straggling rail fence that stretches though it so prominently,
            is not in the least degree offensive, but on the contrary, harmonizes with the scene as finely as the blue hills in the
            distance. But such an object, in one of Cole’s pictures,
            would be very disgusting, because so out of character with
            his poetic manner. There was another landscape, by Mr.
            Cropsy—a scene in early autumn—as far as color is concerned, something in Cole’s manner, but pervaded with a
            different sentiment. Mr. Cropsy is a young artist of great
            promise, and his pictures show rapid improvement. We
            have been told that he is painting a picture to send to England ; but he should be content with the approbation of his
            own countrymen. Englishmen cannot appreciate the merits
            of a purely American landscape, and the artist who sends
            his pictures across the water, for the sake of an English
            reputation, will be sure to meet with a mortifying reception.
            The whole tone and aspect of Nature in America is so entirely unlike Nature in England, that it could not be otherwise. English critics laugh at our descriptions of Autumn
            scenery, as extravagant hyperbole; and even Mrs. Butler’s
            glowing account of our woods in Autumn, was attributed by
            them to her theatrical habits of expression.
         </p>
         <p>NEW-YEAR'S CALLS.
            
         </p>
         <p>It is right that the first day of the year should be a merry
            one: but it unfortunately happens that we cannot be merry
            by rule. Learning, wisdom, and riches, may all be systematically obtained. But merriment must come of itself.—
            We all know what the result was when a certain king commanded all his subjects to be happy on a certain day, and
            offered a premium to the happiest. As anybody but a king
            might have foreseen, he had not a happy subject in his kingdom when the day arrived. It is greatly to be wondered at
            that kings and legislators would not take a lesson from this
            well meaning Prince, and let people alone, to be happy or
            not in their own way, and at their own time. The laissez
            faire principle is the only safe rule for a Legislator. All
            that men need is to be let alone. If they cannot make their
            own happiness laws will do them no good.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>There are no legal requirements compelling men to be
            merry on New-year’s day, but there is a social law, more
            stringent than any statute, whieh ordains that every body
            shall meet the New-year with a smile. On that day we
            must forget all the lame, and blind, and poor ; forget all our
            own aches and cares, and go out into the colds treets with
            laughing countenances, wishing every body many returns of
            the day, and paying every body compliments of the season;
            and when night falls we begin to wish that we may never
            see another day like it.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Nothing can be more truly delightful than calling to see
            one’s friends on New-year’s day, and reviving the friendships, which but for this annual sacrifice on the domestic
            altar, might be chilled to death by neglect. But a delightful social habit is fast becoming a distressing fashion. La-
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>dies boast of the number of calls they receive, and gentlemen of the number of calls they make. Ambitious housekeepers vie with each other in their set-outs, and kind heartedness and good cheer are banished for formal politeness and
            gaudy parade. The elegant and refined are simple and
            cheerful on these occasions, as they are on all others; but
            the vulgar rich, and the aspiring poor, make dreadful sacrifices in the endeavor to be merry on New-year’s day.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Happily, the innocent joyousness of children, the happiness of servants in their gifts, and all who on this day receive from their employers the approbatory present which
            sweetens a twelve month’s toil, are entirely beyond the
            reach of show or ceremony. Pride and envy cannot touch
            them, and for their sakes may New-year’s be always a day
            of gifts and good wishes.
         </p>
         <p>The first day of the year is a fit occasion for moralising,
            but in New-York we leave that duty for the day after.
            
         </p>
         <p>A friend has given us a sketch of the manner of making
            New-years’ calls, which we do not think greatly out of the
            way. Of course it will appear very vulgar to some, but to
            others it may appear very genteel. We think that something like it might have been seen on either side of Broadway this week.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mrs. Skillett is the wife of a dry goods jobber in Cedar
            street; her house is in something place, Seventh street. It
            is a great point to live in a “ place,” with genteel people. Mrs.
            Skillett’s house is two stories high, with attic and basement ; a brick front with red sand stone dressings, and a Grecian door way ; her husband’s name on a silver plate, Skillett, ornaments the door, which is bronzed; the windows
            are shaded by green Venetian blinds on the outside and by
            transparencies of Gothic views in the inside ; the exact size
            of the house is twenty-five by forty feet. The yard contains
            a little circular patch of grass, which is green sometimes, a
            trellised screen painted white, and a grape vine, which looks,
            at this season, like a Boa-Constrictor hung up to dry. On
            the first floor are the two parlors. The hall contains a mahogany hat stand shaped like a harp, a Gothic stove, and a
            Gothic lantern. The parlors are furnished exactly alike, and
            are connected by sliding doors veneered with mahogany;
            the floors are carpeted with the brightest of colors, and the
            walls are whiter than snow, and appear much colder ; the
            chairs are mahogany with Gothic backs and satin bottoms,
            the piano rose wood, and the mantle ornaments bronze.—
            There is a pleasant smell of varnish still lingering around
            the furniture, to remind you that it is perfectly new and in
            the latest fashion.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the front parlor sits Mrs. Skillett, with her two daughters and a friend from the country, flaunting in Cachemere
            dresses, much gayer than the carpets ; all three are gloved
            in white kid, and have gold pencil cases suspended from
            their necks.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In the back parlor stands a marble centre table, heaped
            up with a variety of fancy eatables, prominent among which
            is a huge frosted cake, with a sugar Cupidon, or a pair of
            doves standing in the centre; this is surrounded by a German silver cake basket, filled with cookies,—a salver of the
            same material filled with sandwiches, a fruit dish with
            grapes and oranges, some little glass mugs filled with hot
            lemonade, two decanters of wine, a flask of maraschino,
            and a variety of sugar gimcracks.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A pull of the bell is heard at the street door; the two
            Miss Skillets, and their friend from the country, all three
            run to the window and peep under the blind, and pop back
            into their seats again, to look perfectly unconcerned when
            the “callers” enter.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The door opens, and in come three gentlemen in white
            gloves and very red noses ; they try to smile, but their frozen
            features won’t. One is Mr. Davis, a young attorney, the
            second Mr. Jones, a hardware jobber, and the third is Mr.
            Green, a teller in a bank. They all three ejaculate together,
            in a kind of desperate manner, “ the compliments of the
            season to you, ladies;" upon which the ladies smile and
            curtsey, and say, “ thank you; many returns of the day to
            yourselves.” A few words are exchanged about the weather,
            the Opera, or the Bishop, as the case may be; and Mr. Jones,
            under pretence of looking at the mantel ornaments, steps
            up to the grate and slyly warms the ends of his fingers.
            Mrs. Skillett then says, “ gentlemen, won’t you walk into
            the next room and take some refreshments?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The three gentlemen follow Mrs. Skillett, and two of
            them take a glass of wine, but Mr. Jones, on pretended
            temperance principles, takes a glass of lemonade, because
            it is hot. They all three refuse cake, but Mr. Davis eats
            one grape, and says it is “ splendid.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>They return again to the parlor, and one of the young
            ladies tells Mr. Jones to walk up to the fire and warm himself, upon which that gentleman tells a very palpable story
            in saying that he is “ not in the least cold.” They then
            make a bow, bid the ladies good morning, and hurry off to
            some other “ place,” to repeat the same agreeable ceremony.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>At night, the ladies sum up the number of their calls,
            and the gentlemen boast of the number of their visits. Mr.
            Jones tells his friends, the next day, with an air of indifference, that he did’nt make many calls—only a hundred and
            fifty, or so—and wonders what the ladies of his acquaintance,
            whom he slighted, will think of him.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This imposing ceremony is, of course, attended with a
            good many variations on the above, not the least infrequent
            of which, is the case of a young gentleman from the country,
            who, being unaccustomed to the business, falls into the
            dreadful mistake of drinking full glasses of sweet wine, at
            the first two or three houses which he calls at, and is, in
            consequence, obliged to be carried off to his boarding-house
            and put to bed, before half of his calls are made. H.
         </p>
         <p>A SONG.
            TO MY WIFE.
            A lily thou vast when I saw thee first,
            A lily-bud not opened quite,
            That hourly grew more pure and white,
            By morning, and noontide and evening nurst;
            In all of nature thou hadst thy share,
            Thou wast waited on
            By the wind and sun,
            The rain and the dew for thee took care,
            It seemed thou never couldst be more fair.
            A lily thou wast when I saw thee first,
            A lily-bud, but O, how strange,
            How full of wonder was the change,
            When, ripe with all sweetness, thy full bloom burst,
            How did the tears to my glad eyes start
            When the woman-flower
            Reached its blossoming hour,
            And I saw the warm deeps of thy golden heart!
            
         </p>
         <p>Glad death may pluck thee, but never before
            The gold dust of thy bloom divine
            Hath dropt from thy heart into mine,
         </p>
         <p>To quicken its faint germs of heavenly lore;
            
         </p>
         <p>For no breeze comes nigh thee but carries away
            Some impulses bright
            Of fragrance and light,
         </p>
         <p>Which fell upon souls that were lone and astray,
            To plant fruitful hopes of the flower of a Day.
            James Russell Lowell.
            
            NOTICES OF NEW BOOKS.
            
         </p>
         <p>The American Poulterer's Companion, with Illustrations and Portraits of Fowls, taken from life: By C. N. Bement. New York:
            Saxton &amp; Miles, 1845; pp. 378.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This little treatise, as the author modestly calls it, was
            undertaken by urgent solicitation of his friends, who knew
            the author’s ability for the task. “ There are few persons,”
            he observes, “who do not like a fresh egg, or a fine fat pullet.” He might substitute no, for few; perhaps there is no
            article of food so universally eaten as eggs, and none so
            necessary to eat fresh. “From my earliest youth,” says
            Mr. Bement, “ I have always taken great interest in all
            kinds of domestic stock, especially poultry, when well cooked
            and laid before me." No one who has had the good fortune
            to eat at Mr. Bement’s table—his public one, we mean—will
            doubt this. His treatise is accordingly a labor of love; and
            to those who have ever been engaged in the pleasant business of rearing poultry, it will read like a fairy tale. Hereafter, Mr. Bement will divide attention with Moubray—if 
            he does not supplant that classic of the barn-yard altogether,
            which we regard by no means improbable. The book is
            very handsomely printed, on fine paper, and the cuts, are
            something better than we usually find in similar works.
         </p>
         <p>Flowers for Children : By L. Maria Child, Author of “ The Moth-
            er’s Book,” “ Letters from New York,” etc. etc., No. 1 and 2. C.
            S. Francis &amp; Co., New York.
            
         </p>
         <p>We are gratified to learn that the sale of these charming
            little books is in some degree proportioned to their merits,
            The accomplished author of them never uses her pen in
            vain, because she never uses it with a sinister motive. She 
            has been accused of extravagance and affectation, in some of,
            her writings, merely because she was unaffected, and gave
            a true expression to her feelings. These “ Flowers for
            Children” have all the freshness and unpretending beauty 
            of the flowers for children which God sprinkles in the high
            ways and fields, and we think that children must love them 
            as well, for they have come from the hands of one who has 
            unbounded love for them. It is a most responsible task to
            write a book for a child; and unless it be done by proper
            hands, it were better that books for the nursery should contain nothing more intelligent than the old classic rhymes
            which we have inherited from the fatherland, the “ hey
            diddle, diddles,” and “ goosey, goosey, gander” of our infancy. Very different from nursery rhymes are the “ Flowers” of Mrs. Child. They breathe a fragrance that is as
            grateful in the library as in the nursery. As the child is
            father of the man, his mental food should always be of the
            same quality, though given in different quantities. No book
            is fit for a child that is not profitable for a man. Children
            are quicker to detect untruths than men, because they are
            more truthful themselves ; and therefore, no books can ever
            be acceptable, or profitable to them, which are not simply
            and truthfully written. They are the best critics in the
            world, and the most fastidious, in regard to style. Involved
            sentences, harsh, abrupt, jerked out expressions, high sounding phrases, they will not tolerate. Whoever writes for
            children, must be gentle, truthful, confiding, and above all,
            sincere. It is children who have conferred immortality on
            such truthful writers as De Foe and Bunyan.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mrs. Child has the truthfulness and simplicity of those old
            masters—but she has something besides—a warm glow of
            love for the human race, which seems to surround her pen
            like a halo. Many of these unpretending “ flowers” are as
            fit for men who are just on the verge of second childhood, as
            for those who are yet in their first.
         </p>
         <p>THE MAGAZINES.
            
         </p>
         <p>Among all our M. P’s. (as George Cruikshank calls the
            monthly periodicals,) the Knickerbocker is the oldest. This
            nobody will deny. The London Literary Gazette says it is
            the best, which somebody probably will dispute, for it is
            the fate of every body and everything in this world to have
            enemies as well as friends. If old age is an evidence of a
            good constitution in a man, it is no less so in a magazine.
            The Knickerbocker must have something good about it, or
            it never could have lived to its present age. The January
            number contains an admirable essay on Plagiarists and Plagiarisms by Polygon, who is always instructive and amusing;
            and a delicate piece of verse by John Waters, whose prose
            essays are more like poetry than his verses. These two
            writers would alone give value to a magazine.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Democratic Review comes next to the Knickerbocker
            in point of age, but it has not yet come to hand, with us; the
            election of Mr. Polk, we believe, retarded the publication of
            the last two numbers in some way. The Democratic Review
            for this month, contains a paper on the inequalities of wealth,
            which has merit enough to sanctify all its other contents.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Columbian, for January, appears to have been out of
            print before the month arrived, for we have seen an advertisement in all the papers, informing all those ladies and gentlemen who were disappointed in obtaining their numbers,
            that a new edition had been struck off.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have heard of but one new monthly journal being
            started in the country, Mr. Simms’s Southern Magazine; but
            a good many new ones will make their appearance on the
            first of January, in London : among them are “ The Shilling
            Magazine,” by Douglas Jerrold, published by the Punch
            proprietors, and “Geo. Cruikshank’s Table Book,” edited by
            Gilbert A. aBecket. Chapman &amp; Hall also announce a new
            monthly series of cheap fiction and history, among which
            will be a life of Talleyrand, by Thackeray. The “New Edinburgh Review,” for the million, price a shilling, which has
            been published a few months, appears to be thriving, and a
            new Edinburgh publication, on the million principle, has
            been announced, to be called the “ Edinburgh Tales,” by Mrs.
            Johnstone, price three half pence. A new weekly paper
            will also be started in London, price sixpence, to be called
            the Historical Register.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Bentley’s Miscellany, for December, contains the first of
            a series of papers headed, “ Notes of a Loiterer in New
            York. By Henry Cooke.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But judging from the first specimen of these new Notes
            on America, we should think they were taken by somebody
            who had never been out of the sound of Bow-bells. The
            following is said of the captain of one of our London packets : “ The little captain no sooner took command than he
            began to guess and calculate, speak through his nose, and
            brag—affording us an amusing specimen of his class. His
            ship ‘ was a pretty considerable go-ahead ship, she was;
            she would tear slick through it like a scalded hog, she
            would ; greased lightning was a fool to her, it was.’” It
            would be as impossible for any sailor to talk in this manner,
            to say nothing of the impossibility of the master of a ship
            doing so, as it would for a Russian prince. It is the Cockney imitation of a Western boatman. This is given as the
            reply of the bar-keeper of a steam-boat, which took the
            writer from the Quarantine to the Battery: “ Well, now, I
            calculate, stranger, you’ll get any drink in that there printed
            list, fixed right away, from a sherry cobbler to a common
            cocktail.” Such talk as this was never heard on our seaboard, and if ever heard in America at all, it must have been
            in a region which we have never visited. If Mr. Bentley is
            anxious to enrich his pages with specimens of Americanisms, he can find an abundance of them in American works
            within his reach ; or he will find a plenty of American pens
            that could be employed in his service, for a very moderate
            compensation.
         </p>
         <p>To CORRESPONDENTS—"P" will find a communication for him at
            our office.
            
         </p>
         <p>“ C. M.” puzzles us with his queries. We cannot decide which is the
            most popular Poet, the one whose poems go through fourteen editions of a
            hundred each, or the one whose poems reach no higher than three editions
            of a thousand each.: An edition is an edition beyond dispute, and fourteen are certainly preferable to these:: The proper authority to decide on
            the preferableness of the two cases, we think, are the poet’s publishers.
         </p>
         <p>The advice of “ F." will be duly heeded.
            
            A CARD
            NO. 203 BROADWAY.
            The Proprietor of this well known Establishment once more makes his annual salutation
            to his customers and the public, and respectfully
            begs leave to introduce to their attention his unusually fine assortment of Illustrated
            Books,
            CHOICE ENGRAVINGS AND FANCY GOODS.
            
         </p>
         <p>He would also state, that in view of his intention speedily to resign the Book Department
            of his business, in which he has been successfully
            engaged in the City for the last twenty years, the present is probably the last Card
            he will have occasion to offer to the public, and he is
            determined to sell at lower prices and smaller profits than ever.
         </p>
         <p>EXHIBITION!—A valuable and Interesting Collection of OIL PAINTINGS is exhibited in
            a Gallery connected with the Store
            Admission there one shilling.
            
         </p>
         <p>POSTSCRIPT. Per the Acadia—The Bijou Almanac for 1845; the Illuminated Almanac for
            1845 ; the lluminated Calendar for 1845 ; the
            Forget-me-not for 1845, in velvet, elegant; Ackerman’s Manual of Colors ; Cawse on
            Old Painting, last edition ; Fielding on Painting and on
            Engraving; Hayter’s Perspective ; Bright’s Advanced Drawing Book ; Procession to the
            Royal Exchange ; Comic Album ; Beauties of the
            Opera ; Clans of Scotland, part 10 ; Splendidly Illuminated Album Titles ; The Love
            Gift for 1845 ; Belle of the Hunt; Going to Cover ;
            Female Equestrians; Newhaven Fisherwomen; Foig-a-Ballagh; Opening the Royal Exchange;
            the Death Bed of Wesley, colored ;
            Momentous Question, colored ; Lord Morpeth ; Sly’s Mechanical Prints; Satirical Sketches
            ; Punch’s Locomotive ; and Bits of Fun.
         </p>
         <p>December , 1844.	WM. A. COLMAN, No. 203 Broadway.
            SPLENDID BOOKS
            SUITABLE FOR PRESENTS.
            
         </p>
         <p>JUST received by the subscribers, a large assortment
            of Splendidly Illustrated and Standard Books, all of which are
            offered for sale at reduced prices. In their collection may be found
            many costly works never before offered for sale in the United States.
            Among them are the following:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>DANIELS’ ILLUSTRATIONS OF ORIENTAL SCENERY—
            coloured in the most beautiful manner, in imitation of the original
            drawings. 6 vols. elephant folio, elegantly bound; original cost,
            $1200 ; reduced to $300.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>SELBY’S BIRDS OF GREAT BRITAIN—(in the style of Audubon’s Birds of America). 2 vols. elephant folio ; original cost,
            $600 ; reduced to $180.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>CHAMBERLAYNE’S DRAWINGS OF THE OLD MASTERS
            —being facsimiles of the most celebrated of the Roman, Florentine, and Venetian Schools. Folio ; original cost, $105; reduced
            to $28,00.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>CORONATION OF GEORGE THE FOURTH—illustrated with
            splendidly coloured Drawings, in which the portraits are taken
            from life. Folio; original cost, $262; reduced to $75,00.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>PLOOS VAN AMSTEL’S IMITATION OF DRAWINGS OF
            THE PRINCIPAL DUTCH AND FLEMISH MASTERS—
            consisting of 100 engravings. 3 vols. folio; original cost, $315;
            reduced to $90,00.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>MEYRICK'S PAINTED ILLUSTRATIONS OF ANCIENT
            ARMS AND ARMOR—the plates illuminated with Gold and Silver. 3 vols. folio; original cost, $105; reduced to $65,00.
         </p>
         <p>A Catalogue embracing 25,000 volumes of valuable Books, in every
            department of knowledge, may be had gratis, on application.
            BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, 7 Astor House.
            The Exploring Expedition
            LEA &amp; BLANCHARD are preparing for publication,
            
         </p>
         <p>and will shortly issue, the Narrative of the United States
            Exploring Expedition, during the years 1838r 1839,1840, 1841 r and
            1842, by CHARLES WILKES, U.S.N., Commander of the Expedition, etc., etc., in five magnificent large imperial octavo volumes,
            with an Atlas of Large and Extended Maps. Price Twenty-five
            Dollars to Subscribers, done up in beautiful Extra Cloth Binding.
         </p>
         <p>The First Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for
            the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMT,
            NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.
            
         </p>
         <p>GOLDSMITH’S. PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
            in 10 lessons of one hour each. Terms—Five Dollars.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
            course of instruction,including mercantile arithmetic, also Blanks and
            Stationary. Payable at the commencement.
         </p>
         <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen,
            and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            For sale “ Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
            Price Five Dollars.
            
         </p>
         <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27, 1844.
            Goldsmith’s Gems of Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
            much more important, to |many it is generally considered, and
            Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
            volume before us exhibits move taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
            of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before.
         </p>
         <p>....	•	From the New York Express.
            
         </p>
         <p>Goldsmith's Gems of Penmanship.— We have seen the original, as
            executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
            wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
            to be “ more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
         </p>
         <p>PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY
            AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
            
         </p>
         <p>Comer of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
            the Medal, four first Premiums, and two " Highest Honors,” at the
            Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
            the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
            at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
            the score of economy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American Instruments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polishing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received
            promptly attended to.
         </p>
         <p>GRAHAME’S UNITED STATES.
            THE HISTORY OF THE UNITED STATES OF
            
         </p>
         <p>NORTH AMERICA, from the plantation of the British Colonies
            till their revolt and Declaration of Independence. By James Grahame, Esq. In four volumes.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The work will be put to press as soon as two hundred and fifty
            copies are subscribed for. It will be printed in an elegant style, equal
            to the last London edition, in four volumes octavo, and delivered to
            subscribers at two dollars a volume, in extra cloth binding.
         </p>
         <p>Subscribers names received and the books delivered by Lea &amp;
            WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, New York.
            LEWIS KATEN, SIGN AND ORNAMENTAL PAINTER,
            NO. 45 WILLIAM STREET,
            (BASEMENT OF THE LEATHER MANUFACTURERS’ BANK.)
            Block Letter Signs, Transparencies, Banners, &amp;c., Executed in the
            neatest manner.
            Prospectus of the Broadway Journal,
            To be Published every Saturday.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
            to make it worthy of patronage.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers in the country ; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may “ let loose their
            thoughts,” will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate.
            It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octavo form, of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         <p>Terms $3,00 per annum—Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.
            A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.
            All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor.
            or the Broadway Journal, and all letters on business to
            JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.
            JOHN DOUGLAS, PRINTER, 68 ANN STREET.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      
      <div>
         
         
         
         <span class="person"></span>
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
         
      </div>
      
   </div>
</div>