<div>
   <div class="issueId">18451206</div>
   <div class="front">
      
      
   </div>
   <div class="body">
      
      <div>
         <p>﻿THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
            VOL. 2.
            EDGAR A. POE,
            EDITOR AND PROPRIETOR.
            NO. 22.
            NEW-YORK, SATURDAY, DECEMBER 6, 1845
            The Office of the Broadway Journal is removed to 304
            Broadway, corner of Duane.
            Epigram.
            A REBUS.
            Englished from a Philadelphia Lawyer.
            “What is a rebus V' I asked of Miss Mary,
            As close by my side the young maiden was seated;
            I saw her eye sink, and her countenance vary,
            As she said in reply—“’tis a kiss, sir, repeated.”
            YOUNG HOPEFUL, M. D.
            From the same.
            While o’er Manhattan’s isle the plague impends,
            Young Hopeful seeks the scene of misery;
            “ Many’s the death-bed scenes,” he tells his friend,
            “ This dreary summer, I expect to see.”—
            “ You are too sanguine,” cried the friendly few,
            “ You look for too much business—that you do!”
            W. Gilmore Simms.
            Pass of the Simplon Gorge of Condo.
            
         </p>
         <p>[By the courtesy of the publishers we are enabled to
            present our readers with a chapter in advance from Mr.
            Headley’s forthcoming work, in Wiley &amp; Putnam’s Library of American Books, entitled “The Alps and the
            Rhine.” We can promise our friends a book of even
            more life and spirit than the “Letters from Italy.” Mr.
            Headley has a genius for mountain scenery. His Ava-lanches, particularly, are poetical
            and magnificent.]
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Coming from the warm air of the South, the first
            sight of the Alps gave a spring to my blood it had not
            felt for years. Egypt and Palestine I had abandoned
            and weary and depressed, I turned as a last resort to the
            Alps and their glorious scenery. As I came on to Lake
            Maggiore, I was, as we should say at home, “down
            sick.” A severe cold accompanied with fever rendered
            me as indifferent to the scenery the evening I approached
         </p>
         <p>-----as if I were on the confines of a desert. But the
            
         </p>
         <p>morning found me myself again, and the clear lake
            coming from under the feet of the everlasting Alps, and
            peeping out into the valley as if to see how the plains of
            Lombardy looked, was as welcome as the face of a friend.
            Born myself amid mountains, I had loved them from boyhood. I looked out from our carriage on the Borromean
            Isles, terraced up in the form of a pyramid from the
            water, with their dark fringe of cypresses, without one
            wish to visit them. I did not care whether they were an
            "espèce de creation," or “a huge perigord pie stuck round
            with woodcocks and partridges.” The soft air revived
            me, and the breeze that stooped down from the snow
            summits of the Alps, that glittered far up in the clear
            heavens before me, was like a new fountain of blood
            opened in my system. I left the carriage, and wandered
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>off to the quarries of pink granite among the mountains.
            After listening awhile to the clink of the miner’s hammer, far up in the breast of the rock, and gathering a few
            crystals, I returned to the lake, and passing directly underneath a mountain of stone, from whose summit workmen were blasting rocks that fell with the noise of thunder into the road, sending their huge fragments over into
            the lake,—rejoined the carriage at a dirty inn. The crystal like clearness of the water, and the mountains around,
            reminded me of the wilder parts of the Delaware, where
            I had hooked many a trout, and thinking they ought to
            be found on such gravelly bottoms, I enquired of the landlord if I could have trout for dinner. He replied yes, and
            when the speckled fish was brought on the table, it was
            like the sight of an old friend. The flesh, however, did
            not have the freshness and flavor of those caught in our
            mountain streams. It may have been owing to the cooking; probably it was. After dinner we started up the
            narrow valley that leads to the foot of the Simplon. It
            was as lovely an afternoon as ever made the earth smile.
            Gray, barren pyramids of rock pierced the clear heavens
            on either side, while the deep quiet of the valley was
            broken only by the brawling streamlet that sparkled
            through it. Here and there was a small meadow spot
            from which the dwarfish peasantry were harvesting the
            hay. Women performed the office of team and cart. A
            huge basket that would hold nearly as much as an ordinay hay-cock, was filled, when a woman inserted herself
            into straps fastened to it, and taking .it on her back, walked away with it.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As it lakes twelve good hours to cross the Simplon,
            travellers are compelled to stop over night at Domo D’
            Osola, the last village before the ascent commences. I
            will not describe the dirty town with its smell of garlic,
            nor the “red-capped,” "mahogany-legged,” lazy lazzaroni that lounged through the street. Only one thing interested me in it. There is a hill near by called Calvary,
            with small white buildings stationed at intervals from
            the bottom to the top. Each of these is occupied with
            erra-cotta (earthen) figures representing our Saviour in
            the different stages of his sufferings;—from the trial before Pilate, to the last agouy of the cross. Through an
            iron grating I looked in upon the strange groups, amid
            which, on the earth-floor, were scattered cents and fifths
            of cents;—thrown there by the faithful. In one, the
            ceiling of the building was concave, and painted blue to
            represent heaven. On this angels were painted large as
            life, and represented as hovering over the suffering Christ
            —while they had—babies and all—white handkerchiefs
            in their hands, which they held to their eyes quite à la
            mode. It did not strike me at first as so odd that they
            should use handkerchiefs in heaven, as that such beggarly-looking angels could afford such nice white ones.
         </p>
         <p>But the Simplon. Nature, that wore the day before
            her loveliest, had now put on her angriest aspect. A
            
            
         </p>
         <p>more glorious to-morrow was never promised to man, than
            the sun uttered as he went down that evening amid the
            Alps. There was not a cloud to dim his brightness,
            while the transparent atmosphere and the deep blue sky
            seemed dreaming of anything hut clouds and mists. But
            who can foretell the whim of an Alpine sky ? As we entered the mountains the day grew dark, and from the
            deep gorge that pierced their heart, the mist boiled out
            like the foam of a waterfall. Clouds veiled the giant
            peaks around, and the rain came down as if that were'its
            sole business for the day. The torrent had carried away
            the read in some places, and we strolled slowly over the
            bed of the stream. At length we entered the gorge of
            Gondo, one of the most savage and awful in the Alps.—
            This day it was rendered doubly so by the black Alpine
            storm that swept through it. The road was here squeezed into the narrowest space, while the perpendicular
            rocks rose out of sight into the rain-clouds on either side,
            and the fretting torrent struggled through its torn chan-nel far below. The gallery
            of Gondo, cut 596 feet
            through the solid rock, opens like a cavern over this gulf.
            Stand here a minute and look down the gorge. Those
            perpendicular walls of nature pierce the heavens so high
            that but a narrow strip of tossing clouds is visible, as the
            blast puffs away for a moment the mist that wrapped
            them in such close embrace. A waterfall is sounding in
            your ears, covering the breast of the hill with foam, and
            filling the cavern with the sullen sound of thunder. Torrents leaping from the mountain tops, vanish in spray before they strike the bottom. The clouds roll through the
            gorge, and knock against the walls that hem them in;
            and then catching the down-sweeping, gust, spring over
            their tops, revealing for a moment the head of a black
            crag far up where you thought the sky to be, and then
            dashing over its face, wrap it again in deeper gloom.—
            All around is horribly Wild—the howl of the storm—the
            hissing of the blast around the cliffs—the roar of countless cataracts, and the hoarse voice of the distracted waters that rush on, and the awful solitude and strength
            that hem you in—'make the soul stagger and shrink back
            in unwonted fear and awe. Nature and God seem one—
            Power and Sublimity their only attributes, and these everlasting peaks their only dwelling-place. I would let the
            carriage, that looked like a mere toy among these giant
            forms of nature, disappear among the rolling mist, and
            then stand oh a beetling crag and listen. It was the
            strangest, wildest music my soul ever bowed to, and the
            voices that spoke so loudly around me, had such an accent and power that my heart stood still in my bosom.—
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I grew nervous there alone, and felt as if I had not room
            to breathe. Just then, turning ray eye up the gorge, the
            clouds parted over a smooth snow-field, that lay, white
            and calm, leagues away against the heavens. Oh, it was
            a relief to know there was one calm thing amid that distracted scene—one bosom the tempest could not ruffle: it
            told of a Deity ruling serene and tranquil above his
            works and laws.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>As we approached the summit, the snow increased in
            depth. In one place the road passed directly through an
            old avalanche cut out like a tunnel. These avalanches
            have paths they travel as regularly as deer. The shape
            of the mountain decides the direction they shall take,
            and hence enables the traveller to know when he is in
            danger. They also always give premonitions of their
            fall. Before they start there is a low humming sound in
            the air, which the practised ear can detect in a moment.
            If you are in the path of avalanches when this mysteri-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>ous warning is passing through the atmosphere, you cannot, make too good use of your legs. A few days before
            we passed, the diligence was broken into fragments by
            one of these descending masses of snow. As it was
            struggling through the deep drifts right in front of one of
            those gorges where avalanches fall, the driver heard this
            low ringing sound in the hills above him. Springing
            from his seat, he threw open the door, crying, “Run for
            your life! an avalanche! an avalanche!’’ and drawing
            his knife, he severed the traces of his horses, and bringing them a blow with his whip, sprang ahead. All this
            was the work of a single minute; the next minute the
            diligence was in fragments, crushed and buried by the
            headlong mass.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The top of the Simplon is a dreary field of snow and
            ice, girded round with drearier rocks. The hospice is
            large and comfortable, and does credit to its founder, Bonaparte; and the prior is a fat, very handsome, good-natured man. I had a regular romp with one of the San
            Bernard dogs, who would run and leap on me like a tiger––
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>barking furiously as he came—but harmless as a kitten in his frolics. To amuse us, the Prior let out four of
            them from their confinement. No sooner did they find
            themselves free, than they dashed down the steps of the
            hospice, and bounding into the snow, made the top of the
            Simplon ring again with their furious barkings. After
            we had wandered over the building awhile, and made enquiries respecting lost travellers in winter, the good Prior
            set before us some bread and a bottle of wine, from which
            we refreshed ourselves and prepared to depart. We had
            scarcely begun to descend towards the Vallais, when I
            discovered, straight down through the gorge, a little village, with its roofs and church spire, looking like a miniature town there at the end and bottom of the abyss.—
            Confident there was no town between the top of the
            Simplon and the Brieg, lying nearly twenty miles distant
            at the base, and thinking this could not he that town,
            sunk there apparently within rifle shot of where I stood,
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>I enquired of the vetturino what place it was. “ Brieg,”
            he replied. “Brieg?” I exclaimed: “why, that is six
            hours’ drive from here, and I can almost throw a stone in
            that place.” “You will find it far enough before you get
            there,” he replied, and with that we trotted on. Backwards and forwards, now running along the edge of a gulf
            deep in the mountains and under overhanging glaciers,
            till it grew narrow enough to let a bridge be thrown
            across; and now shooting out on to some projecting point
            that looked down on shuddering depths, the. road wound
            like a snake in its difficult passage among the rocks.—
            Houses of refuge occur at short intervals, to succor the
            storm-caught traveller; and over the road, as it cuts the
            breast of some steep hill, that shows an unbroken sheet
            of snow, up—up, till the summit seems lost in the heavens, are thrown arches on which the avalanche may
            slide over into the gulf below. Over some of these arches torrents were now roaring from the melting mass
            above. Calm glaciers on high, and angry torrents below;
            white snow-fields covering thousands of acres on distant
            mountain-tops, and wrecks of avalanches, crushed at the
            base of the precipice on which you stand; fill the mind
            with a succession of feelings that can never be recalled
            or expressed. It seems as if nature tried to overwhelm
            the awe-struck and humbled man in her presence, by
            crowding scene after scene of awful magnificence upon
            him.
         </p>
         <p>We stopped at Brieg all night, in a most contemptible
            inn. It was some fete day or other of the thousand and
            
            of the world three thousand eight hundred and thirty,
            
         </p>
         <p> and let us, for a few minutes, imagine ourselves at that
             most grotesque habitation of man, the remarkable city of
            Antioch. To be sure there were, in Syria and other
            countries, sixteen cities of that appellation, besides the
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>one to which I more particularly allude. But ours is that
            which went by the name of Antiochia Epidaphne, from
            its vicinity to the little village of Daphne, where stood a
            temple to that divinity. It was built (although about
            this matter there is some dispute) by Seleucus Nicanor,
             the first king of the country after Alexander the Great,
         </p>
         <p>in memory of his father Antiochus, and became immedi-
            ately the residence of the Syrian monarchy. In the flour-
            ishing times of the Roman Empire, it was the ordinary
            
         </p>
         <p>station of the prefect of the eastern provinces; and many
            of the emperors of the queen city, (among whom may be
            mentioned especially, Verus and Valens,) spent here the
            greater part of their time. But I perceive we have arrived at the city itself. Let us ascend this battlement,
            and throw our eyes upon the town and neighboring country.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“What broad and rapid river is that which forces its
            way, with innumerable falls, through the mountainous
            wilderness, and finally through the wilderness of buildings?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>That is the Orontes, and it is the only water in sight,
            with the exception of the Mediterranean, which stretches
            like a broad mirror, about twelve miles off to the southward. Every one has seen the Mediterranean; but let
            me tell you, there are few who have had a peep at Antioch. By few, I mean, few who, like you and me, have
            had, at the same time, the advantages of a modern education. Therefore cease to regard that sea, and give your
            whole attention to the mass of houses that lie beneath us.
            You will remember that it is now the year of the
            world three thousand eight hundred and thirty. Were it
            later—for example, were it the year of our Lord eighteen
            hundred and forty-five, we should be deprived of this extraordinary spectacle. In the nineteenth century Antioch
            is—that is to say, Antioch will be—in a lamentable state
            of decay. It will have been, by that time, totally destroyed, at three different periods, by three successive
            earthquakes. Indeed, to say the truth, what little of its
            former self may then remain, will be found in so desolate
            and ruinous a state that the patriarch shall have removed
            his residence to Damascus. This is well. I see you profit by my advice, and are making the most of your time
            in inspecting the premises—in
         </p>
         <p>――satisfying your eyes
            With the memorials and the things of fame
            That most renown this city.―
            I beg pardon; I had forgotten that Shakspeare will not
            flourish for seventeen hundred and fifty years to come.—
            But does not the appearance of Epidaphne justify me in
            calling it grotesque?
            “It is well fortified; and in this respect is as much in-
            debted to nature as to art.”
            Very true.
            “There are a prodigious number of stately palaces.”
            There are.
            
         </p>
         <p>“And the numerous temples, sumptuous and magnificent, may bear comparison with the most lauded of antiquity”</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>All this I must acknowledge. Still there is an infinity
            of mud huts, and abominable hovels. We cannot help
            perceiving abundance of filth in every kennel, and, were
            it not for the overpowering fumes of idolatrous incense.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>one Catholic saints, and the streets were strewed with
            evergreens, while nearly every second man had a sprig
            in his hat. The streets were filled with peasantry, sauntering about in the evening air; I leaned from my window
            and watched them as supper was cooking. There a
            group went loitering about, singing some careless song I
            could not understand, while nearer by were two peasants, a young man and a maiden, with their arms around
            each other’s waists, strolling silently along in the increasing twilight.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>At Brieg you enter on the Vallais and follow the Rhone
            on its tranquil course for Lake Leman. Its waters were
            yet turbid from their long struggle in the mountains, and
            flowed heavily through the valley. Along this we trotted
            all day, and stopped at night at Sion. If Mount Sion in
            Jerusalem is not a better place than this, the Arabs are
            welcome to it. The falls of Tortemagne, which you
            pass on the road, are very beautiful, from the curve and
            swing of the descending water, caused by the peculiar
            shape of the rocks; and those of Sallenche grand and
            striking. The long single leap of the torrent is one hundred and twenty feet, and as you stand under it, the desscending water has the appearance of the falling fragments of a rocket after it has burst. The spray that
            boils from its feet rises like a cloud, and drifting down
            the field, passes like a fog over the road.
         </p>
         <p>Sonnet.
            Fiumi, nevi gelate, orridi monti,
            Ch’ogn’hor crcscele, il mio cammin lardando,
            E me tenete da’ quegli occhi in bando,
            Per cui convien, ch’ ogni momento io conti;
            
         </p>
         <p>Sara ch’un altra volta il Sol tramonti
            Prima, ch’io lieto a lor giunga volando?
            Ch’ei ver me dolcemente folgorando
            Movan pietosi a riguardarmi, e pronti?
            Ah troppo e la via lunga, e il tempo corto;
         </p>
         <p>Ma non fiia almen, che col pensier non voli,
            Ov’io son sempre, e dove solo ho pace;
            Doglioso intanto il cor, il viso smorto,
            Andro fin ch’io vi veggia, O chiari soli;
            Che cio ch’io veggo senza voi mi spiace.
            Fabio Galeota.
            Four Beasts in One—The homo―Camelopard.
            Chacun a ses vertus.
            Crébillon's Xerxes.
            
         </p>
         <p>Antiochus Epiphanes is very generally looked upon as
            the Gog of the prophet Ezekiel. This honor is, however
            more properly attributable to Cambyses, the son of Cyrus 
            And, indeed, the character of the Syrian monarch does 
            by no means stand in need of any adventitious embellishment. His accession to the throne, or rather his usurpation of the sovereignty, a hundred and seventy-one
            years before the coming of Christ; his attempt to plunder
            the temple of Diana at Ephesus; his implacable hostility
            to the Jews; his pollution of the Holy of Holies; and
            his miserable death at Taba, after a tumultuous reign of
            eleven years, are circumstances of a prominent kind, and
            therefore more generally noticed by the historians of his
            time, than the impious, dastardly, cruel, silly and whim-sical achievments which make
            up the sum total of his private life and reputation.
         </p>
         <p>********** 
            Let us suppose, gentle reader, that it is now the year 
            
            
         </p>
         <p>I have no doubt we should find a most intolerable stench.
            Did you ever behold streets so insufferably narrow, or
            houses so miraculously tall? What a gloom their shadows cast upon the ground! It is well the swinging
            lamps in those endless colonnades are kept burning
            throughout the day; we should otherwise have the
            darkness of Egypt in the time of her desolation.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“It is certainly a strange place! What is the meaning of yonder singular building? See! it towers above
            all others, and lies to the eastward of what I take to be
            the royal palace.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>That is the new Temple of the Sun, who is adored in
            Syria under the title of Elah Gabalah. Hereafter a very
            notorious Roman Emperor will institute this worship in
            Rome, and thence derive a cognomen, Heliogabalus. I
            dare say you would like to take a peep at the divinity of
            the temple. You need not look up at the heavens; his
            Sunship is not there; at least not the Sunship adored by
            the Syrians. That deity will be found in the interior of
            yonder building. He is worshipped under the figure of a
            large stone pillar terminating at the summit in a cone or
            pyramid,, whereby is denoted Fire.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Hark!—behold!—who can those ridiculous beings
            he, half naked, with their' faces painted, shouting and
            gesticulating to the rabble?”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Some few are mountebanks. Others more particularly
            belong to the race of philosophers. The greatest portion,
            however—those especially who belabor the populace with
            clubs—are the principal courtiers of the palace, executing, as in duty bound, some laudable comicality of the
            king’s.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“But what have we here? Heavens! the town is
            swarming with wild beasts! How terrible a spectacle!
            —how dangerous a peculiarity!”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Terrible, if you please; but not in the least degree dangerous. Each animal, if you will take the pains to observe, is following, very quietly, in the wake of its master. Some few, to be sure, are led with a rope about the
            neck, but these are chiefly the lesser or timid species.—
            The lion, the tiger, and the leopard are entirely without
            restraint. They have been trained without difficulty to
            their present profession, and attend upon their respective
            owners in the capacity of valets-de-chambre. It is true,
            there are occasions when Nature asserts her violated do.
            minion;—but then the devouring of a man-at-arms, or the
            throttling of a consecrated bull, is a circumstance of too
            little moment to be more than hinted at in Epidaphne.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“But what extraordinary tumult do I hear? Surely
            this is a loud noise even for Antioch! It argues some
            commotion of unusual interest.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Yes—undoubtedly. The king has ordered some novel
            spectacle—some gladiatorial exhibition at the Hippodrome—or perhaps the massacre of the Scythian prisoners
            —or the conflagration of his new palace—or the tearing
            down of a handsome temple—or, indeed, a bonfire of a
            few Jews. The uproar increases. Shouts of laughter 
            ascend the skies. The air becomes dissonant with wind
            instruments, and horrible with the clamor of a million 
            throats. Let us descend, for the love of fun, and see
            what is going on! This way—be careful! Here we are
            in the principal street, which is called the street of Timarchus. The sea of people is coining this way, and we 
            shall find a difficulty iu stemming the tide. They are 
            pouring through the alley of Heraclides, which leads directly from the palace;—therefore the king is most probably among the rioters. Yes;—I hear the shouts of the
            herald proclaiming his approach in the pompous phrase-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>ology of the East. We shall have a glimpse of his person as he passes by the temple of Ashimah. Let us ensconce ourselves in the vestibule of the sanctuary; he
            will be here anon. In the meantime let us survey this
            image. What is it? Oh, it is the god Ashimah in proper person. You perceive, however, that he is neither a
            lamb, nor a goat, nor a satyr; neither has he much resemblance to the Pan of the Arcadians. Yet all these
            appearances have been given—I beg pardon—will be
            given—by the learned of future ages, to the Ashimah of
            the Syrians. Put on your spectacles, and tell me what it
            is. What is it?
         </p>
         <p>“Bless me! it is an ape!”
            
         </p>
         <p>True—a baboon; but by no means the less a deity.—
            His name is a derivation of the Greek Simia—what great
            fools are antiquarians! But see!—see! yonder scampers
            a ragged little urchin. Where is he going? What is
            he bawling about? What does he say? Oh! he says
            the king is coming in triumph; that he is dressed in
            state; that he has just finished putting to death, with his
            own hand, a thousand chained Israelitish prisoners. For
            this exploit the ragamuffin is lauding him to the skies.—
            Hark! here comes a troop of a similar description. They
            have made a Latin hymn upon the valor of the king, and
            are singing it as they go.
         </p>
         <p>Mille, mille, mille,
            Mille, mille, mille,
            Decollavimus, unus homo!
            Mille, mille, mille, mille, decollavimus!
            
         </p>
         <p>Mille, mille, mille!
            Vivat qui mille mille occiditl
            Tantum vini habet nemo
            Quantum sanguinis effudit!*
         </p>
         <p>Which may be thus paraphrased:
            A thousand, a thousand, a thousand,
            A thousand, a thousand, a thousand,
            We, with one warrior, have slain!
            A thousand, a thousand, a thousand, a thousand,
            
         </p>
         <p>Sing a thousand over again!
            Soho!—let us sing
            Long life to our king,
         </p>
         <p>Who knocked over a thousand so fine!
            Soho!—let us roar,
            He has given us more
            Red gallons of gore
            Than all Syria can furnish of wine !
            “Do you hear that flourish of trumpets?”
            
         </p>
         <p>Yes; the king is coming! See! the people are aghast
            with admiration, and lift up their eyes to the heavens in
            reverence. He comes;—he is coming ;—there he is!
         </p>
         <p>“Who?—where?—the king?—do not behold him;—
            cannot say that I perceive him.”
            Then you must be blind.
            
         </p>
         <p>“Very possible. Still I sec nothing but a tumultuous
            mob of idiots and madmen, who are busy in prostrating
            themselves before a gigantic cameleopard, and endeavoring to obtain a kiss of the animal’s hoofs. Sec! the beast
            has very justly kicked one of the rabble over—and another—and another—and another. Indeed I cannot help admiring the animal for the excellent use he is making of
            his feet.”
         </p>
         <p>Rabble, indeed!—why these are the noble and free citi-
            zens of Epidaphne! Beast, did you say?—take care
            
         </p>
         <p>* Flavius Vopsicus says that the hymn here introduced, was
            sung by the rabble upon the occasion of Aurelian, in the Sarmatic
            war, having slain with his own hand nine hundred and fifty of the
            enemy.
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>that you are not overheard. Do you not perceive that the
            animal has the visage of a man? Why, my dear sir,
            that cameleopard is no other than Antic hus Epiphanes
            Antiochus the Illustrious, King of Syria, and the most
            potent of all the autocrats of the East! It is true that he
            is entitled, at times, Antiochus Epimanes—Antiochus the
            madman—but that is because all people have not the capacity to appreciate his merits. It is also certain that
            he is at present ensconced in the hide of a beast, and is
            doing his best to play the part of a cameleopard; but this
            is done for the better sustaining his dignity as king. Besides, the monareh is of gigantic stature, and the dress
            is therefore neither unbecoming nor over large. We may,
            however, presume he would not have adopted it but for
            some occasion of especial state. Such, you will allow, is
            the massacre of a thousand Jews. With how superior a
            dignity the monarch perambulates on all fours! His tail,
            you perceive, is held aloft by his two principal concubines,
            Elline and Argelais; and his whole appearance would
            be infinitely preposessing, were it not for the protuberance of his eyes, which will certainly start out of his
            head, and the queer color of his face, which has become
            nondescript from the quantity of wine he has swallowed.
            Let us follow him to the hippodrome, whither he is proceeding, and listen to the song of triumph which he is
            commencing:
         </p>
         <p>Who is king but Epiphanes?
            
         </p>
         <p>Say—do you know?
            Who is king but Epiphanes?
            Bravo—bravo!
         </p>
         <p>There is none but Epiphanes,
            No—there is none:
            So tear down the temples,
            And put out the sun!
            
         </p>
         <p>Well and strenuously sung! The populace are hailing
            him ‘ Prince of Poets,’ as well as ‘ Glory of the East,’
            ‘Delight of the Universe,’ and ‘ most Remarkable of Cameleopards.’ They have encored his effusion, and—do you
            hear?—he is singing it over again. When he arrives at
            the hippodrome, he will be crowned with the poetic
            wreath, in anticipation of his victory at the approaching
            Olympics.
         </p>
         <p>“But, good Jupiter! what is the matter in the crowd
            behind us?”
            
         </p>
         <p>Behind us, did you say?—oh! ah!— I perceive. My
            friend, it is well that you spoke in time. Let us get into
            a place of safety as soon as possible. Here!—let us conceal ourselves in the arch of this aqueduct, and I will
            inform you presently of the origin of the commotion. It
            has turned out as I have been anticipating. The singular appearance of the cameleopard with the head of a
            man, has, it seems, given offence to the notions of propriety entertained, in general, by the wild animals domesticated in the city. A mutiny has been the result; and, as
            is usual upon such occasions, all human efforts will be of
            no avail in quelling the mob. Several of the Syrians
            have already been devoured; but the general voice of
            the four-footed patriots seems to be for eating up the cameleopard. ‘The Prince of Poets,’ therefore, is upon his
            hinder legs, and running for his life. His courtiers have
            left him in the lurch, and his concubines have followed
            so excellent an example. ‘ Delight of the Universe,’ thou
            art in a sad predicament! ‘Glory of the East,’ thou art
            in danger of mastication! Therefore never regard so
            piteously thy tail; it will undoubtedly be draggled in the
            mud, and for this there is no help. Look not behind
            thee, then, at its unavoidable degradation; but take
            courage, ply thy legs with vigor, and scud for the hippo-
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>drome! Remember that thou art Antiochus Epiphanes,
            Antiochus the Illustrious!—also ‘Prince of Poets,’ ‘Glory
            of the East,’ ‘ Delight of the Universe,’ and ‘ most Remarkable of Cameleopards!’ Heavens! what a power
            of speed thou art displaying! What a capacity for leghail thou art developing! Run, Prince!—Bravo, Epiphanes!—Well done, Cameleopard!—Glorious Antiochus! He runs!—he leaps !—he flies! Like an arrow
            from a catapult he approaches the hippodrome! He
            leaps!—he shrieks!—he is there! This is well; for
            hadst thou, ‘ Glory of the East,’ been half a second longer
            in reaching the gates of the Ampitheatre, there is not
            a bear’s cub in Epidaphne that would not have had a
            nibble at thy carcase. Let us be off—let us take our departure!—for we shall find our delicate modern ears unable to endure the vast uproar which is about to commence in celebration of the king’s escape! Listen! it
            has already commenced. See!—the whole town is topsyturvy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Surely this is the most populous city of the East!
            What a wilderness of people! what a jumble of all ranks
            and ages! what a multiplicity of sects and nations! what
            a variety of costumes! what a Babel of languages! what
            a screaming of beasts! what a tinkling of instruments!
            what a parcel of philosophers!”
         </p>
         <p>Come let us be off!
            
         </p>
         <p>“Stay a moment! I see a vast hubbub in the hippodrome; what is the meaning of it I beseech you?”
            ‘‘That?—oh nothing! The noble and free citizens of
            Epidaphne being, as they declare, well satisfied of the
            faith, valor, wisdom, and divinity of their king, and
            having, moreover, been eye-witnesses of his late superhuman agility, do think it no more than their duty to
            invest his brows (in addition to the poetic crown) with
            the wreath of victory in the foot-race—a wreath which
            it is evident he must obtain at the celebration of the next
            Olympiad, and which, therefore, they now give him in
            advance.
         </p>
         <p>Annette!
            With fairy feet who treads the flowers?
            Whose voice to the wind-harp sings?
            
         </p>
         <p>Whose laughter startles the silent hours
            And the shadows that brood with wide-spread wings
            On the vine-hung walls of odorous bowers,
         </p>
         <p>And over the waters of star-lit springs?
            Whose smile do I see, thou beautiful one!
            On lips like the leaves of the rose!
            Like the tremulous smile of the radiant sun
            On fields of the crusted snows:—
            Or moonbeams that play where rivulets run
            And crystal rivers repose!
            Whose eyes so surpassing the violet’s hue,
            That the violets envying weep,
            With glances of love in their depths of blue,
            Like the clear, calm skies, so distant and deep,
            Look out beneath fringes soft as the dew
            On the violets in their sleep?
            Annette! Annette! Ah, stay by my side!
            Let me hear thy tremulous tone!
            Thou art gentle and fair, like one who died,
            (Alas that she died!) in days that have flown:
            
         </p>
         <p>And no vision of pain
            Dost thou bring me again
            Of the golden-haired—the violet-eyed,
         </p>
         <p>But dreams of her beauty alone!
            A. M. Ids'
            33.
            The Fine Arts.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Art Union will distribute, on the 19th of December, whatever Paintings the Committee may have selected.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is a notorious fact that their choice of pictures has
            generally been of a character not very creditable to their
            subscribers; and, we think, not conducive to the dissemination of a true feeling for the Fine Arts. It is urged,
            in excuse, that our knowledge of Art is too limited for
            them to dare the commercial feeling of the community
            by expending their capital in purchasing only a few very
            fine paintings, when for the same amount a greater number may be procured, although of questionable merit—or,
            in other words, entirely worthless—for true art admits
            not of mediocrity.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>They say, also, that their list of subscribers would be
            diminished, and their means limited by such a course.—
            We are not sure of that; and even if such were the fact,
            what then? Is there anything gained in the cause of
            Taste, or are the Fine Arts advanced a single step, by
            giving means to painters of no capacity for their profession, and giving to the world pictures of an indifferent
            character? Such-a course only corrupts the generaltaste, and gives an uncertain recompense to the individuals who must eventually starve in the pursuit of an art
            for which they have no natural ability. Philanthropy on
            the one hand would urge the discouragement, at an early
            period, of a. pursuit that must be ruinous in the end, and
            Taste would unquestionably be improved by the destruction of abortive attempts to pourtray nature.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We would not be understood as opposed to the Association; on the contrary, we admit its general usefulness,
            and hope all our friends will give it their support. But
            we cannot forbear hinting at what we feel to be its worst
            characteristic, and hope that future committees will
            avoid all works not calculated to spread a more correct
            taste for the various Arts of Design than now exists in
            the United States.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The amount of the paid subscriptions, at this date, is
            ten thousand dollars, and will probably reach twelve
            thousand before the day of distribution.
         </p>
         <p>On the Loss of the Packet Ship “United States."
            Oh proudly down the glittering bay
            Her path the gallant vessel cleaves,
            Fair breezes speed her on her way,
            And soon behind the port she leaves;
            And friends have wav’d the last farewell,
            To those who wander o’er the main:
            Who now, alas! their fate can tell?
            That ship was never seen again!
            What hearts were in that vessel borne—
            What hopes that time can ne’er restore!
            What lovers parted on that mom,
            With vows to meet and part no more!
            What pray’rs were lor her safety said!
            How oft was Heaven invoked! In vain—
            For those she bore are with the dead—
            That ship was never seen again!
            We dare not hope, for since the mom
            When from her port that vessel sail’d,
            The moon hath twelve times fill’d her horn,
            And twelve times she her light hath veil’d!
            Did we but know how they had died,
            ’Twould be some solace to our pain;
            But fate has that sad boon denied—
            That ship was never seen again!
            We know not how she met her doom,—
            If, whelm’d beneath the raging wave,
            That bark went down ’mid storm and gloom,
            With none to see—with none to save!
            Or if by fire her fate was seal’d,—
            Or hidden rock amid the main,—
            Still is the mystery unreveal’d;—
            That ship was never seen again!
            Could we but learn her destiny,
            How ’twould relieve the aching heart;
            For fancy’s dreams away would flee,
            And all the pangs of doubt depart!
            But time rolls on,—day follows day,
            Yet does her tale untold remain,
            And we but know she sail’d away,
            And that she never was seen again!
            II C. L
            Critical Notices.
            Appleton's Literary Miscellany, No. V. The Life of
            Frederick Schiller. By Thomas Carlyle.
            
         </p>
         <p>It is but a few years since the Life of Schiller, by Carlyle, was first published in this country. The author’s
            name was not prefixed: and the book found readers only
            among the cultivated few who felt an interest in the subject, or were able to discover the rare excellence of the
            work as a literary biography. We cannot help thinking
            it the most delightful of all the writings of Carlyle. It
            was written before he had adopted the eccentricities and
            affectations of style, which have obscured so many fine
            thoughts. He was then only a “secluded individual,”
            on whose mind and heart were painted the character of
            the poet by whom he had been charmed, instructed,
            cheered and moved, and who represented this form to
            others, that they, too, might be inspired by its grace and
            majesty. And nobly did he execute a noble task. We
            rejoice that it was completed before the simplicity of his
            spirit had been invaded and corrupted by caprice; before
            the Fountain of Beauty in his soul had been turned into a
            turbid vortex; before he appeared a foreign and portentious shape to his century—not to purify—but to bewilder
            and mislead it! Nothing but what was great and elevating could emanate from a mind
            that avowed, and abided
            by such” a creed as this:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The treasures of Literature are celestial, imperishable, beyond
            all price; with her is the shrine of our best hopes; the palladium
            of pure manhood; to be among the guardians and servants of this
            is the noblest function that can be entrusted to a mortal. Genius,
            even in its faintest scintillations, is the ‘ inspired gift of God’; a
            solemn mandate to its owner, to go forth and labor in his sphere;
            to keep alive the ‘sacred fire’ among his brethren, which the heavy
            and polluted atmosphere of this world is forever threatening to
            extinguish. Wo to him if he neglect this mandate, if he hear not
            its still, small voice! Wo to him, if he turn this inspired gift into
            the servant of his vile or ignoble passions; if he offer it on the
            altar of vanity—if he sell it for a piece of money.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>This biography—(the present is a new edition, revised
            and reprinted by the author)—is not merely a sketch of
            the poet’s life. Nor is it simply a picture of him, personally and mentally, as he appears in his maturity, and as
            the world and posterity know him. It is a gradual developement of his heart and mind, of his nature as a poet
            and a man, that endears him more to us, while it enables
            us more thoroughly to comprehend him. We can trace
            here the growth of his faculties, and his progress amidst
            the struggles and obstacles of his early career; from the
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>time when his “strong, untutored spirit,” consumed by
            its own activity, was charing blindly, like ocean waves,
            against the barriers that restrained it—through difficulties and vexations which only bis burning energy of soul
            enabled him to overcome—up to that calm, intellectual
            elevation, in the lucid expansion of which he could watch
            the workings of his imagination, and subject the operations of genius to the requisitions of taste. Each of these
            separate eras in Schiller’s existence is marked by the
            character of his productions; so that his personal is
            blended with his intellectual history. Thus Carlyle has
            divided his biography into three parts. The first embraces his youth, and his first plays, the Robbers, Fiesco, and
            Kabale und Liebe; a season of wild aberrations, of stormy
            confusion, and of unregulated, exasperated enthusiasm.—
            The second period in his literary history includes the
            time that elapsed from his settlement at Manheim, to that
            at Jena. The play of Don Carlos was composed at this
            time. The third, and concluding portion, extends from
            his settlement at Jena, to his death. His greatest works
            were, produced in these last years; his character became
            fully formed; his clear, deep and comprehensive intellect was in the zenith of its glory. Yet, “his child-like
            simplicity”—that last perfection of his other excellences
            —was the most discernible. “His was a mighty spirit,
            unheedful of its might. He walked the earth in calm
            power; ‘the staff of his spear was like a weaver’s beam;’
            but he wielded it like a wand.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The translations from the tragedies of Schiller, in this
            volume, are very imperfectly executed. It is evident the
            translator has no ear for rhythm. The literal meaning is
            given, but the subtle spirit of poetry is lost in the transition if thought from one language to the other. But
            in the analysis of the plays, and in the just and discriminating criticisms, the reader may be guided safely and
            most agreeably. He will lay down the book not merely
            with intense admiration of it, but with a more elevated
            sense of the dignity of the poet’s mission, and a deeper
            reverence for the truth that still lives in fiction. He will
            exclaim, at the touching death-bed scene—“Was it not
            enough of life, when he had conquered kingdoms?”—
            “These kingdoms,” truly observes the author, “which
            Schiller conquered, were not for one nation at the expense of suffering to another; they were soiled by no patriot’s blood; no widows’, no orphans’ tears: they are
            kingdoms conquered from the barren realms of Darkness,
            to increase the happiness, and dignity, and power of all
            men; new forms of Truth, new maxims of Wisdom, new
            images and scenes of Beauty, won from the ‘void and
            formless Infinite ‘ a possession forever to all the generations of the Earth.’
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Library of Choice Reading, Nos. 34
            and 35. The Life of Louis de Bourbon, Prince of
            Condé. By Lord Mahon.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If the author of this work, in superintending its translation and preparation for the press, had indulged in occasional philosophic surveys, or in comments, suggested
            by the wild and exciting events he records, such as are expected from every historian who aims higher than a mere
            setting forth of facts—we should have found nothing to
            desire. The portion of history it embraces is that stormy,
            yet most interesting era in the annals of France, connected
            with the life of the great Condé, the chief of the Fronde,
            the illustrious rebel; the hero in whom so many splendid qualities were stained by his ingratitude towards his
            noble wife. The book is without pretension; it is a simple narration; we are hurried on, without pause, through
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>a succession of wars and intrigues; and sufficient material to fill half a dozen volumes is condensed into two.—
            At the close, the reader is left to form his own' judgment
            of the character of the hero. Notwithstanding that
            something is wanting,however, the work is deeply interesting, and a valuable contribution to historical literature.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Wiley &amp; Putnam's Foreign Library, No. V. Father
            Ripa's Residence at the Court of Peking. Translated
            by F. Prandi.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A deeply interesting book—a condensation of Father
            Ripa’s “History of the Chinese College,” published at
            Naples in 1832, in three volumes octavo. This abridgment is designed to give, only such passages of the original as relate to China generally, without particular reference to the College; the latter forming the main subject
            of the Italian work.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Pilgrim's Progress, with a Life of John Bunyan,
            by Robert Southey, Poet Laureate, etc. Illustrated
            with Fifty Cuts, by Adams, after Designs by Chapman,
            Harvey, and others. New-York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            Of course, we do not intend .to say a word in favor, of
            “The Pilgrim’s Progress” per se—we should as soon
            think of recommending the work’s of William Shakspeare; but we may say that this is a very neat edition,
            and that the illustrations throughout are highly meritorious.
         </p>
         <p>The Sufferings of Christ. By A Layman. New-York:
            Harper &amp; Brothers.
            
         </p>
         <p>This able work is the result of a careful investigation
             of the Scriptures, with the view of settling the question
            whether the sufferings of Christ were limited to his manhood alone. A beautiful octavo of 320 pages.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>A Manual of Private Devotions. For the Use of Young
            Persons. Altered from the English Edition. NewYork: Henry M. Onderdonk &amp; Co.
         </p>
         <p>The purpose of this pretty and useful little book is well
            explained in its title.
            The Whiteboy: a Story of Ireland in 1822. by Mrs. S.
            C. Hall. New-York: Harper &amp; Brothers.
            
         </p>
         <p>This is No. 65 of Harper’s Library of Select Novels—
            a series of books that cannot be too highly recommended
            to the public attention. Nowhere, within the same compass, or at the same price, is so much of real entertainment to be found.
         </p>
         <p>The Whiteboy is a powerful novel—full of vivid des-
            cription.
            Epicedium.
            They are fading, they are fading,
            Faintly, slowly, one by one;
            They are dying out. ere manhood’s
            Restless race is well begun!
            —Dim dreamings of the future,
            —They that had their joyous birth,
            In boyhood’s truant wanderings
            Or by our father’s hearth.
            They are fading, they are fading,
            
         </p>
         <p>Like the morning hosts that fling
            Their shadowy forms of glory o’er
            Some voiceful stream of Spring.
         </p>
         <p>
            —Then ye watched their gorgeous wreathings,
            —Now ye see them dimly rise,
            Till, vague and insubstantial,
            They are lost within the skies.
            They are fading, they are fading—
            And, as one by one they set,
            I do struggle to forget!
            Or, to reason vainly turning,
            Since I cannot bid them stay,
            How oft I strive to deem it but
            Wild Fantasie’s decay!
            But a sorrow, deep and voiceless,
            Across my soul will creep;
            And bitterly, oh! bitterly
            I cannot choose but weep,
            When I feel them ever fading,
            Ever dying, one by one,
            They that were wont to joy me, ere
            My boyhood’s days were done.
            R. S. Rowley
            Musical Department.
            
         </p>
         <p>Ole Bull’s Farewell Concert was attended by at least
            three thousand persons, who never, perhaps, regretted
            more not to have heard him oftener than on this evening.
            He played his Niagara and Carnival de Venice with even
            more than usual taste; and his Memory of Washington
            seemed to have new life on that evening. The Duett of
            Miss Northall and Ole Bull, composed by the latter, was
            applauded to the very echo; but we think that Miss
            Northall’s part was entirely too low to let her voice appear to any advantage. Mr. Duffield’s song pleased us
            much, as that gentleman’s songs generally please. At
            the end of the performance, a shower of bouquets, wreaths
            and poems came down on our Virtuoso, and a very short
            speech, which has had the honor of a second improved
            edition in the daily papers, concluded the evening’s entertainment Mr. Ole Bull’s luggage is now fairly
            on board the Havre packet-ship, and those who hoped
            for another opportunity of hearing the great artist,
            are this time surely disappointed. We wish him a hearty
            farewell; and may he find as many sincere friends in the
            Old country as he has left true ones in the New.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Huber’s Concert.—Our engagements kept us from attending Mr. Huber’s Concert, which appears to have been
            decidedly successful. We give, in the absence of anything from ourselves, the account of the accomplished
            critic of the Evening Gazette :
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Huber’s First Concert was a complete triumph for the great artist. Belore an audience than which he could hardly have found
            another more exacting, he displayed such a consummate mastery
            over his instrument, and so complete a comprehension of its genius, that by those who know, and the audience was full of such,
            he took first rank among the few great artists who have visited us
            and placed his violoncello by the side of the violin of Vieuxtemps
            and the piano forte of De Meyer. This was a greater feat than
            either of them have performed; for the violoncello, while it is the
            greatest, is at the same time, the most difficult of all instruments.
            The length of the stop while it enables the performer to sing upon
            this instrument more than upon the violin, makes performance
            upon it far more tasking to both the mind and the fingers. The
            tone of the violoncello has a sweetness and dignity as well as a
            power which the violin, even in the hands of the greatest performers never can have; and its harmonics have a body of tone which
            is like the highest notes of a fine flute; the violin is always a little
            flageolety.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have yet to learn whether Servais or Franchomme are more
            accomplished masters of this great instrument thsn Christian Huber. His exquisitely pure tone, sounding at times like the echo of
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>a sweet soprano voice, his power over the feelings, and the wonderful ease, almost indifference, with which he performs the greatest difficulties, place the idea of greater performances far in the
            realms of conjecture.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>His staccato is even more perfect than Ole Bull’s; because with
            equal rapidity it is both purer in tone and firmer. His harmonic
            variation in his second piece of last evening produced the greatest
            effect; it was like the softest tones of two flutes played in more perfect tune than flutes are played, save by such flutists as Mr. Kyle,
            whose performances of this evening did even him great credit, and
            were well appreciated.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We will not speak at length of his perfect bowing, his intonation, his accent, his intricate and accurate double stopping, and the
            seeming recklessness and certainty with which he passes instantly
            from the highest notes of the treble clef to the open base string;—to
            those who are not musicians it would be of little service, and those
            who are, will observe it for themselves.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>But all can appreciate the perfect ease with which all this is
            done, and the very apparent fact that he makes all this knowledge
            completely subservient to his music, and not the music to his skill.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have but time to add our satisfaction with the piano-forte
            accompaniments of Miss Huber; and also with Mr. Bristow, who,
            we are glad to see, chose this evening to make his first appearance
            in two duetts with Mr. Kyle. He deserves to become a favorite.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Tabernacle was crowded to witness the performance of Paulus, by Mendelssohn Bartholdy. Mrs. Mott
            and Mr. Paige acquitted themselves ably; and Mrs. Loder’s good style is so well known, as to allow any other
            remark than that she sang like herself.
         </p>
         <p>Miss Northall’s Concert had an unusually rich bill
            to offer. A further notice in our next.
            
         </p>
         <p>New Music.—The Bohemian Grand March, arranged
            for the Piano with the Æolian Attachment, composed by
            H. S. Saroni, published by John F. Nunns.
         </p>
         <p>Forget Thee!
            Forget thee!—oh! my spirit’s weary,
            With its long, unbroken chain!
            Forget thee!—oh! were life more dreary,
            Still thine image would remain—
            Blending with each fancy vision,
            Thoughts of love too false and frail—
            Youthful hopes that had arisen,
            Leaving manhood to bewail.
            Thine eyes of light, and face of beauty!
            Come they with a wildering spell,
            To mock my dreams of love and duty,
            With thy mystic fare thee well!
            Forget thee!—oh! though lost for ever,
            Fondly loved through vain regret—
            With a charm time may not sever,
            Memory round thee lingers yet.
            II. S. De Grove.
            ON READING MISS BARRETT’S POEMS.
            Sweet as the god-enchanting, golden song
            Which honey-tongued Apollo sung at even,)
            Before the crystal-shining gates of heaven—
            Pausing in chariot of celestial fire
            Upon the sapphire-paven street among
            The thronging angels—when, from out his lyre,
            Was rained, in lofty piles of echoing thunder,
            Which, rapt the stars with brighter newborn wonder—
            The lightning of his song which filled the sky,
            And, on the music-troubled ether-sea,
            Threatening to wreck Time’s argosy on high,
            With the swift whirlwinds of his melody—
            Was thine Evangel, sung by thee, sweet Swan!
            While floating on the streams of Albion, T. H. Chivers.
            
            Editorial Miscellany.
            
         </p>
         <p>Those of our city subscribers who failed to receive the
            Journal last week, are requested to send for it to the office, 304 Broadway. We shall endeavor to have it punctually delivered in future.
         </p>
         <p>—
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. Thomas H. Lane is the only person (besides ourself) authorized to give receipts or transact business for
            “The Broadway Journal.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>N. B.—This notice is not intended to apply to Mr.
            Wm. Fairman who, for the present, is our authorized
            agent in obtaining city subscriptions.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Edmund Burke, the editress of the “Frogpondian
            Teetotaller,” assures us, with tears in her eyes, that we
            are mistaken in supposing her “a little old lady in a
            mob cap and spectacles.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Our present impression is that she lies. However—
            we will take another look at her when we pay our next
            visit to Frogpondium—which will be soon—as we have
            a fine poem that we wrote at seven months—and an invitation to “deliver” it before the Lyceum. They want
            it immediately—they can’t wait.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The manner in which we are maltreated, of late days,
            is really awful to behold. Every body is at us—little
            dogs and all.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The littlest of all the dogs is perhaps the “Nassau
            Monthly”—whatever is the “Nassau Monthly.” Only
            hear what it says:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Every one acquainted with the literature of the day knows that
            we are abundantly supplied, it not in danger of being utterly overwhelmed, with a mass of writing, the characteristic of which it
            mere brilliancy of expression—a charming style. Examine it and
            you find no thought. You will find sparkling wit and an exquisite
            music of words, and this is all. These are the facts, we don’t intend to philosophize and so shall not seek for the causes. It may
            be the plentiful lack of genius in the present race of writers, the
            great mass of whom are mere penny-a-liners who have adopted
            writing as a mechanical trade, or it may be the general superficiality of the present race of readers which has induced this effect.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Our attention was attracted to this subject by an article of Edgar
            A. Poe, which lies among the mass on the table before us, headed
            “The Imp of the Perverse.” The author is an excellent illustration of the remarks we have just made. If asked to what species
            of the genus humbug this article properly attaches itself, we should
            reply to the humbug philosophical. We have not time to analyze,
            but would say that the author introduces himself as in pursuit of
            an idea; this he chases from the wilderness of phrenology Into that
            of transcendentalism, then into that of metaphysics generally; then
            through many weary pages into the open field of inductive philosophy, where he at last comers the poor thing, and then most unmercifully pokes it to death with a long stick. This idea he calls
            the “Perverse.”
         </p>
         <p>Byron somewhere says,
            “―there’s a courage which grows out of fear
            
         </p>
         <p>Perhaps of all most desperate, which will dare
            The worst to know it: when the mountains rear
            Their peaks beneath your human foot, and there
            You look down o’er the precipice, and drear
            The gulf of rock yawn—you can’t gaze a minute
            Without an awful wish to plunge within it.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>If Mr. Poe had been content with this and the following stanza
            he might have saved himself his chase, and his readers the trouble
            of elucidating his philosophic nonsense.
         </p>
         <p>We copy from “The Tribune” the truly beautiful lines
            which follow, not because they have not been universally
            
         </p>
         <p>copied and admired, but because we wish to place them
            carefully away within the leaves of our Journal as a precious record of unaffected pathos and enthusiasm.
         </p>
         <p>A Farewell to Ole Bull.
            BY ANNE C. LYNCH.
            There was a fountain in my heart
            Whose deeps had not been stirred—
            A thirst for music in my soul
            My ear had never heard.
            A feeling of the incomplete
            To all bright things allied—
            A sense of something beautiful,
            Unfilled, unsatisfied.
            But, waked beneath thy master-hand,
            
         </p>
         <p>Those trembling chords have given
            A foretaste of that deep, full life
            That I shall know in Heaven.
         </p>
         <p>In that resistless spell, for once
            The vulture of Unrest,
            That whets its beak upon my heart,
            Lies, charmed, within my breast.
            Pale Memory and flushed Hope forget;
            Ambition sinks to sleep;
            And o’er my spirit falls a bliss
            So perfect that I weep.
            
         </p>
         <p>Oh, Stranger! though thy Farewell notes
            Now on the breeze may sigh
            Yet treasured in our thrilling hearts
            Their echo shall not die.
         </p>
         <p>Thou’st brought us from thy Northern home
            Old Norway’s forest tones,
            Wild melodies from ancient lands
            'Of palaces and thrones.
            Take back the ‘Prairie’s Solitude,’
            The voice of that dry sea,
            Whose billowy breast is dyed with flowers,
            Made audible by thee.
            Take back with thee what ne’er before
            To Music’s voice was given—
            The anthem that ‘Niagara’ chaunts
            Unceasingly to Heaven.—
            The spirit of a people waked
            By Freedom’s battle-cry—
            The ‘Memory of their Washington’—
            Their song of victory.
            Take back with thee a loftier Fame,
            A prouder niche in Art,
            Fresh laurels from our virgin soil,
            And—take a Nation’s heart!
            
         </p>
         <p>We make no apology to our readers for occupying so
            much of our space with the following pregnant extracts
            from Mr. Simms’ editorial farewell, in the last number
            of his Magazine:
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The business, as conducted by Harper &amp; Brothers, is pretty
            much that of every publishing house in the country, except that, in
            few instances, do we find the publishers to be printers also. That
            they are so, gives Harper &amp; Brothers some advantage. The pub–
            lishing cities are three in number. New-York takes the first rank
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>in regard to the frequency of its issues. Philadelphia occupies the
            next place, and Boston the third. In the latter city, the tastes are
            more fastidious, and the critical standards more parochial. Here
            they do not often publish the works of any but New-England authors; and their local criticism, influencing the publishers necessarily, seems to have had the effect of narrowing their regards to such
            writings only, as, forbearing to offend conventional taste and opinion, are not likely to venture upon any of those daring outlawries
            which constitute what is called genius. A nice propriety of manner, a delicate taste, a subtle or a pretty fancy, admitting a little
            quaintness of style or its affectation as an. ingredient that may serve
            instead of other condiment—these, with the requisite amount of recognized philosophy—are the qualities which satisfy commonly the
            Boston publisher. He puts forth the greatest amount of verse which
            is published in the country. He has a faith in Lowell and Longfellow, and Whittier, and even believes in Miss Gould and Mrs.
            Sigourney. That he is right in regarding the three former as persons of very considerable merit, is unquestionable. We look upon
            Lowell as decidedly the best of the three, more of a poet and less of
            an artist than Longfellow, and more pregnant with thoughts and
            fancies, original and fresh, than either. That he has certain affectations from which he has need to free himself with all expedition,
            is probably the consequence of his too greet subservience, just now,
            to the spirit that presides over his local criticism. Longfellow is
            an artist—delicate, graceful, ingenious—in all the respects of versemaking. He has an exquisite ear for the appreciation of the harmonies of language—but it strikes us that it would not be difficult
            to point to the ear-mark of another in the thoughts contained in
            every sentence which he ever penned. His first labors in verse
            were the most servile copyings of Bryant. The Germans and
            early English song writers furnish his present models. His drama
            of the ‘Spanish Student,’ with some pretty passages, is a bald and
            feeble copy, with little that is original, with nothing that is bold,
            and, very little that is marked with vivacity or spirit. It is the
            grace and sweetness of his verse, and that extreme simplicity of the
            thought which taxes no intellect to scan—which we read as we run
            —that constitutes his claims upon the reader. Whittier has energy
            and life. He is bold and manly, and with less of the spiritual, or
            higher element of poetry, possesses much of the faculty which is
            successful in the didactic, the moral and the descriptive. He has
            force enough for an ode writer, and upon national or sectional topics, could meet the requisitions of the moment with much more
            success than either of the former. A Fourth of July ode,—something on the battle of Bunker’s Hill, or a vindictive apostrophe to
            Virginia, Carolina, or Louisiana, on the subject of slavery, and the
            treatment of good old Mr. Hoar, the representative of Massachusetts—would, at his hands, be a fierce lyric that would not discredit
            the days of Puritanism in its fervor, its energy, its concentrative
            audacity of aim and flight. His muse is declamatory at present—
            a few years hence and she will mature into the contemplative, and,
            unless she becomes more spiritual at the same time, will become
            drowsy in due degree with her loss of energy and blood. Our hope
            of these three, is in Lowell. But he must address himself to his
            work as if it were work, and abandon the making of fugitive verse.
            His genius will do better things in taking longer flights.* Hawthorne, a delicate, essayical prose writer, has a fine fancy of his
            own, which sometimes imps the soarings of the ambitious muse —
            He is a naive and generous in his genius, quite unaffected, (as we
            think,) and capable, in another atmosphere, of more courageous
            things. Of Emerson, we frankly confess, our expectations are very,
            high in spite of his Carlyleisms. We are not disposed to underrate
            Carlyle, but we loathe this readiness, which is so American (in our
            literature at least) of being this or that Englishman’s man. Emerson’s Essays'declare a mind of his own, which can only be sure of
            itself and of future justice, by breaking loose, as soon as possible,
            from the leading strings of the European model. Some of his
            poetry has always seemed to us at once fresh, felicitous and true.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“The Poets and Poetry of Europe,” by Longfellow, has reached
            us. This is a volume that has been looked for with some anxiety
            It is a work of interest and value, but not, altogether, such as we bad
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>* Here we disagree. A long poem is a paradox. Whatever
            hereafter shall be done greatly must be done in fugitive verse.—
            Ed. B. J.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>a right to look for, at the hands of Mr. Longfellow. It will amply
            answer the demands of the public, affording certainly, a general,
            and not incorrect idea, perhaps, of what the muse has been doing,
            in past and present times, upon the continent. But it has not been
            a labor of love with the editor. He has not expended much of his
            own time or talent upon it. His own good taste does not frequently inform its pages. He has been content to compile it from whatever materials have been most convenient—has helped himself,
            without scruple, to the riff-raff translations of beginners, who, learning the several languages, have sent their crude exercises to the
            magazines. Mr. Longfellow’s own hands do not sufficiently appear in these translations, and the work might just as well have
            been executed by a common workman. Now, it is as a translator,
            that Mr. Longfellow’s chief excellence appears, and his own reputation, no less than the public expectation, required that he should
            have given himself up more thoroughly to this performance. Still,
            the volume is a fair one, which will answer the proposed object.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In New York, as might be expected in the case of the metropolis,
            there is a degree of activity in the publishing world, to which we
            find no approach in any other part of the country. This is due to
            several causes,—the great number of the population,—the commercial intercourse which it maintains by its shipping, with other
            places, and its intimate connection with Europe. We need not go
            into details. It is inevitable, perhaps, that the great metropolitan
            city of a country will be the place in which the men of science and
            literature will ultimately congregate. Here will they attain their
            levels, by comparison with rival minds, and in the determination
            of their several statures, fix the standard of merit for the guidance
            of a nation at large. It has been one of the evil circumstances in
            the way of just judgment, and of impartial criticism among us, that
            we have several rival publishing cities, in all of which, conflicting
            standards are set up, each swearing by its own particular idol.
            France has but one Pans, England but one London, and we hear
            nothing of the great names of either country, away from its capital
            city. New York must and will be our centre, and present indications seem to show that the period rapidly approaches, when her
            superiority will he completely acknowledged. The sufficient proof
            is in the fact, that hither tend writers from all quarters of the country, east and west, north and south, in order to obtain utterance
            through the medium of the press. We allude, now, to the purely
            literary and original writers. Compilers of school books, dictionaries, grammars, &amp;c. as they address themselves only to a demand
            which is arbitrary and absolute, and appeal but little to the tastes,
            and wholly to the necessities of the country, are never suffered to
            enter into any general estimates of the literary doings of a people.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>It is ordinarily hard work to pursuade one’s immediate neighbors of his possession
            of any special merits;—“’tis distance lends
            enchantmentto the view,"—and this locally disparaging judgment,
            was still farther exercised by an influence, which has always been
            unfavorable to works of original character. Our publishers,—not
            usually men of letters themselves,—are in the habit of retaining
            certain employees, who examine manuscripts, and declare upon
            their merits. These persons, in the language of the trade, are ordinarily styled “readers.” An author whose merits are known to
            the publisher, by frequent appearances before the public, is, of
            course, seldom or never subjected to an ordeal, which is sometimes
            an humiliating one,—since, as in the case of Scott and Bulwer,
            he most admirable writings of genius may be put under the ban,
            by an individual not capable of understanding them, or one who
            may have his own prejudices, or other personal virtues operating
            to make him commit an injustice, from which,—at least so far as
            Ms employers are concerned,—there is seldom any appeal. It
            would amuse, did our space allow, to point to the number of instances, in England and America, Where books, which have proved subsequently the most famous and successful, have been thrown
            out and rejected, by the “readers” of some of the greatest publishing houses in the two countries. For an interesting view of this
            subject, let us refer the reader to the volume, by H. R. Horne, entitled “The False Medium,” a work intended to show by what
            variety of influences, the man of genius is kept from the hearing
            of the public. Now, a moment’s reflection will serve to convince
            any reflecting mind that, ordinarily, the critic for a publishing
            house must, necessarily, give Ms judgment against works of original
         </p>
         <p>
            
         </p>
         <p>merit. He is engaged by the. publisher, because of the supposed
            safety of his judgments. He is usually a person well read in the
            current literature of the day and country,—he is supposed to know
            what ordinarily pleases the public, what, in other words, is likely
            to sell,—and to be heedful that the works published shall offend no
            sects and parties, by which the success and circulation of the publication will be prevented, or impaired. To be able to pen a respectable common-place English paragraph in regard to the book
            he recommends,—to be able to say of it, that it is in the beaten
            track, that it violates no usages, or standard principles,—that it is
            in the common fashion of such things,—that it is safe,—will do,—
            must sell,—will suit the vulgar taste, and vex no vulgar prejudices,—these are all the ordinary requisites that go to make up the
            “reader” for a modern publishing establishment. Now, at the
            first blush of the matter, we must see that the, very fact of originality is against the book offered for the examination of such a
            critic. The very requisition of the publisher, under and for whom
            he works, makes against the writer. He startles,—he may offend,
            —he is novel, but may not be popular. It is safer to reject than to
            publish, and the original production is vetoed accordingly. This
            s a frequent history in literature; and it arises from a cause the
            operations of which are particularly manifest in the history of
            American literature. Thus guided, thus governed, our publishers
            do not keep pace with the progress of the very mind they teach.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Having furnished their readers, for twenty years or more, with
            a certain class of books, calculated for a people in their leading
            strings, they are slow to discover that they, in time, come to need
            higher authorities. They fancy the popular mind to be as they
            found it, and make no allowances for a progress inevitable from
            their own publications. These publications have gradually lifted
            the mind, and no longer suffice to satisfy its cravings. The people look around for stronger aliment, but the old publishers, having survived their mission, keep hammering away at the old
            rate, as if they still had to deal with children in their accidence.
            Suddenly, a new publisher starts up. A happy casualty informs
            him. A sudden suggestion unseals his vision. He sees, or fancies, an opening,—tries the experiment,—furnishes a new class
            of writings to his public, and leaps suddenly into fortune, rubbing his eyes and wondering at his own good and wholly unexpected luck. We have a case of this sort in the history of
            Wiley and Putnam’s “Library of Choice Reading.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>He, therefore, whose object is pecuniary recompense, will do well
            to weigh cautiously the question before renouncing, for the pursuits
            of letters, the ordinary objects of social enterprise and industry.—
            The man whom nature drives, in his own spite, and in utter disregard to his neighbors, has a destiny to obey, and must submit with
            meekness and patience to his allotment. But to him who hankers
            after the creature comforts, let him turn to any other craft; securer
            in. any other, of much more wot Idly recompense than be will find
            in this. Nor is the pay derived from periodical writing of a better
            character. It should be better, for no species of literary labor is
            more utterly exhausting, as its habitual exercise demands constant
            transition of subject, and as constant transitions of the mind from
            thought to thought. But, of all the American periodicals, there is
            not one which pays all its contributors. Among the best of them,
            but one in a score receives any compensation, and this is usually
            an amount so small, as to discourage the industry of writers who
            set much value upon their performances. Godey’s and Graham's
            Magazines, have been among the most liberal, having paid certain
            of their contributors for their articles, at rates which would not discredit the reported liberality of the British publishers. But the
            palmy days have gone by, even with these journals, and they were
            never marked with a white stone by the generality of contributors.
            These statements differ largely from some that occasionally make
            their way into the newspapers; but they are not the less true for all
            this. The vanity of authors frequently prompts them to report their
            anticipations as realized results; and a false civility, and something of the same passion, keeps the publisher from contradicting
            them. In the matter of magazine and periodical writing, we may
            add, that the author is constantly the victim of lying editors and
            publishers, who beguile him of his writings and abuse him, from
            their chair of criticism, if he ventures to complain. There is not a
            professional literary man of the country, who has not a long story
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>to relate, of the arts by which he has been swindled of his contributions* by that class of insects of literature, whom Moore compares
            with the maggot who is said to feed and fatten upon the brains of
            the elk,—the noble animal perishing finally, the prey of the miserable insect which has fed upon his life.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“The New York Evangelist”—in all respects an able,
            and what is still more rare, an unprejudiced journal, has
            a strongly condemnatory review of “Festus” from which
            (the review) we quote a few passages, without altogether
            acquiescing in the opinions expressed.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>In justice to the author of this poem, we ought to say that it was
            commenced before he was twenty years of age. This he tells us
            in its dedication to his father, calling it “a boyish feat,” and stating
            also that it took three years to complete it. This being the case, if
            his father read the poem before it was published, however rich
            might be the promises of genius which he saw in it, had he been a
            wise parent, he would have committed it to the flames, or locked it
            up for his son’s perusal some ten years older. The genius possessed by its author could have lost nothing in the destruction of
            this wild, deformed, perverted offspring, and the world would have
            lost less. As it is, the father and son must have been educated under the strangest compound of grotesque beliefs and unbeliefs that
            ever had existence, to have felt willing to exhibit to the world such
            a medley ol insane speculation, bad theology, and blasphemous,
            immoral principles. If to many of the readers of this poem we
            seem harsh and severe, let it be remembered that we deny not the
            genius and talent manifest in many parts of It, a degree of genius
            that might have composed a poem which would instruct all mankind, and which the world would not willingly let die. But how
            can we justly praise the talents that are so wantonly, so miserably
            perverted and misapplied?
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The genius and rich imagery in the poem will be praised by
            many, who care little or nothing forks moral or immoral coloring
            and tendency, and the gifts of imagination displayed in it are the
            very vehicles by which alone its poison cart be carried into society.
            Divested of that, its doctrines would be rejected as the stale and depraved ravings of an impious mind; just as some of Byron’s productions would be seen nowhere but in filthy, festering hawkshops,
            were it not that genius has stooped to dip up the mud, and put it
            in a jeweled case for respectable drawing rooms and circulating
            libraries! Depraved genius does more to deprave the world, than
            any other source of evil.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Amherst College.—From the catalogue of Amherst
            College, just published, it appears that the number of
            undergraduates is 118, viz: Seniors 26, Juniors 23, Sophomores 35. Freshmen 34. Besides the President, Rev.
            Edward Hitchcock, LL-D, there are five Professors, and
            two other instructors. The Hon. Wm. B. Calhoun lectures on political economy.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>German Newspapers.—It will be remembered that by an edict
            of the German Government, German papers printed in the United
            States have been prohibited an entry into the Germanic States.
            Some German editors in ibis country have written to Mr. Buchanan proposing to send their papers to the U. S. Legation in Berlin,
            and asking whether, in the event of their in erception, the U. S.
            Government will acquiesce in that proceeding,
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. Buehanan replies that the German Diet have an undoubted
            right to make laws lor the Germanic Slates, and that the U. States
            Government will not, of course, interfere with their execution. He
            says that the edict in question  "must be condemned by liberal men
            on both sides of the Alantic,” but that we cannot interfere with it
            in any way.—Tribune.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Literature of the Sandwich Islands.—There are
            five newspapers now published at Honolulu;—four in
            English and one in the Hawaiian language;—a striking
            illustration of the power of Christian instruction, which,
            in the course of twenty-five years, has raised these islands
            from the lowest state of degradation to a respectable rank
            among civilized nations.
         </p>
         <p>* We ourselves have no complaint to make on this score — Ed B. J.
            
            
         </p>
         <p>The Author of the “Vestiges.”—It is said that Sir
            Richard R. Vyvian, Bart. M. P. author of “Vestiges of
            the Natural History of Creation,” is preparing for the
            press another philosophical work, to be entitled “The
            Harmony of the Visible Creation.”
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>New Literary Paper.—Charles F. Hoffman, Esq., is
            about to assume the editorship of a new and expensive
            weekly journal of literature and criticism, which will
            be published by Hewitt, the embellisher of Shakspeare.
            The new paper is to be called the “Excelsior.”
         </p>
         <p>NEW BOOKS,
            TO BE PUBLISHED BY
            MESSRS. WILEY &amp; PUTNAM,
            IN DECEMBER.
            I.
            
         </p>
         <p>Carlyle’s new Work. The Letters and Speeches of Oliver Cromwell, with Elucidations, by Thomas Carlyle, in 2 vols, 8vo., with
            Portrait, engraved by F. Hall from an original by Cooper, in the
            possession of Archdeacon Berners. Also, 2 vols. 16mo., in the
            “Library of Choice Readings.”
         </p>
         <p>II.
            
         </p>
         <p>Stories from the Italian Poets, being a summary in Prose of the
            Poems of Dante, Pulci, Bolardo, Ariosto, and Tasso, with comments throughout, occasional passages versified, and Critical Notices of the Lives and Genius of the Authors. By Leigh Hunt,
            16mo.
         </p>
         <p>III.
            The Book of Christmas. By T. K. Hervey.
            IV.
            Views and Reviews in American History, Literature, and Art. By
            W. Gilmore Simms.
            V.
            The Alps and the Rhine. By J. T. Headley.
            VI.
            Mrs. Southey's Poems. The Birth-day, and other Poems—Solitary
            Hours. By Caroline Southey, 2 vols. lGmo.—(Shortly.)
            VII.
            The Author of “ Undine.” Theiodolf the Icelander. By La Motte
            Fouqué, 16mo.
            VIII.
            
         </p>
         <p>Tales from the German of Zschokke, second series. Illumination;
            or, the Sleep-walker—The Broken Cup—Jonathan Frock—The Involuntary Journey—Leaves from the Journal of a Poor Curate in
            Wiltshire. By Parke Godwin.
         </p>
         <p>IX.
            The Vicar of Wakefield—An edition on superior paper, with
            choice Illustrations by Mulready.
            JUST PUBLISHED.
            The Life of the Great Corule. By Lord Mahon, forming Nos.
            XXXIV. and XXXV. ot “The Library of Choice Reading.”
            Dec 4	WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            PAINE &amp; BURGESS, 62 JOHN STREET.
            HAVE lately published—
            1. The Artist, Merchant and Statesman, 2 vols. l2mo.
            2. Trippings in Authorland, by Fanny Forrester, 12mo.
            3. Songs and Ballads, by Geo. P. Morris, 32mo. gilt.
            4. Prariedom; Rambles and Scrambles in Texas, or New Estra-
            madura, with a Map, by a Southron, 1 vol. 12.no.
            5. Autobiography of Alfieri, 1 vol. 12mo.
            6. Citizen of a Republic, by Ceba, 1 vol. 12mo.
            7. Florentine Histories, by Machiavelli, 2 vols. 12mo.
            8. Challenge of Barletta, by D’Azeglio, 1 vol. lmo.
            9. Musical Spelling Book, by E. Ives, 1 voi. 8vo.
            10. Beethoven Collection of Sacred Music.
            
         </p>
         <p>11. Rambles by Land and Water, or Notes of Travel in Cuba and
            Mexico,elegantly illustrated by B. M. Norman, 1 vol. 12mo.
            NEARLY READY.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>1. Montezuma : The Last of the Aztecs, an Historical Romance on the Conquest of Mexico, by Edward Uaturin, 2
            vols. 12mo.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>2. Morris&amp; Willis’ Library of the Rose and Poetry of Europe
            and America, 1 vol. royal 8vo. An elegant and valuable
            Gift Book.
         </p>
         <p>3. Old Continental: or the Price op Liberty, by the author of
            “Dutchman’s Fireside,” 2 vols. l2rao.
            4. Man in the Republic, by C. Mathews, 32mo. gilt.
            5. Musical ABC, for children, lGmo.
            6. Greece of the Greeks, by G. A. Perdicaris, late U. S. Consul
            at Athens, 2 vols. 12mo. illustrated.
            7. Musical Reader, 4to.
            8. The Prince, by Machiavelli, 1 vol. 12mo.
            9. The Musical Wreath, 4to.
            10. Over the Ocean! or Glimpses of .Many Lands, by a Lady.
            
         </p>
         <p>Statue for Mr. Clay.—The ladies of Virginia, who
            have united to raise money to erect a statue of Henry Clay,
            announce that they have been successful in obtaining the
            necessary funds; and that they have selected Joel S. Hart,
            a native of Kentucky, to make the statue.
         </p>
         <p>A Siamese Newspaper is now published in Bangkok,
            chiefly under the direction of the American Missionaries.
            ELEGANT NEW WORK.
            C. SHEPARD, BOOKSELLER, 191 BROADWAY.
            
         </p>
         <p>C HAUNT OF LIFE—and other Poems, by Rev. R. Hoyt, a
            Clergyman of the Episcopal Church, New York. Parts 1 &amp; 2.
            This work is beautifully printed on fine paper, embellished, and
            handsomely bound: Price 37 1/2 cents.
         </p>
         <p>The following are extracts from a few of the notices it has re-
            ceived from the Press:—
            
         </p>
         <p>“There is a natural vigor in this poem (World for Sale) which
            is wrung from the life,—a wild music from the very heart strings.”
            —Morning News.
         </p>
         <p>“This is a scene (snow) that every one will recognize as life-
            like and truthful,—no artist could paint it better.’—Hud. Riv.
            Chronicle.
            “We have seen many quartos, not taken either from the lowest
            rank of dullness, with far less that is acceptable in them.”—Dem.
            Review. 
            
         </p>
         <p>“We commend this volume to the lover of true poetry, and can
            say, in all sincerity, if Mr. Hoyt, in his following numbers, sustains the character of this, there is no doubt of his success.”—N.
            Y. Evening Mirror.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“It is primed in a very neat and even elegant style, worthy of
            the grace, delicacy and beauty of the poems.”—A’. Y. Courier and
            Enquirer.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“He writes with grace, taste and genius, and many of his productions possess merit of the highest order. Some of his best
            pieces will be incorporated in a new edition of the Poets and
            Poetry of America.”—Phil. Nat. Gazette.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“We give a stanza from the principal poem in the volume,
            commending this delicious little brochure as one of the best New
            Year’s presents that could be selected.”—N. Y. Express.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>"The Chaunt is one of the finest modern poems that we have
            read this many a day, and abounds in highly wrought and beautiful
            passages. The author, Rev. Ralph Hoyt, is destined to a high
            rank in the American temple of poetry, and we heartily thank
            him for providing us such a rare poetic feast as he has given us
            in this volume.”—N. Y. Rambler.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“ Full of delicate description, perfect truth and beauty of sentiment; and style pare and limpid as the chrystal stream, all enveloped in a charming atmosphere of grace and piety and purest imagination. It is a gem and a noble offering,"— Churchman.</p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“Part II. contains the second canto of a very fine poem,—the
            Chaunt of Life: From the first stanza we quote three remarkably
            beautiful lines. The fourth and fifth stanzas are very noble.—
            The poem Old has so many rare and peculiar excellences, that
            we shall venture to copy it in full.”— Broadway Journal.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“The Chaunt of Life is like the opening of some glorious majestic strain of music,
            through which the mournful spirit of the
            past gives tone and unutterable earnestness to the aspirations of
            the present and the hopes of the future. Such strains as those of
            our author will be heard. They sink at once into the heart and
            abide there.”—Prot. Churchman.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>“We have not seen a volume in a year that we have been more
            taken wi˙h than this. It is a pleasure to meet an author who can,
            like Mr. Hoyt, make his theories attractive and his method striking without setting up for a misanthrope, or invoking the aid of
            the internals.—Phil. Sal. Eve. Post.
         </p>
         <p>GURNEY’S
            PREMIUM DAGUERRIAN GALLERY,
            189 BROADWAY, NEW-YORK.
            
         </p>
         <p>PICTURES taken at this Establishment are not excelled in this
            country—so say his numerous patrons. The public are invited to call and judge for themselves.	o2
         </p>
         <p>G. B. CLARKE,
            
         </p>
         <p>MERCHANT TAILOR, (from Brundage, Broadway)
            No 132 William Street, 3 doors from Fulton, N. Y.
            Dress Coat, from $12 to $20 00              Making and Trimming
            Pants,	“	2 50 to 8 00    Dress Coat, from $6 00 to 9 00
         </p>
         <p>Vest,	“	150 to 4 50     Pants,	«	150 to 2 00
            Vests,	“	1 50 to 2 00
            N. B. Seasonable SACK COATS, VESTS, &amp;c. always on
            hand, from $1 50 upwards.	nov8—3m
            
            THIS DAY IS PUBLISHED—IN ADVANCE OP THE LONDON EDITION,
            LIFE OF THE GREAT CONDE.
            BY LORD MAHON.
            Two Numbers beautifully printed, in clear type, $1 00. “A highly interesting and skilful
            narrative.”— Quarterly Review
            The above work forms Nos. 34 and 35 of the Library of Choice Reading.
            Published and for sale by WILEY &amp; PUTNAM, 161 Broadway.
            	J. F. B R O W N E &amp; CO.
            MANUFACTURER OF THE
            IMPROVED PATENT DOUBLE-ACTION HARP,
            By Royal Letters Patent, London. Established 1810. (Many years, with Erard.
            JF. BROWNE respectfully informs his Friends and the Musical World, that he has established
            himself for the manufacture
            • and importation of these very beautiful instruments, at
            281 BROADWAY, and 73 1-2 CHAMBERS STREET.
            His arrangements are such as to enable him to transact business at European prices,
            thereby saving purchasers the high duties
            mposed by Tariff on these Instruments.
            
         </p>
         <p>J. F. Browne would observe, these Harps are constructed on the most approved principles,
            with all the modern improvements of
            London and Paris, are unequalled in brilliancy of tone, fineness of touch, and perfectness
            of mechanism. Particular care is taken
            to fit them for the extremes of climate in this country, in which respect they will
            be found far superior to any of European manufacture, imported in the usual way.
         </p>
         <p>These Harps are patronized by the elite of musical taste and professional talent in
            Europe; among the latte r,he would mention
            N. C. Boscha, who invariably selects from this establishment.
            J. F. Browne begs to offer the opinions of some of the first professional talent in
            this country.
            
         </p>
         <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir Having had for several years past, the opportunity of making
            a professional use of your Harps and of
            testing their qualities, it affords me pleasure to certify, that in point of tone,
            workmanship, and above all, a solidity that stands proof
            against the inconstancy of our trying climate, they have in all cases given me the
            most entire satisfaction
         </p>
         <p>January, 1845.	I am yours, CHARLES THIBAULT, No. 40 Beach St., N. Y.
            
         </p>
         <p>Dear Sir I write to express the delight I experienced in performing on one of your
            Harps at Sig. Casella’s Concert in this citv—
            The mechanism is perfect, and the quality of Tone certainly superior to any harp I
            have heard for many years. I remember my old
            Master, Boscha, always gave the preference to your Harps, indeed he himself used no
            other. Yours, most truly H. G. TRUST
            Philadelphia, March 4th, 1844.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir :—I have much pleasure in saying, that the Harp of your make
            I performed on at the St. George's Society
            Concert, is, in brilliancy of tone, touch, and elegance of workmanship, the finest
            I ever played on. This will apply to all your Harps
            The grand six and a half Gothic Double action, is a most splendid instrument. Yours,
            with respect, ELIZABETH SLOMAN.
            New York, January 16th, 1845.	A pupil of N. C. Boscha.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Mr. J. F. Browne, Sir Having at your request closely scrutinized your double-action
            Harps, I find they possess the best qualities of the first makers in Europe combined. That in the ease of touch, by which the
            most brilliant tone is obtained, in perfection and
            ease of modulation, they are superior to any I have used; their elegance of exterior
            must gratify the most refined taste. Your new
            Grand Gothic six and a half octave, is the most splendid effort of art yet produced
            in the musical world ; it will give me great pleasure
            in recommending your Harps at every opportunity.	Yours Truly, HENRY HORN.
         </p>
         <p>January 12th, 1845.	An eminent professor, and Member of the Royal Academy.
            
         </p>
         <p>These are but a very small part of the testimonials received, but will suffice to
            show the estimate of persons every way capable of
            making a correct decision. J. F. Browne has also received the Franklin Medal of the
            Society of Aits, Philadelphia, for his splendid
            improvements in this delightful Instrument.
         </p>
         <p>Harps from 300 to 1000 dollars. Harps repaired, strings, &amp;c.
            
         </p>
         <p>JOHN N. GEN IN,  FASHIONABLE HAT AND CAP ESTABLISHMENT,  214 Broadway.	JAMES PIRSSON,
            PIANO FORTE MANUFACTURER, 88, 90, and 92 A Walker street, near Elm. A large stock
            of the finest instru- ments always on hand. Terms moderate. For Sale—A splendid Harp,
            nearly new—to be sold at a, great bargain for cash. 
            PIANO FORTES.  CHEAP FOR CASH.—The Subscribers have on hand a  handsome assortment,
            6, 6 1/2, and 7 octave mahogany and rose- wood Pianos, which they will warrant and
            sell low for cash or ap- proved paper. GLENN, ROGERS &amp; CO.,  Manufacturers, 152 Fulton
            street, east of Broadway.	
            	J. BALLARD,  PROFESSOR OF THE GUITAR, SINGING AND FLUTE. No. 135 Spring-street.
            General Furnishing Hardware, Cutlery, Tools. &gt;fcc-  OSBORN &amp; LITTLE,  Importers and
            General Dealers in English, German and  American  hardware, cutlery, &amp;c.,  No. 33
            FULTON STREET,  BETWEEN PEARL AND WATER STREETS,  [Where the business has been carried
            on lor Eighty Years past,]  CHARLES OSBORN. » NEW YORK.  CHARLES S. LITTLE. )  Hardware,
            Cutlery, Nails, Locks, Latches, Butts, Screws, An vils Vices, Saws, Files, Shovels
            and Spades, Hollow Ware, Corn and’ Coffee Mills, Rivets, Pumps, Curriers’ Hones, Crucibles,
            Black Lead Pots, &amp;c. &amp;c. Also Genuine Haarlem Oil. Ameri- can Coopers and Carpenters
            Edge Tools, of Albertson’s Conger’s Barton’s, Horton’s, Gifford’s, and other makers.
            Also, Cooper’s Truss Hoops. nov8—3m	PENMANSHIP.   RE-OPENING OF GOLDSMITH’S WRITING
            ACADEMY 289 Broadway—La Farge Buildings, corner of Reade street Terms reduced to three
            dollars, and no extra charge.  Mr. Oliver B. Goldsmith respectfully informs the citizens
            of New York and Brooklyn, that his rooms are now open, during the day and evening,
            lor Pupils and Visitors. Mr. G’s. specimens of PENMANSHIP  have received the First
            Premium Five Years, from the American Institute, and he guarantees to all in TEN EASY
            AND INTER- ESTING EXERCISES, a free and elegant style of writing, that the pupils
            cannot possibly ever lose in their future practice.  For sale at the Academy GOLDSMITH’S
            GEMS OF PEN- MANSHIP.  Ladies’ Class meets daily at 11 o’clock. Gentleman’s day and
            evening. See circular. .s18
            	WEDDING, VISITING, &amp; PROFESSIONAL CARDS    Engraved and Primed at VALENTINE’S, 1
            Beekman-st. Lovejoy’s Hotel.
            JOHN ANDERSON &amp; CO.  IMPORTERS AND DEALERS IN  CHOICE SEGARS, and Manufacturers of
            Premium Tobacco and Snuffs—a Wall, and 13 and IS Duane streets, ew-York. nov8-3m	
            	JOHN BURFORD,  PORTRAIT AND LANDSCAPE PAINTER,  27 Dey Street.
         </p>
         <p>,
            CATALOGUE OF TEAS,
            ON SALE AT THE TEA WAREHOUSE OF THE
            PEKIN TEA COMPANY,
            Importers of fine Green and Black Teas, No. 75 Fulton-st.
            New York.
            
         </p>
         <p>[The Teas mentioned in this Catalogue are done up in quarter,
            half pound, and pound packages—the first, or inside wrapperis lead,
            the second wrapper is water proof paper, and the third or outside
            wrapper is of Chinese Rice paper. The Company sell none but
            good Teas, done up in this superior manner, all of them grown in
            the most luxurious districts in China. Country dealers can select
            as small a quantity of each kind as they like and have them packed
            in one chest. These Teas also come in five pound Chinese packages, called quattoons, a very convenient, fanciful and portable
            shape.]
         </p>
         <p>Green Teas*	Black Teas.
            Young	Hyson, sweet cargo,	             50               POUCHONG, good, full flavor,	38
            do.	do. do. do. finer	    62 1/2				     do.			            fine,	50
            do.	do. finer cargo,                         75	              do.	            very
            superior,	75
            do.	do. extra fire,	      87 1/2
            do. do.      Silver Leaf,	1 00            Souchong, good,	38
            Silver Leaf—Seldom sold, even                          do.      extra fine,	50
            by large dealers, because of the
            very small profits made on its                 Oolong, strong, flavor fine,	50
            sale. Tins is a very superior	     Oolong—This tea is a great favor-
            tea.	ite, and gives universal satisfaction
            do. do. Golden Chop, Plantation lion.
            or Garden growth,      1 50	 do.	very fine,	62 1/2
            Golden Chop—This is the finest                do. in one pound and half
            Green Tea cultivated in-China.	pound cattys, extra fine, 75
            It is of the first pickings, and ex
            cels all other Green 'Peas for its         Ne Plus Ultra,	1 50
            
         </p>
         <p>delicacy of flavor, strength aid    Ne Plus Ultra—This tea is as
            aroma. Heretofore this tea has fragrant and sweet as a nosegay,
            never reached this country, ex-	It yields a perfume that is truly
         </p>
         <p>cept in small lots, as presents to delightful. It is of garden growth,
            importers.	and superior *o any thing of the
            Hyson,* very fine,                               75	kind ever sold in this country,
            do. Plantation growth,	1 00
            Gunpowder, good,	English Breakfast Tea, very
            do. superior, (Read “ mon-	tine, 50
            strous fraud” below.) 1 00               do. do. do. in one
            do. small leaf, plantation	pound and half pound cat-
            growth,	1	25	tys,	62 1/2
            Imperial, god,	—
            do.	brisk and fragrant,[read	IIowqua’s Mixture, a strong and
            “ monstrous	fraud”	be-	rich black tea, Pekoe flavor,    75
            low,]	I	00
            do. curious leaf,	very supe                   Congo, good,	       37 1/2
            •	rior,	1 25	do. very fine,	50
            Hyson Skin, good, fine flavor,             38    Pekkoe Flowers, good,           
            871/2
            do. do. extra fine,	62 1/2      do.   do. garden growth,             1 50€
            
         </p>
         <p>♦Caution. —Large quantities of Hyson Skin are retailed in
            this market as being a Hyson Tea. It is well worth while to compare the Hyson tea usually sold at 75 cents with the genuine article that the Company offer at the same price. The difference is so
            perceptible on trial as to render any farther comment unnecessary.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Monstrous Fraud.—Gunpowder and Imperial Teas cannot be
            retailed by small dealers, in this country, at 75 cents per pound,
            because they frequently cost that money in China, and no Importer
            in this city can sell good Gunpowder or Imperial Tea at a less
            price than 75 cents per pound by the hundred packages. T. F.
            Davies, Esq., in his interesting work on China details the manner
            in which he saw the lowest grades of Black Teas manufactured
            and colored with Prussian Blue, so as to closely imitate Gunpowder and Imperial Teas,-and adds, the Prussian Blue being a combination of Prussic Acid with Iron, is of course a dangerous poison. Let purchasers therefore beware of adulterated teas, and
            deal with those venders whose characters and resources raise them
            above suspicion. Beware of the Gunpowder and Imperial Teas
            retailed at 75 cents per pound, and compare them with the genuine
            article sold by the Pekin Tea Company. No one, it is presumed,
            wishes to drink poison. The Company have published a book,
            giving full details on this subject, which may be had at their
            Warehouse, 75 Fulton street, free of charge
         </p>
         <p>RECOMMENDATIONS.
            
         </p>
         <p>We drink Green Tea, and for many years have been paying one dollar per
            pound for it. But thanks to the Pekin Tea Company, we now get a better tea
            from them at 75 cents per pound. We drink one pound per week, by which
            we are now saving thirteen dollars per year, and enjoying better tea in the
            bargain. Commend us to the Pekin Tea Company, say We.—Mirror.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street, are performing a great and good
            work, and will, jn a few years, beyond all doubt, drive all the poor teas which
            have deluged this country, and defrauded consumers of the article, out of the
            market. They import none but pure and fragrant leas, and retail them by the
            single pound at wholesale prices. Families are always sure of obtaining good
            teas at this great tea warehouse, in quantities to suit their convenience, and at
            the same price that the merchant pays who buys to sell again.—Daily True
            Bun.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>You may be sum of obtaining at all times, pure and highly flavored teas, by
            the single pound, at who'esale prices, of the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton
            street.—They have probably the largest stock, and greatest variety of fine
            green and black teas, of any one establishment in the United States. They
            are doing a large business, and a great benefit to consumers of tea.—Atlas.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Heretofore it has been very difficult, indeed impossible, to always obtain
            good green and black teas. But now you have fttily to visit the ware-rooms of
            the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Pulton street, to obtain as delicious ana fragrant
            teas as you could wish for.—Daily Sun.
         </p>
         <p>If any of our readers desire to have good tea, they can obtain it of the Pekin
            Tea Company, 75 Fulton street.—Mercury.
            AWord to Tea Drinkers.—The Pekin Tea Company, 75 Pulton street
            
         </p>
         <p>have imported into this market some five hundred thousand dol'ars worth o
            the finest grades of Green and Black Teas, grown in the Celestial Empire, done
            up in all the various fancy packages that Chinese ingenuity can invent. It is
            a privilege to buy teas at this great establishment, and a luxury and comfort
            to drink them They sell good teas only, and retail them at wholesale prices.
            Country merchants who wish to always sell good teas can always obtain them
            at this place, on reasonable terms.—Emporium.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>The Pekin Tea Company—We very cheerfully call the attention of all
            lovers of pure and fragrant Teas, both in town and country, to the great Tea
            warehouse of this Company. Our long acquaintance with the proprietors enables us to bespeak for them the entire confidence of the public. We know
            that their Teas, loth in quality and price, are all that is stated of them. Many
            a lover of the fragrant herb has been competed to eschew the drinking of Tea
            in consequence of its injurious effects, until at length he has become hopeless
            of finding, among any if the imported varieties of Tea in our market a kind
            which had not such an effect. In this, however, such persons will be agreeably disappointed. The Pekin Tea Company have commenced the importation
            of choice varieties of Garden Teas, of most delicious flavor-cultivated and
            picked with great care, which have heretofore never been introduced into this
            country, except as presents to importers. Among these they have an Oolonog,
            mild as zephyr, and fragrant as a rose, which we especially recommend to all
            nervous persons. Its effect upon many of those who have tried it. has been
            to make them confirmed tea-drinkers. Ladies who have used it, say they
            never before drank such tea. But all tastes can here be suited, with the great
            advantage over other stores of getting a pure article at wholesale price, however small the quantity. The Company’s Warehouse is at 75 Fulton street.—
            New World.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>Tea.—The Pekin Tea Company, No 75 Fulton street, unquestionably sell
            the best teas imported into this market. That they sell them cheaper than any
            other establishment, is a fact proven in a thousand instances since they have
            opened their store.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We would advise our friends to call at this place, and if they don’t wish to
            buy at least to obtain a little pamphlet, kept on their counter, entitled “Hints
            to Tea-Drinkers,” and therefrom leai n a little useful information on the subject.
         </p>
         <p>The pamphlet is given gratis.—Anglo American.
            
         </p>
         <p>The finest specimens of green and black teas ever sold in this country, are
            imported by the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street. Those who want good
            teas at reasonable prices, can always get them there.—Tribune.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>We have tried the teas imported by the Pekin Tea Company, 75 Fulton street,
            and if we live will try them often. They are selling the most delicious teas
            we ever drank, and retail them at wholesale prices.—Evening Post. oct8
         </p>
         <p>PIANO FORTES.
            V. F. HARRISON, 23 CANAL STREET, N. Y.—In-
            
         </p>
         <p>* struments made with the most recent improvement, such as
            Iron Frames, &amp;c., with a compass of 6 and 7 octaves. They are
            made from choice materials, and highly finished, with the most
            j faithful workmanship, the result of 23 years experience in the busi-
         </p>
         <p>ness.
            N. B.—Wanted a second hand Parlor Organ.
            Piano Fortes hired by the month.
            AEOLIAN ATTACHMENT.
            Hermann s. saroni, professor of music,
            116 Leonard street, New-York, teaches the Piano-Forte, with
            or without Coleman’s celebrated Attachment.
            ~ PIANO FORTES.
            
         </p>
         <p>H WORCESTER, No. 139 THIRD AVENUE, COR• ner of 14th Street, respectfully informs his friends and the
            public, that he has a good assortment of Piano-Fortes, in Rosewood and Mahogany cases, from 6 to 7 octaves. Persons wishing
            lb purchase will find it to their advantage to call and examine before purchasing elsewhere.
         </p>
         <p></p>
         <p>To THE Public.—Edgar A. Poe, Esq. having purchased my interest in “ The Broadway Journal,” is now sole
            proprietor of the same. All persons indebted to the paper will please make settlement with him.
         </p>
         <p>John Bisco.
            New-York, Oct. 24, 1845.
            THE BROADWAY JOURNAL:
            Edgar A. Poe,	Editor and Proprietor.
            IS PUBLISHED EVERY SATURDAY----------OFFICE 104 BROADWAY,
            CORNER OF DUANE.
            terms three dollars per annum—single numbers six and a quarter era.
            
         </p>
         <p>The Broadway Journal is, in its general character, a literary paper: occupying itself with original, and more especially with critical
            I articles, in every department of Literature, properly so called—with
            a preference, nevertheless, for the Belles Lett re sand the
            Fine Arts. There is no better medium in the country for
            literary or artistical advertisements.
         </p>
         <p>agents:
            Redding &amp; Co., Boston, Mass	Thos. H. Pease, New-Haven, CL
            R. G. H. Huntington, Hartford, Ct                  J C. Morgan, New-Orleans.
            M. Baultemet, Mobile, Ala.	W W. Kingsley, New-London, Ct.
            Robinson &amp; Jones Cincinnati ,O.	G. N. Beesley, Utica, N. Y.
            D. M. Dewey, Rochester, N Y.	H.B. Strang, Peekkill, N. Y.
            J. Robertson, Syracuse, N. Y.	Haliburton A. Dudley Motion, Mass.
            W. E. Russell, Schenectady, N. Y.	S. Thomson, Worcester, Mass.
            Levi Willard, Troy, N Y.	Peter Cooke, Hanford, Ct.
            G. Jones, Albany. N Y.	H. Esten, Providence R.I.
            8. F. Hoyt, Newburgh, N. Y.	Safford &amp; Park, Norwich. CL
            Shurtz &amp; Wilde, Baltimore, Md.	John Tomlin, P. M. Jackson. Tenn.
            Colon &amp; Adriance, Philadelphia.	S. Hart, Son., Charleston, S. C.
            PRINTED AT THE OFFICE OF THE FARMER AND MECHANIC.
            Incorrect paging, from 339—344, appearing in the original edition,
            has here been corrected. Vol. 2, No. 22 is here entirely complete.
            
         </p>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      
      
   </div>
</div>