<div>
   <div class="front">
      
      <div class="ab">                          THE BROADWAY JOURNAL.
         <br>VOL. 1.          NEW YORK, SATURDAY, FEBRUARY 1, 1845.          N° 5.
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="body"> 
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="cit"><span class="quote">Truth, whether in or out of fashion, is the measure of knowledge and the business of the understanding; whatsoever is beside that, however authorised by consent or recommended by variety, is nothing but ignorance, or something worse.</span><div class="bibl"><span class="person">Locke.</span></div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="section" id="#s1">
         <div class="head">REVIEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p1">
            <p>A Course of English Reading, adapted to every taste and capacity,
               with Anecdotes of Men of Genius.By the Rev. James Pycroft,
               B. A., with additions by J. G. Coggswell. New York, Wiley &amp; Putnam, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Miss Jane C.,”-says Mr. Pycroft, in his preface, “divided
               her in-door hours into three parts: the house-keeping andFor
               dinner-ordering cares of life, claimed one part; hearing two
               younger sisters say their lessons, a second part; and during
               the third, and most delightful remainder, she would lock
               herself up in her bed-room, and move on the marker of Russell’s ‘ Modern Europe,’ at the rate of never less than fifteen
               pages an hour, and sometimes more.”
            </p>
            
            <p>It was to cure this unfortunate person of her strange mania,
               that Mr. Pycroft composed the book which we have before
               us. He tells us that the remedy worked well, and the lady
               was cured of her disorder. But it strikes our mind that a
               course of medical treatment would have been the safer experiment in such a case. Mr. Pycroft, however, knew his patient,
               and it appears that he prescribed wisely; but as such cases
               must be exceedingly rare, we do not discover any very good
               reason for his publishing his remedy, for so peculiar a disease. The disease, fortunately has never reached this country,
               to our knowledge, excepting of the type Henry Russell,
               which was quite a different complaint.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Coggswell has added a preface to the present edition,
               as well as an appendix, in which the work is highly commended, and being a scholar of extensive and varied bookknowledge, his opinion upon such a subject, must not be
               lightly regarded. But, to make use of a refined vulgarism,
               our own view of the work must be taken from our own point
               of observation, we cannot pretend to view it from the same
               altitude with the learned editor.
            </p>
            
            <p>The utmost that can be done in such an attempt as this of
               Mr. Pycroft’s, is to recommend such books as have come under one’s own observation; and as any one man’s observation
               of general knowledge, must be extremely limited, when compared with the necessities of the human mind, and his ability
               to judge critically of the fitness of a work to meet the cravings
               of particular classes, still narrower; it is very clear that his
               labors will be of little benefit to any but those whose necessities are the same as his own. The few words of wisdom to
               be written on the subject of general reading might be inscribed on your thumb nail. Read only such works as give you
               pleasure. This, it is true, is the burthen of our author’s instructions; hut it is so overlaid with gossip of one kind and
               another, that the novice who reads the book for information,
               Will be very likely to miss it entirely. His ideas of the worth
               of historical writings are very admirable, but his recommendations of particular works are of no worth. Hume, Smoll ett,
               Keightly, Robertson, and Gibbon, are his staples, and they
               probably form the staples of the majority in this country, who
               flatter themselves that they are studying history, when they
               are poring over the wordy pages of these writers. The great
               defect of the book is the lack of general principles, in the
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>place of which we have particular instructions. But there is
               much sound sense distributed through the work, which appears to less advantage for want of a proper arrangement.
               There are many pious mothers, who would sooner see their
               sons wasting their time in listless idleness, or engaged in
               entertaining their guests at an evening party with the most
               wearisome of small talk, than in reading a novel, though it
               were Caleb Williams, or the Golden Ass of Apuleius. But,
               Mr. Pycroft says with truth:
            </p>
            
            <p>"The lowest order of intellectual is preferable to mere physical resources. A book containing but little good, has kept many a youth
               from company productive of positive evil. The excitement and gross
               immorality of even the worst class of the old fashioned novels is a less
               pernicious stimulant than lounging night after night with a cigar to
               the billiard-room. Not long since, I heard a father say: If I could
               only see my boy reading Tom Thumb, I should be happy: that would
               be a beginning; but he avoids a book as if it had the plague. The
               habit of seeking amusement with books, is so truly valuable in conducing to limit the sphere of youthful temptations, that a parent does
               wisely, if he encourages it at almost any cost. Children should be
               taught that books are as natural a source of fun as tops and balls.”
            </p>
            
            <p>How differently do our fathers and merchants generally
               reason in regard to young men placed under their care. It
               is almost an universal prejudice among merchants, that books
               are unbecoming to business men. In a very large wholesale
               dry goods establishment, in this city, the principal of which
               was a rigidly pious man, whenever one of the clerks was
               discovered with a book in his hand, in an interval of business,
               he was immediately sent on some idle errand, or some unnecessary work as a punishment. Clerks who employ their
               leisure hours in study, very rarely, if ever, become defaulters.
               But the greatest number of these unfortunates have either
               been the gay and dashing, who seek for amusement in theatres and ball-rooms, or the sternly pious, whose source of
               excitement has been found in religious assemblies.
            </p>
            
            <p>“In paying so much deference to the excitement class of readers, I
               only act on the principle that if we wish to keep a child quiet, we
               must give him such toys as he is in humor to play with. Children are
                found of all ages; and, as Aristotle says,  'whether young in years, or
                young in character, matters not for my argument;’ for doubtless, in
                bis day, as in ours, children often attained to the so-called years of
                discretion without being able to run alone. I say, then, those of
               youthful taste and mind must be indulged in their own way, and
               gradually led on, by timely encouragement, and the influence of superior minds, to mingle works of valuable information with those of
               more thrilling interest. But, after all, let the taste of youth be what
               it may, it is better that they should read after their own way, than
               not at all.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Pycroft’s “plan” for studying any particular subject is
               very good, but the “course” of study recommended by him,
               must be objectionable, because he reasons from his own
               tastes, while he recommends that others should follow theirs.
            </p>
            
            <p>"And for the study of History, which I will consider under the fol-
               lowing divisions:
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">HISTORY,
               <br>  MODERN,  
               <br>  of Great Britain ; 
               <br>  of the Continent, Colonies, and
               <br>  of India, America;
               <br>  ANCIENT,
               <br>  of Rome; 
               <br>  of Greece;
               <br>  of the Egyptians, Persians, &amp;c.
            </div>
            
            <p> "Divide and conquer, that is, choose one department and master it,
               and you will have accomplished, in point of time and labor, much
               more than a sixth part of the whole. You would do well to read the
               lists of books in all these departments, before you decide. For your
               decision should be deemed irrevocable, otherwise you will be continually changing, in a vain hope of escaping difficulties which really attach to all.”
            </p>
            
            <p>This is the main principle of the plan in every department
               of study, to divide off, and master a portion at a time, and not
               attempt to grasp an entire study at once. A very judicious,
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page66"></div>
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>
               and obviously necessary course, such as would naturally be
               followed by any student who had a serious wish to become
               tolerably well acquainted with any department of learning.
            </p>
            
            <p>The part of the book which relates to the translation of the
               classics is well entitled to consideration. He candidly and
               honestly admits that it is better to read Plutarch and Xenophon, &amp;c., in the English translations, than in the original,
               for the reason that they can be comprehended with greater
               ease and mastered in less time.
            </p>
            
            <p>“With a little reflection, all must allow, that when a critical knowledge of the text, and an accurate recollection of the matter of sixteen,
               or more, Latin and Greek books are required, very little time can remain for reading the many works which are so desirable to illustrate
               them.”
            </p>
            
            <p>“The first thing to consider is, for what purpose are you commencing a course of study. If to humor a literary ambition, to be thought
               learned, and to excite the wonder of the ignorant, believe me, that till
               you abandon this vile and degrading purpose, your vanity will increase
               faster than your learning; what you gain in head you will lose in
               heart; your mind will be tilled, but not refined; and you will excite
               far more jealousy than admiration. Read, as Bacon said, for the
               glory of your Creator, and for the relief of man’s estate, to improve
               your talents for the race that is set before you, to prevent that periodical void within, which is doomed to fill, and that with gnawing cares,
               and soul debasing thoughts. That is true of our faculties, which an
               old officer told me of his men, that there was no such security for good
               behaviour as active service.”* * * “Among the many who desire to be
               thought literary characters, nothing is more common than an inclination to lock up the temple of knowledge, and throw away the key; or,
               on attaining an eminence, to kick away the ladder, that none may follow them. So beware of this class of literary impostors; their life is
               one continued lie; a lie partly positive, because they pretend to know
               far more than they do know; and partly a lie in direct, but far more
               mischievous, because they seek to magnify difficulties, hint that things
               are not so easy as they seem, and pretend that a peculiar talent is required for their favorite subjects. In every department of knowledge,
               the man really proficient, is ever desirous to lead others on; and forgetting all the difficulties to be encountered, firmly believes, and as
               honestly confesses, he could teach his friends in half the time his
               learning cost himself.”
            </p>
            
            <p>These extracts prove the author a sincere honest man, one
               in whom you can trust as far as his own knowledge extends;
               and if he had confined himself simply to the course of reading
               which he had mastered himself, his book would have been
               twice as valuable as it now is, when, according to his own
               account, for much that he has recommended, he has depended
               upon the advice of others.
            </p>
            
            <p>In the department of art, where every one thinks it necessary to dabble, though he be profoundly and willingly ignorant of every thing else, he gropes his way like a blind man
               on a strange road. He stands like Bartimeus in Raffaelle’s
               Cartoon, feeling for something tangible, but missing it. The
               famous writers in art are very few, and among these few,
               those who can be read with profit, form but a very inconsiderable part. Mr. Pycroft recommends the whole, which is
               certainly safe, though it would have been safer to recommend
               none.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Lectures of Sir Joshua Reynolds we may expect, as
               a matter of course, to stand first on the list of an Englishman’s enumeration of readable works on Art. But the discourses of Sir Joshua, though very agreeable reading, are
               pervaded by errors in principle, which render them among
               the most dangerous books that can be placed in the hands of
               a neophyte. He is a popular author still, though his countrymen have begun to say that he was great in practice in spite
               of his errors in theory. Hazlitt is recommended as well as
               Sir Joshua, but his principles in criticism are the antipodes
               of the theories of Sir Joshua. Unless the reader have sufficient knowledge to perceive the truth himself, he would be
               completely bewildered by such conflicting systems. Allan
               Cunningham, who has contrived to imitate all that is bad in
               both of these writers, without mingling in their faults any
               good of his own, is also recommended by Mr. Pycroft. In
               short, he includes in his catalogue everybody who has written on Art excepting Leonardo and Lanzi. In his list of architectural works he has omitted two of the best of modern
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>times—Hope’s Essay and Gwilt’s Cyclopoedia. But his remarks on this subject are exceedingly brief, and prove that
               he felt but little interest in it. He would have acted more
               judiciously in letting it alone altogether. The space devoted
               to Biblical Literature is very ample, as might have been expected in a book of this kind from a clergyman.
            </p>
            
            <p>His directions on the study of poetry and works of taste,
               are very curious. Johnson’s Lives is recommended as a handbook or guide to the poets.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Cowley, Waller, Philips, Parnell, Rowe, Prior, Gay, Green, Tickell, Somerville, Swift, Collins, Dyer, Churchill, Akenside, Lyttleton,
               Armstrong, J. Warton, T. Warton, Mason, Beatty, are authors of
               whom those of limited opportunities may be contented to read such
               parts only as Johnson, or other critics point out.”
            </p>
            
            <p>This is strange company to find Swift in; and the others,
               excepting Prior and Gay, would probably be as much astonished at being associated with him, as he with them. Mr.
               Pycroft, of course, has never read a line of Swift, or he
               would have shown better discrimination. If there is any
               book in the English language sure of immortality, it is the
               Tale of a Tub. But we should think it was too solid food for
               the digestion of Mr. Pycroft, who seems to have a strange
               craving for flummery.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Shakspeare no one should ever cease reading: begin with the tra-
               gedies.”
            </p>
            
            <p>We wish that Mr. PycToft had given some reason why
               readers of Shakspeare should begin with the tragedies, or
               what series of the tragedies, whether Titus Andronicus and
               Pericles, or King John and Richard the Second; and it would
               not have been amiss in giving so peremptory an order as to
               never cease reading an author, to state why he should be read
               at all. There is little need of directing any English reader to
               Shakspeare, yet we have known men who confessed that
               they read him, as a duty, but could not take any pleasure in
               him. There can be no such thing as a universal directory in
               study. Byron found Milton heavy, and Cobbett made Shakspeare the butt of his irony. To name so humble an instance
               as ourselves, after these illustrious names, may sound absurdly, but no one is too humble to illustrate a principle; we never
               could get through with a tithe of Robinson Crusoe, perhaps
               the most universally read book in the language. Many an
               idle hour have we loitered away in our summer days with
               Dr. Doddridge or one of the dramatists of Charles the Second’s
               time, but we never could get up an intimacy with Robinson
               Crusoe.
            </p>
            
            <p>Among the works on America which Mr. Pycroft recommends, are Mrs. Butler, Mrs. Trollope, Miss Martineau, Captain Hall, Dickens, and Sydney Smith. Why he should omit
               Marryatt and Hamilton, is not easy to discern. The works
               of American authors which he recommends, are very few.
               Anthon’s Lempriere, Catlin’s Notes on the Indians, Two
               Years Before the Mast, and Stuart’s Letters to Dr. Channing,
               are all.
            </p>
            
            <p>Mr. Coggswell, in his Appendix, fills up the deficiencies
               of the author with a liberal hand. He adds every work that
               has ever been heard of on the subject of America, excepting
               one, which he had not, probably, heard of himself. This is
               an account in La Mosaique de L'Ouest, of the discovery of this
               continent by a Norman navigator, who landed at the mouth
               of the Amazon, in 1488, four years prior to the discovery by
               Columbus. This navigator was a native of Dieppe, named
               Cousin, from which port he sailed on a voyage of discovery,
               fitted out by the merchants of his nation, whom he had
               persuaded to engage in the undertaking, upon representations
                similar to those which Columbus had made to his patrons.
               Among the adventurers who accompanied Cousin was a boat swain, or mate, contra-maitre, named Vincent Pinzan, who
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page67"></div>
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>quarrelled with his commander, and afterwards was one of
               the most sanguine of those who seconded the endeavors of
               Columbus, as is well known. A very satisfactory library
               might be formed out of the works which neither Mr. Pycroft
               nor Mr. Coggswell have alluded to.
            </p>
            
            <p>His notes on the poets are highly amusing.</p>
            
            <p>“Of Addison—read Cato, and Psalm 23.” This differs
               Widely from Dr. Blair’s advice, “Give your days and nights
               to Addison.”
            </p>
            
            <p>“Of Pope—the Essay on Criticism, and the Dunciad, show
               that Pope could write as strong lines as any writer.” Pope
               was strong in the Dunciad, among poets, in the same sense
               that the skunk is strong among animals.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Of Coleridge—like Shelley and others of the same school,
               he often failed in the single step which would have attained to
               the sublime, and therefore their writings seem to remain in the
               regions of the ridiculous.” Here is a very common error
               among thoughtless writers. The step from the sublime to
               the ridiculous, is the step downwards—not from the ridiculous to the sublime. One may fall in a moment from a height
               which he has been all day in reaching, but no one ever fell
               upward by a false step.
            </p>
            
            <p>The book is published in a very handsome manner, and
               but for the leaden tint of the ink, would look like an English
               edition.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p2"> 
            <p>The Chimes, A Goblin Story. By Charles Dickens, Esq. New York, 
               E. Winchester. Republished.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Chimes are in the Dickens vein, but not the true vein
               —there’s neither a laugh nor a tear among them all. If the
               Christmas Carol had not come first, the Chimes would never
               have come at all. It is the first time that Boz has attempted to repeat himself; and he has failed as signally as
               though he had attempted to imitate somebody else. The
               Carol was a bright bubble, a perfect sphere with all the primitive colors playing upon its surface; the Chimes is nothing more than a painted shell. Scrooge and Tiny Tim
               will live for ever, but there is nobody in the Chimes whose
               life will last a twelvemonth. Toby Veck has no individuality, but such as his clothes give him—which is nothing.
               Richard and Meg, and Alderman Cute, the Member of Parliament, the Goblins of the Bells, and all, are misty, unsubstantial personages. It is Boz, but living Boz no more. The
               Chimes, too, give out a tone that is becoming wearisome:
               we do not like the key note—it has that dismal wail which
               is becoming fashionable among dandies and misers, the cant
               of philanthropy. Mr. Dickens has almost caricatured the
               tribe in the exaggerated portrait of Sir Joseph Bowerley, intended probably to personify the “new generation.” He
               gives Young England some terrible thwacks—hard enough,
               we should think, to demolish so young a gentleman.
            </p>
            
            <p>In calling the Chimes a failure, we only compare it with
               the other productions of the same author; compared with
               the successful works of many others, it is prodigious. No
               one can read it without feeling that Dickens is a thorough
               good fellow: one who sympathises keenly with the lower
               orders of society, and who sees through the flimsy veil which
               respectable rogues throw over their own actions. Like all
               of his productions, it is bold, rapid, and sincere. You cannot
               perceive any marks of doubt or hesitancy: no erasures, no
               after-thoughts, no mending of passages; but you are conscious of having before you the first conception of the author,
               in its original integrity, without having been submitted to
               the emasculating corrections of a calculating prudence, or
               the refinements of a fastidious taste. It is this freshness
               which distinguishes all his writings, that gives them one of
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>their chief attractions. His copy goes from his hand to the
               printer before the ink is dry. There are many slovenly passages in his writings in consequence, but no stiff ones. The
               Chimes contains many passages of unapproachable beauty,
               and some impersonations which are equal to any thing that
               he has done before in the same way. The wind is his favorite element: he writes of its pranks in a spirit of love. In
               Martin Chuzzlewit, and in the Christmas Carol, it seemed
               like a witch element to him. Of the same nature it appears
               in the Chimes:
            </p>
            
            <p>“For the night wind has a dismal trick of wandering round and
               round a building of that sort, and moaning as it goes; and of trying
               with its unseen hand, the windows and the doors: and seeking out
               some crevices by which to enter. And when it has got in: as one
               not finding what it seeks, whatever that may be; it wails and howls
               to issue forth again: and not content with stalking through the aisles
               and gliding round and round the pillars, and tempting the deep organ,
               soars up to the roof, and strives to rend the rafters; then flings itself
               despairingly upon the stones below, and passes, muttering, into the
               vaults. Anon, it comes up stealthily, and creeps along the walls;
               seeming to read, in whispers, the Inscriptions sacred to the Dead.
               At some of these it breaks out shrilly , as with laughter; and at others, moans and cries as if it were lamenting. It has a ghostly sound
               too, lingering within the altar; where it seems to chaunt, in its wild
               way, of Wrong and Murder alone, and false Gods worshipped; in defiance of the Tables of the Law, which look so fair and smooth, but
               are so flawed and broken. Ugh! Heaven preserve us, sitting snugly
               round the fire! It has an awful voice, that wind at Midnight, singing
               in a church!
            </p>
            
            <p>“But high up in the steeple! There the foul blast roars and whistles! High up in the steeple, where it is free to come and go through
               many an airy arch and loop-hole, and to twist and twine itself about
               the giddy stair, and twirl the groaning weathercock, and make the
               very tower shake and shiver! High up in the steeple, where the
               belfry is; and iron rails are ragged with rust; and sheets of lead and
               copper shrivelled by the changing weather, crackle and heave beneath
               the unaccustomed tread: the birds stuff shabby nests into corners of
               old oaken joists and beams; and dust grows old and grey; and speckled spiders, indolent and fat with long security, swing idly to and fro,
               in the vibration of the bells, and never loose their hold upon their
               thread spun castles in the air, or climb up sailor-like in quick alarm,
               or drop upon the ground and ply a score o; nimble legs to save a lie!
               High up in the steeple of an old church, far above the light and murmur of the town, and far below the flying clouds that shadow it, is the
               wild and dreary place at night; and high up in the steeple of an old
               church, dwelt the Chimes I tell of.”
            </p>
            
            <p>We have heard a good many wonderful stories of miserly
               hearts being melted, and churls made amiable, by the mere
               reading of the Christmas Carol, but we fear that the good
               done by the Chimes will not be as great. There are parts
               of it that make riches appear hateful, but none that render
               poverty pleasant. Mr. Filer and Alderman Cute are verygross caricatures, so is Lady Bowerley; but there is something
               inexpressibly fine, a satire terribly scorching on the benevolence of the upper classes, in her ladyship’s charitable designs.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Let him be made an example of, by all means,” returned the lady. “Last winter, when I introduced pinking and eyelet-holeing
               among the men and boys in the village, as a nice evening employment, and had the lines,
               
               <div class="lg"><br>Oh let us love our occupations,
                  <br>Bless the squire and his relations,
                  <br>Live upon our daily rations,
                  <br>And always know our proper stations,
               </div>
               set to music on the new system, for them to sing the while: this very
               Fern—I see him now—touched that hat of his, and said,  'I humbly
               ask your pardon my lady, but an’t I something different from a great
               girl?’ I expected it, of course; who can expect anything but insolence
               and ingratitude from that class of people? That is not to the purpose,
               however. Sir Joseph! Make an example of him!’ ”
            </p>
            
            <p>In that kind of writing called grotesque, Dickens stands at
               an unapproachable height; his page teems with phantoms;
               the commonest objects assume a fantastic shape the moment
               he touches them; rusty hinges, battered doors, toppling chimneys, bits of lead, scraps of tin and old nails become instinct
               with life, and suddenly assume a new character as though
               the wand of an enchanter had touched them. But his grotesques have not that aimless merely grotesque existence
               which the wizard shapes of other authors have; they speak
               to us smoothly, and their words are imbued with a wisdom
               above that of ordinary men.
            </p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page68"></div>
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div> 
            <p>" 'The voice of Time,’ said a phantom, 'cries to man, Advance!
               Time is for his advancement and improvement; for his greater worth,
               his greater happiness, his better lite; his progress onward to that
               goal within its knowledge and its view, and set there, in the period
               when Time and he began. Ages of darkness, wickedness, and violence, have come and gone; millions unaccountable, have suffered,
               lived, and died; to point the way before him. Who seeks to turn
               him back, or stay him on his course, arrests a mighty engine which
               will strike the meddler dead; and he the fiercer and the wilder, for
               its momentary check!'
            </p>
            
            <p>" 'I never did so, to my knowledge, Sir,' said Trotty. 'It was
               quite by accident if I did. I wouldn’t go to do it, I’m sure.’
               " 'Who puts into the mouth of Time, or of its servants,’ said the
               Goblin of the Bell,  'a cry of lamentation for days which have had
               their trial and their failure, and have left deep traces of it which the
               blind may sec—a cry that only serves the Present Time, by showing
               men how much it needs their help when any ears can listen to regrets
               for such a past—who does this, does a wrong. And you have done
               that wrong to us, the Chimes.’ ”
            </p>
            
            <p>The English Reviewers have all spoken highly of the
               Chimes, and the Edinburgh gives it a notice longer than the
               book itself; but the same causes which help to render it popular there, have hardly an existence here. Our rich and
               poor occupy different positions. The poor here is the privileged class. We have no Aldermen Cutes, do Toby Vecks,
               God be praised for it. The Chimes is a politico-comic production, and will be more popular with politicians than idle
               readers. The illustrations which ornament the London edition are by famous artists, but have nothing but the names
               of the artists to recommend them.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p3">
            <p>The Natural Boundaries of Empires, and a New View of Colonization. By John Finch, Esq., Corresponding Member of the
               Literary and Historical Society of Quebec, and of the Natural History Societies of Montreal, New York, New Brunswick, Delaware,
               etc. London: Longmans, 1844. Imported by Wiley &amp; Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">(Second Notice.)</div>
            
            <p>As this book is not likely to be placed in the hands of our
               reading public, we give a few more extracts from it, to show
               more fully than our notice of last week could do, the general
               spirit which pervades it.
            </p>
            
            <p>“ 'War,’ said the great captain of his age, war is the trade of barbarians. The whole art consists in assembling a force superior to
               your adversary.’ This can be accomplished by a great naval power,
               which is thus enabled to seize, much to her own detriment, on various
               small isolated portions of the world, and on extensive kingdoms which
               have not yet arrived at their full power, or which have become imbecile and weak from age.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Happy therefore would it be for every nation, if the ocean would
               rise with storm and with tempest against ships of war, and tranquil
               seas and favouring gales were reserved for honest merchant ships and
               gaily painted yachts. Then when the land was infested by war, each
               one who was peaceably inclined might advance to the shore and embark in his yacht, with a plentiful store of provisions and wine, sail
               about on the tranquil surface of the ocean, and return to the land when
               the war was over. Less tyranny would be practised, and the independence of nations would be much promoted.’’
            </p>
            
            <p>It is hardly possible that a work like this, which makes
               war upon the deepest rooted prejudices of the world, can exert any influence in removing the errors which grow out of
               them. Reformers must not be too radical, if they would do
               good. The world has but little sympathy with those who
               have keener sight than itself. It was a difficult thing for
               Columbus to persuade the monarchs of his time to aid him
               in his attempt to discover a new Continent; but now that
               everything is discovered, every nation sends out ships on voyages of discovery. If the Genoese had aimed at nothing
               more than an island, it is probable that any of the Christian
               monarchs would have seconded his designs. But a new Continent was too much for their understanding. So, an amendment of an odious law, or the curtailment of what are called
               the national defences, may sometimes be accomplished, but an
               attempt to abolish altogether, would be resisted by the conservative instincts of society.
            </p>
            
            <p>There is food for deep thought, for missionaries of all kinds,
               in the follow ng extract.
            </p>
            
            <p>"In Upper Lusatia, in Germany, is a tribe of people called Wends,
               descended from the good Saxons who resisted with such true valour
               the armies of Charlemagne. They dress in the skins of sheep, and
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>dwell in tents. They are perfectly happy, lor they lead a pastoral
               life, and cordially pity those unfortunate people who are compelled to
               reside in towns. Towns! where Mother Earth is carefully hidden from
               view by a heavy pavement of brick or of stone; where the air is polluted by a thousand vitious exhalations, and where sleep, silence and
               solitude are unknown.
            </p>
            
            <p>“In the midst of Christian Europe they retain a solemn Pagan rite,
               and a grove of majestic oak trees, near the centre of their territory, is
               their object of religious adoration. They were formerly under the government of the Elector of Saxony, who allowed them to pursue their
               own course without interference, having perceived the folly of any attempt to control them. In the exchange of territory which took place in
               Europe during the year 1815, they were transferred, along with some
               other Saxon subjects, to the jurisdiction of Prussia. The monarch of
               that country, when informed of the circumstance, issued an immediate
               order that they should pay a tax and contribution, and attend Christian worship. An officer was appointed to execute the decree.
            </p>
            
            <p>“It was soon discovered that, unless they were caught and chained
               to the benches, it was impossible to procure their attendance in the
               cathedral of Luchaw. Two companies of infantry were then detached
               to cut down the sacred grove; but the tribe threatened destruction to
               all who engaged in the attempt. The commissioner of Prussia, wishing to avoid bloodshed in a newly acquired territory, desisted from
               this part of the enterprise.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The project of converting them forcibly to Christianity having
               failed, it was thought highly desirable that they should pay tribute,
               and a large sum was demanded. The chiefs of the tribe replied, that
               money was totally unknown among them; that flocks of sheep and
               herds of cattle were the only things they possessed, and they could
               not, with any convenience to themselves, part with and of them.
               They said that if the King was hungry, and came that way, they
               would kill a lamb and roast it for his dinner; but they resolutely refused to pay any tax, and immediately assembled in arms to defend
               their property. The Prussian officer finding he could do nothing with
               this inexorable race, was obliged to leave them in possession of their
               ancient freedom.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Like this tribe, the people of every country have certain habits,
               customs, feelings, opinions, and prejudices, by which they are distinguished from other nations. These customs are so powerful, that it is
               impossible to eradicate them; nor would it be desirable.
            </p>
            
            <p>“As medals are more valued for the variety of their impressions, so
               nations present a more pleasing aspect from the variety of their customs, the difference of their opinions, and the distinct character of
               their political institutions.
            </p>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>" 'The shuddering tenant of the Frigid Zone
               <br>Boldly proclaims the happiest spot his own;
               <br>Extols the treasures of his stormy seas,
               <br>And his long nights of revelry and ease.
               <br>The naked Negro, panting at the Line,
               <br>Boasts of his golden sands and palmy wine;
               <br>Banks in the glare, or stems the tepid wave,
               <br>And thanks his gods for all the wealth they gave.
               <br>Such is the patriot’s boast, where’er he roam,
               <br>His first, best country', ever is, at home.’
            </div>
            
            <p>“This circumstance contributes much to the comfort and happiness
               of the human race; each nation considers its own law, custom, and
               institution—soil, climate, and provision—habit, manner, and government, as far superior to all others. There is one thing which every
               nation adores, and that is itself; each nation believes itself the most
               free, the most wise, the most brave, the most every thing.
            </p>
            
            <p>"The praise and the superiority of his native land is the pleasing
               theme of every orator in every country. lie who assures his audience
               they are the best and most enlightened people on the face of the earth,
               will always receive abundant applause. Were it otherwise, it would
               show a great want of proper feeling; for ingratitude is one of the
               worst vices that can be charged against individuals; but the man who
               is grateful for kindness conferred on him, possesses many other good
               qualities. An orator and his audience thus mutually delighted with
               each other, present a very pleasing spectacle.
            </p>
            
            <p>"Frequently a community considers its own law, government and religion, so excellent, it desires to enforce them on other nations. Hence
               arises one cause of war.”
            </p>
            
            <p>Our next extract is of a similar character; but we are not
               sure that the reasoning is correct. The government of a
               country cannot be said to form the people, but the people
               must create the government, let its character be what it may.
               Every nation makes its own rulers; it matters not what
               names they may bear, whether kings or senators.
            </p>
            
            <p>“The most important circumstance connected with the welfare of
               man, is the government which exercises a control over his actions and
               his thoughts; for, in every country where the human race have existed for some time under one species of power, his sentiments and his
               ideas become gradually assimilated to the government under which
               he is placed. A single glance at the countries that were formerly prosperous and flourishing under free institutions, and which are now rendered desolate and oppressed by despotic power, would confirm so irresistibly this view of the subject, and has been so often illustrated
               by various writers, that it is not worth while to cite any examples.
               They will readily occur to any one who is conversant with history.
            </p>
            
            <p>“There is not any nation which desires to have a good government;
               that is, it is not the first and principal object which they desire. The
               first wish of all nations, and which they are unhappy if they do not
               attain, is to be governed according to their peculiar ideas and prejudices. There
               is no doubt they believe these to be founded in truth
               and justice; but how fur this is from being actually the case, the history of every country will elucidate. Even if a nation should desire it,
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page69"></div>
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>—as governments are carried on by human agents, and their power is
               exercised over human subjects,—how is it possible it should be per-fect? they of necessity
               partake of the general imperfection of all human things. Can we construct a temple which shall continue to attract for ages the admiration of mankind with diminutive bricks, or
               will you raise a pile of timber to last for centuries?
            </p>
            
            <p>“Let us therefore make a few enquiries what the human race are.
               In the first place, in respect to their form, which has some relation to
               the subject, although it may appear a distant one; and in the next,
               with respect to their disposition or character, on which, in point of
               fact, governments depend for their development. Do we find perfection of form or character in any member of the human race with
               whom we have ever been acquainted? A French author has very
               truly observed, that we are surrounded by merely halves and quarters
               of men.
            </p>
            
            <p>With reverence be it spoken, the reason why angels are not permitted to visit the earth, except at very distant intervals, is because they
               would be stared at as curiosities; and yet the accounts which are given to us of angelic natures is, that they merely exhibit all the good
               qualities of which man is capable, wrought to the highest degree of
               intensity. Who ever saw perfection in the human figure? and what
               lumps of men we see around us, and what a variety! Why is it that
               the statues of the Apollo di Belvidere and the Venus de Medici always excite in us such emotions of pleasure and delight ? If we met
               Apollos walking in the street, and Venuses were our companions every moment of our leisure hours, we should pass by the statues without observation. It is because they are very beautiful and differ from
               anything we see in common life, that they attract our notice.
            </p>
            
            <p>“Monarchy, especially hereditary monarchy, is expensive; it is so
               of necessity. All people, all nations, connect ideas of dignity with
               expense and luxury. It is a false association of ideas, but so general,
               that it is adopted by every nation. It is therefore necessary that the
               monarch presiding over the destinies of a nation should excel all his
               subjects in luxury and expense, as much as he exceeds them in power.
               There have been but two monarchs since the commencement of time
               who were maintained at a very trifling cost to their subjects; and the
               nations over whom they ruled were so exasperated against them on
               that account, that they put one to death and were constantly conspiring
               against the other. The first was the beautiful white ox that reigned
               in Egypt, and of whom an account is given in the pages of Herodotus.
               He was one of the best monarchs the world ever saw ; he never engaged in bloody wars to gratify an unreasonable ambition, or to extend his dominion; and while he chewed the cud, his subjects were
               peaceful and happy. It was under his reign that some of those beautiful temples were built, which have attested to a later age the power and magnificence of ancient Egypt, and which the modem degenerate nations of Europe make not even an attempt to imitate. A
               plentiful supply of grass, with a little corn and pure water, were all
               that he required; but at length his subjects were so indignant against
               him, because he would not spend more money, that they rose in rebellion, effected a revolution, and cruelly put him to death.”
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p4">
         <div class="head">AMERICAN PROSE WRITERS.
            NO. 3.
            R. H. Dana.
         </div>
         
         <p>If fancy (as we justly conceive the case to be) represent
            the leading traits in the intellectual constitution of Mr.
            Willis: sentiment, we apprehend, with no less characteristic force, forms the most prominent features in the genius
            and writings of Mr. Dana. No mere sentimentalist, our author is emphatically a man of sentiment: no hypocritical Joseph Surface, full of cant and moral pretensions, but a genuine man of feeling, unlike, or rather superior to, Mackenzie’s
            hero, in being, in addition, a true philosophic observer of
            life and character, a stem self-student, and, a powerful
            painter, according to the stereotyped phrase, of men and
            manners.
         </p>
         
         <p>This attribute of sentiment, in the instance of our author,
            is at one and the same time, a moral and an intellectual
            quality, religious, high-toned, upright, masculine, partaking
            of the softness of Mackenzie and the stern dignity of Wordsworth. Apart from this faculty, Mr. Dana is a writer of
            great purity and power, of much acuteness and elegance in
            other walks than in those of philosophic sentiment or of
            sentimental description; but in those he is a master, and
            ranks first among his contemporaries and countrymen. He
            has vast powers in depicting the struggles of the darker passions, jealousy, hatred, suspicion and remorse. Paul Felton
            has touches of Byronnic force, and discloses a similar vein to
            that so fully opened and with such popular effect in the
            works of Godwin and Chas. Brockden Brown.
         </p>
         
         <p>This, however, is what one would call, perhaps, with a
            certain degree of innocence, the uncomfortable portion of
            Mr. Dana’s genius, and of which the tendency is doubtful.
            It is an open literary question, as to the extent that such
            characters as that of Paul Felton should be taken, for the delineation of real characters. An idiot, a madman, a monomaniac, may be made very effective in vigorous description,
            but is not the simple-hearted Jonathan Fords, for example,
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>a better character both for study and imitation? Doubtless
            more than one Paul Felton has birds, but we do not go to
            nature, in bad extravagances or capricious words, for instruction or delight—else the records of a Prison or a Lunatic
            Asylum would form the truest volumes of history, instead of
            merely furnishing a few supplementary chapters of strange
            idiosyncrasies, or morbid developments. But, we have no
            idea of going into a deep question of psychological criticism
            at present; merely remarking that we have not the remotest
            idea of any, but the purest intention, in the mind of the creator of that wretched man, as he has himself called him, and
            yet from false sympathy or an unhappy bias, that way, the
            readers of that most terrible history may become unaware so
            strangely interested in the character and fate of the hero, as
            to feel the ill effects of such an unmanly weakness long after
            he had hurriedly perused the story—the wonderful truth and
            fidelity of the analysis of the heart, and the vivid description
            of the darkest passions, set off and release the hateful moral
            deformity of the diabolical passions, that festers and finally utterly corrupts the heart of their victim. Otherwise, as a
            picture of naked hideousness, the tale could be read only by
            the wisest and the weakest.
         </p>
         
         <p>The sentiments of the writer even in the midst of these
            harrowing scenes, comes in as an angel during a whirlwind
            excited by the most malicious fiends in hell, spreading a heavenly calm, and casting a pure bright effulgence over an atmosphere of gloom and despair.
         </p>
         
         <p>In Paul Felton, Mr. Dana has exhibited power in depicting
            passion, as well as sentiment: and the same criticism applies to his Thornton, though in a much inferior degree.
            Yet he is most at home in pictures of domestic life; in describing the charm of home scenes, in realizing the ideal of
            conjugal felicity. Strange, that the author, who as a man is
            so enthusiastic on such a theme, should, as a poet, (for he is
            one as much in Tom Thornton and Paul Felton, as in the
            Buccaneers,) delight in pictures, also, of gloom, of crime, of
            remorse.
         </p>
         
         <p>Sentiment furnishes the key, also, to the criticisms of
            Dana. We noticed this in his lectures a few winters since
            on the poets and dramatists. He finds this, his favorite faculty, beautifully expressed by the ballad writers and the Shaksperian dramatists among the old writers; and by Wordsworth and Coleridge, among the new; and to them he has
            given his heart. The single critical paper in the volume of
            Dana’s selected works, on the acting of Kean, is full of it, no less
            than of acuteness and deep insight into the mysteries of art,
            both of which indeed are colored and refined by it, to a point
            and degree that may be honestly declared as not being very
            far distant from perfection. The paper is almost equal in its
            way, to Elia’s admirable miniature sketches: differing, as
            widely in spirit, as they resemble each other in execution.
         </p>
         
         <p>As a writer of sentiment, love, in its forms both of sentiment and passion, (for it varies in different natures, and is the
            offspring of the temperaments of the affections and of the
            fancy, according to the individual constitution, mental or moral, or sensitive of the recipient and cherisher of it,) constitutes
            the staple of Dana’s inventions and speculations—of love in
            all of its degrees, he is a delicate limner or a vigorous painter, according as the subject is a delicate woman or a manly
            man: a quiet, retired, meditative nature, or a stirring, active,
            ambitious character. The female character has full justice
            done it, by the writer of Edward and Mary. Judging from
            his writings on this subject, Mr. Dana has been a happy man.
            Yet he can paint a weak credulous mother, or a dashing,
            heartless woman of fashion (see Tom Thornton) with as
            subtle skill as he can delineate the fond, confiding heart, the
            clear and wise judgment, the gentle and amiable tastes, of
            a true woman and a good wife.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have other points to speak of, than that only of our author’s sentiments, however, and must not dwell too long on
            that.
         </p>
         
         <p>Mr. Dana has been connected in ties of literature and family connection, with the first artist and finest poet of our
            country. Allston and Dana married sisters, and remained to
            the last intimate associates. We have heard Mr. D. speak of
            his works out at Cambridgeport (we think where Allston resided) and his conversations there with the Poet Painter, as
            among his richest pleasures, nor should we forget that Bryant was the early associate, as he remains the "oldest friend
            of our author. Some of Dana’s finest portrait contributions,
            were included in Bryant’s New York Review. The father,
            too, is happy in a son who has written one of the best books
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page70"></div>
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>of its class since the world renowned fiction of De Foe. With
            these connections to boast of, the nobility of genius has had
            to contend with comparative neglect and poverty: sure ever
            of a high place in the esteem and admiration of good critics,
            honest readers and worthy men, whose applause constitutes
            his fame, but who have little else to give beyond sympathy
            and respect.
         </p>
         
         <p>The late reviews of American novelists, in the Quarterly,
            just and fair in the main, was yet guilty of omissions that
            should have been noticed at the time, and filled up by a
            competent critic. It is not our purpose, at present, to occupy
            the whole ground, nor fill the entire vacancy—that is to be
            left to the writer, who can honestly appraise the merits of
            the authors less unnoticed, in a sort of article supplementary. Three comic writers, at least as worthy of notice as Miss
            Leslie,—Neale, Matthews, and the author of Harry Franco, our best comic satirists since Paulding’s Salmagundi,
            have escaped notice entirely; while two serious writers, of
            unquestionable excellence, Allston in his Monaldi, and Dana,
            in certain prose dramas, among prose fictions, what the
            masterpieces of Heywood or Middleton would prove by the
            side of the Shaksperian drama, have been passed by without
            ever attracting a casual remark.
         </p>
         
         <p>This neglect may furnish some excuse for the foregoing
            remarks and the critical observations that may follow, albeit, we had hoped the task might have been committed to
            other hands. Nor shall we attempt to disentangle the meshes of the tales themselves; skilful unwinding of the thread
            of a narrative, or the decomposition of a plot, or an analysis
            of the conduct of the incidents, ranking in our opinion, when
            well done, almost with the original poem that gave birth to
            the fiction. And as we do not write tales, but merely criticisms upon them, we shall speak of the qualities displayed
            in the construction of these narratives, rather than the incidents or the characters they contain. Another and an equally good reason, as it appears to us, for the present sketch,
            may be found in the fact, that our authors had been gradually lost sight of by the generation of readers that have risen
            since he wrote. To a large number, we fear, nothing of
            Dana is known beyond his name; with whom, too, his name
            is getting to be matter of tradition. It is now nearly a quarter of a century, since we have seen anything in print by the
            author of the Idle Man. During which period so many candidates for public honor and claimants for a niche in the
            temple of fame have been pouring in, that the public eye is
            well nigh clouded by the sparkling ephemerida, and the
            public ear confounded by loud clamors and noisy appeals.
            In the midst of this hubbub, the silent speculative genius
            of Dana, and the power, the purity, and the classic genius
            of Dana’s writings, have passed almost unregarded.—
            Among the thousands who devour James, the tens who
            study Dana may be easily enumerated; the lovers of historical melo-drama, see nothing in simple, undisguised,
            unaffected, yet most real and vigorous, true dramatic painting. Perhaps the American is too much of a philosopher for
            those readers, who are captivated by detailed narrative and
            circumstantial description; though, as a mere writer of tales
            full of striking characters, closely crowded with stirring incidents, set in a frame of poetic description, and enshrined
            within a halo of imagination, Dana is in the first rank of novelists. It is wrong to speak of him as a mere tale writer:
            for his tales are not only as long as certain short novels (as
            long and longer than Rasselas, Zadig, Candide, the Man of
            Feeling, or the admirable fictions of Richter, Zschokke,
            and other German novelists) but they are as closely woven,
            that they read sometimes like abstracts of longer works.
            There is nothing to be spared; the utmost economy is observed, consistent with real richness and vigor. Yet, as we
            said, the evident philosophic character of the author, the
            basis, indeed, of his portrait character, as well; the love of
            speculating upon character, the motives to action, the principles of conduct, may deter the mere readers for amusement, since Dana is manifestly a teacher of men, and is to
            be estimated rightly only in that character. He had selected
            prose fiction, we imagine, only as a vehicle for conveying
            certain pictures of life, portraits of individuals, certain wholesome moral satire, an ideal of contented private enjoyments,
            and of a life of action, enlightened duty. His invention
            is probably, therefore, voluntary, and the offspring of ready
            impulse. Hence a want of the popular manner and of the
            “taking” style. He is not a popular writer, and has,
            rightly, not aimed at popularity. This he confesses, and
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>justifies with sense and honesty. His real mind—the cast of
            a writer’s mind must be popular, to render his writings
            such, yet there is no element of that kind in our author’s
            intellectual constitution. He is too honest to disguise his
            defects to individuals; too sincere to please the literary mob.
            He is sure of the aristocracy of genius and scholarship and
            true worth; the class composed of the wisest and best—the
            true aristocracy. To take an elevated example, he, like Milton, will always be read by the choice few, while, like him,
            he must remain caviere to the mass of readers.
         </p>
         
         <p>We insinuate nothing, byway of comparison between the
            two; for Milton is first among the greatest, while Dana
            would be too wise to accept of a place among the greatest at
            all. He is first among the lesser lights, the Dii Minores of
            our literary firmament.
         </p>
         
         <p>The facts of Mr. Dana’s literary career are known to few.
            Beside the history of his literary connexions, mentioned before, we have heard of little else. We once heard Mr, D.
            speak of his life as passed in his room. He has been much of
            an invalid, and has led, we understand, a retired life. The
            only account the public at large, even here, at home, have
            of one of the first men we can point to, is to be found in
            Blackwood’s Magazine for 1824 or 5. It occurs in a paragraph, in a series of papers on American writers, ascribed to
            John Neal, and evidently from his pen. It is instinct with
            the shrewdness and sense of that very clever man, and dashed off in his slashing off-hand style. Without a number of
            the Magazine by us, we must quote from memory. Neal
            complains of Dana’s indolence and careful polish; though he
            gives high and just praise for soundness, purity, and true
            genius, he adds certain censure on his excessive care, somewhat after this manner. Dance (a misprint) is pure, sound,
            full of genius, but timid, where he has a fair chance, shuts
            the wrong eye and is apt to miss. Fond of carving heads,
            or cherry stones with his friend Bryant; but the public care
            nothing for the otto of prose. Neal says, that he almost
            ruined himself and damned the North American Review,
            by an article on Hazlitt’s Poets—an exaggerated sentence in
            the true John Neal style. When or how long Dana edited
            the North American Review, we cannot exactly discern.
            Two only of his reviews have attracted much attention—on
            Moore and on Hazlitt’s lectures—the latter harsh, and we
            think, unjust. Mr. Dana thinks (or did think) Hazlitt very
            much inferior to the notion his admirers entertain of him.
            The paper on Moore is just, manly, and creditable to the
            critic’s heart, as well as his taste. Much excellent matter is
            doubtless buried under a heap of quarterly rubbish. Neal,
            in a concluding sentence, reproves our author for his silence
            and indolence, stating that Dana had done in several years
            as much as he (Neal) could have done in as many weeks or
            months. Very likely, but with a difference; with a different
            quality, we make bold to think, however, and hardly destined
            to survive its year or deeds. Neal, with great cleverness,
            and wit, and industry, has furnished hardly anything, except
            a few critical sketches and moral essays, with a few brilliant
            tales, that show how much more might have been accomplished. Neal could have been the first magazine writer of
            his day; but he could never equal Dana, lacking, as he does,
            the profound and subtle genius of the latter.
         </p>
         
         <p>In a general survey of the genius of Dana, we may remark
            his defect of wit and humor. He sometimes indulges in
            playful sarcasm, as in the letters from town (would he had
            given us more), which are models of their kind—elegant,
            familiar, and Addisonian, in the best sense—the natural union
            of sense and gaiety, of reflection and feeling.
         </p>
         
         <p>Dana is a master of characters: his observation is keen
            and benevolent, and can at the same time grapple with vigorous and strongly-marked characters. He has painted a
            character in the First Letter, which somewhat resembles his
            own; and which, together with the character of Edward,
            and a few touches (of the maiden kind) in the youthful character of Paul Felton, go to make up a pretty fair and just
            idea of the author.
         </p>
         
         <p>Dana has more imagination than fancy, and which gives
            his fictions the air of reality. He is too habitually serious to
            be fanciful or fantastic. His imagination delights in tragic
            situations, and dark characters, and terrible deeds, that carry
            a fearful moral with them. His style is admirable; close,
            clear, precise, final. He is equally powerful in his critical
            capacity, as he is an original writer. His essays are musings,
            the finest reflections of a scholar, and many given to reverie
            and sentimental disquisition. The man, too, is but the natu
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page71"></div>
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>ral converse of the author—kind, sincere, honorable; without a meanness, without a flaw—such is Richard H. Dana,
            one of our very best writers; one of our very best men.
         </p>
         <div class="byline"> J.</div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p5">
         <div class="head">BARBARITIES OF THE THEATRE.</div>
         
         <p>Dullness and absurdity are not the only or the least causes
            of the decline and fall of the present Drama. The stage has
            something to answer for, on the”score of positive inhumanity. In Hogarth’s delightful print of the Strolling Players
            behind the scenes, the characters are represented as preparing
            for a burletta. The imperial Eagle of Jove is feeding one of
            the bantlings of the company with pap out of his projected
            talons; the tragedy Queen raves to the imaginary gods, while
            a rent is getting stitched on her leg; two imps are quarrelling
            for a pot of porter; a lady is pleasantly distressed at the appearance of her first pair of breeches, and reinforces her
            courage with a glass of cordial; the mitre is filled with play
            books, and a cat is tossing the royal globe on the floor as a
            bauble. It is a very happy print to look at, for every character in it, is steeped to the very crown in that sovereign bath
            for the misfortunes of the world, the humor of a full overflowing heart. But alas! the picture has its reverse, and the same
            great master might have drawn upon the same scene for additional materials to his shuddering prints of the Four Stages
            of Cruelty. He might have set his burletta in motion, and
            anticipated a scene which has just occurred at Drury Lane,
            and forms one of the most horrible realities, yet one so obvious that it may occur again, at any moment, of the theatrical
            life. Miss Clara Webster, a dancer of ability and a favorite
            with the audience, was performing in the opera of the Revolt
            of the Harem, in the bath scene, where there is a miserable
            attempt at the representation of water, and women bathing
            in it, that, when we witnessed it at the Park Theatre, seemed
            as natural and agreeable to the eye, as the stiff, tawdry.
            French pictures smeared on band boxes. There is nothing
            to be said against the indecency of such an exhibition, for it
            was too painful and revolting to produce any other feeling
            than an uncomfortable disgust. Painted actresses with staring eyes, fixed on a narrow strip of foothold, like rope-walkers,
            illuminated in a glare of light, like Dante’s figures in purgatory, offer the least attractive subject of contemplation in the
            world. Miss Webster was engaged in this gross show of
            tinsel, when her gauze dress took fire from the lights placed
            below. She was immediately enveloped in flames, and ran
            about the stage shrieking for help, avoided and shaken off by
            the other dancers, at the peril of their lives, till the carpenter
            at the side scene, rolled himself over her, and extinguished
            the fire at the cost of great personal suffering to himself. She
            was taken home to die—and the play went on to the conclusion. This reads like a reflection on the humanity of an English audience. So it occurred. Yet, as they were men and
            women, that vision, clad in fire, must rise up before them as
            a horrible portent—the extremest agony of pain, lit up by the
            blaze of a theatre. What light foot can tread the boards
            again? This disaster will, doubtless, attract the attention of
            men of sense and feeling, who busy themselves in England,
            in all such cases, Sydney Smith may find a deeper horror,
            and a more available subject for relief in this, than in the famous Railway Disaster with locked doors. A similar fatal
            occurrence in France, vividly related by Froissart, took place
            in a species of mummery and masking, at the Court of
            Charles VI. <span class="anchor" id="a001"><a href="#n001"> Link </a></span></p>
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <p>It remains for theatrical managers to take the strictest precautions against the recurrence of similar accidents in future.
            We have often noticed with alarm, the flaring of the footlights at the very steps of the actresses. The lights should
            be carefully protected, as recommended by the London Coroner, with a net-work of wire, and as he exhibited, the dresses
            might also be rendered incombustible. Such steps are suggested, not only by humanity, but by the interests of managers.
            An occurrence of the kind happening here, would damn the
            boards of any theatre to perpetual infamy. The whole class
            of dangerous theatrical performances should beat once modified and amended. There is little pleasure for the audience as
            safety for the performers, in these exhibitions. Ellsler really
            delights us by her grace of motion, and piquant archness in
            walking across the stage; she simply shocks all agreeable
            feeling when she transports herself on a wire, or hangs suspended from the ceiling. The blue-lights and sulphur are a
            nuisance which, out of the theatre, would be indictable at
            common law. On what principle a manager fills the house
            with soot and smoke, unless to give color to the assertions of
            those pious people who maintain that the stage is the devil’s
            portal, we are at a loss to conceive. Mr. Povey may, very mysteriously, by some unknown laws of assimilation, continue
            to grow fat in such an atmosphere, but it is death to the audience.
         </p>
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page72"></div>
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <p>There is a host of minor grievances, each sufficient in itself to account for the general disappearance of the audiences,
            without recurring to the unfortunate laws of the drama, for a
            single argument. There is one sentiment that, we have observed, always comes home to the house, and is delivered
            with an air of perfect naturalness, by the actors. It is the
            passage in Hamlet where “the air bites shrewdly—it is very
            cold.” There is no mock unction in the player’s art here.
            We should have no plays performed in winter but such as
            Macbeth, Hamlet, and others lying in hyperborean regions, to
            keep up the historical keeping which Mr. Macready so much
            values. Masaniello, or the Tempest, are absurdities.
         </p>
         
         <p>Now we have a very great respect for the cast-iron stove at
            the Park Theatre, with its open mouth in the lobbies, and the
            pieces of coal, set on like oysters, to roast. It does something
            to fill up a vacuum in the deserted hall, and it is society for
            the door-keepers, who have frequently nothing else to look at;
            but bless you! for all purposes of warming the Theatre, it
            might as well be round the comer, or supply fuel for the political bonfires in the Park. Within there is neither flue, nor fire,
            or pipe visible or perceptible. It is a comfort even to see poor
            Grandfather Whitehead warm his feeble fingers, in the person of Mr. Chippendale, over the painted embers of Langley’s
            inhospitable hearth. Pity the poor actors! We have seen a
            strong current of air sweep the ribons of an actress’s hair, and
            a star, too, round into her face, that she could scarcely sing
            for the annoyance. Bare n ecks look pitiable in such northern
            blasts. Oh “the pity of it, the pity of it,” Mr. William B.
            Astor!
         </p>
         
         <p>There is another word to be said, too, of those curiously
            contrived instruments of torture for the audience, the boxes,
            which to gentlemen who have legs, recal the idea very sensibly, of Ravaillac’s boots. The problem of what infinitesimal
            quantity of straw will protect the covering of the seats from
            too exhaustive a friction on the boards underneath, has been
            very satisfactorily solved too. Verily, if a man goes to destruction through the gate of the theatre, he goes to it like a Popish anchorite, without ever treading the soft primrose path.
         </p>
         
         <div class="byline">E. A. D.</div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p6">
         <div class="head">NATIONAL NOMENCLATURE.</div>
         
         <p>Our countrymen are very much in the habit of pointing to
            the Patent Office in Washington to prove the fertility of the
            inventive powers of the nation. But it would require a dozen
            such collections to weigh against the contrary evidence of the
            Blue Book. Combination is the word for the Patent Office.
            Imagination or invention, we can lay no claim to, if we look
            to our national nomenclature for the proof. In the immense
            catalogue of American names, there is hardly one we can
            claim as our own. They are all of foreign or Indian derivation. The inconceivable repetition of certain names of towns,
            proves us to be the most unimaginative people in the whole
            world. There are one hundred and eighteen towns and
            counties in the United States, called Washington. In all
            Europe, there is but one London; we have five Londons, one
            New London, and seven Londonderrys. We have six towns
            called Paris, tweny-one Richmonds, sixteen Bedfords, nine
            Brightons, nine Chathams, eleven Burlingtons, sixteen Delawares, fourteen Oxfords, fourteen Somersets, nine Cambridges, twenty-five Yorks, and other English names in proportion. There are twelve towns with the prefix of Big, four
            Great, and sixteen Little. There are nine Harmonys, seventy-eight Unions, and eighteen Concords; forty-four Libertys,
            and thirteen Freedoms; twenty-one Columbias, and seven
            Columbuses. There are one hundred and four towns and counties of the color Green, five Vermillions, and twenty-four
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>Browns. Almost every name in Scripture, has been reproduced on our soil: Goshens fifteen, Canaans eleven, Salems
            thirty, Bethlehems eleven. All the classical writers have
            been largely honored in our national baptisms: there are fifteen Miltons, five Homers, nine Addisons, two Byrons, two
            Drydens, and only one Virgil. We have five Avons, three
            Stratfords, one Romeo, and one Juliet, but no Shakspeare.
            We have twelve Athenses, eight Romes, one Romulus, and
            four Scipios. Of Troys we have sixteen. “Ilium fuit” need
            be written no longer. We have six Sheffields, and twelve
            Manchesters. There are one hundred and fifty towns and
            counties called New Somethings and only six Old. The most
            imaginative name on our roster, is Richland, which is multiplied no less than thirty-eight times, we have precisely the
            same number of Springfields; and Bloomfields, and Greenfields without number. Of Oranges there are twenty-six,
            and not one Lemon. We have three Dresdens, fourteen Berlins, twenty Hanovers, and four Viennas. All the cities
            of the East are multiplied a great many times, with the
            exception of Constantinople, in place of which, we have a
            Constantine. The national habit of imitation is very strongly
            shown in our names: there are few that occur but once.
            Smallpox, a town in Joe Davies county, Illinois, stands alone
            yet, or it did when the census was taken; so does the town
            of Jim Henry, Miller county, Missouri; but they will, doubtless, be imitated before long. We have ninety-one Jacksons,
            sixty-nine Jeffersons, fifty-eight Monroes, fifty Madisons, thirty-two Harrisons, nineteen Adamses, sixteen Van Burens,
            twenty-one Clays, three Websters, and not one Tyler. Of
            Bentons there are fourteen, Franklins eighty-three, and Lafayettes thirty-four. The popularity of an individual can
            hardly be inferred from the number of limes his name occurs
            on the map. Clinton is multiplied twenty-seven times, Decatur nine, and Perry fifty-one.
         </p>
         
         <p>The indigenous shrubs and fruits of the country give names
            to but few towns. The Pepperidge, one of the most beautiful of our forest trees, has never been used at all, nor the
            Persimmons; but we have a Willow and a great many Oaks.
         </p>
         
         <p>We have thought it would be a good way to compel the
            country to tax its imagination, by passing a law prohibiting
            the use of a name for a town or county that had ever been
            used before for the same purpose; but such a law would
            lead to worse consequences still, all our towns would then
            be numbered, as our new streets are now, and we should
            have Nine hundred and twenty-first city, Fifty-fourth county,
            New York, and we should see letters directed to Eighty-fourth
            city, Sixty-fifth street, Forty-first county. Sooner than live
            in such an arithmetical world as that, we would infinitely
            prefer a dozen Joe Davieses, and ninety-one Jacksons.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p7"> 
         <div class="head">THE DEVICES OF BEGGARY.</div>
         
         <p>Mr. Bumble, the beadle in Oliver Twist, was very indignant at a pauper, who went and starved himself to death, on
            purpose to bring odium upon the parish overseers; and Mrs.
            Corney, the matron of the poor house, made terrible complaints that some old woman or other, always took it into her
            head to die, just as she, (Mrs. Corney,) was going to take
            a comfortable cup of tea. The poor are terrible bugbears to
            the rich; little emaciated children and pallid old creatures,
            with their rags fluttering in the winter wind, are forever intruding themselves upon the elegant repose of the well-off.
            A clergyman, who published his complaints on this subject,
            not long since, made a very feeling statement of his griefs,
            in not being able to eat his breakfast in quiet, for the obtrusiveness of street beggars, who would be asking for some
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page73"></div> 
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>thing to eat. Probably they did not know his profession, or
            they would have kept clear. That any man, woman, or
            child ever begged, but from sheer necessity, for something to
            eat, we do not believe. It is a very prevalent opinion, however, among the well-to-do, that beggars go about from sheer
            wantonness, with crying infants in their arms, or with shrivelled limbs, on purpose to disturb the upper classes, by exciting
            their sympathies. One day, last week, we saw a fat lawyer,
            whose person was enclosed in a blue cloth cloak, with an
            abundance of velvet, talking rather harshly to a little boy,
            with some almanacs in his hand, standing in his bare feet on
            the rugged ice of the pavement.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Look at this little rascal,” said the legal gentleman, “he
            goes about without shoes or stockings, on purpose to make
            people buy his almanacs.”
         </p>
         
         <p>The culprit was a beautiful little fellow, of some ten years
            with a profusion of glossy hair, and a look of intelligence
            which showed that he or his parents had seen better times.
            His feet were the color of mahogany, and they looked as
            though they were touched with the frost; his dress was exceedingly scant, but he had a very healthy look, notwithstanding. Indeed I have rarely seen a prettier boy. In spite
            of his rags, and destitution, he had such a look of happy innocence, that I doubt not John Jacob Astor would gladly
            have changed places with him, and given his twenty millions for the poor boy’s ruddy cheeks, bright eyes, and frosted
            feet.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Is it true,” I asked, “that you go bare-footed to sell your
            almanacs?”
         </p>
         
         <p>The little fellow blushed at the question, and looked
            down at my boots, at which I blushed in return.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Indeed, I should be very glad to wear shoes, if I could
            get them,” he said, “but it is more than a month since I have
            had any. Perhaps it is some other boy that the gentleman
            means.”
         </p>
         
         <p>"No, no, you are the very scamp,” persisted the lawyer.</p>
         
         <p>“There’s a boy boards with my mother, it may be him,”
            continued the youngster.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Does your mother take boarders?” I inquired.</p>
         
         <p>“She takes this little boy, because he has got no mother,
            and when he gets a shilling by selling almanacs, he gives it
            to her. Will you buy one of my almanacs?”
         </p>
         
         <p>‘‘Don’t you;’’ said the lawyer, “depend upon it, he’s a
            cheat.”
         </p>
         
         <p>“I hope he is,” I replied, “there’s something to be hoped
            of a boy who can endure such hardships as this little fellow
            does, for the sake of two or three cents profit on the sale of
            an almanac. Just cast your eyes on the opposite side of the
            street, and look at the sleek negro, dressed in a cocked hat,
            and a laced coat, at the entrance of that fancy bazaar; what
            do you think he wears that finery for? Is it not to entice
            customers into his employer’s shop? Look a little further, at
            those immense sheets of plate glass in a hatter’s window,
            what do you think they are for? Solely to admit light, or to
            induce customers to drop in? for what purpose do you carry
            that bundle of tape-tied papers under your arm, if not to gain
            clients, by persuading the world that you are overrun with
            them, knowing as you do that it is the way of the world to
            help the prosperous? And will you censure this little fellow
            for practising the only arts that he possibly can, to attract
            customers, by leaving off his shoes and stockings, this bitter
            morning?”
         </p>
         
         <p>“Well, there’s something in that, I believe 1 will buy an
            almanac, for the truth is I want one; but I don’t like to encourage roguery said the lawyer.
         </p>
         
         <p>“Very possible!” thought I, “seeing that you live by it.”</p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div class="section" id="#s2">
         <div class="head">Original Poetry.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p8">
            <div class="head">THE RING.
               (TRANSLATED FROM THE GERMAN OF LUDWIG UHLER.)
            </div>
            
            <div class="byline">BY <span class="person">MARIA LOWELL</span>.
            </div>
            
            <div class="lg"><br>There rode upon a morning
               <br>A knight across the lea,
               <br>Of his lady many a warning
               <br>And anxious thought had he.
               <br>"My little trusty ring of gold
               <br>From care can set me free;
               <br>In thee my loved one’s pledge I hold;
               <br>How stands her constancy?”
               <br>Now while he looks upon the ring,
               <br>It flies from off his hand,
               <br>It rolls and bounds with many a spring
               <br>Across the meadow land.
               <br>Across the meadow would he skim
               <br>To catch it as it flew,
               <br>But golden blossoms dazzle him,
               <br>And grass bedropped with dew.
               <br>The ring a falcon spieth
               <br>From off a linden tree;
               <br>And downward swiftly flieth,
               <br>The ring on high lifts he.
               <br>On mighty plumes his way doth take
               <br>In the free air to swing,
               <br>His brothers follow in his wake
               <br>To seize the little ring.
               <br>But none can win the little ring,
               <br>It drops adown the sky,
               <br>The knight he watch’t it falling
               <br>On the deep sea silently.
               <br>The fish are gaily dancing
               <br>To seize the golden prize,
               <br>But down the ring is glancing,
               <br>Beyond the reach of eyes.
               <br>“Oh little ring, in meadows fair
               <br>The flowers drew thee aside,
               <br>Oh little ring, in the blue air
               <br>The birds behind thee glide.
               <br>“Oh little ring, from ocean’s spring
               <br>Thou draw’st the fish above,
               <br>I fear thou tellest, little ring,
               <br>Strange news of her I love!”
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p9">
         <div class="head">The Drama.</div>
         
         <p>The Chatham.—Chatham street has been a favorite location for theatres during the past twenty-five years. Since
            Barriere had his Pavilion and lemonade garden, where the
            Chatham street chapel afterwards stood, there have been
            some half a dozen different Thespian temples erected in the
            neighborhood. The first dramatic representation that we
            ever witnessed was under Barriere’s management, and we
            remember hearing a good many discussions among the frequenters of that classic spot, about the relative merits of
            Mrs. Entwistle and Mrs. Waring. It was here that General Morris, then only a colonel, produced his first Opera of
            Briar Cliff, in which that immortal song was introduced,
            “William was holding in his hand, &amp;c.” long before the days
            of Henry Russell and the “Tree,” and long before “long
            time ago,” even; here, too, Mr. Woodworth, the coadjutor
            of the Brigadier in the Mirror, produced the beautiful native
            Opera of the “Forest Rose,” and the celebrated Micah
            Hawkins brought out some of his classic dramas. These
            were the palmy days of the drama, when the celebrated 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page74"></div>
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>Colonel Stevenson, since a tobacco inspector, kept the refreshment room and served drinks to the ladies who frequented that charming spot. But these days are gone, never more
            to return, as some poet says. Mrs. Entwistle, we believe,
            has been gathered to her fathers, and Mrs. Waring became
            Mrs. Blake a long time since, and has doubtless grown old.
            The beautiful Mrs. Wallack first unveiled her charms to the
            public here, and the great Andrew Jackson Allen here made
            his most brilliant displays of costumery. A low comedian
            named Stevenson, used to give immense delight here by singing the favorite song “Such a beauty I did grow.” Sanquirico and De Begnis were then eating macaroni in Italy,
            little dreaming that they would ever come to America and
            sing comic songs in the Tabernacle. How destiny shuffles
            men about, as though they were a pack of cards, excepting
            that in cards there are as many kings as knaves, while
            among men there are but few kings, and of knaves a good
            many.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Chatham street people are essentially dramatic in
            their character: they are exceedingly fond of theatrical display, as may be seen by walking through that renowned
            thoroughfare any sun-shiny morning, or clear evening. Every thing here has an air of exaggeration and caricature. It
            was here that the big boot was first set up. You look in
            vain lor repose or quiet. It appears, therefore, the most
            natural thing in the world that a theatre of some kind should
            always exist in Chatham street. The Park Theatre has
            been closed, to make room for the classic equestrians, but
            the Chatham is still devoted to the legitimate drama; what
            that is we do not very clearly comprehend, but we believe
            that tragedies and comedies in five divisions, which do not
            represent real life, are generally called the legitimate drama. The prices of admission to the Chatham theatre are by
            no means extravagant, a shilling being the price to the pit,
            and two shillings to the dress circles. A corner of the pit is
            partitioned off to form a saloon, at the entrance of which
            hangs-a transparency, informing the patrons of the drama
            that the best of liquors are sold within at three cents per
            glass, and that pigs’ feet and soused tripe may be obtained at
            the bar. This is all legitimate, of course; the city authorities confer the privilege of selling the best of liquors at three
            cents per glass to the youngsters who frequent this Thespian
            temple, as a special license; and take part of the profits of
            the same, to help support the rogues of one kind and another
            that are made by such means. We thus see how regularly
            and beautifully the cog-wheels of society are moved, apparently giving motion to each other, without revealing the
            power which sets the whole a-going. By way of antidote
            to the “best of liquors,” the theatrical decorator has made
            an imitation of the entrances of the House of Detention in the
            two ornamental doors at the sides of the proscenium, which
            seem to say to the youngsters in the pit, “take care!”
            This is a very happy idea, and the Egyptian style of architecture harmonises very well with the other parts of the
            house, particularly the view of West Point on the drop curtain, which contains some very remarkable examples of drawing in perspective.
         </p>
         
         <p>We heard a very eloquent sermon a Sabbath or two since,
            on the destitution of the Turcomans in respect of good books.
            The preacher, who was a bishop, shewed himself perfectly
            familiar with the reading of the Sultan’s subjects, and begged
            very hard for aid to send them something better. We wonder whether there be a licentiate, or a doctor of divinity in this
            great city, who has ever troubled himself to inquire into the
            nature of the mental food which is nightly administered to
            the young care-for-naughts, who fill the pit and galleries of
            this theatre? Yet it is surely of as much importance, in
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>every respect, that the apprentices and newspaper boys of
            our city should be rightly instructed, as the learned barbarians of the east. These boys may possibly go to church once
            a week, but they go to the theatre every night. It is admitted that the stage is the most powerful method of enforcing
            a moral truth; and we do not see why some of those benevolent souls who bestow so much consideration upon the
            production of tracts to be circulated at home and abroad,
            should not give some attention to the amusements of the destitute youth of our city. It is one of the best and most commendable designs of “young England,” to elevate the amusements of the poor, and to furnish them with the means of rational enjoyment to entice them from the ale-house and the
            ring. There are sometimes highly objectional representations put upon the stage, which must hare an injurious effect, beyond calculation, on the morals of the young who witness them. If some of the publications of the tract society
            were dramatised, we have no doubt that they would be
            highly popular. What people admire most is novelty; and
            a religious drama, divested of sectarian cant, would possess
            this charm in a high degree. The popular taste may easily
            be discovered by watching the causes of popular approbation;
            and we have always remarked, that among audiences like
            those of the Chatham, the best sentiments and the most virtuous actions receive the warmest applause.
         </p>
         
         <p>Bulwer’s Lady of Lyons was recently played here to a
            crowded house, and the virtuous sentiments contained in it
            produced rounds of applause. We could not but feel vexed
            that the author had so spoilt an admirable moral, one so
            well adapted to benefit an audience of apprentices, in misrepresenting the true story upon which his drama was founded. La Perouse, or the Bellows-Mender, was the tale which
            he worked into a play; bnt by changing the course of action, by which the hero raised himself from poverty, he entirely destroyed the beauty of the moral, and rendered his
            drama much less effective than it would have been, if he
            had adhered to the integrity of the narrative. La Perouse,
            the original of Claude Melnotte, to prove himself worthy of
            the wife whom he had unworthily won, goes to Paris, and
            by industry and strict integrity in trade acquires a fortune,
            and returns to claim his bride, who has retired to a convent;
            but Bulwer has made him a soldier, who makes himself rich
            by robbing the Italians, and returns after two years of butchery and plunder, tricked out in epaulettes and plumes, and
            rescues his bride just as she is about to sell herself for money to his rival, after having sworn fidelity to her first husband. The whole teaching of his play is mischievous, and
            the sentiment of it exceedingly mawkish. As a work of art,
            the Lady of Lyons does not rise above the low standard of
            the conventionalities of the stage. People make long harangues at the elbows of others, who conveniently remain
            deaf and blind to all that passes, until the proper time comes
            for them to open their ears and eyes. Claude Melnotte returns from Italy after an absence of nearly two years, and is
            not recognised by his wife during a long conversation, because
            it would disturb the denouement of the plot if he were to do
            so. There are, in truth, as many gross inconsistencies in the
            drama now, as in the days of Nick Bottom. While, in all
            other departments of art improvements have been made to
            meet the exactions of a critical age, the stage has remained
            unchanged for the last two hundred years; we do not mean
            in the machinery of the stage, which is of no account, but in
            the construction of the drama, which is every thing. If
            Shakspeare could be laid on the shelf for half a century, an
            incubus would be removed from the drama, and it would
            rise to a level with the other arts.
         </p> 
      </div>
      <div class="pagebreak" id="#page75"></div> 
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div class="section" id="#s3">
         <div class="head">VARIETIES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p10">
            <div class="head">LETTER FROM DR. A. SIDNEY DOANE.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">New York, Jan. 23, 1845.
               <br>To the Editor of the Broadway Journal.
            </div>
            
            <p>Sir,—On the 16th of January I was requested by my friend
               Dr. S. Vital Bodinier, recently from Paris, to witness the
               extirpation of a humor from the neck of a female, which he
               said would be performed without her consciousness, and
               without suffering, “while she was in a magnetic sleep," he
               having operated twice under similar circumstances in Paris,
               and with success.
            </p>
            
            <p>Being rather incredulous, but at the same time extremely
               anxious to see so great a boon conferred upon suffering humanity, I went to No. — Chambers street, previous to the
               hour appointed for the operation (which was half-past one),
               in order to witness the process of putting the female to sleep.
               After being in the house about five minutes, the patient came
               into the basement room and seated herself in an easy chair.
               She seemed extremely bright and nowise sleepy, with a rosy
               cheek, black eyes, and dark hair. After an inquiry or two
               as to her health, and feeling her pulse, which was natural,
               Dr. B. proceeded to make what are termed “magnetic passes,” and so successfully, that in five minutes the eyelids
               drooped, and in ten minutes—say at twenty minutes of twelve
               —she was sound asleep. I learned from Dr. B. that she
               had been placed in this state some ten or twelve times previously, with a view to secure her entire insensibility. Dr.
               Bodinier now demonstrated on the female the operation to
               be performed, and requested me to examine the tumor. It
               was a lymphatic tumor in the parotid region, which had existed for five years, but had increased very rapidly within a
               few months. I left the patient at twelve o’clock, still sleeping soundly.
            </p>
            
            <p>I returned to the house at quarter past one, in company
               with Prof. J. W. Francis and Mr. J. S. Redfield, the publisher. A few moments after, we were joined by Drs. Mott,
               Belafield, J. Kearney Rodgers, Taylor, Nelson, Dr. Alfaro,
               a highly distinguished physician from Madrid, Mr. Parmly
               the dentist, and one or two others. Descending to the basement, we found the patient still asleep, a fact of which I
               believe all the medical gentlemen present were satisfied.
               Every thing being arranged, Dr. Bodinier stated briefly that
               the operation would be neither rapid nor brilliant, on account of the facial nerve, the division of which caused great
               deformity. He then with a convex bistoury made an incision
               two inches long, beginning below the lobule of the ear, dissected the tumor from its lateral attachments, separated it
               from the subjacent parts with the blunt edges of a pair of
               curved scissors, and removed it; it was the size of a pullet’s
               egg, and the operation occupied two and a half minutes only.
               During this operation I stood at the head of the patient.
               There was not the slightest change in her face or respiration;
               she continued to sleep on quietly and calmly through the
               whole of it. Dr. Bodinier seemed to be operating rather
               upon a cadaveo than on a living being. The wound was
               now dressed, and the patient still remaining unconscious,
               previous to the departure of the gentlemen who witnessed
               the operation, Dr. B. invited them to return and see the patient roused. I availed myself of the invitation, and went
               again to the house at ten minutes past four. She was still
               sleeping, but at quarter past four, the time indicated, she was
               demagnetized by Dr. B., Drs. Taylor, Parmly, and others
               being present. I immediately inquired, “How she felt?”
               She answered, “rather tired.” “Had she suffered during
               her sleep?” She said, “No.” “Had she been cut?” She
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>replied “ No, the operation was to be performed the next
               day,” as Dr. B. had previously stated to her would be the
               case. She was now shown the tumor, at which she seemed
               much surprised and gratified., Since that time the patient has
               recovered rapidly, and to-day, Thursday, one week since the
               operation, the wound is entirely healed, and she has resumed
               her duties in the family.
            </p>
            
            <p>The operation was performed very skilfully, and Dr. B.
               justified the high expectations formed of him, by his great
               reputation in Europe, and the manner in which Prof. Berard,
               of the Hospital La Pitie, the celebrated Orfila, Dean of the
               Faculty of Medicine, and the illustrious Guizot, Minister of
               Foreign Affairs, have spoken of him in their letters to this
               country.
            </p>
            
            <p>This, however, is not the only case in which surgical
               operations have been performed, the patient being in a magnetic sleep. Some six years since, a schirrous breast was
               extirpated at Paris by Prof. J. Cloquet, the details of which
               were communicated by him to the “Academie Royale.” Dr.
               Bodinier also, as we have already stated, operated twice in
               June last, at Paris, successfully. Some two years since a
               leg was amputated at Bangor, and lately I see by the papers
               that at Augusta, a tumor has been removed from the breast.
            </p>
            
            <p>I have thus complied with your request to state what I
               witness solely from a sense of justice to the distinguished
               surgeon who performed the operation. I have told you
               what I saw. You can draw your own conclusions.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">Respectfully yours,
               <br>32 Warren Street.
            </div><span class="person">A. SIDNEY DOANE</span>, A.M., M.D.
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p11">
            <div class="head">THE MOZART-INSTITUTE OF FRANKFORT - ON - THE - MAINE.</div>
            
            <p>On the loth of February, 1828, a society of Amateurs was
               formed in Frankfort, under the name of the “ Lieder-Kranz,”
               Wreath of Songs; partly for social intercourse, but mainly
               for the practice of Vierstimmigen Mannergesang, quartette
               chorusses, songs composed for four male voices, first and second tenor and first and second bass. As every thing new in
               art or literature creates a sensation in modem times, it was
               very natural that the performances of the Lieder-Kranz
               should cause a considerable excitement. The society continued for several years to prosecute its objects, and by the
               amount of its fine talents and a continual striving after the
               most classical compositions, it ventured at last to give a
               public performance. It did so on several occasions, prompted
               by a holy desire to honor the greatest poets of the fatherland,
               Schiller and Goethe; to do honor to the European master of
               sound, Mozart; and to make a thank-offering to the immortal Guttenberg. It did so, too, to gratify the feelings of the
               heart for the sufferings of others, and to turn the natural sympathy for misfortune to productive effect.
            </p>
            
            <p>The satisfaction shown by the public at these performances, was the best acknowledgment of their merit; at the
               same time, it gave an impulse to the perfection of the German Mannergesang; and finally, it was an exhortation to
               unite with the whole Fatherland in a grand national vocal
               festival. The Lieder-Kranz entertained the joyful hope, that
               its intentions would everywhere be received with eagerness.
            </p>
            
            <p>Its object was not by this Festival to prepare a mere passing enjoyment for the participators, but to lay the cornerstone of an imperishable institution. The proceeds of the
               Vocal Festival were to be appropriated to the foundation of
               a Musical Institute, to be called the “Mozart-Stiftung;" intending thereby to erect a moral monument to the greatest
               tone-poet of the world. The first performance of the Lieder
               Kranz for the benefit of the Mozart Institute, took place at
               Frankfort in July, 1838, and the constitution of the society 
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page76"></div>
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>provided that an annual concert should be given by the Lie-
               der-Kranz for the same purpose.
            </p>
            
            <p>The Constitution of the “Mozart-Stiftung” consists of
               forty sections, detailing the manner in which its objects shall
               be attained, the principal of which are the education of
               youthful musical talent, and the production of musical compositions. Youths of all countries, where the German language is spoken, can receive the aid of the Institute, provided that their lives are blameless, and their musical talents
               respectable.
            </p>
            
            <p>It was natural that all artists glowing with a true love for
               this science, should contribute, either by concerts or by their
               compositions, to the perfection of the Mozart Stiftung, and
               the completion of this admirable work. The noble Franz
               Litzt was one of the first who gave concerts for the benefit
               of the institute; among other contributors we find the names
               of Spohr, Ferdinand Hiller, Mangold. Dr. Felix MendelssohnBartholdy, the composer of the Lobgesang, has promised to
               write six Vierstimmigc Mannergesange for the benefit of the
               institution. Franz Litzt has given it four imposing choruses.
               The highly-esteemed Schnyder Von Wartensee, one of the
               honorary members of the Lieder-Kranz, gave the institute a
               sum of money for the formation of a particular fund for the
               purchase of classical music. This happened very opportunely, for they were enabled to purchase thereby a great
               part of the works of Sebastian Bach from the estate of (alas,
               too early dead!) John Nep. Schelble, the worthy founder of
               the “Cecilien Verein” in Frankfort. From New York, also,
               the sum of one hundred and sixty florins was sent to the Mozart Institute by friends of the cause.
            </p>
            
            <p>Slowly, but surely, this magnificent work approaches to
               completion, and the joyful consciousness of a noble deed will
               compensate its high-hearted founders for the indefatigable
               zeal which they have shown in their interest for the German
               National Monument—the Mozart-Stiftung.
            </p>
            <div class="byline"><span class="person">Charles Perabeau</span>.
            </div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p12">
            <div class="head">PLACES WORTH VISITING.</div>
            
            <p>The Governor’s Room in the City Hall.—The suite of
               rooms in the City Hall, called the Governor’s Room, can be
               visited, free of cost, at any time of day, by application to the
               keeper. The chief attraction here, consists of the pictures,
               of which there are a good many, mostly authentic portraits.
               The Mayors of the city are all here, of the common kit-cat
               size; and the Governors of the State are represented at full
               length. The best picture among them all, is the portrait of
               Governor Yates, by Vanderlyn. It is the best that he ever
               painted; superior, in truth, to his Caius Marius. It proves
               that the only true historical painting, is portraiture. The best
               painted head in the collection, perhaps the best in the country,
               is the portrait of Governor Marcy, by Page; the general effect is inferior to some others in the room, owing to an illdisposed flag suspended over the head of the Governor, and an
               uncomfortable prominence which is given to a ponderous
               table cover; but in other respects it is an admirable painting;
               one that does honor to the arts in this country, and which
               should be seen by every foreigner who would form a just estimate of the advance of art among us. There are also two portraits, by Inman; one, the most elaborate of all his pictures,
               of Mr. Van Buren; the other, one of his most free and dashing subjects, of Governor Seward. Here, too, is a full length
               portrait of Lafayette, painted by Mr. Morse, the President of
               the National Academy; it is a very passable portrait, but the
               most unnatural piece of coloring that was ever seen. But its
               merit as a painting will always be of secondary interest; as
               a portrait of a man, whose name will ever be dear to an
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>American, it will seem full of grandeur and beauty. It is
               much superior to the portrait which hangs in the House of
               Representatives at Washington.
            </p>
            
            <p>Some of the most interesting pictures here, are the portraits
               of the heroes of our last war; may it ever remain the last!
               Those of Perry and Hull, particularly,are very spirited, though
               not to be commended as mere works of art. The citizens of
               New York pay a good round price for these pictures, and they
               should avail themselves oftener than they do, of their right to
               inspect them. The children of the charity schools in London,
               have the privilege of visiting the lions in the Tower, free of
               charge; and the children of our Public Schools should be
               allowed to visit the Governor’s Room on a certain day of the
               week. It is the only free gallery in the city, and should be
               made the most of.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p13">
            <div class="head">WALL STREET ARCHITECTURE.</div>
            
            <p>A block of brick stores has just been built upon the site
               of the old Wall Street Church, in which a novelty in street
               architecture has been introduced, that will probably be extensively copied hereafter. It consists of clustered pillars and
               gothic ornaments, the effect of which is by no means unpleasant. There is now every possible style of architecture in
               Wall Street, excepting only the Egyptian. There are sphinxes at the entrance of some of the banks, we believe, which
               must be owned area very suitable emblem for such a purpose.
               The Cyclopean is the favorite style in this region; and it appears to have been adopted to give an impression of stability
               to the corporations which do their business in the buildings.
               Herodotus relates an anecdote of a certain king who employed
               an architect to build him a treasury for his wealth, which it
               should be secure from thieves. But the architect left a stone
               loose in the building by which means he and his son entered
               it and stole the king’s gold. The public should not place too
               great faith in these Cyclopean structures in Wall street, lest
               there be a loose stone somewhere, through which the contents of the vaults may be abstracted. There are two buildings in Wall street, which are probably the costliest that
               were ever built in any part of the world; the Custom House
               and the Exchange. One is a mountain of granite and the
               other of marble. They will doubtless stand forever, monuments of the inefficiency of mere money to produce anything
               great in art without the assistance of knowledge or genius.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p14">
            <p>Catalogue of the Mercantile Library in New York,
               1844.—The library of this all-important institution now contains 21,000 volumes, the use of which can be had for the
               mere trifle of two dollars the year. We are surprised to
               learn that the members of the association do not increase
               more rapidly. Every merchant in the city should see
               that his clerks are all subscribers to it; and where they
               cannot afford it, it would be to the interest of the employer to present the employed with the necessary funds.
               The present Catalogue is divided into three parts. In the
               first, works are arranged in alphabetical order, under their authors’ names, or, if anonymous, under the leading word in
               the title. In the second, they are classified under general
               heads, which are themselves arranged alphabetically. The
               Classified Catalogue forms an index to the Alphabetical Catalogue, and reference can readily be made from the former to
               the latter, as the first word in the title of every book is the
               same in both. Biographies, only, stand, in the body of the
               Catalogue, under their authors’ names, and, in the index, under the names of their subjects. The third part, or Appendix,
               comprises Novels, which are not in the other divisions of the
               Catalogue.
            </p>
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page77"></div>
         </div>
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div class="piece" id="#p15">
            <p>The Difference.—The Chimes, by Dickens, was sold in
               London at a dollar and a quarter; it is sold here at a sixpence. The London edition is better printed, of course,
               and better bound, with gilt edges, and illustrations; but the
               illustrations are by no means good ones, although they are
               by such celebrated artists as Maclise and Leech. The
               book is about equal to a shilling volume, and the publisher
               and author divide the enormous profits on the sale of the
               Work between them—which is right and proper. Such a
               book, so published, in the United States would not sell at
               all. We doubt whether one copy could be disposed of at
               such a price. Two of our publishers paid thirty dollars each
               for their copies, to the importer; they issued their editions
               at the lowest possible fraction—four cents to the trade; and
               the next day the entire book was reprinted by a newspaper
               publisher and sold for two cents. Knavery and swindling
               can descend no lower. But this is neither knavery nor swindling, but fair and legal trade; by which nobody makes any
               thing, and all for the want of a copyright law. Lawrie Todd
               states that Galt got three thousand guineas from the sale of
               the book of that name; we are informed that Mary Clavers,
               the author of two very popular books, has not received fifteen hundred dollars for all that she has ever written. One
               of the publishing houses that paid thirty dollars for an early
               copy of the Chimes, had the MS. of an original work by an
               American author of established reputation, whose writings
               have been extensively republished in England, offered to
               them gratis, upon condition of their publishing it, and they
               declined it.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="section" id="#s4">
         <div class="head">BITS OF NEWS.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p16">
            <p>Mayor Harper has refused to sign the bill, giving the
               use of the Rotunda, in the Park, to the New York Gallery of
               Fine Arts, because he thinks it would be establishing a bad
               precedent. The reason is a good one. To show the Common Council that it was not owing to hostility to the cause
               of art, the Mayor informed them that he was a member of
               the institution. The price of life-membership is one dollar.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p17">
            <p>John P. Ridner, Esq. of this city, for several years the superintendent of the Apollo Association, has recently been appointed an honorary secretary of the Art-Union of London,
               and is authorised to receive subscriptions for that institution.
               The engraving to be distributed by that association to the
               subscribers of the present year, which will terminate on the
               31st of March next, will be executed by Mr. G. T. Doo, from
               a celebrated painting by W. Mulready, R. A., called “The
               Convalescent.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p18">
            <p>The Harpers, it is said, are going to publish a new work
               by Cornelius Matthews, in April, to be called “Little Abel
               and Great Manhattan.”
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p19">
            <p>Mr. Prescott is engaged upon a new work, the “Conquest of Peru,” which will probably equal in interest his
               last publication.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p20">
            <p>Simms’s Monthly Magazine has just made its appearance
               from the Charleston press. It professes to be a Southern and
               Western Review, and the first article in it is called “Americanism in Literature,” which is chiefly remarkable for containing nothing in relation to that subject. There are papers
               by Mr. Headley and Evert A. Duyckinck, and a few slight
               notices of books by the editor. Mr. Simms complains of the
               great amount of money which the South expends for Northern productions in art and literature, and of the small amount
               which the North pays for Southern works of a like class.
               Probably not without good reason; and if he were earnest in
               his desire to produce a Southern magazine, he should, in his
               initial number at least, have filled his columns with the product of southern pens. The best things in the present number come from the north.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p21">
            <p>It is said that Bishops are going out of fashion. Several
               ladies have been seen in Broadway without these appendages.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div class="section" id="#s5">
         <div class="head">LITERARY NOTICES.</div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p22"> 
            <p>Appleton’s Historical Library. History of France, from the earliest period
               to the present time. By M. Michelet. Translated by G. H. Smith, F.G.S.
               D. Appleton A Co., 200 Broadway. No. 1, pp. 158. Price 25 cents.
            </p>
            
            <p>The merits of Michelet, as a historical writer, are too universally
               well known to require any commendation at this time. The need of a
               work like this has long been felt among English readers, and the
               American publishers have conferred an obligation upon the public by
               the issue of this marvellously cheap edition of a desirable work. The
               present number contains 158 pages in double columns of neatly printed matter. The end of the second book, included in this number,
               reaches to the time of Hugh Capet, and the third begins with a geo.
               graphical picture of France. This cannot fail to be a profitable publication, for even though the publisher should reap no profit from it, the
               public will. We have but one charge to prefer against the publication. It does not inform us where the translation was made. It may
               be inferred from the absence of any note of copyright that it is republished from an English edition; but it is an inference which we have
               no right to draw.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p23">
            <p>Forest Life. By Mrs. Mary Clavers, in two volumes. Farmer &amp; Daggers,
               30 Ann Street.
            </p>
            
            <p>A new edition of a very popular work. Mrs. Clavers was a resident of Michigan when Forest Life first came out, but she is now a
               resident of this city.
            </p>
            
            <p>As a narrative writer she deserves a place at the head of American
               female authors, and as a delineator of character she is greatly in advance of them all. Since her return to city life she has published
               nothing but an occasional sketch in a magazine; but the materials
               for a book are as abundant in our high-ways, as m the by-ways of
               the west. And we hope to see an announcement before long, of a
               work from her hand, sketching the peculiarities of city life, wherein
               she would be free to exercise her fine powers of observation, without
               the fear of displeasing one of their high mightinesses, the editors of
               the pictorial magazines. It is not a little remarkable that these gentlemen are extremely fond of tales of love, seeing that they generally
               have so so little of that commodity themselves, excepting for themselves.	
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p24">
            <p>Uncle Peter’s Fairy Tales. Farmer &amp; Daggers, 30 Ann Street.</p>
            
            <p>This little book was designed for English children between the ages
               of eight and fourteen, and it contains too many local allusions, we
               should think, to prove a very profitable book for readers of the same
               age on this side the Atlantic. It is not as prettily printed as a book of
               Fairy Tales should be, but well enough for the price asked for it. It
               has several entirely unpronounceable names in it, which will render it
               less acceptable to those for whom it was designed than it would otherwise be, Children being very delicate critics, and requiring the purest
               and most idiomatic English in their reading. In other respects it is a
               delightful work of the class to which it belongs; and a friend, in
               whose judgment we have implicit faith, says that he pities any grown
               up man who is not fascinated by it.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div id="#25">
            <p>Poor Jack, Illustrated with Wood Cuts from designs by Stansfield: Farmer
               &amp; Daggers, 30 Ann Street.
            </p>
            
            <p>Poor Jack is the best of Captain Marryatt’s sea stories—novels is
               not the right names for books like his. We have always felt exceedingly mortified to hear him abused by our countrymen, who appear to
               have strangely misunderstood his character. Captain Marryatt is a
               genuine sailor; there’s nothing about him but suffers a sea change.
               He must not be judged by the standards by which other men are
               measured. As a delineator of the sailor character, he has never been
               approached, but they are not sailors only that he has delineated;
               sailor’s wives, children, tradesmen, in short, all who live by navigation, from the bum-boat women to the ship carpenter, are all presented in his pages with the truthfulness of a daguerreotype. His
               stories are all clumsily constructed, but we read them, not for the sake
               of the plot, but for the characters which they contain, as we read
               Shakspeare’s historical tragedies.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p26">
            <p>Lawrie Todd. By John Galt, with an original preface by Grant Thorburn.
               New York : Farmer &amp;c Daggers, 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>We have here a new edition of this once popular work, with a preface from the Original who furnished the author with the hints for his
               volume. Mr. Thorburn informs us that Galt received three thousand
               pounds from the sale of this work alone. An incredible sum, considering the character of the book. If the author had accomplished no 
               <div class="pagebreak" id="#page78"></div>
               
               
               <div class="columnbreak"></div>other good by writing this book, it was enough to have made a simplehearted old man perfectly happy. Mr. Thorbumhas grown fat, figuratively, upon the reputation of Lawrie Todd; he looks as smiling as
               one of his own perennials whenever any one asks him if he was really
               the Original of Gall’s hero. The career of Mr. Thorburn has been an
               exceedingly common one, and it is proof of his simple heartedness
               that he regards himself as an evidence of divine goodness, in having
               attained to the venerable age of seventy-two. But we have known a
               parrot that attained to a greater age even than that.
            </p>
            
            <p>While Mr. Thorburn lives, Lawrie Todd will find plenty of readers,
               and when he shall be numbered among the departed, a long time
               hence, we hope, Lawrie Todd will preserve his memory to another
               generation.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p27">
            <p>The Book of British Ballads. New York: James W. Judd &amp; Co., New
               World Press.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is a reprint from Mr. Hall's illustrated edition, with a very sensible and straight forward introduction by Park Benjamin. The Ballads are fifty-two in number; some of them, but not all, the best in
               the language. Mr. Hall’s book was a very costly one, and probably
               the best specimen of illustration in wood cuts ever published in England; and we have no doubt but that a republication of the prints
               would have been profitable here. It is the designs, more than the cuts,
               which make the high cost of illustrated books, and as these could
               have been got for nothing, we regret that the experiment was not
               tried of publishing a fac simile. The book is a valuable one as it is,
               and we are glad to learn that the Editor has found it a profitable one.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p28">
            <p>Mike Martin, or the Last of the Highwaymen. By F. A. Durivage.
               Boston: Charles H. Brainard &amp; Co., 1845.
            </p>
            
            <p>This is the story of an Irish pick-pocket of the same name, who
               was hung in Boston twenty-three years ago. His confession was very
               ample and romantic, and Mr. Durivage has worked it up into a romance of the Jack Sheppard school. Such characters, if held up in a
               proper light, may do good after their execution, to others besides the
               surgeon; but when made the heroes of romance, there is but too much
               danger that their evils will live after them. The rope that ends their
               lives does not always end their mischiefs. All writers who take a
               thief for their hero, should also take the History of Jonathan Wild for
               their model.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p29">
            <p>Punch’s Snapdragon. Farmer &amp; Daggers, 30 Ann Street.</p>
            
            <p>Some two or three hundred years hence, Punch will be looked upon
               as a veritable personage, and learned lecturers will read essays before
               Village Lyceums on his life and times. One half the good things attributed to Rabelais are as old as Herodotus; but there seems to be
               a disposition with the world to father upon one individual all its jokes
               and smart sayings. Punch’s Snap-Dragon, as republished, is a rich
               two shillings’ worth of fun and satire
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p30">
            <p>Manners and Customs of Nations. Parley’s Cabinet Library, Part I. John
               Allen, 139 Nassau St. New-York.
            </p>
            
            <p>This well known series of children’s books has reached the seventeenth number, which is now before us. The frontispiece is a well cut
               wood engraving of a street scene in Paris, which gives a lively and
               truthful representation of one of the picturesque views in the French
               Capital.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p31">
            <p>The Southern Quarterly Review for January, contains the following
               articles:
            </p>
            
            <p>Education in Europe by D. K. Whitaker, the Sieur de la Salle, by J.
               D. B. De Bowe. Literature of the Bible, by Rev. Dr. Hamilton of
               Mobile. Life and Writings of Rabelais, by G. F. Holmes. La Havane, by Hon. A. H. Everett, Works of Wilhelm Hauff,by Miss M. E.
               Lee, Miss Gray’s History of Etruria, and Memoirs of Aaron Burr, by
               F. B. Porter of Tuscaloosa.
            </p>
         </div>   
         
         <div class="piece" id="#p32">
            <p>Chemistry, as exemplifing the Wisdom and Beneficence of God. By Geo.
               Fownes, Ph. D., F. R.S., etc. In 1 vol. small 8vo. Price 50 cents. Wiley
               and Putnam.
            </p>
            
            <p>Works of this class are valuable only for whatever positive information they may contain. If such a project for impressing men with an
               idea of God’s power were carried out, as that proposed in the Bridgewater treatises, and other works of a similar kind, every object in creation from an ant to an elephant, and every member of every animal
               would require a separate volume, before the plan could be complete.
               But we trust that the perception of mankind is not yet so completely
               blunted, as to require this kind of pointing to the wisdom of God, as
               displayed in his works.
            </p>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div class="piece" id="#p33">
         <div class="head">THE CONCERT ROOM.</div>
         
         <p>The New York Vocal Society.—After endeavoring to correct existing abuses, the next duty of a journalist is to call the attention of
            the public to any thing which may be in operation for its benefit ox
            amusement. We regret to say that even when awakened, the public
            is but too often neglectful of much that is truly excellent, unless it
            happens to hit decidedly the taste or fashion of the moment, irrespective of its merits or its tendency. Such is the case, unfortunately, with
            the Society in question, for although its objects are of the highest musical importance, and its performance fully equal to the noble works
            it executed, yet it has asked in vain for public sympathy and support.
            We cannot account for this lukewarmness, otherwise than that it has
            not yet become the fashion to admire classical Vocal Music. To repine
            at this want of appreciation, is vain; to remonstrate, useless; we can
            only hope that taste will be of a rapid and healthy growth, far outstripping the petty brushwood and creeping parasites, which encumber
            it with rank luxuriance.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Vocal Society was founded in the early part of the year 1843.
            Mr. George Loder, we believe, originated the idea, and on suggesting
            it to some musical friends, a meeting of the profession was called, and
            after some discussion, it was determined to establish a society, for the
            purpose of practising and performing the highest class of Vocal Concerted Music, whether Glees, Quartettes, &amp;c., or Chorusses. The Society to be called the New York Vocal Society, and to consist of Professors of Music, with a due proportion of amateurs, Ladies and Gentlemen. Both professor and amateurs to be vocalists, of course. A
            Constitution was then formed, and the Society met for practice, after
            electing a President, in the person of Fanning C. Tucker, Esq.
         </p>
         
         <p>Having seen it fairly started upon its doubtful voyage, we will examine the materials of which it was composed, for upon these depended
            its durability and the success of its undertaking. Among the Ladies of
            the orchestra, were Mrs. Edw. Loder, Mrs. Burkhardt, Mrs. Weidenhoffer, Mrs. W. A. King, the Misses Watson, DeLuce, Cumming,
            Windmuller, &amp;c. Among the gentlemen, were Messrs. G. Loder,
            Timm, H. C. Watson, Alpers, W. A. King, Beames, Maynard, Massett, Kyle, J. A. Kyle, Ensign, Ives, Reiff, with many others, equal in
            every way to their duties.
         </p>
         
         <p>From such an array of names, it would appear to us that the public
            should have placed unlimited confidence in the stability and sterling
            excellence of the undertaking, to which these names were appended
            as a guarantee. But on glancing over the list, the eye dwelt not upon
            a long array of Madames and Signors! they were, alas! but simple
            Mistress, Miss, or Mister! Was it to be credited that any vocal music worth the hearing, could proceed from throats neither Italianized
            nor Frenchified—in short, from throats where the nightingale never
            nestled? The idea could not for one moment be entertained; and so
            the Vocal Society was left to struggle, unaided and unsheltered by
            public fostering, against every difficulty. It did struggle, however, and
            manfully too, for, by the self-sacrifice of the principal professors, assisted by the amateur members, and some twenty subscribers, (we
            should like to publish their names, that they might be honored as true
            lovers of music) four admirable Concerts were given in 1843-4, and the
            first season concluded, leaving the Society free from debt. This was
            a great achievement, considering the adverse circumstances; but the
            Society had made nothing: no dividend was paid to the actual members,
            and the hopeful spirit (a vile spirit of gain!) was dead in the breasts of
            many of them, and their interest in the Society (monied interest) had
            ceased forever. Had there been but a dividend of two dollars each, it
            would have served to have kept up the spirit of hope among the mercenary, and have induced them to cling to the Society for the shadowy
            chances of the future. Those who sacrificed time and money to sustain the character of the Society, were by no means disheartened.
            they did not labor for a consideration; the Art and its interests animated their endeavors throughout, and neither the want of appreciation
            in the public, nor the lukewarmness, and even treachery of some of its
            own body, could induce them to slacken their efforts in what they
            deemed a just cause.
         </p>
         
         <p>We will give a brief account of the works which were performed at
            the four Concerts of this Society. Some twenty of the finest English
            and Italian madrigals were performed in a manner never equalled in
            this country; several exquisite glees, both English and German; two
            grand pieces, called Psalms, by Spohr, beside selections from the Last
            Judgment, and smaller pieces by the same great composer; a wonderful composition called the Forty Second Psalm, and an exquisite Ave
            Maria, by Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, also pieces by Haydn, Hummel, Weber, and many other great names. The most important of 
            <div class="pagebreak" id="#page79"></div>
            
            
            <div class="columnbreak"></div>these pieces were produced by the Vocal Society for the first time in
            this country, which would in any other land he more than sufficient to
            establish firmly its high character in the public estimation. The vocal
            performances, as may be imagined from the well-known abilities of its
            members, were admirable in every respect. All the competent judges
            Who attended the concerts, were unanimous in saying, that concerted
            vocal music had never before been heard to such perfection in this
            country.	
         </p>
         
         <p>We shall, in a future number, discuss its prospects for this its second
            season, and place in a prominent view its advantages as a school for
            classical music.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p34">
         <div class="head">CORRESPONDENCE.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">Dear Mr. Editor.</div>
         
         <p>My brother did not expect that you would print his letter about
            the boys, and we have had the laugh on him all the week; they have
            been at a Polka party every night since, which has made him dreadfully out of temper. But I tell him that there is a certain quantity of
            nonsense in every man, and that it is much better it should evaporate
            in his youth, when frivolousness seems natural, than to be locked up
            by restraint until he gets old, and then burst out when nobody expects
            it. For my own part, I despise a frivolous old man, as much as I do a
            grave young one; and I am well pleased to see the boys follow the
            course of nature, and dance before they get too heavy. Of all things
            ] dislike to see a stout old gentleman in a cotillion.
         </p>
         
         <p>But there is one thing, Mr. Editor, which I wish you would attend
            to—Punning. A gentleman who visits our house, puns about everything. I cannot open my mouth, but he answers me with a pun. I am
            sure it is dreadful uncivil; don’t you think so? Dr. Johnson, I have
            been told, said that a man who would make a pun upon another’s name
            would pick a pocket. And really, the gentleman I allude to, makes
            such dreadful puns about everybody, that I have thought it best to
            lock up all my trinkets whenever he calls upon us. Can’t you write
            something very severe about this vile habit? I am afraid that I shall
            fall into it myself, if I admit the punning gentleman into my company
            any more. I have written off a long list of his puns, which I mean to
            send you, to satisfy you of the enormity of his offence. What makes
            it more singular, is the fact, that none of us ever laugh at his puns, although he always laughs himself. Your friend,
         </p>
         <span class="person">Mary Ann P.</span>
         
         <div class="note">P.S. We have lost three silver mugs lately; do you think that the
            punning visitor could have taken them?
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p35">
         <div class="head">A PAINTER’S SKETCH.</div>
         
         <div class="lg"><br>In search of brighter clime or sky
            <br>Still let the restless wanderer roam,
            <br>No fairer meets the painter’s eye
            <br>Than mantles o’er our English home.
            <br>Green are our woods, and sweeter stream!
            <br>Ne’er onward rolled in brighter beams.
            <br>More varied scenes what land can boast,
            <br>From castled craig to mountain vale?
            <br>Field, forest, sea-encircled coast,
            <br>The pencil charm: the pictured tale
            <br>Of sun and shade, of shifting skies,
            <br>No fairer clime than ours supplies.
            <br>Dear is the woodland cot, where trees,
            <br>Low bending o’er the rushy brook,
            <br>Fling their wild branches to the breeze,
            <br>Around the hereditary nook;
            <br>While chequered sunbeams trembling throw
            <br>Above the thatch, a golden glow.
            <br>If to thine eye be dearer still
            <br>The riven craig or crumbling wall.
            <br>The leaping foam from mountain rill,
            <br>Or deepest glen or loftiest fall,
            <br>Or hoary castle, dim and gray,
            <br>That mournful mocks the eye of day;
            <br>Turn to the wilds in northern land,
            <br>Whose circling mountains shroud the sky—
            <br>From snowy wreath and icy band,
            <br>Mysterious grandeur frowns on high—
            <br>Ben Nevis hoarsely shouts aloud,
            <br>And Lomond answers from its cloud.
            <br>Fill from the farthest spring of Thames,
            <br>And pledge Old England’s wide domain;
            <br>Fill to the high and honoured names
            <br>Which Genius hallows—not in vain—
            <br>Since bounding hearts in worship burn,
            <br>Before each consecrated urn.
         </div>
         
         <div class="byline"><span class="person">W. H. CROME.</span></div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p36">
         <p>Notice to Readers and Correspondents.—Our promised Engraving of " a Suspended Bishop,” ice are compelled to omit this week
            in consequence of an accident to the artist who had it in hand. It will
            be given next week.
         </p>
         
         <p>The communication of  "G. H. S.’’ "Somerville and " G. T.” are left
            at the desk of our publishing office.
         </p>
         
         <p>In reply to " E. V."  we pay for all communications that are worth pay,
            according to agreement. We shall be happy to receive his sketches.
         </p>
         
         <p>The letter of Dr. Doom was intended for our last week's paper, but it
            arrived too late.
         </p>
      </div>
      
      
      <div class="columnbreak"></div>
      <div class="section" id="#s6">
         <div>
            <div class="head">HUNT’S MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE
               and commercial review.
            </div>
            
            <p>BY FREEMAN HUNT, Editor and Proprietor. Published Monthly, at 142 Fulton Street, New York—at Five Dollars
               per annum, in Advance.
            </p>
            
            <p>THE MERCHANTS’ MAGAZINE and COMMERCIAL REVIEW embraces every subject connected with Commerce, Manufactures and Political Economy, as follows Commercial Legislation;
               Commercial History and Geography; Mercantile Biography; Descriptive Statistical and Historical Accounts, of the various commodities which form the subject of Mercantile transactions; Port Charges;
               Tariffs Customs and Excise Regulations; Commercial Statistics of
               the United States and the different countries of the world, with which
               we have intercourse, including their Physical Character, Population,
               Productions, Exports, Imports, Seaports. Monies, Weights, Measures
               Finance and Banking Associations, and Enterprises connected with
               Commerce embracing Fisheries, Incorporated Companies, Railroads,
               Canals Steamboats. Docks, Post Offices, &amp;c.; Principles of Com.
               merce, Finance and Banking, with Practical and Historical Details
               and Illustrations; Commercial Law, and Mercantile Law Reports, and
               Decisions of Courts in the United States and Europe, including Insurance Partnership, Principal and Agent, Bills of Exchange, Sale,
               Guaranty Bankruptcy. Shipping and Navigation, &amp;c., and whatever
               else shall tend to develope the resources of the country and the
               world and illustrate the various topics bearing upon Commerce and
               Commercial Literature.
            </p>
            
            <p>It has been, and will continue to be, the aim of the Editor and Proprietor of the Merchants’ Magazine, to avoid every thing of a par.
               tv political, or sectional bias or bearing, in the conduct of the work
               —opening its pages to the free and fair discussion of antagonistic doctrines connected with the great interests of Commerce, Agriculture,
               Manufactures and the Currency.
            </p>
            
            <p>Complete sets of the MERCHANTS’ Magazine, embracing eleven
               semi-annual volumes, of about 600 large octavo pages each, bringing
               it down to December, 1S44, inclusive, may be obtained at the Pub-
               lisher’s Office, 142 Fulton-street, New-York, at the subscription price.
            </p>
            
            <p> Publishers of newspapers, in the United States, by giving this
               advertisement two or three insertions, and remitting Two Dollars to
               the Proprietor, will be entitled to the Magazine for one year.
            </p>
            
            <p>Office of Merchants’ Magzine, January 1st, 1845.</p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">JOHN DOUGLAS,
               BOOK AND JOB PRINTER,
            </div>
            
            <p>No. 68 ANN STREET, one door from Gold. Every de scription of Printing, both Letter-Press and Stereotype, executed
               with neatness, accuracy, and despatch, on terms which he feels confident will be satisfactory to those who employ him.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">January 16,1845.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">LEWIS EATEN, SIGN AND ORNAMENTAL PAINTER,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 45 WILLIAM STREET,
               <br>(basement of the leather manufacturers’ bank.)
               <br>Block Letter Signs, Transparencies, Banners, &amp;c., Executed in the
               <br>neatest manner.
            </div>
         </div>
         	
         <div>
            <div class="head">Dr. Arnold's Life and correspondence.</div>
            
            <p>D APPLETON &amp; CO. have just published, THE LIFE
               .AND CORRESPONDENCE OF THOMAS ARNOLD, D.D.
               By Rev. E. P. Stanley, M.A. From the Third English Edition, 2 vols.
               8vo. in 1 vol. 12mo. Price $1 50.
            </p>
            	  
            <p>The Life of Dr. Arnold will be found to be of unusual value and interest to all literary persons, Heads of Colleges and Seminaries of
               Learning Students and Teachers in public and private schools.
            </p>
            	  
            <p>No considerable review in England, representing either the high or
               low parties in Church or State—no weekly or daily publication has
               failed to express the wonderful power and beauty of this volume of
               Biography.
            </p>
            	  
            <p>NEW HISTORY OF THE FRENCH REVOLUTION. D. Appleton and Co. have recently published—History of the
               French Revolution—its causes and consequences; by F. Maclean Rowan; 2 vols  18mo, cloth 75 cts., or 1 vol. 63 cts.
            </p>
            	  
            <p>“This work has many and valuable recommendations. Its compilation has been effected with care and good judgment; its style is essentially popular, its arrangements clear and methodical, and the
               whole form as condensed, comprehensive, and succinct a history of the
               most important event of this age, (both in itself and its consequences,)
               as we remember to have seen in so brief a space.”—English Critic,
               Sept. 16, 1844.
            </p>
            	  
            <p>In a few days, Part 2, price 25 cents—
               HISTORY OF FRANCE, from the earliest period;
               translated from the French of M. Michelet, by G. H. Smith.
            </p>
            
            <p>The celebrity of this work on the continent, and the want in English
               literature of a good history of France, has induced the publishers to
               introduce it to the American public at a price within the means of ail.
            </p>
         </div>
         <div class="pagebreak" id="#page80"></div>
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">DISEASES OF THE TEETH.</div>
            
            <div class="ab">Washington, D. C., May, 1844.</div>
            
            <p>THE neglect of the Teeth is the cause of much suffering
               and regret, and should not be disregarded by the most thoughtless.
               The undersigned having received the benefit of Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s
               professional skill, and believing him well qualified in the science of
               Dental Surgery, and an accomplished and skillful operator, we most
               cheerfully certify to the ease and safety with which Dr. B. performs
               the various and important operations, so essential to the usefulness,
               durability, and beauty of the Teeth.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">   Hon. J. W. M. Berrien, Geo.                Hon. John B. Dawson, La,
               <br>Joshua Herrick, Me.	                      John H. Lumpkin, Geo.
               <br>James Irvin, Pa.	                          J. Thompson, Miss.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">Dr. A. G. Bigelow’s Office and Residence, 103 Liberty st., New York.</div>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">PROPOSALS FOR PUBLISHING BY SUBSCRIPTION,
                               TRANSACTIONS
                                  OF THE
                     Ethnological Society of New York.
            </div>
            
            <div class="ab">VOLUME I.</div>
            
            <p>THIS volume will consist of articles by members of the
               _L Ethnological Society, relating to various topics of interest to the
               Antiquary and Philologist. It will consist of from four to five hundred
               pages 8vo., printed on good paper and in the best manner.
            </p>
            
            <p>A number of engravings illustrative of the several papers, will ac-
               company the volume.
            </p>
            
            <div class="ab">CONTENTS OF THE VOLUME.</div>
            
            <div class="ab"><br>Art. I. Notes on the Semi-civilized Nations of Mexico, Yucatan, and
               <br>Central America. By Albert Gallatin.
               <br>Sec. 1st. Languages.—Vocabularies, grammar, derived and com-
               <br>pounded words.
               <br>2d. Numeration.—Vigintesimal.
               <br>3d. Calendars and Astronomv.—Mexico, Yucatan, Chiapas.
               <br>—Extent of Astronomical knowledge.
               <br>4th. History and Chronology.—Paintings designating years;
               <br>only four known—Tradition; early writers discussed—
               <br>Uncertainty of dates and events. 
               <br>5th. Conjectures on origin of semi-civilization in Ameri-
               <br>ca.—America inhabited at a very early dale.—Astrono-
               <br>my.—Agriculture.—Extinct race.
               <br>No. 1. Appendix.—Grammatical notices.—Mexican, Tarasca,
               <br>Ottomi, Maya, Guatemala, Huestaca.
               <br>No. 2. " Notes on Lord Kingsborough’s collection.
               <br>—All paintings, but one, Mexican.—All but four relate to
               <br>Mythology and Judicial Astrology.—Codices Borgianus
               <br>and Vaticanus.
               <br>Art. II. An Essay on the Grave-Creek Mound in the Ohio Valley—
               <br>By Henry R. Schoolcraft, embracing:
               <br>1st. A description of the Tumulus, its dimensions and mode of
               <br>structure.
               <br>2d. An accurate drawing and description of the Inscription found
               <br>in one of the vaults.
               <br>3d. Other antiquarian articles disclosed by the opening of that
               <br>mound, or found in other parts of the Grave-Creek Valley
               <br>and its neighborhood.
               <br>4th. Conjectures upon the character of the Alphabet, and the
               <br>probable era of the Inscription, &amp;c. The whole illustrated
               <br>with carefully executed plates.
               <br>Art. III. A Dissertation on some curious evidences of an Era of An-
               <br>cient Semi-civilization in the West, noticed in the progress
               <br>of settlements in the Mississippi Valley and the Lakes. By
               <br>Henry R. Schoolcraft.
               <br>Description of some extensive Horticultural Beds and Furrows,
               <br>found in the prairies and forests of the Lake Region, about
               <br>the latitude of the sources of the Illinois and St. Joseph’s,
               <br>with an engraving.
               <br>Art. IV. An account of Ancient Remains in Tennessee. By Gerard
               <br>Troost, M. D.. Prof, of Chemistry, Geology, &amp;c. in the
               <br>University of Tennessee.
               <br>1.	The Mummies found in the Saltpetre Caves, with conjectures
               <br>as to their antiquity.
               <br>2.	The ancient Burial Places.
               <br>3.	Traces of Phallic Worship among a people once occupying that
               <br>section of country.
               <br>Art. V. On the recent discoveries of Himyaritic Inscriptions, and the
               <br>attempt made to decipher them. By Wm. W. Turner.
               <br>Kingdom of the Himyarites.—Discovery of Inscriptions.
               <br>Himyaritic Alphabet.—Alphabets found in Manuscripts—
               <br>Alphabets from the Inscriptions.—Ethiopic Alphabets.
               <br>Himyaritic Language.—Ehkili Language.—General results.
               <br>Art. VI. A visit to the Lybio-Phanician Monument at Dugga, near
               <br>the site of ancient Carthage. By Frederic Catherwood.
               <br>With an account of the inscription; and a view and ground
               <br>plan of this ancient and interesting monument.
               <br>Art. VII. An Account of the Serreculies, or Serranalies, with hints re-
               <br>specting several other tribes or families of people composing
               <br>the Fullah nation, and those inhabiting the neighboring
               <br>Counties of Western Nigritia. By Theodore Dwight, Jr.
               <br>1.	The statements of authors respecting the Serreculies.
               <br>2.	The Geography, History, Learning, Arts, &amp;c., of the Serrecu-
               <br>lies.
               <br>3.	Their Language.
               <br>4.	Remarks on Neighboring Nations and Tribes.
            </div>
            
            <p>Subscriptions received by BARTLETT &amp; WELFORD, Booksellers
               and Importers, 7 Astor House, New-York.	J
            </p>
         </div>
         
         
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>
         <div>
            <div class="head">PLUMBE DAGUERRIAN GALLERY</div>
            
            <p>AND PHOTOGRAPHIC DEPOT, 251 Broadway,
               Corner of Murray street, (Over Tenny’s Jewelry Store,) awarded
               the Medal, four first Premiums, and two “Highest Honors," at the
               Exhibitions at Boston, New York, and Philadelphia, respectively, for
               the best pictures and apparatus ever exhibited.
            </p>
            
            <p>Price of these superb Photographs reduced to that of ordinary ones
               at other places, so that no one need now sit for an inferior likeness on
               the score of economy.
            </p>
            
            <p>N. B.—Imported German Cameras, also French and American Instruments of the very best quality, with plates, cases, chemical polishing materials, &amp;c., kept constantly on hand. All orders received
               promptly attended to.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="head">Mrs. Sigourney’s Pictorial Reader.</div>
            
            <p>THE PICTORIAL READER, for the Use of Schools, consisting of Original Articles for the Instruction of Young Children.
               By Mrs. L. H. Sigourney. Being an Introduction to the Boy’s Reading Book and Girl’s Reading Book, by the same author. Illustrated
               by nearly One Hundred and Fifty Engravings. A very interesting and
               instructive Book for Children, whether in school or out. Published by
               TURNER &amp; HAYDEN. No. 10 John Street,
               And for sale by all the Booksellers.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div>
            <div class="note" type="headnote">The First Premium awarded five years by the American Institute for
               the best Specimen of Off-hand Penmanship.
            </div>
            
            <div class="head">GOLDSMITH’S WRITING AND BOOK-KEEPING ACADEMY,</div>
            
            <div class="ab">NO. 189 BROADWAY, NEW YORK.</div>
            
            <p>GOLDSMITH’S PREMIUM SYSTEM of Mercantile and Epistolary Writing, guaranteed to all (old and young)
               in 10 lessons el one hour each. Terms—Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>Double Entry Book-Keeping, Fifteen Dollars, for a thorough
               course of instruction, including mercantile arithmetic,also Blanks and
               Stationary. Payable at the commencement.
            </p>
            
            <p>Class Hours—9 A. M., 3, 5 3-4, and 8 P. M. daily for gentlemen,
               and from 11 to 1 o’clock for ladies. Private instruction given.
            </p>
            
            <p>For sale “Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,” elegantly bound.
               Price Five Dollars.
            </p>
            
            <p>From the Courier and Enquirer, July 27,1844.
               Goldsmith’s Gems of Pennmanship.—The Chirographic art is
               much more important to mankind than it is generally considered, and
               Mr. Goldsmith may well claim to be considered at its head. The
               volume before us exhibits more taste and ingenuity, and higher proofs
               of manual dexterity than we have ever seen before -
            </p>
            
            <p>From the New York Express.
               Goldsmith’s Gems of Penmanship,—We have seen the original, as
               executed by his own hand, and a more beautiful, and indeed a more
               wonderful display of the power of that little instrument which is said
               to be “ more potent than the sword,” we never witnessed before.
            </p>
         </div>
         
         <div> 
            <div class="ab">CHARLES PERABEAU, Professor of Music,
               <br>No. 9 Whitehall Street, Nac York.
            </div>
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div class="piece" id="#p37">
         <div class="head">Prospectus of the Broadway Journal.</div>
         
         <div class="ab">To be Published every Saturday.</div>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will differ from any of the weekly Periodicals now published in this city, as it will be made up entirely of
            original matter, consisting of Essays, Criticisms on Art and Literature,
            Domestic and Foreign Correspondence, and Literary and Scientific
            Intelligence.
         </p>
         
         <p>Illustrations will be given as often as good original Designs can
            be procured, and drawings and plans of all new public buildings that
            have either elegance or novelty to recommend them to notice. Particular attention will be given to this department, and no pains spared
            to make it worthy of patronage.
         </p>
         
         <p>Efficient aid has already been secured in the services of some of the
            best writers in the country; but it is hoped that a free channel being opened through which true-hearted men may “let loose their
            thoughts,” will be the means of drawing out some of the slumbering
            talent amongst us which has not yet been seen afloat on the surface of
            our periodical literature.
         </p>
         
         <p>The Broadway Journal will espouse the cause of no political party, but will hold itself free to condemn or approve any men or measures, that a patriotic regard for the welfare of the country may dictate.
            It will be printed on fine paper with clear type, in the Octave form of
            16 pages, double columns.
         </p>
         
         <div class="ab">Terms $3,00 per annum—Single numbers 6 1-4 cts.
            <br>A liberal discount to Periodical Agents.
            <br>All Communications for the Editor must be addressed to the Editor
            <br>of the Broadway Journal, and all letters on business to
            <br>JOHN BISCO, Publisher, 153 Broadway.
         </div>
      </div>
      
      <div>
         <div class="ab">John Douglas, Printer, 68 Ann Street.</div>
      </div>
      
   </div>
   <div class="back">
      <a href="#a001"> Link </a><div class="note" id="n001">
         <p>The narrative is a very curious one, and brings before us “the form and
            pressure” of the period, with all the natural incidents of such an event. It
            may serve, while it fixes the reader’s attention profitably upon this class of
            occurrences, to relieve by its historic distance, the painfulness of the more
            recent misfortune. We follow the old English of Lord Berner’s translation,
            modernizing the spelling.
         </p> 
         <div class="columnbreak"></div>  
         <p>"It fortuned that a marriage was made in the king’s house between a
            young knight of Vermandois and one of the Queen’s gentlewomen; and because they were both of the king’s house, the king’s uncles, and other lords,
            ladies, and damsels made great triumph; there were the dukes of Orleans,
            Berry, and Burgundy, and their wives, dancing and making great joy. The
            king made a great supper to the lords and ladies, and the queen kept her
            estate, desiring everyone to be merry : and there was a squire of Normandy,
            called Hogreymen of Gensay, who advised to make some pastime. The day
            of the marriage, which was on a Tuesday before Candelmas, he provided for
            a mummery against night: he devised six coats made of linen cloth, covered
            with pitch, and thereon flax like hair, and had them ready in a chamber. The
            king put on one of them, and the Earl of Jouy, a young lusty knight, another,
            and Sir Charles Poictiers the third, who was son to the Earl of Valentinois,
            and Sir Evan of Foix another, and the son of th6 Lord Nantouillet had
            on the fifth, and the squire himself had on the sixth, and when they were
            thus arrayed in these said coats, and sewed fast in them, they seemed like
            wild savages full of hair from the top of the head to the sole of the foot. This
            device pleased well the French king, who was well content with the Squire
            for it. They were apparelled in these coats secretly in a chamber that no man
            knew thereof but such as helped them. When Sir Evan of Foix had well advised those coats, he said to the king, “Sire, command straitly that no man
            approach near us with any torches or fire, for if the fire fasten on any of
            these coats, we shall all be burnt without remedy.” The king answered and
            said, “Evan, you speak well and wisely: it shall be done as you have devised,” and incontinent sent for an Usher of his chamber, commanding him
            to go into the chamber where the ladies danced, and to command all the
            varlets holding torches to stand up by the walls, and none of them to approach near to the savages that should come thither to dance. The usher end
            the king’s commandment, which was fulfilled. Soon after the Duke of Orleans entered into the hall, accompanied with four knights and six torches,
            and knew nothing of the king’s commandment for the torches, nor of the
            mummery that was coming thither, but thought to behold the dancing, and
            began himself to dance. Therewith the king with the five other came in;
            they were so disguised in flax that no man knew them; five of them were
            fastened one to another: the king was loose, and went before, and led the
            device.
         </p>
         
         <p>“When they entered the hall every man took so great heed to them that
            they forgot their torches. The king departed from his company, and went
            with the ladies to sport with them, as youth required, and so passed by the
            queen and came to the Duchess of Berry, who took and held him by the arm
            to know what he was; but the king would not show his name. Then the
            duchess said, “ You shall not escape me till I know your name.” In the mean
            season great mischief fell on the other, and by reason of the Duke of Orleans;
            howbeit it was by ignorance, and against his will, for if he had considered
            before the mischief that fell, he would not have done as he did for all the
            gold in the world: but he was so desirous to know what personages the five
            were who danced, he put one of the torches that his servant held so near,
            that the heat of the fire entered into the flax (wherein if fire take there is no
            remedy) and suddenly was on a bright flame, and so each of them set fire on
            one another; the pitch was so fastened to the linen cloth, and their shirts so
            dry and fine, and so joining to their flesh, that they began to bum and to cry
            tor help. None durst come near them. They that did, burnt their hands, by
            reason of the heat of the pitch. One of them, called Nantouillet, advised him
            that the buttery was thereby. He fled thither and cast himself into a vessel
            full of water, wherein they rinsed pots, which saved him, or else he had been
            dead as the others were. Yet he was sore burnt with the fire. When the
            queen heard the cry that they made, she doubted of the king, for she knew
            well that he should be one of the six: wherewith she fell in a swoon, and
            knights and ladies came and comforted her. A piteous noise there was in the
            hall. The Duchess of Berry delivered the king from peril, for she did cast over
            him the train of her gown, and covered him from the fire. The king would
            have gone from her. ‘ Whither will you go?’ quoth she, ‘ you see well how
            your company burns. What are ye?’ 'I am the king.’ quoth he. ‘Haste you,’
            quoth she, ‘ and get you into other apparel, that the queen may see you, for
            she is in great fear of you.' Therewith the king departed out of the hall, and
            in all haste changed his apparel, and came to the queen; and the Duchess of
            Berry had somewhat comforted her, and had shewed her how she should see
            the king shortly: therewith the king came to the queen; and as soon as she
            saw him, for joy she embraced him and fell in a swoon; then she was borne
            unto her chamber, and the king went with her. And the bastard of Foix, who
            was all on fire, cried out with a loud voice. ‘Save the king, save the
            king!' "
         </p>	
      </div>
   </div>
</div>